AN INDEPENDENT SAFETY AGENCY.
WE WILL REVIEW ALL AVAILABLE INFORMATION IN
MAKING A JUDGMENT AS TO WHETHER THE PLANT
WOULD MEET SAFETY STANDARDS IF RESTART WERE
PERMITTED.
WHAT DO YOU WANT TO SEE THE NRC DO?
>> >>GUEST SPEAKER: I DON'T THINK EDISON'S
BEEN OPEN AND HONEST WITH THE NRC OR WITH
THE PEOPLE IN SOUTHERN CALIFORNIA.
SO IT'S HARD TO LET A PLANT RUN WHEN THE OWNER
OF THE PLANT HASN'T BEEN OPEN AND HONEST.
>> >>AMITA: ARNIE, THANK YOU FOR SPEAKING
TO US TODAY.
>> >>DWANE: AN ANNUAL REPORT ON DRUG VIOLENCE
IN MEXICO SAYS THE PROBLEM APPEARS TO BE IMPROVING.
THE STUDY COMES FROM THE UNIVERSITY OF SAN
DIEGO'S TRANS BORDER INSTITUTE.
FRONTERAS REPORTER ADRIAN FLORIDO JOINS US
FROM THE NEWS CENTER.
HOW BIG OF A DECLINE ARE WE TALKING ABOUT?
>> >>GUEST SPEAKER: WELL, AT THE END OF 2011,
THE REPORT THAT THE USD PUTS OUT EVERY YEAR
SAID THAT DRUG VILE NS WAS STILL INCREASING
IN MEXICO, BUT IT SEEMS TO BE LEVELING OFF.
IT WAS INCREASING AT A SLOWER RATE THAN IT
HAD AT YEARS PAST.
THIS YEAR THEY'RE SAYING IT MIGHT HAVE DECREASED
IN 2011 THERE WERE 27,000 HOMICIDES IN MEXICO.
THIS LAST YEAR THERE WERE ESTIMATED TO BE
ABOUT 20 TO 25,000 NATIONALLY.
>> >>DWANE: DO WE KNOW HOW MANY OF THOSE WERE
DRUG RELATED MURDERS?
>> >>GUEST SPEAKER: IT'S ALWAYS KIND OF TRICKY
TO TELL BECAUSE IT'S DIFFICULT DATA TO COLLECT.
IT WAS ESPECIALLY TRICKY FOR THE RESEARCH
INSTITUTE THIS YEAR BECAUSE THEY WEREN'T ABLE
TO GET DATA FROM THE MEXICAN GOVERNMENT.
BASED ON SCOURING OF NEWS REPORTS ON TALLIES
THAT THE NATION'S LARGEST NEWSPAPERS KEEP,
THEY ESTIMATED THAT BETWEEN 25 AND 50% OF
ALL THE HOMICIDE LAST YEAR WEREÊ
>> >>DWANE: FRONTERAS DESK REPORTER ADRIAN
FLORIDO.
AT LEAST 30 PEOPLE HAVE DIED FROM THE FLU
IN SAN DIEGO SINCE NOVEMBER. THE YOUNGEST
WAS 42 AND THE OLDEST PERSON WAS NOIFNLT ALL
BUT ONE OF THOSE PATIENTS HAD UNDERLYING HEALTH
PROBLEMS. THE AGENCY HAS CONFIRMED 3,000 CASES
OF THE FLU THIS SEASON BUT SAYS THE NUMBER
IS LOW BECAUSE MANY CASES AREN'T RECORDED.
THERE'S STILL TIME TO GET A FLU SHOT. TO FIND
A LOCATION NEAR YOU CALL 211 OR VISIT SDIZ.ORG.
WE HAVE AN UPDATE ON A STORY WE'VE BEEN FOLLOWING
FOR QUITE SOME TIME HERE AT KPBS.
RESEARCHERS HAVE DISCOVERED THE FIRST U.S.
CASES OF WHOOPING COUGH THAT MAY BE IMMUNE
TO THE VACCINE.
MOST OF THE FOLKS WHO GOT SICK WERE ALREADY
IMMUNIZED.
SCIENTISTS DON'T BELIEVE THE NEW STRAIN IS
MORE DEADLY BUT SUSPECT THE NEW VACCINE MAY
NOT FIGHT AGAINST IT. THE NEW BUG HAS BEEN
IDENTIFIED IN JAPAN, FINLAND AND FRANCE.
BOB FILNER WANTS THE NUCLEAR TOIR REGULATORY
COMMISSION TO HOLD A COURT STYLE HEARING ON
WHETHER SAN ONOFRE IS RED TEE OPEN.
AMITA SHARMA IS IN FOR PEGGY PICO TONIGHT.
SHE SPOKE WITH THE MAYOR ABOUT SAN ONOFRE
INCLUDING A RANGE OF OTHER TOPICS.
>> >>AMITA: MAYOR BOB FILNER, WELCOME TO THE
PROGRAM.
THE BIG NEWS THIS WEEK IS THE JUDGE THROWING
OUT IRWIN JACOBS REMODELING PLAN FOR PLAZA
DE PANAMA ON GROUNDS THAT IT VIOLATED CITY
CODE.
HOW DOES A PLAN LIKE THIS GET PAST THE CITY
ATTORNEYS OFFICE, PAST THE CITY COUNCIL WITHOUT
ANYONE SEEING IT VIOLATED CITY LAW.
>> >>GUEST SPEAKER: I THINK THEY WERE TOLD
THAT.
I TOLD THEM THAT AT A CITY COUNCIL MEETING,
THEY CHOSE NOT TO LISTEN.
THEY THOUGHT THEY COULD BULLY THEIR WAY THROUGH
THE WHOLE SYSTEM.
WE APPRECIATE DR.ÊJACOBS PHILANTHROPY AND
WILLINGNESS TO HELP.
WE ALSO AGREE WITH THE END RESULT THAT IS
TO GET THE CARS OUT OF BALBOA PARK.
I THINK THAT CAN BE DONE NOW AT A MUCH CHEAPER,
LESS LOWER TECHNOLOGY WAY THAT WILL PRESERVE
BOTH THE TOPOLOGY AND GEOGRAPHY OF THE PARK,
BUT KEEP CARS OUT.
WE HAVE AÊ I WROTE A PLAN 20 YEARS WHEN I
WAS ON THE CITY COUNCIL TO PARK CARS IN THE
PERIMETER OF BALBOA PARK, PARKING STRUCTURE
OUTSIDE, AND THEN USE A TRAM SYSTEM TO GET
PEOPLE INTO THE PARK.
THAT TRAM SYSTEM BECOMES PART OF THE EXPERIENCE
OF BALBOA PARK.
>> >>AMITA: DO YOU EXPECT SOMETHING LIKE THAT
TO HAPPEN BEFORE THE CENTENNIAL CELEBRATION
IN 2015?
>> >>GUEST SPEAKER: I DO, BECAUSE THE CENTENNIAL
CELEBRATION WOULD HAVE REQUIRED SOMETHING
LIKE THAT ANYWAY BECAUSE WE'RE GOING TO HAVE
TO KEEP CARS OUT.
SO WE WOULD HAVE HAD TO DO THIS IN ANY CASE.
SO LET'S START NOWVMENT SHOW THAT IT WORKS
AND BUILD FROM THERE.
>> >>DWANE2: ON THE TOPIC OF ALLOWING MEDICAL
MARIJUANA DISPENSARIES TO OPERATE WITHIN THIS
CITY, YOU'RE WORKING ON AN ORDINANCE YOU SAY
IS SIMILAR TO ONE THAT WAS ADOPTED BY THE
CITY COUNCIL TWO YEARS AGO.
BUT THAT WAS SUCCESSFULLY REPEALED.
HOW DO YOU MAKE SURE THAT DOESN'T HAPPEN AGAIN?
>> >>GUEST SPEAKER: THIS IS A BALANCE WE HAVE
TO TRY TO STRIKE I'M GOING TO ATTEMPT TO DO
WITHIN ABOUT THREE OR FOUR WEEKS.
THAT IS ON THE ONE HAND THE STATE REFERENDUM
AND HUMANITARIAN CONCERNS REQUIRE WE PROVIDE
ACCESS TO MEDICAL MARIJUANA TO PEOPLE WHO
NEED IT, WHO HAVE CANCER A DOCTOR'S PRESCRIPTION,
IN CHRONIC PAIN.
ON THE OTHER HAND, WE DON'T WANT NEIGHBORHOODS
TO BE INTRUDED ON, CHILDREN TO HAVE ACCESS
TO MARIJUANA, AND WE HAVE TO RESTRICT IT TO
THOSE WHO NEED MEDICAL MARIJUANA.
THAT'S A BALANCING ACT THAT'S HANDLED PARTIALLY
THROUGH ZONEING AND THE CITY COUNCIL PREVIOUSLY
I THINK WAS TOO RESTRICTIVE.
I THINK IF WE RESTRICT TO INDUSTRIAL AND COMMERCIAL
ZONES, FOR EXAMPLE, IF WE HAVE A PERM TT FEE
THAT IS REAL THAT WOULD JUST KEEP FLY BY NIGHT
PEOPLE OUT THAT WE HAVE STRICT REQUIREMENTS
ABOUT DISTANCES FROM SCHOOLS AND CHURCHES,
FOR EXAMPLE, WE COULD HAVE THE BALANCE THAT
WE NEED.
WE'RE GOING TO TRY TO STRIKE THAT BALANCE.
IT'S NOT EASY BUT WE WILL TRY TO DO THAT.
>> >>AMITA: SEVERAL PROMINENT DEVELOPERS AND
OTHER SUPPORTERS OF CARL DEMAIO'S IN THE NOVEMBER
ELECTION ARE HELPING TO PAY DOWN YOUR CAMPAIGN
DEBT.
DID YOU SOLICIT THAT MONEY?
>> >>GUEST SPEAKER: WE WERE LEFT WITH IN THE
SCHEME OF THING AS PRETTY LOW AS THESE THINGS
GO, ABOUT A HUNDRED THOUSAND DOLLARS.
WE ASKED OUR PREVIOUS CONTRIBUTORS AND ANYBODY
WHO WANTED TO SUPPORT ME IN MOVING FORWARD
TO BRING DOWN THAT DEBT.
THE CITY LAW REQUIRES ME TO DO THAT WITHIN
SIX MONTHS OR YOU CANNOT RAISE MONEY AFTER
THAT.
I INVITE ANYBODY AND EVERYBODY WHO WANTS TO
CRIB TEUT DO THAT.
EVERYBODY KNOWS FROM MY 30 YEARS IN POLITICS
NOBODY CAN BUY ME WITH A CAMPAIGN CONTRIBUTION.
I'M GOING TO BE AN INDEPENDENT NO MATTER WHAT.
I'M NOT EVEN SURE ALWAYS WHO HAS BEEN GIVING
BECAUSE WE PUT A REPORT AFTER SIX MONTHS.
SO EXCUSE MEÊ I INVITE PEOPLE, WE HAVE A
500 DOLLAR LIMIT OB CAMPAIGN CONTRIBUTIONS
TO MAYORAL CANDIDATES AND ANYBODY WHO WANTS
TO JOIN IN TO HELPING ME WITH THAT, WE WELCOME.
>> >>AMITA: YOU'VE SPOKEN ABOUT THE NEED FOR
THE CITY OF SAN DIEGO TO PLAN FOR CLIMATE
CHANGE FOR SEA LEVEL RISE.
AND YET, THERE ARE THESE FLOOD PROJECTION
MAPS THAT SHOW THE SAN DIEGO CONVENTION CENTER
EXPANSION UNDER WATER IN 38 YEARS.
HOW CONCERNED ARE YOU ABOUT THOSE MAPS?
>> >>GUEST SPEAKER: I'M VERY CONCERNED.
AS I SAID, DURING THE CAMPAIGN, IF WE WANT
TO PROTECT OUR BEACHES, WE SHOULD GET OUR
HEAD OUT OF THE SAND.
THAT IS, WE HAVE TO TAKE THIS SERIOUSLY.
OBVIOUSLY, INTERNATIONALLY, NATIONALLY, STATE
WIDE, AND LOCALLY.
WE HAVE A RESPONSIBILITY IN SAN DIEGO TO DO
WHAT RVE WE CAN.
WE CAN'T STOP THE GLACIERS FROM MELTING, BUT
WE CAN TAKE IN OUR ENERGY SITUATIONS, USE
OF OUR WATER, OUR CARBON EMISSIONS, WE CAN
TAKE STEPS HERE.
I'VE ASKED A COUPLE PEOPLE TO CHAIR A COMMITTEE
WHICH WE'LL ANNOUNCE SOON TO COME UP WITH
A VERY STRATEGIC CLIMATE MANAGEMENT PLAN FOR
SAN DIEGO WHICH WILL REQUIRE THINGS LIKE,
YOU KNOW, 0 ENERGY KINDS OF BUILDINGS IN THE
FUTURE.
AND WE HAVE TO CONTRIBUTE WHATEVER WE CAN
TO THIS EFFORT.
>> >>AMITA: AS YOU KNOW, SOUTHERN CALIFORNIA
EDISON WANTS TO REOPEN SAN ONOFRE NUCLEAR
POWER PLANT AT A REDUCED CAPACITY.
SEVERAL CITIES IN SOUTHERN CALIFORNIA ARE
PRESSURING FEDERAL REG YRLTS NOT TO LET THAT
HAPPEN UNTIL A TRIAL LIKE PUBLIC HEARING IS
HELD.
IN WHICH EDISON HAS TO PROVE THAT THIS PLANT
IS SAFE TO REOPEN.
WHAT'S YOUR POSITION?
>> >>GUEST SPEAKER: I THINK THAT HEARING IS
CRITICAL AND NECESSARY.
WE DON'T WANT TO BE A FREE MOUND, WE DON'T
WANT TO BE A CHERNOBYL.
WE DON'T WANT TO HAVE A SITUATION AS THEY
HAD IN JAPAN.
I MEAN, THE SAFETY OF NUCLEAR PLANTS IS VERY
SHAKY.
IF THEY'RE ON EARTHQUAKE FAULTS OR NEAR THE
OCEAN AS SAN ONOFRE IS, AND IN THIS CASE WHEN
A STEAM GENERATOR HAS SOME PROBLEMS WITH SOME
OF THE CRITICAL COMPONENTS, AS SOMEONE WHO
HAS TO CARE PRIMARILY ABOUT THE SAFETY OF
OUR CITIZENS, I WILL BE A VOICE FOR SAYING
UNLESS YOU CAN ASSURE US, ALL OF OUR CITIZENS
OF THE SAFETY OF THAT PLANT, WE SHOULD NOT
REOPEN IT.
WE HAVE TO HAVE A HEARING TO DO THAT.
>> >>AMITA: SO FAR THE CITY OF SAN DIEGO HASN'T
TAKE AN FORMAL POSITION ON THIS.
DO YOU WANT TO SEE THAT HAPPEN?
>> >>GUEST SPEAKER: I HAVE AND I WOULD HOPE
IF THE CITY COUNCIL WILL NOT, I WILL SPEAK
AS THE MAYOR AT THOSE HEARINGS AND SAYÊ I
THINK THEIR PLAN FOR RUNNING IT AT A REDUCED
LEVEL TO SEE HOW SAFE IT IS IS VERY IRRESPONSIBLE.
YOU'RE TALKING ABOUT NUCLEAR ACCENT.
WE'RE TALKING ABOUT MILLIONS OF PEOPLE WHO
CAN BE AT RISK.
SO I DON'T WANT TO SEE IT OPEN BEFORE IT'S
PROVEN SAFETY FIRST.
>> >>AMITA: SAN DIEGO MAYOR BOB FILNER, THANK
YOU FOR COMING ON THE PROGRAM.
>> >>GUEST SPEAKER: THANK YOU.
>> >>DWANE: COUNTY SUPERVISORS VOTED FOUR
TO ONE TO APPROVE A SOLAR POWER PLANT IN RAMONA.
THE SOUL OMP RD PROJECT WILL COM COVER 43
ACRES WITH SOLAR PANELS WHERE A DAIRY FARM
IS KURNLTLY LOCATED.
SOME NEIGHBORS SAY THE PLANT WILL BE AN EYE
SORE.
MOSTLY POSITIVE REACTION FROM SAN DIEGANS
WE SPOKE TO ABOUT NEWS THE POSTAL SERVICE
PLANS TO SUSPEND SATURDAY MAIL DELIVERY THIS
SUMMER.
THE PLAN TO SHRINK DELIVERY FROM SIX DAYS
TO FIVE WOULD ONLY AFFECT FIRST CLASS MAIL
BEGINNING IN AUGUST WHILE PACKAGES, MAIL ORDER,
MEDICINES, PRIORITY AND EXPRESS MAIL WOULD
STILL GET DELIVERED ON SATURDAYS.
THE POSTAL SERVICE LOST 16ÊBILLION DOLLARS
LAST YEAR AND THINKS THE MOVE WILL SAVE ABOUT
TWO BILLION A YEAR.
>> >>GUEST SPEAKER: IT'S ABOUT TIME.
IF THEY'RE GOING BANKRUPT THEY'VE GOT TO CUT
THEIR EXPENSES.
ALL THE BUSINESSES HAVE CUT BACK, THEY NEED
TO.
>> >>GUEST SPEAKER: EVERYBODY E MAILS AND
IT'S A CHANGING TIME AND THEN THEY LET EVERYBODY
TAKE THEIR BUSINESS LIKE UPSÊ
>> >>GUEST SPEAKER: MY OPINION IS IT'S A LONG
TIME COMING, IT REALLY IS.
AS FAR AS THE POSTAL ESTABLISHMENT, THEY NEED
TO LET THE GOVERNMENT JUST GET OUT OF IT ALL
TOGETHER AND LET IT BE A COMPANY RUN SO THEY'LL
MAKE THE MONEY THEY NEED TO MAKE AND HAVE
THE GOVERNMENT STAW STOP TAKING THE MONEY
THEY'RE MAKING NOW.
>> >>GUEST SPEAKER: I THINK THERE IS A PLACE
FOR THE POST OFFICE, BUT IT IS A BUSINESS
SO THEY DO NEED TO MAKE THAT DECISION.
I AGREE WITH IT.
>> >>DWANE: AND HERE'S WHAT A LOCAL REPRESENTATIVE
WITH THE POSTAL SERVICE SAID QUOTE THERE IS
NO LONGER SUFFICIENT VOLUME TO SUSTAIN SIX
DAYS OF MAIL DELIVERY.
WE DEVELOPED THIS APPROACH WORKING WITH OUR
CUSTOMERS TO UNDERSTAND THEIR DELIVERY NEEDS
AND BY IDENTIFYING CREATIVE WAYS TO GENERATE
SIG SIGNIFICANT COST SAVINGS.
THE MOVE ACCENTS PACKAGE DELIVERY HAS GONE
UP 14% SINCE 2010, WHILE LETTERS AND OTHER
MAIL HAS DECLINED WITH THE INCREASING USE
OF E MAIL, AND INTERNET SERVICES.
PEOPLE FACING A TERMINAL ILLNESS WILL HAVE
A NEW OPTION FOR CARE IN THE NORTH COUNTY.
A SIX BEDROOM HOSPICE HOUSE WILL OPEN IN CARLSBAD
A.ONE MILLION DOLLAR FEDERAL GRANT FROM THE
CITY MADE IT POSSIBLE.
THIS COMES IN THE WAKE OF SAN DIEGO HOSPICE
FILING FOR BANKRUPTCY AND AS WE REPORT SAID
LAST NIGHT, SCRIPPS HEALTH IS ADDING HOSPICE
CARE.
PUBLIC SCHOOL LEADERS SAY TEEPER PREPARATIONS
PROGRAMS LEAVE INSTRUCTORS WELL VERSED IN
THEORY BUT NOT SO WELL EQUIPPED TO MANAGE
A CLASSROOM.
KYLA CALVERT TELLS US HOW HIGH TECH HIGH CHARTER
SCHOOL CREATED THEIR OWN TEACHER TRAINING
PROKING PROGRAMS AND DEVELOPED A GRADUATE
SCHOOL OF EDUCATION IN THE PROCESS.
>> >>GUEST SPEAKER: IT'S TIME FOR PEER CRITIQUE
IN THE ADVISORY CLASS AT HIGH TECH MIDDLE
SCHOOL IN POINT LOMA.
THAT MAGIC WORD WAS PROJECT TOAP YOU.
STUDENTS STARTED THIS UNIT BY BRAIN STORMING
QUESTIONS; QUESTIONS THEY HAD ABOUT ANYTHING.
THEN THEY CATEGORIZE THE QUESTIONS OF THE
CLASS.
>> >>GUEST SPEAKER: THROUGH CREATING THOSE
CATEGORIES WE FOUND SIMILARITIES IN OUR QUESTIONS
AND ALSO FOUND HOW OUR QUESTIONS ABOUT OURSELF
CONNECT WITH QUESTIONS ABOUT THE WORLD.
>> >>GUEST SPEAKER: THEN GROUPS OF STUDENTS
CHOSE ONE OF THE BROAD QUESTION CATEGORIES.
>> >>GUEST SPEAKER: WE'RE MAKING THAT ONE
QUESTION AND THEN WE'RE TRYING TO LOOK OUT
FOR WHAT CAN WE MAKE OUT OF THAT QUESTION.
LIKE, WHAT PRODUCT CAN WE MAKE.
>> >>GUEST SPEAKER: HER GROUP'S IDEA FOR A
PROJECT WAS A FAMILY TREE.
>> >>GUEST SPEAKER: WE'RE DOING A 3 D TREE
AND PUTTING OUR ANCESTORS AND MAKING AN ARTICLE
ABOUT ONE ANCESTOR AND WHAT KIND OF HISTORY
THEY TOOK IN.
>> >>GUEST SPEAKER: STUDENTS ARE READING OTHER
GROUPS PROJECT IDEAS AND LEAVING THEIR COMMENTS
ABOUT WHAT WILL WORK AND WHAT MIGHT NOT ON
BRIGHT POST IT NOTES.
AT THE 11 HIGH TECH HIGH CHARTER SCHOOLS IN
SAN DIEGO, PROJECT BASED CLASSES ARE THE NORM.
STUDENTS DESIGNED PROJECTS ARE EVERYWHERE
ON THE SIX SCHOOLS.
ON THE WALLS AND CEILINGS, DECORATING THE
BATHROOMS.
SINCE THE FIRST HIGH TECH HIGH SCHOOL STARTED
IN 2000.
THAT GREW INTO A STATE LICENSED TEACHER CREDENTIALING
PROGRAM AND THEN INTO TWO MASTER DEGREE PROGRAMS
IN TEACHER AND SCHOOL LEADERSHIP WHICH STARTED
IN 2007.
BEN DAILY, CHIEF ACADEMIC OFFICER OF THE HIGH
TECH HIGH GRADUATE SCHOOL OF EDUCATION SAYS
THEY'RE OFFERING THE KIND OF HANDS ON TRAINING
THAT'S MISSING FROM MANY TRADITIONAL PROGRAMS.
>> >>GUEST SPEAKER: IT'S NOT LIKE IN TRADITIONAL
GRADUATE SCHOOLS, THERE'S NONE OF THAT RK
THERE'S NOTHING PRACTICAL AND IN OUR SCHOOL
NOTHING THEORETICAL.
WE'RE SAYING WHATEVER THAT BALANCE IS, WE
THINK IT'S A LITTLE OUT OF WHACK AND WE'RE
TRYING TO SWING IT BACK TO MORE PRACTD OWS
BASED MODEL.
>> >>GUEST SPEAKER: HE POINTS TO THAT PRACTICALITY
AS THE MAJOR DIFFERENCE BETWEEN THIS PROGRAM
AND THE TRADITIONAL CREDENTIALING PROGRAM
HE WENT THROUGH WHEN HE FIRST STARTED TEACHING.
>> >>GUEST SPEAKER: IT'S APPLIED, INTEGRATED
INTO WHAT I'M DOING.
SO MY ACTION RESEARCH WHICH IS AROUND DEMOCRATIC
LEARNING AND COLLABORATIVE DESIGN WHICH YOU
GUYS SAW EARLIER TODAY, YOU KNOW, I RESEARCH
THAT IN THE FIRST YEAR AND PREPARED CREATED
A THESIS PROPOSAL, AN OUT LINE OF WHAT I WAS
GOING TO DO IN MY RESEARCH, AND THAT'S WHAT
I'VE DONE THIS YEAR.
>> >>GUEST SPEAKER: THE GRADUATE SCHOOL STUDENTS
WORK FULL TIME AND ATTEND EVENING CLASSES
WUNSZ A WEEK DURING THEIR FIRST YEAR, AND
ONCE EVERY OTHER WEEK DURING THEIR SECOND
WHEN THEY'RE CONDUCTING THEIR RESEARCH PROJECTS.
WHAT THEY DO IN THOSE CLASSES CAN BE PRETTY
SIMILAR TO WHAT THE MIDDLE SCHOOLERS WERE
WORKING ON.
A RECENT FIRST YEAR SESSION STARTS WITH A
CLASS DISCUSSION, THEN STUDENTS BREAK INTO
A GROUPS TO GET PEER FEEDBACKS FOR THE PROJECTS.
>> >>GUEST SPEAKER: SOME SORT OF STRUCTURE
PEOPLE CAN INTERACT WITH AND IT WOULD MAKE
MUSIC.
>> >>GUEST SPEAKER: WHILE MANY THE GRADUATE
STUDENTS WORK IN ONE OF HIGH TECH HIGH SCHOOLS
THEY COME FROM TRADITIONAL PUBLIC SCHOOLS.
MUL LIS UH SAYS INTEGRATEING PROJECT BASED
WORK AND STUDENT FEEDBACK INTO HER TRADITIONAL
CLASSROOM CAN BE STRESSFUL.
>> >>GUEST SPEAKER: MY BENCH MARK'S GO TOOK
LOOKED AT THERE'S THIS PRESSURE I HAVE TO
GO BACK AND TEACH ACCORD TO THE DI DISTRICT'S
CURRICULUM, BUT I'VE CHOSEN NOT TO.
BUT TO TEACH IN THE WAY I THINK MY STUDENTS
ARE RESPONDING TO.
SO I FEEL THAT THE CLASH HAS BEEN MORE INTERNALLY
FOR ME.
>> >>GUEST SPEAKER: STACEY DIRECTS THE TEACHER
LEADERSHIP PROGRAM AS THE GRADUATE SCHOOL
MOVES THROUGH THE ACCREDITATION PROCESS, THEY'RE
NOT LOOKING TO REVOLUTIONIZE TEACHER ACCREDITATIONÊ
>> >>GUEST SPEAKER: OUR GOAL IS NOT TO CREATE
A BUNCH MORE HIGH TECH HIGHS.
THE GOAL IS FOR PEOPLE TO EMERGE FROM OUR
PROGRAMS WITH A BETTER SENSE OF WHAT THE EDUCATION
IN THE SCHOOL THAT THEY KIND OF ASPIRE AND
DREAM ABOUT LOOKS LIKE AND TO HAVE MADE SOME
STEPS TOWARDS THAT WHILE THEY'RE HERE.
>> >>GUEST SPEAKER: BUT LEARNING TO RUN HER
CLASSROOM MORE LIKE SHE MIGHT IF SHE WORKED
AT A HIGH TECH SCHOOL IS WHAT DREW HAWN TO
THE SCHOOL SCIVMENT ID GO TO THEIR EXHIBITIONS
AND COME AWAY FEELING LIKE THESE KIDS LOVE
WHAT THEY'RE LEARNING AND I DIDN'T EVEN NEED
TO FIND THE TEACHER.
THE KIDS WERE HAPPY, FELT PROUD, AND I REMEMBER
GOING HOME AND THINKING WHY CAN'T MY STUDENTS
ARE V THAT.
>> >>GUEST SPEAKER: THE GRADUATED SCHOOL STUDENTS
MAY LEAVE THE PROGRAM EQUIPPED TO LEAD PROJECT
BASED CLASSES AND SCHOOLS AND TO CHANGE THE
FACE OF PUBLIC EDUCATION.
KYLA CALVERT, KPBS NEWS.
>> >>DWANE: SAN DIEGANS DRIVE MORE HIGHWAY
MILES EACH DAY THAN JUST ABOUT ANYONE ELSE
IN THE STATE.
IN FACT, AMERICANS SPENT FIVE AND A HALF BILLION
HOURS IDLING IN TRAFFIC IN 2011. THE COST
IS MORE THAN JUST TIME.
MATT FREEDMAN HAS THIS STORY.
>> >>GUEST SPEAKER: WASHINGTON IS WELL KNOWN
FOR POLITICAL GRID LOCK, BUT IT NOW ALSO HOLDS
THE DUBIOUS DISTINCTION OF BEING THE MOST
TRAFFIC GRID LOCKED CITY IN THE U.S.
>> >>GUEST SPEAKER: WE HAVE LARGE NUMBERS
OF COMMUTERS AND WE HAVE GROWN ENORMOUSLY
AND WE HAVE FAILED TO EXPAND OUR TRANSPORTATION
SYSTEM AS WE HAVE GROWN WITH PEOPLE AND BUSINESS.
>> >>GUEST SPEAKER: AND BEING STUCK IN TRAFFIC
ISN'T JUST AN INCONVENIENCE, IT COSTS EVERYONE
MONEY.
THE LATEST URBAN MOBILITY REPORT SAYS CLOGGED
ROADS COST AMERICANS 121ÊBILLION DOLLARS
IN TIME AND MONEY IN 2011.
>> >>GUEST SPEAKER: IT'S HORRIBLE, ALWAYS
BACK TO BACK, AND THE ROADS ARE WORSE ENOUGH.
THIS TAKES FOREVER.
>> >>GUEST SPEAKER: THAT'S NO SURPRISE TO
COMMUTERS IN SAN FRANCISCO, THE THIRD MOST
CONGESTED IN THE CITY.
MOVERRED HERE FROM AMERICA'S SECOND MOST CONGESTED
CITY AND DIDN'T SEE MUCH DIFFERENCE.
>> >>GUEST SPEAKER: IT'S SUCH A SMALL CITY.
I USED TO LIVE IN L.A. BUT IT TAKES AS LONG
FOR ME TO COMMUTE.
>> >>GUEST SPEAKER: THE REST OF THE TOP 10
INCLUDE NEW YORK, BOSTON, AND HOUSTON, TRIPLE
A SAYS DRIVERS SHOULD CONTACT LAW MAKERS AND
ASK THEM TO MAKE TRANSPORTATION FUNDINGA BIGGER
PRIORITY.
>> >>GUEST SPEAKER: IF THEY CAN WORK FLEX
SCHEDULES SO THEY DON'T HAVE TO DRIVE OR COMMUTE
IN
THE PEEK OF RUSH HOUR, THAT'S HELPFUL.
MORE TELECOMMUTING WOULD BE HELPFUL.
>> >>GUEST SPEAKER: STILL A REPORT FINDS THAT
ON AVERAGE AMERICANS ARE ALLOWING AN HOUR
FOR A COMMUTE THAT WOULD TAKE 20 MINUTES WITHOUT
TRAFFIC.
MATT FREEDMAN, ASSOCIATED PRESS.
>> >>GUEST SPEAKER: I'M JEFFREY BROWN ON THE
NEXT NEWS HOUR, THE BOY SCOUTS DECIDE WHETHER
TO CHANGE THEIR POLICY AGAINST GAY MEMBERSHIP.
THAT'S THIS WEDNESDAY ON THE PBS NEWS HOUR.
>> >>DWANE: WELL, IT LOOKS LIKE WET WEATHER
IS HEADED OUR WAY, RAIN MOVES IN ALONG THE
COAST WITH TEMPERATURES IN THE 50S THROUGH
SATURDAY.
THE SAME IS EXPECTED THROUGH THE INLAND VALLEYS.
SUNNY THURSDAY IN THE MOUNTAINS, MID 50S,
DROPPING TO THE 30S WITH RAIN ON FRIDAY, PARTLY
CLOUDY IN THE DESERT WITH HIGHS IN THE UPPER
70S TOMORROW.
RECAPPING TONIGHT'S TOP STORIES, THE CALIFORNIA
SENATOR SAYS SHE HAS NEW INFORMATION ON THE
SAN ONOFRE SHUT DOWN AND WHAT SOUTHERN CALIFORNIA
EDISON KNEW ABOUT PROBLEMS WITH ITS STEAM
GENERATORS BEFORE THEY WERE INSTALLED.
SENATOR BARBARA BOXER CALLED ON THE NATION'S
NUCLEAR WATCH DOG TO INVESTIGATE.
RESEARCHERS HAVE DISCOVERED THE FIRS U.S.
CASES OF WHOOPING COUGH THAT MAY BE RESISTENT
TO THE VACCINE.
SAN DIEGO COUNTY WENT THROUGH ITS WHOOPING
COUGH EPIDEMIC IN 2010.
KPBS WAS THE
FIRST TO REPORT MOST
OF
THE PEOPLE WHO GOT SICK WERE IMMUNIZED.
SCIENTISTS DON'T BELIEVE THE NEW STRAIN IS
MORE DEADLY, BUT THEY SUSPECT THE VACCINE
MAY NOT WORK
AS
WELL AGAINST IT.
YOU CAN FIND TONIGHT'S STORIES AND DOWNLOAD
THE KPBS APP ALL
ON OUR WEBSITE, KPBS.ORG/EVENINGEDITION.
THANKS FOR JOINING US.
YOU HAVE A GREAT NIGHT.
CAPTIONS PROVIDED BY ECAPTIONS.