here, that I wanted to
be at Blue Hill.
There wasn't anywhere else
that I wanted to be.
If I came here to eat with my
parents, just because they
were visiting from Florida, they
were like, well, where
should we go eat?
I was like there's this place
called Blue Hill.
And I want to try it.
I want to go so bad.
We came.
I can remember exactly where I
sat, where my mother and my
father sat, at what table, and
just had a mind-blowing meal.
It's exciting.
It's alive.
So at that point is when
I knew that I had to
come here and work.
My name's Trevor Kunk.
I'm a Chef de Cuisine at
Blue Hill New York
in Greenwich Village.
Farm to table is kind of
loosely used right now.
If it's a seasonal restaurant.
But it's more of a
micro-seasonal.
When we say seasonal, it's
truly seasonal with the
vegetables that we're serving
here, the fruit that we're
serving, with the meat,
with the fish.
And that window of usage is
anywhere from, let's say, two
weeks to three months.
There isn't really any dish
that's on the menu year round.
That somebody could come here in
January and then come back
in June and say, you know what,
I was here in January, I
really want that salt-baked
rutabaga.
They're not going to have it
when they're coming in June.
So what we have here is a gill
feather rutabaga, though this
is salt dough made
with compost.
The initial idea behind this was
the way of taking a salt
crust and cooking something
inside.
Why can't we use the compost
to bake with?
A little bit of hay as well.
The hay does lend a little bit
of flavor, a little earthiness
to the rutabaga.
We just played with the recipe
a little bit and essentially
developed a way to use
the salt crust.
Kind of an earthy depth that
the rutabaga already has.
But it just kind of helps
develop it a little bit more,
and it wakes it up
a little bit.
What we found is we work
incredibly hard to source the
best ingredients possible.
And we look everywhere.
We were looking for a great
source of venison, and we
found it with Halloran Farm.
We actually made a road
trip up there.
They proposed to us that they
would farm the venison for us
exclusively.
We hopped on it right away.
And it is truly the
best venison that
you will ever taste.
-Oh my God.
-It's so good.
TREVOR KUNK: I think what
initially drew me to Blue Hill
was at that point the local
seasonal idea was just
starting to take off.
And there wasn't anybody that
was doing it like Blue Hill
was doing, and what
Dan was doing.
Blue Hill New York was started
by Dan and David Barber.
I don't know if Dan ever knew
that it was going to
take off like this.
I don't know if he knew
it was going to
grow in this direction.
RUBY DUKE: Almost two years
ago, Trevor got
in touch with us.
And he had heard that we were
raising whey-fed pigs.
Basically, we work with
only three chefs.
Trevor is one of them and
really, he supports our farm.
Really makes it possible
for our farm to exist.
-Very, very fatty, but
well-marbled kobe as well.
TREVOR KUNK: We're cooking
for the ingredient.
We prepare it simply in the way
that their ingredient is
going to be showcased, and
elevate that flavor.
It's truly a passion.
It's truly a family.
Torch it here.
And then when we pour
it, we'll pour it
over here on the table.
So Katie Bell was a service
director here.
She's also, I guess, a cocktail
maker, or cocktail creator.
Kenny Hogue is sous chef here.
He's been here for about a
year and a half or so.
So we left Blue Hill
about 9 o'clock.
First of all, it's going
to be actually our
first time out together--
KATIE BELL: Yeah.
TREVOR KUNK: --for
a meal, ever.
So that's very, very exciting.
We're going to Gwynnett Street
in Williamsburg, because
there's Owen and Justin.
KATIE BELL: Living in Brooklyn,
I obviously have a
little bit of a different
perspective.
But I think Brooklyn gets such
a rap for good food, but
absolutely lack of service, and
just snooty attitudes, and
all this sort of stuff.
I think there's incredible food
being made in Brooklyn--
absolutely gorgeous food.
And then also the knowledge
to back it up and really
beautiful service.
TREVOR KUNK: What happens here
in Blue Hill is the people
that we bring on end up
becoming friends.
They end up being family.
So once they do move on from
Blue Hill, they'll go to
another restaurant.
OWEN CLARK: Hey, what's up?
TREVOR KUNK: Went to go visit
Owen, as well as Justin who's
the chef at Gwynnett.
JUSTIN HILBERT: You don't
want to be on TV?
You get ladies when
you're on TV, bro.
TREVOR KUNK: It's amazing for
us to be able to go visit
them, the new location, see how
they're doing, taste the
food that they're cooking.
All right, cheers.
KATIE BELL: Cheers!
First night out.
TREVOR KUNK: First
night out ever.
KATIE BELL: Took a year.
TREVOR KUNK: One of the
staples, whisky bread.
So I think they bake
it to order, right?
KATIE BELL: Yeah.
TREVOR KUNK: It takes like 10-12
minutes to come out.
It's really delicious.
TREVOR KUNK: Beautiful.
KENNY HOGUE: Nice.
TREVOR KUNK: All looks
incredible.
KENNY HOGUE: Yeah, it does.
JUSTIN HILBERT: I guess it's
modern American cuisine.
It's in par with fine-dining
food, but it's much more
relaxed so there's no pretension
involved or
anything like that.
You can wear whatever
you want.
You just go in and have a good
time and enjoy your meal.
We're just trying to do our own
thing for the most part.
TREVOR KUNK: Food-wise, I would
say the highlights for
me were the egg dish with the
squid, which was mind-blowing.
JUSTIN HILBERT: Take squid, you
char it on the flat top.
Slice it really thin and that
gets sauteed with celery root
that we make noodles out of.
So the eggs have been poached
slowly for about an hour.
And then this is
sea salt that's
mixed with smoked paprika.
Just gives it a little spice.
That's it, man.
TREVOR KUNK: There was a little
bit of heat, there was
definitely the salt,
there was the acid.
It was like it was warm, it was
welcoming, it was what I
think we needed.
We had a pretty hectic day
yesterday, so Katie, Kenny and
I didn't really have a chance to
eat that much, which was I
think in the end a
very good thing.
What's the--
dried lime?
KENNY HOGUE: Yeah, it's like
a hint of lime in there.
It just looks like
shaved lime zest.
TREVOR KUNK: I will
taste things and
we'll learn from it.
With the egg that we had
tonight, there's definitely
some kind of preserved lime--
something to that.
Weather it's dried lemon grass
or dried lime leaves, that's
something that we'll probably
try to figure out
how they did it.
It's amazing.
It wakes your pallet up.
And it's a wakening.
KENNY HOGUE: Since we are open
seven days a week, whatever
one of the cooks gets a day off
to go eat, everyone's like
where'd you go eat?
Where'd you go?
Tell us about it.
TREVOR KUNK: Right.
JUSTIN HILBERT: Thought you
might like some dessert.
TREVOR KUNK: All right.
KENNY HOGUE: Thank you.
TREVOR KUNK: Thank you
for everything.
Well I think with Justin,
having the experience of
working in a pastry department,
whether inside a
wd-50 or any restaurant,
working in the pasty
department is incredibly
important.
You're not only learning
technique, we you're also
learning how to think outside
the box a little bit.
KATIE BELL: They're really into
the savory and sweet.
TREVOR KUNK: And I think with
Justin, he's taken that
experience and not only
developed that technique of
the sweet side, but it also
lends to the savory side.
Comes with the ability to be
able to have some sweetness in
a savory dish, but not have it
be overpowering, but lend
itself to a duck that we
ate last night with the
lingonberry jam.
Yes, it was sweet, but it went
very well with that succulent,
savory duck breast.
And it comes to the plating,
it comes with the flavors.
We thought it was to
mind-blowing as well, egg yolk
encasing the cod.
We had a pretty phenomenal
meal.
OWEN CLARK: Where are
we off to, Eunice?
KENNY HOGUE: I think next
is Mother's Ruin.
OWEN CLARK: Where
is this place?
TREVOR KUNK: I guess
like NoLIta area.
OWEN CLARK: It's weird.
Living in this neighborhood and
working over here all the
time, it is so nice to not
be in Williamsburg
for a little while.
That's the same skinny
jeans dufus.
It's like hey, what's up?
TREVOR KUNK: Dude, I'm
wearing skinny jeans.
So after we left Gwynnett
Street we
went to Mother's Ruin.
And walking in, I don't want to
call it a neighborhood bar,
because I don't think it
really is, ultimately.
But it was kind of like
walking into home.
Everybody was very friendly.
And everybody that was there
was excited to be there.
And you could tell that they had
been there before and they
want you to come back again.
It was like an instant party.
TJ came over with the Amaro.
A couple of Amaro shots.
Cheers, everyone.
TJ LYNCH: All right,
happy Tuesday.
Salute.
TREVOR KUNK: The cocktails
were great.
TJ told us the little
story having to do
with the slushie machine.
It began as a gift. and now
they're selling it.
They're like OK, we'll take
your slushy machine.
We'll see what we
can do with it.
Left it on the bar.
Started playing with
different ideas.
And slowly developed into the
whiskey slushie that we had
last night, which
was delicious.
Whiskey, they had like some
fall, aromatic spices as well.
We're going back to Blue
Hill for family meal.
OWEN CLARK: Nice.
TREVOR KUNK: And we want you to
come if you can swing it.
TJ LYNCH: Yeah, cheers, guys.
TREVOR KUNK: All
right, cheers.
TJ LYNCH: It's nice when
I get out of there.
TREVOR KUNK: Yeah?
[INAUDIBLE].
TREVOR KUNK: The new
addition is TJ.
The other TJ, yes.
And actually, I'm a TJ as
well, born and raised.
But when I came to New York,
I became Trevor.
TJ LYNCH: We're going to go
for family meal, huh?
TREVOR KUNK: We are.
TJ LYNCH: Very exciting.
TREVOR KUNK: Special.
TJ LYNCH: Tacos.
TREVOR KUNK: Yeah, like Penny
said, taco Sunday on Tuesday.
Hello!
So we came back to Blue Hill
and cooked what we like to
call a family meal.
So it was kind of our taco
Sunday that we do every Sunday
for our staff, but elevated
to times 20.
Michelle, our wine director,
opened up a double magnum of
champagne, so we were able to
share that as we got back.
In the kitchen I cooked what was
essentially like a braised
pig head that we had diced and
pressed, and then just fried
off in the black pans.
So it's a pig head.
We cooked it in a [INAUDIBLE],
then finished with raw
shallots, pickled shallots,
lots of chopped herbs.
Now the idea is that it's going
to start popping, it's
going to start rendering.
All the fat's going
to come out.
All the protein's going
to get crispy.
Kind of like a sisig, the
Filipino traditional dish.
There's something in that realm
of the world that I
guess I really like when
I'm not working.
KENNY HOGUE: Everybody
contributed.
TREVOR KUNK: Francine Lee who
works in our pastry department
here was born and
raised in Korea.
So she'll make a kimchi and
bring it in for us to share
with the family.
Alfredo who's was one of our
prep cooks here, is from
Mexico originally.
And his mother is a very, very
good cook, especially when it
comes to her mole.
So I think the rotation's
like once a month or
so she'll make mole.
She'll freeze it and then she'll
ship it to Alfredo.
So Alfredo actually came in on
his day off yesterday to cook
that for us and to
share it with us.
Here we go.
Haskell, you're next
buddy, let's go.
Come on.
The kind of amazing thing with
Haskell is, is he's been
eating here since he
was a small child.
But he used to come in like
once or twice a year.
He would come in with his mom.
He was just very passionate
about food
and loved Blue Hill.
So over the years, after all
those meals, he decided to go
to a special school here in
New York, kind of like a
technical school slash
culinary school.
After finishing that,
he's like I want to
intern at Blue Hill.
That's where I want to be.
It reflects on what we
do for our guests.
We cook our hearts out for them,
and we want to serve
them the best food possible.
But we also have found that the
staff that's serving them,
our family, is incredibly
important as well.
And to keep them the happiest
is to feed them well.
It just makes people happy and
it makes people excited.