>> Right now it is my pleasure
to introduce our luncheon
speaker today George P. Bush.
George is a partner in
Pennybacker Capital.
I can give you a little
bit of his background
and I'm sure he'll fill
you in with some more.
He received his bachelor's
degree from Rice University
and then he's also a UT Alum.
He graduated from the law school
with his JD here
at, from UT Austin.
Prior to joining Pennybacker, he
practiced law with Akin, Gump,
Strauss, Hauer and Feld doing
corporate and securities law,
and before that he
clerked in Dallas
for federal district
Judge Sidney Fitzwater
who I also clerked for so
we know each other that way.
It's my pleasure to
introduce George P. Bush.
As you all know, he comes
from a family with a long
and storied tradition of
public service and he continues
that as a naval reserves
intelligence officer
and he recently was
mobilized to Afghanistan
and I'm sure he'll tell us a
little bit about that as well.
So please join in
welcoming George P. Bush.
[applause]
>> Thank you Ronnie [assumed
spelling], I appreciate it.
Thank you Ronnie and thank you
for what you do for Subiendo.
The very little that I know
about the organization
I've been blown away
with what you guys are
accomplishing this week.
I wouldn't be surprised if
there's a future president in,
in this room and I'm I'm
really delighted to to get
to know y'all and my hope
is that you guys can think
of any questions that
you might have for me,
any comments you might have
about the Bush family that you'd
like to share, and any any kind
of stories you'd like me to kind
of focus on because I really
wanted this to be interactive
and about you guys and
maximizing the time
that you guys have here
on the beautiful campus
University of Texas in Austin.
When I was asked to talk a
little bit about leadership,
I I wanted to talk a little bit
about my personal experiences
and I want to first
say at the outset
that I'm a truly blessed kid
to be born into,
into the Bush family.
When I was 12 years old,
my grandfather was
first elected president
after Ronald Reagan left office.
But right before he was
sworn in as president
of the United States I
was asked to join with a,
a group called Americares
which is one
of the largest non-for profit
organizations in the world,
and they deliver needed supplies
to to disaster recovery
efforts throughout the world.
And I don't know if you recall
but in 1992 there was one
of the largest earthquakes
recorded in human history
in Armenia which was a former
soviet republic or a republic
within kind of the shield of
the sov- former Soviet Union.
And I was asked at the age of
12 years to fly in a cargo plane
with the first supplies
to to Armenia
to deliver much needed supplies
to kids of of that were victims
of the earthquake and I
was totally blown away
by the experience.
This was a very desolate
area of the world.
50,000 people died,
most of whom died
under the rubble while they
were waiting for supplies
that we were attempting
to deliver.
The Soviets themselves were
unable to deliver these supplies
to to their own people and yet
we at Americans at the height
of the cold war we were
the first ones delivering
these supplies.
And I'll never forget going
to a children's hospital
where a 5th grade class was,
was sitting in class
learning their their cl-
learning their their
instruction for the day
and the earthquake taking place
and over half of
the students died.
And one kid that I met
survived that rubble,
survived during his time in the
rumble after the earthquake.
He had lost several limbs
and I delivered him a bible
because this was a
religious school.
And the kid cried and he told
me this is the best Christmas he
ever had.
And to me at a young age,
at the age of 12 to to have
that perspective of
what the true meaning
of Christmas was all about
was, was mind-blowing.
Following that, when my
grandfather was in office,
I had a chance to live
in the white house
which was pretty cool.
You know Dwight D. [inaudible]
President Eisenhower built a
bowling alley in the in the
basement of the white house.
There's also the rose
garden where you know some
of my favorite professional
athletes,
you know when they win the
championship they always go
and say hello to the
president, deliver a jersey,
so that was pretty
cool getting getting
to know professional athletes
and getting their autographs.
But my grandmother,
for those of you
who may not know Barbara
Bush, kind of the silver fox
of the Bush family, wears the
pants if you will [laughter].
She's kind of the boss.
She made sure that none of
us as grandkids were spoiled
so she wanted us to go
work at a at a soup kitchen
which I did during the time
that I lived in the white house.
And again, at the young age of
14, learned tremendous amount
about about those that
are less fortunate in one
of the poorest areas
of our country.
When my uncle was elected to
office from 2000 and and served
until 2008, I had the chance
to join three American
delegations throughout the world
and I had a chance to see more
perspectives, more perspectives
than most kids my age.
Probably the most powerful
experience was getting to go
to Nicaragua, Nicaragua
for those that are,
for a different accent,
but during the first
peaceful transfer of power
in that country's history
following a president
by the name of Chamorro
where during her swearing in,
the inauguration
had to be called off
because of violence basically,
threats of of of
her assassination.
And so we, the the new
president that was sworn
in was President Bolanos and
being in a foreign country
and following the
American flag to the podium
in which the American
delegation sat
down behind the newly
sworn president
in the first peaceful transfer
of power was an amazing moment,
especially when half the
crowd was booing the US.
It really puts things in
perspective in terms of,
in terms of of being patriotic
and supporting your country.
The point of all these
stories that I wanted
to convey is is the importance
of giving back, the importance
of volunteering,
of being thoughtful
of others in your community.
That's the best way to
become a leader I think
and understanding
those that need help,
those that need support.
When I was in high school
I had the opportunity
to teach inner city
kids in Havana,
in little Havana, baseball.
I was, the only reason why I
got into Rice basically was
because of my ability
to play baseball.
I had a chance to play with
Alex Rodriguez in high school
which is kinda cool,
and Lance Berkman
and a few other pros at Rice.
But but working with with
inner city kids and baseball
and teaching them the life
skills of of basically stepping
up and being leaders
in their own homes,
in their own right was was
also an important experience.
In, in Houston when I was at
Rice I also had the chance
to to work for a Catholic
charity on the weekend with,
with kids, also in inner
city schools in Houston.
And there, once again,
had an incredible experience
teaching English to the child
of an undocumented immigrant
who was illiterate
even, even in Spanish.
And so we worked, he was a very
unruly child, I was assigned
by one of his teachers who
had difficulties with him,
and we worked over the
course of two years.
Eventually he learned English.
He graduated from junior high,
was the first in his family
to graduate from high school and
and being patient and working
with him, again, was a
transformational experience,
and I think I grew
as a person in terms
of learning what what's
important in life.
And to this day I'm involved
with Big Brothers, Big Sisters.
I'm sure some of you in the room
have heard of this organization.
There's an interesting
program that we're working
at Big Brothers, Big Sisters
where over 90% of kids
of of felons do not go on to
graduate from high school.
And when you look at
our state of Texas,
even within the Latino
population in many areas
of our great state, we have
a dropout rate of over 50%.
This to me is one of the, the
the largest crisis that we face
and that your, our generation
collectively will face
as future educators,
future leaders
in our state and our country.
And so I look forward to working
with you on, on these issues.
The importance of public
service can't be denied.
You know it's very easy
when you when you look
at the voting participation
rates in our country,
you know whether you're looking
at the last presidential
election cycle, less than 25%
of 18 to 29 year olds bothered
to show up at the polls.
Many of you will be
voting for the first time
in the next election cycle and
I encourage you to register
to vote, to to get involved
in that way and get involved
in the political campaign.
That's the best way
to to to learn
about the issues of the day.
There's other w- forms of
public service as well.
My, another experience that I
had was serving in the military
and seeing firsthand
in Afghanistan,
the fifth poorest
country in the world,
the importance of
public service.
We spend $2 billion a week
in in this country rebuilding
and creating a democracy
in an area of the country
where not a lot of
people want democracy,
where self-identification
is more defined by tribe
as opposed to country.
You ask the average Afghan
whether they consider themselves
Afghan, they consider
themselves Pashtun or Gerudo or
or some other ethnic tribe
as opposed to Afghan.
And so even though we as
Americans are doing so much
in Iraq and Afghanistan, part of
public service has to come from,
from the community, from
people like all of y'all.
And so I I look forward
to to further talking
about the importance of that.
Here in the U.S. I I
can't help but think
about when people complain
about politics and they complain
about government, that at
the same time they don't get
involved and run for office or
help out political campaigns or
or or do, or volunteer
in their communities.
And I can't help but think of a
quote from Plato where he says
that the consequence of
of not being involved
in your government and not being
involved in public service is
that you end up being
governed by your inferiors.
And that's not to say that
our current political leaders,
republican or democrat,
are inferior or a cast
of of inferiors, but
it is to say that if
if our generation doesn't step
up, then we face a huge crisis,
a huge deficit where people
choose not to get involved
in public service and
leadership positions.
There's so many different ways
to get involved outside
of politics.
As a member of a
Bush family it's,
it's easy to say you know
go out and run for office,
but there's non-for-profit
organizations
that I know y'all are already
involved in in your high schools
and that you will be
involved in in college.
There's also non-for-profit
organizations that affect issues
that that you feel
passionately about.
And it doesn't necessarily have
to be education or mentoring,
but there's so many different
special interest groups
that you can get involved in and
I would just encourage you all
to volunteer time
and your effort.
You know the extra moments
that you spend with,
with others makes a difference.
One person at a time.
I remember being an inner city
high school teacher and starting
out the year with 150
students and by the end
of the year I was left
with about 90 students.
I had several, several kids
drop out due to possession
of narcotics, possession
of weapons,
and what I learned is instead
of looking at, you know,
the macro issue sometimes,
sometimes your victories
are one kid at a time,
one student at a time.
And so I I encourage you to
look at issues that way as well.
So with that I want to
turn it back to you guys
to offer any kind of, any kind
of commentary that
you might have.
I'm I'm, I want to
open a dialogue
to any questions you might have
'cause otherwise I could be
up here all all night long, all
afternoon long talking to you
so I'd encourage any
questions you might have.
>> All right.
Hello. So you know I think
that everything the
United States does
for other countries is amazing,
you know with Americare,
with giving back, you know
helping Afghanistan rebuild
themselves, Iraq, but you know
while all that is happening,
in the U.S. we have
our own crisis.
27,000 high school students, you
know, are gonna be without 70%
of funding because of the
education budget cuts.
So what is your stance on
the education budget cuts?
>> Well thankfully I'm not in
elected politics so I don't ,
I don't have a committed
position on the issue but,
you're absolutely right.
I mean we have, we're spending
billions of dollars a week
if not every month on both the
conflicts in Afghanistan, Iraq,
now Libya, and we're looking
at other, other conflicts
that arising with the
spring, the Arab spring
if you will call it that,
and Syria and Yemen.
And it's it's a generational
change
that many people never
thought that they would see
in the middle east and so
what, not only rhetorically
as Americans in terms
of our foreign policy is
it important what we do,
but in terms of how we
commit our existing assets
and resources is
going to be vital.
I am one to to believe that
we are still the most powerful
country in the world and
that that our matter,
that our actions matter.
And so you know I commend
our current leaders
to their thoughtful approach
to what's happening
in the middle east.
In terms of what's happening
here in the state of Texas,
absolutely, we face
an education crisis.
The stats speak to themselves
whether you're talking
about high school dropout
rates in the valley
within the Hispanic population.
When you look at the state
budget, education is roughly 60%
of the overall budget.
We had, come heading into this
legislative session we had
about a 20 to $30
billion shortfall
which is a pretty large,
large deficit to make up.
And so when you're, when you're
talking about closing that gap,
if you're serious about it,
for better or worse you have
to look at cuts in education.
So since we're doing that,
unless you want to raise taxes
which is not always the most
politically popular thing to do.
So when doing that you have to
balance where, where do we cut?
And one of the, I haven't been
following it as closely as most,
but in terms of what we're
seeing right now is is allowing
for more tenured teachers
and you know teachers
that are closer to
retirement to retire early and
and basically you know
younger teachers that are going
into the profession are paid
a little bit less than the
than the more experienced
and and veteran teachers.
There's also you know looks
of accounting you know
gimmicks basically
to to basically instead of
have it go with inflation,
keep it fairly flat lined for
the next two years so that,
so that revenues will
catch up with spending.
So, long winded way of
saying that we're gonna have
to make some tough decisions.
It's not gonna please everybody.
There will probably be some
teachers that are let go,
but if we're gonna be
serious about, you know,
balancing our budget, you
know you and if you're serious
about doing it, you
look at a majority
of the budget, it's
in education.
And so, so what I would
also advocate is looking
at maximizing, you know,
the dollars to make sure
that every dollar
that we're spending
in education is doing
what it's intended to do.
So I would put everything
on the table,
how do we reform education
to make it such that
when you guys are
graduating from college,
you you are paid
accordingly for for results.
So that if you are working
in an inner city school
and you are taking a class of,
in in a failing school from,
you know mediocre test
results to to above mediocre
or above average, you
should be rewarded for that.
And so, implementing some types
of reforms I think would
go a long way as well.
Excellent question by the way.
>> You spoke of high
dropout rates,
what would you propose
to lower those?
>> To me, you know when I was in
an inner city high school school
and in Miami when I was
teaching, I was actually
in the dropout prevention
program.
So a lot of the kids in
the state of Florida,
and I believe it's
the case in Texas
that when you turn 16
you can legally drop out.
So most of the kids at my
class, this is freshman year,
9th grade, that were already 16,
well a lot of my young
women were were pregnant
and I already had, you
know many young men
that had a prison record or,
you know, had been in and out
of of juvenile institutions.
So without sounding sarcastic,
there's gonna be a percentage
of students that we're gonna be,
that that's gonna
be very difficult
to reach out to and change.
We we can't rescue every kid,
but what we can do is create a
curriculum that's more relevant
to the lives of those
that are thinking
about a different path in life.
As a p-, not every kid is gonna
go to, to Harvard and Yale
or great schools like UT.
What can we do in our curriculum
to make, make it more relevant
so that if kids have an interest
in, you know, technology,
or an interest in auto repair,
that they can do so immediately
in high school when they're
not learning about, you know,
16th century, you know, art.
You know and and it's just
not not as relevant in terms
of what they're gonna
see in terms
of a tangible job out there.
We're blessed to be in a
state where we've created,
in in the last since
the beginning
of the recession almost a third
of every job created in the U.S.
which is unbelievable
to think about.
So, you hit on a very important
issue, how do we get that kid
who is in 9th grade
thinking about dropout,
just to hold on until
12th grade?
There's been measures proposed
to to to pay students to get
through high-- I I'm
not an advocate of that.
I do believe that if we
incentivize teachers, the best
and the brightest that come
out of our universities,
that want to take on a career
in education that they go
into the inner city
like Teach for America
which is a great program,
to go out and take
on these huge challenges.
'Cause I think with
passionate teaching
and passionate administ-
you guys know,
you're in high school.
You you learn more with teachers
that are engaged and passionate
about your, your own life.
And so if we can incentivize and
create a structure for teachers
to do that, I think that would
go, go a much longer way.
>> Hi my name is
Stephen Dominguez.
I'm from here in Austin, Texas
and well first of all thank you
so much for sharing your
story, it was very inspiring,
and for being here today.
We have this proposal project
going on that we're supposed
to find a problem maybe within
our community and how to fix it,
my question is maybe
what do you think
that we could do right now, the
coming rising seniors going back
to our senior year
in high school
to maybe improve our community
in any way since you have
such great experience?
>> Absolutely.
There there's a there's a
lot of different issues.
I think mentoring
is is a big one.
You know Big Brothers,
Big Sisters is a,
I'm a huge advocate for it.
There's so many different
non-for-profit organizations
that, that get involved
in the community.
There's recycling programs,
environmental programs
that I think you can build
the leadership, build a board
of advisors if you will
that would guide you towards you
know raising a certain amount
of money to-- I would
consider being an entrepreneur
in non-for-profits you
know because you're,
after having visited with you
you're obviously, you know,
a bright kid and a huge future.
Why not create your
own non-for-profit
and you know create a business.
You know there's a cool industry
that's developing here in Austin
in terms of social
entrepreneurship
where you take small
business principles,
go out create a non-for-profit,
write a business plan,
go out and raise money
and then impact an issue
that you personally
feel passionate about.
Rally other people
around the cause.
Get a board of advisors of
people that have experience
in that area to allow
you to go out
and build it, build the dream.
Here at UT, I can't tell you how
many great non-for-profits have
stemmed from UT students
that were here during college
and created these wonderful
business plans while they were,
while they were studying because
they felt passionate about it.
They found time and prioritized
time in their own schedule
to do it which is
pretty amazing.
In fact one that I'm
involved with here
in Austin is called East
Side Community Connection
where we feed predominantly
transient families
that that are either seeking
political asylum in our country
or are undocumented immigrants.
And you know the poverty
rate is fairly high,
and while they stabilize
their lives,
you know we help them get
educated, we help feed them,
we provide financial literacy
as they get acclimated
to to Austin.
The the organization was
founded just six years ago.
It was kind of a, it's almost
like starting a small business;
it's kind of a risky venture
at first but we were able
to get a good board of
advisors, we got great speakers.
We had Colt McCoy come
one year which is cool,
and and raised a lot of money
and the rest had
kind of taken off.
So I would, I wouldn't rule
that out as well as kind
of joining an existing,
you know, non-for-profit.
>> Hello [inaudible] George
Garcia from Brownsville, Texas.
And okay so aside from funding
issues and dropout rates,
I know that compared to
other leading nations
in the education system, the
states score lower than 50%
in some of the tests, and
in fact Washington D.C.,
the nation's capitol, scores
about 6%, the lowest in fact
of the whole United
States and it's just proven
that our education
system is not as effective
as other nations,
leading nations.
I wanted to ask you what do
you think is setting us back
and what we can do
to improve it?
>> That's a very good question.
I think, you know, to
further add to your question,
one of the most startling
aspects
where we're behind
is math and science.
When you c- when you look
at the totality of it,
we are you know roughly 50
percentile, but when you look
at science and math
we're we're at the bottom
of industrialized nations
and so that's problematic
for our future.
The tiny country,
the tiny country
of Taiwan is producing roughly,
roughly 10 times the amount
of patents, intellectual
property,
that we are producing
as Americans.
Here at UT it's one of the
few areas, we're blessed
to be surrounded by brilliant
scientists and engineers
that are putting out, you
know, intellectual property,
you know, on a daily basis.
But there's not enough of that.
So what I would propose is,
again going back to the point
of designing a curriculum
that's more germane to the lives
of people in terms
of finding a job.
'Cause I think there's
this huge gap
between high school
and the real world.
And you know there's, one of
the first investors in Facebook,
Peter Thiel, I don't know if
you've heard of that name,
he's he's a radical
on this issue.
He says that much of
what we're learning
in in high school is really
irrelevant to to what kind
of jobs you're gonna take on.
And so what I would
propose for those
that demonstrate an interest in
math and science in junior high
that there's there's a feeder
system for you to go on and
and work in a laboratory early
on, and you're working side
by side by engineers,
and so there's an apprenticeship
approach where you're learning
with people in the field and
you have an ability to get a job
at say Exxon or Shell or a
huge publicly held company
that are dying for engineering
and and science talent.
Another thing that's happening
is is that, using the example
of Rice at grad school,
in the computer sciences school
I think there was roughly
over 100 students, 90%
were Chinese nationals
and they graduated at
the top of the class.
And what we did is that most
of them went back to China.
They, because they saw more
opportunity and and not only
that but you know we we
have reduced the amount
of H1 visas that, H1B visas
which we provide to those
that want to learn in math and
science, the ability to stay
in our country to take on jobs.
Why not r- I mean, the U.S.
univers- post-secondary,
including UT in the analysis
is still the number one choice
in the world.
You you travel across the
the world and you still see
that the the influential,
and their societies are still
sending their kids here.
Why not tap that talent and
and create incentives for them,
for them to stay as well as
change the organic structure
of our own country
to get involved more
in math and science?
The second point that I
wanted to make with respect
to your question is just
overall wholesale reform.
Right now our approach
to education
in the 20th century is a
factory, is a one size fits all.
So, in my opinion, the
structure of what a school
in Highland Park is the same
as what you see in Brownsville
and that's not, I don't think
that matches with reality.
I think you have, we need to go
back to a little red schoolhouse
on the on the block
approach to education
where the teachers know the
students, there's open lines
of communication, there's
parent teacher interaction
and we've reduced
the size of classes.
I remember when I was a teacher
and I had over 40 students
in my class, you guys
know what it's like;
it's it's just pandemonium.
When you have, and when you
go to great schools you'll see
that you're you're going to,
the learning experience
is gonna be enhanced
when you have more one
on one interactions
with teachers as well.
So reducing class sizes I
think would go a long way and
and making schools more
relevant to the communities
in which they're
reliant as opposed to a,
a factory sized approach
to, to education.
>> Hi my name is Alexa Edwards
and I'm from Dallas and,
once again, thank
you for being here.
And I just wanted to point out
obviously we are the generation
of technology and I really
just wanted to know your stance
on technology in
schools 'cause I know
that it has its advantages
and disadvantages,
advantages being you know it's
easier to use, it's faster,
you know it's most relevant to
what's going on in our society,
but the disadvantages
that our skills in writing
and math obviously
are decreasing.
So I just wanted to know
how, do you think it's better
that technology is becoming such
an important factor in schools
or do you think that we
should pay attention more
to the basics and
the fundamentals?
>> Well I I think that's a very
good question and it's one that,
you know, as as educators
we constantly have
to think about honestly.
I I personally would advocate
that we embrace technology.
You know the, the scale by which
technology is improving our
lives is dramatic.
There's definitely downside.
I mean taking the experience
of being a high school teacher,
most of my students you know
basically write in short,
truncated sentences as opposed
to well thought out paragraphs.
That's certainly a downside.
But the upside is that
you're you're catching a huge
tidal wave.
You know companies like
Apple, Facebook, Google,
really were created by
entrepreneurship and creativity
and I think if we are
embracing technology in a
in a secondary education
environment,
we're giving young
Americans a chance to,
to think about how we
can further innovate and
and further think of
ways to make, you know,
technology more interesting
and relevant
to the lives of of the world.
That's one of the advantages
that we have I think
as Americans is that
we have Silicon Valley.
Silicon Valley is now
exporting more than just
about any other region
of our country because,
you know you you read their
articles in India and China
about the latest Apple
products that are released,
you see lines going
out the door.
We've traditionally as Americans
have exported, you know, Chevy's
and cars and I think
those days are are gone.
But everybody around the world
has got a Facebook account,
and so I think to the extent
that we can dovetail technology
with, with high school education
and make it, make it relevant,
and apply business models to,
to what's out there I think
that it's an exciting thing.
Without losing grasp of of
fundamental education, the X's
and O's that that that kids need
before, you know, graduating.
>> Hello, I'm [inaudible] a
deaf student from [inaudible]
and I aspire to be a surgeon.
I want to know what is your,
what is your opinion of the,
what, what do you think
is a growing problem
in the medical community,
a growing problem
in the medical community
that requires the
attention of everybody here?
>> Do do you mind
restating please?
Sorry.
>> Sorry I'm--
>> No no no.
>> What is your opinion, what do
you think is a growing problem
in the medical community?
>> In the, which commun-
medical community?
>> Yeah.
>> What do you think is
a, is the growing problem
of the medical community?
>> Very good question.
It's a- it's definitely at
the center of everybody's mind
in terms of, you know,
the recent proposal
that has come from, from
the white house in terms
of what the future of healthcare
looks like in our country.
Not only that but applications
to medical schools are
are down significantly.
It's no longer viewed
as as the profession
in many respects
as as it once was.
Unfortunately there are
too many lawyers, and the,
and I can say that as a lawyer.
And and I would not
discourage you to to
to not look at medicine.
I think it's a wonderful
profession
and you know it's obviously
been beneficial to our country.
But in my opinion, in my humble
opinion, I think there needs
to be, similar to my
thoughts on education,
there needs to be reform with
respect to, to healthcare.
One of the great things
about our country is is having
optionality whether it's,
you know, going down the street
to to get McDonald's as opposed
to Burger King or
hopefully choosing the school
that you want to send your kids
to as opposed to another school
that the same would apply to
healthcare, that you would get
to choose basically what doctor
you see for what purposes
and at what time, as opposed
to having mandates that kind
of dictate how healthcare
should look like.
I'm I'm a bel- I believe
in decentralized government
where whether you're talking
about, you know, education,
healthcare, that power basically
flows to, to local communities
because people have
different needs
in different parts
of our country.
So there's obviously
a looming crisis.
You look at, as a percentage
of our national budget,
and this has been the
discussion of the Medicare
and Medicaid discussion,
entitlements are roughly 60%
of our of our total budget
and healthcare represents
about a third of that.
And so again it's similar
to the question about,
you know, Texas education.
You know you really can't
talk about reducing the size
of our debt without
talking about healthcare,
so you know we really have a lot
of important decisions
ahead of us.
Thankfully I'm not in politics
so I don't have to worry,
worry as much about it.
>> Hi my name's Jennifer.
Actually I will be moving
to Baltimore after this
and doing Teach for America.
So I'm really excited
about that--
>> Congratulations.
That's awesome.
>> Thank you.
Thank you.
But my question,
you were talking
about I guess training
different schools
to do I guess vocational
opportunities for students,
but I think my concern with
that would be getting teachers
or counselors who automatically
assume minorities would
eventually go that route and
not give them the opportunity
for them to actually
excel in their studies.
>> Yeah.
>> So my question for you
would be, how would you prevent
that from happening
for students?
Instead of, you know, giving
them a chance to succeed
in school in their
studies versus, you know,
just automatically assuming
a vocational route for them?
>> Absolutely.
That's a great, a great point
and a great question 'cause
it can't be a self-selecting
criteria mainly because of
your background as a student
and what community
you reside in.
It would be an opt in program
where basically teachers
and the students,
basically would have to make
that that decision together
as a joint decision as opposed
to you know some higher
power from Austin,
Texas or Washington,
D.C. deeming you
to be a kid who's going on
a certain, certain track
as opposed to one
that you desire.
So I I probably should
clarify that in terms of,
in terms of having a curriculum
that's more relevant to the
to the to the lives of those.
I I just think that there's
a wonderful opportunity
to to re-approach education in a
way that there's an open canvas
in which we really delve into
the interests of of students and
and creating the bridge between
growing up in the community
and going off to a
job of the future.
Because even though we have more
4 to 500 companies in this state
than any other state
in the country,
in other words there's a lot of
opportunity out there, we still,
in my opinion have not created
a pipeline by which dir-
where where these students
can go on and get those jobs
of the future that, for
companies that are innovative
and going out and creating.
I mean Facebook for
example, they're,
they've just moved a large
office here to Austin
which is really exciting
and they're they're gonna bring
I think roughly 1,500 employees.
Legalzoom.com, Zynga, and so
what's happening here in Austin
on the tech side of things is
really exciting back to your,
your question earlier
about whether,
whether we can embrace
technology and if a kid early
on demonstrates an interest in
saying that's the company I want
to work for, I want to work
for Facebook and I want
to be CEO one day,
creating a curriculum
that would allow a kid, instead
of learning about, you know,
medieval, and I'm a history
major, medieval military history
or something wouldn't
be the most relevant
to getting that job.
So, so creating a structure I
think that's flexible would be,
would be ideal.
>> Hi my name is Perla Roman,
I'm from Houston, Texas.
I have a question about
immigration and education.
As I personally have
friends who have dropped
out of high school claiming that
they can't pursue a career or go
to college because of
their legal status,
so I would like to
know what's your stand
on granting illegal immigrant
students citizenship?
>> Well there's been a
proposal that was pending
in congress called
the the dream act
which would allow the children
of undocumented immigrants the
ability to obtain state citizen,
state citizens, same tuition
as as state kids basically,
in state tuition is
what I'm trying to say.
And that was recently,
it's basically scuttled
in the senate.
I think there's ways, there's
there's a middle ground 'cause
obviously it's a very
competitive education
environment and there are
families here in Texas
who feel slighted that children
of undocumented immigrants get
the same pay in price point as,
as an in state person.
I I think there's litmus,
there's a litmus test.
Instead of looking at it
as you know black and white
that there's a spectrum there.
So if if, if an undocumented
family, if let's say,
and I'm just talking out
loud here 'cause, you know,
this is UT and we think
creatively, is that,
is that you know if the
parents demonstrate an ability
to pay back taxes, have
taxes with withheld
on a going forward basis so
they're paying into the system,
so there's less kind of concern
about where you know public
funding stands in terms of,
where the kid stands and what
they're what they're taking
from the system,
and they demonstrate
over a certain amount
of years a,
a kind of a continuous
occupation
and you know there's fluency
in English and that there's,
you know, no commission
of felony, felonies during
that time, that we're
beginning to move in a direction
where I think we should
allow for in state tuition
because again it goes
back to the issue
about how we make changes
to to our education system
and creating incentives by which
we have very talented people
that were, had no control
over where they're,
where they were born and
where they were educated
and what their legal status is.
So there's, there's a,
many people in immigration
unfortunately view it as a black
and white issues and republicans
are just as guilty as democrats
in that issue for being not
constructive in this debate.
There are 20 million
undocumented immigrants
that live in our country today.
This is another issue
that we as a ge-
as our generation will face and
how do, and they're having kids,
they're having a lot of kids.
You know in the Anglo community,
the average child per
family is is less than 2.1
which is roughly the amount you
need to you know keep your pa-
your population growing.
And among the Hispanic
community it's,
it's it's above that,
which is great.
We need to embrace, you know,
we need to embrace a
vibrant immigrant community,
that's what our country
was built on and,
and you I think there's there's
gotta be incentives there
for the kids that want to
get a higher education.
So I'm, again I'm glad
I don't have to deal
with that issue 'cause I think
it's a complicated one but,
because when people talk about
immigration it touch- touches
on every issue indirectly
-- education, healthcare,
national security,
drug trafficking.
So, but I'm I'm for
proposals like the dream act.
I think it's it's a wonderful
incentive to make sure
that there are incentives there
to get a higher education we
shouldn't be dis- discouraging.
>> Join me in thanking
[inaudible] [applause]