jealous by the end of today show. The extraterrestrial
explanations coming up in just a bit.
First up today, we have an update for you
on Malala Yousafzai. She is the 14-year old
from Pakistan who was attacked and shot by
the Taliban recently. Malala had spoken out
against the group and called for education
rights for girls. That`s something that the
Taliban are against. On Monday, Malala was
airlifted from Pakistan to a hospital in England
for specialized medical treatment. Doctors
say, her recovery could take months. As of
Wednesday, Malala was in stable condition,
but she wasn`t able to speak. Malala was attacked
on October 9th on her way home from school.
And she wasn`t the only one who was hurt in
the shooting. Reza Sayah traveled to the region
in Pakistan where Malala is from. He talked
to one of the other girls who was shot that
day and visited their school. Here is his
report.
(BEGIN VIDEOTAPE)
REZA SAYAH, CNN CORRESPONDENT: The city of
Mangora in Pakistan`s scenic Swat Valley.
This is the region the Taliban took over in
2008, forcing shut then blowing up girls`
schools. Threatening to kill anyone who stood
in their way. This is also where Malala Yousafzai
and her classmate Kainat Ahmed (ph) defied
the Taliban by going to school anyway. Kainat
was seated next to Malala when Taliban gunman
stopped their school van and opened fire.
One of the bullets hit Kainat in the arm.
In her hospital room, a mob of reporters shoved
their way through for a glimpse of Kainat`s
ten minutes visit with Pakistan`s interior
minister.
(on camera): Do you regret standing up against
the Taliban now that you`ve been hurt?
KAINAT AHMED, INJURED IN TALIBAN ATTACK (through
translator): No, sir, I don`t regret it. God
willing, I will continue my education.
SAYAH: What do you want the world to know?
AHMED: Girls` education here is more important
than boys`. Because boys can have any jobs
they want to, but girls cannot. I want to
tell all the girls to continue their mission
to get an education.
SAYAH: We have left Kainat in the hospital,
we are heading to Malala`s school, and we
are really racing at high speeds and in armed
convoy. And it shows you, even thought the
government says, they`ve cleared the Taliban
out of this region, there are still a lot
of safety concerns.
We arrived at Malala`s school, this is where
Kainat went to school as well, so did Shazi
(ph) and the other school girl who was hurt.
When the Taliban took over this region, this
was one of the few girls` schools that remained
open. The headmaster was Malala`s father.
He essentially said, no, we are staying open.
Much of what Malala learned was in classrooms
here, despite the attack on students here,
the school opened three days after the shooting.
(on camera): How can you take practical steps
to make sure these little girls are safe?
REHMAN MALIK, PAKISTANI INTERIOR MINISTER:
We are taking practical steps, but we have
to change the mindset. There is the mindset
we need to change. And the first practical
step is, to take action against (inaudible),
these terrorists.
SAYAH (voice over): Before she was attacked,
Malala was working on starting a charity to
promote female education. In the report, you
just heard Kainat talking about the importance
of girls getting an education in Pakistan.
To learn more about Malala and the cause that
she and her friends have fought for, click
the "impact your world" link in the spotlight
section of cnnstudentnews.com
(END VIDEOTAPE)
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: What`s the word? Is the
study of objects and materials that are outside
of Earth`s atmosphere?
Astronomy, that`s the word.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: There is a lot of sky. A lot of universe
out there for astronomers to study, sometimes
those astronomers at NASA crowd source, and
what that means, is they give wide groups
of people access to the same information to
see if they can come up with anything.
For example, the Kepler telescope, that`s
what this is, its mission is to search the
galaxy and collect data about stars and planets.
And NASA made this data available to the public,
and that`s how two amateur astronomers discovered
something like this: it`s called a circum
binary planet, which means it orbits two suns,
only the one that was just discovered is believed
to be orbited by two more distant stars, so
you are looking at one planet, four suns.
The citizen scientists compared their findings
with professional astronomers to confirm the
finding of the four star planet.
This yellow wristbands you are probably seeing
all over the place are from the Live Strong
cancer charity. Cyclist Lance Armstrong who
was a cancer survivor helped found that organization
15 years ago. Yesterday, he announced he is
stepping down as LiveStrong`s chairman.
The U.S. Anti-Doping Agency says it has overwhelming
evidence that Armstrong used banned performance-enhancing
drugs during his career. Armstrong denies
doping, he said he is walking away from the
Live Strong organization to "spare the foundation
any negative effects as a result of controversy
surrounding my cycling career."
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: Today`s "Shoutout" goes
out to Mr. Ibarra and the students and teachers
at Lunsford Middle School in Chantilly, Virginia.
What is the capital of Texas? You know what
to do, is it Dallas, Houston, Austin or ElPaso?
You`ve got three seconds, go!
The capital of the lone start state is its
fourth largest city Austin. That`s your answer
and that`s your "Shoutout."
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: Just outside of Austin, you can hop
on highway 130 to toll road, and it`s one
way to get from the state`s fourth largest
city to its second largest, which is San Antonio.
But if you do take highway 130, starting next
month, you might be able to make that trip
a little faster. That is because the speed
limit is going up for a stretch of 41 miles.
The new limit will be 85 miles per hours.
When that happens, this section of highway
130 will officially become the fastest road
in America. 35 states have raised speed limits
to 70 or higher. And the engineers who built
this one, say that 85 is the safe and right
speed for highway 130. But some safety expert
have raised concerns. They say that increasing
speed limits leads to more accidents and more
severe injuries in those accidents.
All right, we are going to stay on the road
for this next report, but we are going to
move into the bike lane. Now, you`ve seen
road bikes, mountain bikes, dirt bikes, but
the two wheeler that Isha Sesay is talking
about, is in the class all its own. And that
is because of the material that it`s made
out of. Check this out:
(BEGIN VIDEOTAPE)
ISHA SESAY, CNN CORRESPONDENT: Setting the
wheels in motion on a breakthrough: with its
pedal power and traditional two wheel frame,
this may look like a typical bicycle. But
the Israeli entrepreneurs behind this bike
call it the future of low cost transportation.
NIMROD ELMISH, CARDBOARD BICYCLE PROJECT:
Basically, this bicycle is built out of 95
percent recycled cardboard, which is the most
cheapest raw material that you can find in any country.
SESAY: And there is no metal parts. The rest
is recycled car tires and plastic bottles.
Not only is the bike eco-friendly, it's cheap.
Each costs just $9 to build.
Inventor Izhar Gafni (ph) came up with the design
in his backyard chair.
IZHAR GAFNI, INVENTOR, CARDBOARD BICYCLE:
What I did is when I took the cardboard I
tried to overcome all the weaknesses that
the cardboard as a shipping material as we all know had.
SESAY: Using a secret process, Gafni says
his cardboard bike is both waterproof and
fire resistant. And by using green materials
and keeping production costs low, he hopes
the bikes can be given away in poor countries.
ELMISH: When you see something like this,
you understand quite fast that this is a real
game changer. I know that the lifespan of
the regular bike is maximum five years. So,
in five years basically I can replace all
of them, because that would be cheaper, faster,
stronger and ecological.
SESAY: Production is set to begin on three
bicycle modules and a wheelchair. They should
be on sale within a year. Isha Sesay, CNN,
Atlanta.
(END VIDEOTAPE)
AZUZ: So, a cardboard bike might work, but
a cardboard anchor - that could produce some
challenges. For example, trying to get him
to ride a bike. We thought this will be off
the chain, but it didn`t really work. He can`t
figure out how to sip hot chocolate, needs
someone to spill it out for him. All right,
man, stop mugging for the camera.
He doesn`t need much help getting ready to
go on camera, but, you know, this can go - hair
today, gone tomorrow.
Especially since he is an absolutely terrible
news anchor. Look at him, always falling down
on the job. You know, it`s worse that we came
up with all of these plans and all of these
situations for cardboard Carl, but in all
of them, his performance was absolutely flat.
Well, we did the best we card, and hopefully,
you weren`t board by it. Back tomorrow to
close out the week. I`m Carl Azuz.
Let`s go, Buddy.