started. I saw people shouting "Fire! Fire!"
They were terrified. When I realized that
there was fire, I rushed out of there.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
CARL AZUZ, CNN ANCHOR: Fire he is talking
about is the one at the nightclub in Brazil
over the weekend, and that last thing he said
about rushing out is really important, because
experts say that when a crisis happens, every
second counts. When you`re in a crowded place
like a club or a theater, there are some thing
you can do to be ready for an emergency.
(BEGIN VIDEOTAPE)
STEVE ALMASY, CNN PRODUCER/WRITER: Thanks,
Carl. We talked to some fire protection and
life safety experts this week after the fire
in Brazil. And what they told us is, there
are two things that are very important when
you are going to a venue or whether it`s a
public event. And that`s preparation and don`t
hesitate if there`s an emergency. But another
thing they told us is, before you even go,
make a plan with your friends where you`re
going to meet in case something happens. It
might be the car, it might be a public transit
stop, it might have to be some place else
in case the parking lot is too busy, or you
can`t get to your car because it`s blocked.
So, what you do is like, say, you`re going
to a movie theater or you go to a night club,
identify who the workers there are, they might
be wearing a particular color shirt. You might
ask them where the extra exits are, or if
they are unavailable to do that, then go,
take a lap around, or if you`re sitting in
the movie theater, look around to see where
the extra exits are, because if an emergency
happens, most people are going to head out
the way they came in, that`s what`s familiar
to them, and people tend to stick with that.
If you familiarize yourself with the alternate
exits, then that`s the way you`re going to
go, if you can in case there`s an emergency.
Now, if you hear a fire alarm, don`t hesitate.
Head for the exits. One expert told me, it`s
those ten seconds that can cost you your life.
So head for the door, if you can`t see, because
the smoke is coming down, or it`s too sick,
then feel your way forward, go in a straight
line until you hit a wall. When you hit the
wall, then you`re going to take your hand
and you`re going to follow it around until
you get to maybe a door or you get to a window.
(END VIDEOTAPE)
AZUZ: Brazil is going through three days of
morning for the hundreds of people killed
in that night club. Police have arrested several
people in connection with the fire, those
people are being held temporarily, five days
to start with. Authorities say they need to
do that in order to get more information for
their investigation.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
CESAR VALDEZ, UNDOCUMENTED IMMIGRANT: I went
to the registering office, and they just let
me know, you know, you`re undocumented, the
laws have changed, you can`t register.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: Undocumented immigrants like Cesar Valdez
aren`t allowed to join the military because
they are living in the U.S. illegally. Cesar
isn`t alone, there are about 11 million undocumented
immigrants in the United States. A group of
senators want to give them the chance to stay
here legally.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
SEN. CHARLES SCHUMER, (D), NEW YORK: We believe
this will be the year Congress finally gets
it done. The politics on this issue have been
turned upside down. For the first time ever,
there`s more political risk in opposing immigration
reform than in supporting it.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: That was Senator Charles Schumer. He
is one of eight senators, four Democrats and
four Republicans, who announced an immigration
reform plan yesterday. It includes things
like overhauling the country`s legal immigration
system and creating a path to citizenship
for undocumented immigrants. Critics sometimes
call that last part "amnesty". U.S. Representative
Lamar Smith said it would make the situation
worse.
"When you legalize those who are in the country
illegally, he says, it costs taxpayers millions
of dollars, costs American workers thousands
of jobs and encourages more illegal immigration.
By granting amnesty, the Senate proposal actually
compounds the problem by encouraging more
illegal immigration." We`re going to have
more on this issue for you this week. The
president is set to talk about it, and you
can always get the latest details at cnn.com.
You`ve heard it over and over again, higher
education can mean higher pay. Here`s proof
from cnnmoney. Without a high school diploma,
Americans earn an average of $478 a week.
It works out to about $25,000. But if you
do get your diploma, look at the jump to $647
a week, or more than $33,000 a year. Going
for a bachelor`s degree, you are likely to
pull down more than a thousand dollars a week,
or over $55,000 a year. And a higher degree
than that can spill out more than 1300 a week,
or over 71,000 a year. Keep in mind, higher
education doesn`t necessarily mean a four
year college degree. If you go in a construction,
for instance, you may need to go to trade
school or get a formal apprenticeship, and
you can average $740 a week or a little under
$40,000 a year. Some registered nurses and
dental hygienists who may have associates
degrees, can earn between $65 and $70,000
a year. So the take away here, if you`re hoping
to make more money, is to make sure your education
doesn`t stop at high school.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: It`s time for "The Shoutout."
"Parents can only give good advice or put
them on the right path, but the final forming
of a person`s character lies in their own
hands." Now, who said that? Was it Benjamin
Franklin, Anne Frank, Mohandas Gandhi, or
Justin Bieber? You`ve got three seconds, go!
Anne Frank wrote these words in her famous
diary. That`s your answer and that`s your
"Shoutout."
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: People showing their character is what
our next two stories are about. First one,
from a restaurant in Houston. This is Milo
(ph). He`s five years old, and he has Down
syndrome. Heno`s family went out to dinner
recently. When they sat down, the family in
the next booth reportedly got up and moved
tables. Milo`s mom didn`t really know why,
but the waiter heard the family that moved
to say this.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
MICHAEL GARCIA, WAITER: Special needs children
need to be special somewhere else. That`s
like saying you can`t come in here because
you have a different skin color.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: Saying goes that the customer is always
right, but Michael Garcia decided what he
heard was wrong. He stood up for Milo and
refused to serve the other customers who walked
out. And the owners backed up the waiter and
said Michael made the right call.
These three guys are high school seniors,
Zick, Jesse and Drew. They were all up for
homecoming king. Jesse, the guy in the middle,
won, except he didn`t. None of them did, because
they al thought that Scotty, the student you
see here, should get the crown. Reporter Jamey
Tucker with the CNN affiliate in Tennessee
tells you what happened.
(BEGIN VIDEOTAPE)
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: Scott is loved by everyone
in school.
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: Scott will make a gloomy
day bright.
JAMEY TUCKER, WHNT TV CORRESPONDENT: Scottie
Maloney, a high school junior, Community High
in Unionville, born with William`s Syndrome,
a neurological disorder that inhibits speech
and learning, but often, and in Scottie`s
case, makes people who have it, abundantly
friendly and happy.
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: He`s a star of this school.
A lot of us look up to him.
TUCKER: Seniors Zig Grissam (ph), Drew Gibbs
and Jesse Cooper were nominees for the school`s
homecoming king. But before the votes were
counted, they came up with an unselfish idea.
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: He is always happy. So
he deserves some recognition for who he is.
TUCKER: With the entire school and most of
the community watching Scottie was named homecoming
king.
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: I`ve seen (inaudible) before,
but I didn`t think it could quite drop (ph)
that much.
TUCKER: And for the next 30 seconds, the crowd
gave Scottie a standing ovation.
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: It was a ton of emotion
just from everybody. I think I saw Scottie
show a few tears, you know, Jesse was pretty
emotional. I mean we`re all emotional out
there on the court.
TUCKER (on camera): It means an awful lot
to you, brother.
SCOTTIE MALONEY: Yes.
TUCKER: Scottie hasn`t taken his medal from
around his neck, and may not, for a long time.
Homecoming king is a high point in one senior
year, but really, who remembers after a few
years.
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: I wouldn`t wear it to school
every day, I would put it on my shelf and
say, I got that, thanks, everybody, for voting
for me. And him, he`s so passionate about
it.
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: You know, every time we
get together, hey, you remember when Scottie
won a homecoming king, and we always look
back and cherish that.
MALONEY: Thank you.
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: You`re welcome, Scottie.
(END VIDEOTAPE)
AZUZ: Well, whether it`s Michael Garcia standing
up for Milo, or those seniors giving Scottie
the memory of a lifetime, people put character
on display all the time. Have you stood up
for someone? Do you know someone who has?
Go to our blog at cnnstudentnews.com, talk
to us about your story.
Which came first - the chicken or the egg?
This Youtube video just doesn`t help clear
things up.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: That`s (inaudible) of a
normal one, not (inaudible), is the one that
has come out more chicken. It`s nearly - nearly
ten inches round.
(LAUGHTER)
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: Oh, my God.
UNIDENTIFIED CHILD: What is that?
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: Shut up.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: An egg inside of an egg - scramble your
brain. If you want to eggsplain that mystery,
you just have to crack the case. But in the
end, the yokes on you, because it`s all just
a show game. For CNN STUDENT NEWS, I`m Carl
Azuz. We`ll see you tomorrow.