So I tell that to Nick--
you probably don't even
remember this--
and Nick said, but
they're so heavy.
Do you remember that?
NICK BUBASH: I don't
remember anything.
I can remember the little
things, but
that's in that article.
She wrote that in
that article.
THOM DEVITA: Oh, is
that the one?
Oh, it was that girl?
NICK BUBASH: She called you
up and interviewed you.
THOM DEVITA: No, she didn't
interview me.
NICK BUBASH: On the phone?
THOM DEVITA: No, it
was an intervisit.
NICK BUBASH: Did she
come up here?
THOM DEVITA: It was
an intervisit.
NICK BUBASH: OK,
THOM DEVITA: Because I don't
give interviews.
NICK BUBASH: This is
not an interview.
JOHN WYATT: When they meet
Thom, they will realize
they've never met anybody
like him before.
He's probably the most different
person, without
trying to be different, of
anybody I've ever met.
ROBERT RYAN: I was a deVita
devotee from the beginning.
It just unlocked this whole
world that I was already
totally into of the lower-East
Side of New York.
There was just this creative
energy there that I think
Thom's work definitely
emanates.
SCOTT HARRISON: He does
what he's inspired
to do at the moment.
He observes and he thinks
carefully about what he sees
and he develops his
own take on it.
-He wasn't just a tattoo
artist, he was
an artist who tattooed.
-You know, it was all one big
ball of wax with him.
Everything he did was art--
the way he lived, the way he
talked, the way he thought,
what he did, where he went.
The tattoos were just as
important as the floor.
THOM DEVITA: If I said
I was an artist, then
I'd be shaming artists.
[INAUDIBLE].
Want to see 100 of them?
-Sure.
THOM DEVITA: When you see color
in my work, that means
it didn't work in black
and I had to color it.
ED HARDY: Just his perceptions
are so completely unique.
And all these years we've been
trying to get the high art
world to recognize him.
And he's just so out there
they just didn't know
where to place it.
They didn't know what
to do with it.
CLAYTON PATTERSON: deVita's
actually extremely important.
Nobody gets it.
But that's the mistake, because
if you don't save that
person's history it
doesn't exist.
THOM DEVITA: And I stopped
going to tattoo
shops after a year.
Every shop I went in, I'd
tell them I'm deVita.
And they never heard
of deVita.
You walk out like you're
an idiot, you know?
Who the hell is deVita?
-And now they're honored
to have you.
THOM DEVITA: No,
let me finish.
You'll have to go in
with the camera.
CLAYTON PATTERSON:
Yeah, I know.
THOM DEVITA: I like
photography.
-You hate filmmakers?
-Who is the cameraman
representing?
THOM DEVITA: I don't know.
He just walked in.
No, he's doing something
on me.
-We're doing a documentary
about Thom.
-Who is the video--
the documentary?
-It's for Vice.
-So are you a part
of Vice, Thom?
THOM DEVITA: Vice squad?
-Yeah.
THOM DEVITA: No, in New York
City the vice squad were the
police who arrested prostitutes
and [INAUDIBLE] of
vice.
-Oh, that goes way back.
I see what you're saying.
Not vice.
All right, yeah.