PATRICK O'DELL: Good.
AARON MEZA: How many slams
have you taken?
PATRICK O'DELL: I don't
even talk about it.
Have you ever been on
this ferry before?
AARON MEZA: Never.
I've never really been
to Washington before.
PETER HEWITT: It's been a while
since I've been here,
but I seem to remember it's
a nice little ride.
There's all kinds of
stuff out there.
I've seen porpoise, there's
orcas swimming around.
I just saw a bald eagle
right over there.
AARON MEZA: Really?
PETER HEWITT: Yeah.
Had a big ol' fish.
MALE SPEAKER: Where
are they going?
MALE SPEAKER: They're
going to Orcas.
So are we!
MALE SPEAKER: Big
roll, big roll!
[YELLING]
PATRICK O'DELL: What's up?
We're on the ferry heading
to Orcas Island.
There's a really good
park there.
And everyone's going to skate.
This the second demo
of the trip.
It's been like a week
and a half so far,
but only two demos.
There's three demos total.
I don't know if it'll
be crowded because
it's hard to get to.
But it's going to be big.
Because everyone's really
amped to skate it.
There's camping.
We're going to camp for a couple
days on the island.
We got to do like a long
hike to get there.
And I don't know, I'm
pretty excited.
MALE SPEAKER: Oh!
That's so beautiful, dude.
Come on, little birdies.
Come on, pelican.
Oh, you got it, you got
it, you got it!
One of them's going to come
in hard on you dude.
MALE SPEAKER: Whoa!
ROBBIE RUSSO: It's a good
day for flying a kite.
RICK HOWARD: Wow.
Robbie!
He's going to get
it, this guy.
AARON MEZA: Is that
your wizard stick?
MALE SPEAKER: Man,
yours is weak.
MIKE CARROLL: I just
started, barely.
AARON MEZA: Is there always
a cup at the bottom?
MIKE CARROLL: Well, I had
another cup, and I was going
to try to put them together.
Couple people said it's not
fair or it's against
regulation.
MALE SPEAKER: Oh, whoa, whoa.
Epicly faded.
Epicly O'Douled.
AARON MEZA: Brian.
Did you just puke?
Are you all right, Brian?
That looked all red.
BRIAN ANDERSON: I'll
be all right.
It was red, huh?
AARON MEZA: Yeah, it
looked like blood.
Like I was freaked out.
BRIAN ANDERSON: Yeah,
let's look at it.
Does that look like blood?
AARON MEZA: What did you eat?
BRIAN ANDERSON: I don't
know, dude.
MALE SPEAKER: You did
puke up blood?
BRIAN ANDERSON: I don't know.
MALE SPEAKER: Did you have
anything, like Powerades to
drink or anything?
BRIAN ANDERSON: I probably
did, yeah.
MALE SPEAKER: Put the
light on it again?
TONY MIORANA: Yeah.
Beer, blood.
AARON MEZA: Looked really
red coming out of there.
TONY MIORANA: OK.
MALE SPEAKER: It's not thick
enough to be blood, though.
Beer blood?
MALE SPEAKER: That's
what she said.
AARON MEZA: Hey TMo, tell me
about your wizard stick
TONY MIORANA: OK.
The wizard stick's probably--
this is my first
one I've ever done.
But this tells exactly where
you are in the night.
You can walk with anyone, they
can see how many heights they
got, or how many cans
they got down.
And if they're a real wizard.
If they're not a wizard, you're
like, yeah, you only
got four cans?
Not worthy of even
hanging out with.
Why would I even talk to you
right now, waste my time.
I'm a real wizard.
AARON MEZA: So how many
beers until it's
official wizard status?
TONY MIORANA: Your height.
You can just cross it out in
front of your tent and say,
don't cross this path.
There's a drunk wizard
in here.
Why would you mess with
a drunk wizard?
MALE SPEAKER: Regulation.
AARON MEZA: Regulation what?
MALE SPEAKER: Regulation
tape size to the can.
MALE SPEAKER: Can't
waste the tape.
MALE SPEAKER: That
shit's expensive.
Just duct tape, baby.
MIKE CARROLL: Can't
waste the tape.
AARON MEZA: Preston, are
you a wizard yet?
PRESTON: Nope.
I'm an inch below.
AARON MEZA: Even though you
got all those side beers?
PRESTON: Yeah.
Doesn't count.
AARON MEZA: Had you known
that, would you
still have done it?
PRESTON: No, I'm just going to
keep it below my height all
night so I don't ever
become a wizard.
AARON MEZA: Rick, where's
your wizard staff?
RICK HOWARD: I'm uh,
night off staff.
AARON MEZA: You're going to win
the demo then, tomorrow.
RICK HOWARD: I don't think so.
I've got half a leg.
One and a half legs, so.
I'm doing the heel up today.
MIKE CARROLL: Who's not
a wizard yet and
wants to be a wizard?
Let's do the shocker game.
Ready?
Set?
Oh.
MALE SPEAKER: (LAUGHING)
That's you.
MALE SPEAKER: It
was that fast?
MIKE CARROLL: It's not even that
fucking strong, though.
That's what sucks.
AARON MEZA: Robbie, put that
thing next to you.
ROBBIE RUSSO: Fucking massive.
MALE SPEAKER: I'm
Robbie Wizard.
MALE SPEAKER: Use your
fucking brain, OK?
You use your brain.
MALE SPEAKER: Wow.
If we shoot off a flash
right here--
MALE SPEAKER: You got more
of a brain than both
of us, so use it.
MALE SPEAKER: Wow, that really
killed like, the rest of the
camp, right?
MALE SPEAKER: You got
your photo, man.
That's a pretty good one.
MALE SPEAKER: Turn
the light out.
Turn that fucking
light out now.
Ugh.
MALE SPEAKER: I'm so mad.
You didn't drink
as much as me.
That's what happens when
you're a weak bitch.
And you can't drink
as much as me.
MIKE CARROLL: Sleeper
play fight.
MALE SPEAKER: You just lost
your whole staff.
You just lost your
whole staff.
Your staff sucks.
Your staff sucks!
All right.
T, would you chill
the fuck out?
You're going to get
fucking mopped up!
MALE SPEAKER: Shh, shh.
MALE SPEAKER: Chill.
Chill.
Ugh.
I hate when you do
the feet thing.
Stop with the feet thing.
We're friends!
Get away!
We're hugging!
We're hugging.
You better get me near
him right now.
MALE SPEAKER: This is
aggressive hugging.
MALE SPEAKER: Get me near him.
Why are they holding us
back from one another?
We're friends!
MALE SPEAKER: Turn the fucking
light off. dude.