My name is Annette Ramos.
I'm the fashion editor
at Vice.
And today you're at my house
because I am babysitting for
my parents' sugar gliders.
I know that they're
from Australia.
They're marsupials.
They are closely related
to koalas.
They are called sugar gliders
because of their preference
for nectarous foods.
And they basically just
eat fruit and insects.
I'm feeding them peach yogurt.
They hate all other flavors,
though, which is weird.
They are very easy to take care
of-- apples, Gatorade,
and grain, and maybe
some yogurt.
Their tails are so long because
they can actually use
them to wrap around things.
And they have these crazy
long tongues, too.
They are, like, this long.
They clean themselves.
You'll see them huddled up in
a ball together just, like,
licking each other.
They have little flaps
underneath both of their arms.
If you put them on a high
ledge, they fly off.
No, no, no, you're not
going in my closet.
When we first got them, it took
a while to get used to
them because they would
just jump on you.
And sometimes, if you're not
turned the right way, they'll
jump into your hair and just,
like, dangle there.
Come on, yeah.
[LAUGH]
During the day, I let them crawl
around because they are
normally really tame
and sleepy.
So they're not trying
to experiment.
Where is she?
They actually sleep
most of the day.
They're nocturnal, so they wake
up at 10:00 PM, normally,
and they go to bed
around 10:00 PM.
But every now and then they wake
up during the day just to
play, and then they
go back to sleep.
But when they're awake,
they're awake
for, like, 12 hours.
They love this wheel, which
is extremely loud.
Because they're awake all night,
it's a little difficult
taking care of them in
a studio apartment.
And then occasionally at night,
they will bark if they
want your attention, like when
they first wake up, they want
to see you.
My dogs, they're fascinated
by them.
I have an Italian Greyhound.
My little Chihuahua really
likes them too.
She would just sniff at them if
you have them in your hands
when you're feeding them.
I think they're about done
with us for today.
They're going to go back to
sleep and wake up at 10:00.
They don't want to play
with us anymore.