Filipino version of a
flavored snow cone.
In the Philippines, typically
it's topped up with, like,
Rice Krispies that are like
the bootleg version.
They're not even in a box.
They're in the bag.
They're like on the bottom
shelf, and they're in the bag.
And it's like, hey,
man, I looked at--
I was like, if I'm going
to put cereal on this.
I'm going to put like
dope cereal on it.
I'm going to put Cap'n Crunch.
It's my favorite.
Seriously, dude, some people
get it, some people
just don't get it.
Well, people who do love it,
they take a bite of it, and
there's this instant
childhood memory.
And you could tell that it
clicks with some people.
And when it doesn't,
you're just like--
you had like granola
and yogurt, right?
Your parents were hippies
or some shit.
And they didn't give
you crappy cereal.
Because I grew up on that,
and I love that shit.
[CHUCKLES]
[THEME MUSIC]
DALE TALDE: Hi.
My name is Dale Talde.
This is Talde Restaurant,
Park Slope, Brooklyn.
The food here at Talde
is Asian-American.
It's holding on to some of these
very traditional dishes
and then giving it a Brooklyn,
local, American feel to it.
The neighborhood needed not
just regular Tom Yum soup
because they can get that in
any Thai place around here.
They wanted something more.
I love Pad Thai.
It's my thing.
So I put brunch and
Pad Thai together.
And then I will just gild the
lily a little bit and add some
more oysters to it.
If I was hung over
and--like today--
and to fix me up, to
me, Pad Thai is the
perfect hangover food.
It's starch.
It's greasy.
It soaks up all the poison.
And when I thought about it,
I was like, you know what?
For me, if I could have it for
brunch, I would every day.
First restaurant
job was Outback
Steakhouse, Bloomin' Onions.
I was absolutely terrible.
Pretty bad when you get stoned
before you go to work.
And then you're trying to work
a station, and you're not
really good at cooking
as it is.
And you're trying
to do it stoned.
Didn't work out too well.
I love what I do, but I don't
take myself too seriously.
Top Chef gave me enormous
opportunities.
I mean, you get to travel.
You get to meet tons
of cool people.
I mean, Dave recognized me
walking into Enoteca, where at
the time he was the GM and
recognized me because he
watched the show.
And honestly, if I hadn't gone
on the show, I probably won't
be here right now.
So last night, David Massoni,
my partner, and John Bush,
bartender and owner--
at the end of the shift
we went to Franny's.
JOHN BUSH: I am hungry.
DAVID MASSONI: I
am hungry, too.
DALE TALDE: Me, too.
JOHN BUSH: They know
we're coming?
DAVID MASSONI: They
know we're coming.
Martin and the boys are ready.
DALE TALDE: You don't need
to go to Manhattan.
You really don't.
I mean, if you want to eat well,
stay at the borough of
Brooklyn because they're
doing a killer job.
MARTIN GOBBEE: Yeah.
Should we seat you, guys?
DAVID MASSONI: Shall we go ahead
and have a seat, yeah?
DALE TALDE: Hi, how's
it going?
Dale, Dale Talde.
It's nice to meet you.
He was a fucking
big dude, man.
If he came around my kitchen,
I was like--
I don't know.
I'm not exactly the tallest
dude in the world, man.
You got to be like 6'4".
DANNY AMEND: Franny's is
definitely a southern Italian
restaurant.
We do make hand noodles, but
most of our noodles are dry,
which is what you
would typically
find in southern Italy.
So this is definitely my
favorite dish right now.
And it might be my favorite
Franny's dish ever--
real basic citrus salad.
Growing up in California--
I'm from northern California.
My mom had a satsuma tangerine
tree that grow on our deck.
And I used to eat this
all the time.
So it tastes a little
bit like home.
When I finish it,
it has parsley.
It has red onion, pistachios,
hot peppers that we
pickle in the house.
So it's got a lot
more soul to it.
DALE TALDE: I mean their level
of execution in what they're
doing is so spot on.
They were the benchmark for
what we hope to be.
They are destination restaurant
on Flatbush Ave.--
on Flatbush Ave., like four
blocks away from where the
Mets are going to
play next year.
People are coming out to see
them because the food is
fucking dope.
And they're doing a good job.
They're doing everything
in-house.
You can tell.
DANNY AMEND: Spigarello, which
is basically broccoli leaf.
For me, I never had it before
I came to Franny's.
And that's another cool thing
about the restaurant is we do
a lot of things that most
people have never had.
DALE TALDE: Mm.
It's so fucking good.
It's like the best cool
flavor I've ever had.
What we're doing is
just a craft.
With them, you could tell
that the level of
craftsmanship is so high.
Hopefully, we can get there.
I mean, we're working
hard every day.
This is the fucking pasta
I want to do.
This kind of food makes
you fucking jealous.
[LAUGHTER]
DAVID MASSONI: It makes
you jealous?
DALE TALDE: Yeah, it's
like-- what the fuck?
What have I done with my life?
[CHUCKLES]
I'm making fried rice.
DAVID MASSONI: This food makes
you wish you were Italian.
DALE TALDE: It really does.
DAVID MASSONI: Cheers, guys.
The first night out since we
opened the restaurant--
DALE TALDE: --together.
And it depends on the level
of sobriety on that.
It's what I want to eat.
So I've had two whiskeys.
I'm being somewhat civilized.
And if I've gone on to, like
three or four, then I'm really
starting to get into the gross,
uncivilized pizza with
a ton a ranch and sriracha.
And it's total blasphemy,
but I'm down.
I've got dope fat kid moves--
making a box of mac and cheese,
eating half of it, and
then saving the hot sauce
for the last half.
So all of a sudden it tastes
different and shit.
So like, oh, no, I have
a new mac and cheese.
Somebody farted.
DAVID MASSONI: It wasn't me.
DALE TALDE: Somebody farted.
DAVID AND JOHN (OFFSCREEN):
Whoever smelt it, dealt it.
[CHUCKLES]
DALE TALDE: From Franny's we
jumped in a cab and went to
Pearl's Social Club in Bushwick,
deep in Bushwick--
those mad handlebar mustaches
and really tight pants.
Goddamn, in the borough,
you could tell, like
Monday is for pros.
Friday and Saturday is for
amateurs, and Monday is for
the pros to go out because it
was like all industry folks.
And it was two, three
at the bar deep.
DAVID MASSONI: Hi, can I have
three shots of Jamesons and
three Tecates?
DALE TALDE: People are
drinking cheap beer.
And I was like good, this is
getting fucked up, but I'm
having a good time.
And it's awesome.
That bar is awesome.
DAVID MASSONI: To hanging
out again.
Salud.
DALE TALDE: So we all did a shot
of Jameson, drank a beer.
And then Betsy, who
owns the bar--
awesome, awesome person-- she
made us a cocktail and made it
with the tobacco bitters.
JOHN BUSH: What are
these called?
BETSY MAHER: Red dawn.
DALE TALDE: America,
fuck yeah!
And that was it for me.
That was the--
you get to that point, and you
just know that it's the end of
your night?
And that was the end
of the night.
And we were only like 2/3.
[CHUCKLES]
We weren't even halfway there.
DAVID (OFFSCREEN):
Can somebody get
Dale a glass of water?
DALE TALDE: It's
like that big.
DAVID MASSONI: A
glass of water?
DALE TALDE: I feel like
a lot of pressure.
Like, I have to actually
cook for people now.
And I'm going to get shit-faced
and now, I have to
fucking cook.
JOHN BUSH: So Betsy, you want
to come back and have some
food with us tonight?
We got some grub munchies.
DALE TALDE: And we asked all the
guys, Martin, the chef of
Franny's, Betsy to come on in.
Hey, Bill, so we're
on our way back.
DAVID MASSONI: [LAUGHTER]
JOHN BUSH: You better
be good, man.
I'm hungry and I
got to go bed.
DALE TALDE: Not really.
I'm not really prepared
to cook shit.
I've been cooking
fucking all day.
Now, I'm rundown.
I told my guys there better
be like 3 pounds of butter
outside so I can make something
fucking taste good.
Brought it back here.
And to be honest with you, I
hope it tasted good because I
remember very little what
the fuck happened.
Planning some black
bean lobster--
uh, I'm sorry, black
bean clams.
Where the fuck is everything?
Chow fun noodles--
I don't have the clams.
Clams seem to not be here.
No, I've no fucking idea what
I'm planning to do right now.
[LAUGHTER]
I do not recommend using a wok
when you're fucking hammered.
They're about 180,000 btus,
jet flames that
pop out of that wok.
It's taken ice from ice to
boiling in 4 minutes.
Do a little hot sauce.
Cooking is about fire and food
and the application of heat
and/or salt and/or whatever.
But I'm not one of those
cooks that are subtle.
And my food's always been "punch
in your face" flavors.
I will sacrifice the
way something looks
over taste any day.
Chili black bean, brown
butter clams.
"Nooder?" Did anybody ask for
some "nooders?" Chow fun
"nooder?"
I gotta serve you guys.
You guys hooked us up.
A little red-cooked pork shank
with the chow fun noodle,
charred red cabbage, and
some bean sprouts.
This restaurant is
my last name.
It's kind of a tribute to my
family and my mom and my dad,
who've helped me get
to where I am.
When we ate celebratory meals,
it was always like--
it was my mom and eight of her
sisters and her entire family.
So it was all of us getting
together and eating.
You have to love that part of
restaurants, that atmosphere
of hospitality and cooking
for others and
doing all for others.
Making people happy, that's
what it's about.
[MUSIC PLAYING]