resigned his
government. "The Square"
is a newly-released documentary
that gives a street-level look
at the ongoing
revolution since 2011.
AHMED HASSAN: [SPEAKING ARABIC]
[GUN SHOTS]
[CROWD CHEERING]
JACOB SOBOROFF: It's up
for an Oscar this Sunday.
And we've got the filmmaker
Jehane and the producer Karim
right here.
Hi, guys.
JEHANE NOUJAIM: Hey, what's up?
KARIM AMER: How are
you doing, YouTube?
JACOB SOBOROFF: Guys, tell
us about the challenges
of making a film like this.
JEHANE NOUJAIM: All of us got
either arrested, tear gassed,
shot at at various points
in the making of the film.
JACOB SOBOROFF: When they first
debuted the movie at Sundance,
it wasn't even
reallt done, right?
JEHANE NOUJAIM: It was
a work in progress,
and we promised all
of our characters
that we would go back
and continue filming.
Because we had a very neat
story from the bringing
down of a dictator to the
election of a president.
But the story wasn't over,
because all of our characters,
when we were on the
way to Sundance,
were back in the streets
again, basically saying,
this newly-elected president,
first freely-elected president
of Egypt, is using
the tools of democracy
to create another dictatorship.
[CROWD CHANTING IN ARABIC]
JACOB SOBOROFF: So these guys
just put the movie on YouTube
for the people in Egypt.
What motivated that, and
how does it work exactly?
KARIM AMER: YouTube
was an integral part
of this revolution.
When you live in a country where
the media is in full control
and is lying about what's
happening on the ground,
our young activists used
YouTube as their own channel
to spread their stores.
AHMED HASSAN: [SPEAKING ARABIC]
JACOB SOBOROFF: Obviously,
right now there's
protests in Venezuela,
unrest in the Ukraine.
Why now is this time important
for people to see this film,
do you think?
JEHANE NOUJAIM: What
these kids are fighting
for is what this
country was founded on,
which is civil
liberties and freedom
of expression and human rights.
I mean, it's the civil
rights struggle of our time.
And that's what's
happening in Egypt
right now as they're
being silenced.
And so releasing this
film now and the support
of the international
community makes it
so that it's not just a
lonely fight of protesters
on the frontlines in Egypt.
It makes it a global fight.
AHMED HASSAN: [SPEAKING ARABIC]
JACOB SOBOROFF: Jehane's
the only female director
nominated for an
Oscar this year.
Where can people see this movie?
JEHANE NOUJAIM:
Well, you can see it
on Netflix in 47 countries,
including the US.
And also internationally,
you can see it
by going to our YouTube site.
JACOB SOBOROFF: Thank you
so much to these guys.
We've put together a playlist
with moments of triumph
from Tahrir Square.
You could see that
after the show.
[MUSIC PLAYING]