DAN: I really wanted
to be in the NBA.
That didn't work out.
And then I skateboarded, and
I didn't really think about
anything else.
And then, just go to art school,
because you can't go
anywhere else.
And you just start taking it
seriously at some point.
I didn't assume that I could
make a living off of it as
quickly as I did.
It's fortunate that I didn't
have to figure out
something to do.
I don't think I'm that
good of a painter, or
anything like that.
I just figure it out.
It's not natural.
It's all really formulated.
Painting from a photograph,
you just study it.
And you just figure out.
If I just keep putting dots
down, really, really slowly,
forever, it'll just work out.
People really like my
candle paintings.
That's what they really like.
The last one I finished, it
took me a year to make.
So they take a long time.
I just found this image.
I was looking though a Disney
book a long time ago.
It's just a still
from Pinocchio.
It's Geppetto's work table.
The candle's just extinguishing
in all the
paintings, and there's
smoke coming out it.
And there are those
words up there.
I don't pick them randomly,
but there's no
theme to the text.
One says, "fuck,." One said,
"so long." This one says
"whatever."
I made a "blow me" one.
And I really liked it.
And I must be a moron for it
not having occurred to me.
But when somebody pointed out
the double entendre to it, I
really started disliking it.
But it was already gone.
I don't really know
what it's about.
But it's not that.
INTERVIEWER: How many
of those candle
paintings have you made?
DAN: There is two hung
over there, that are
being worked on.
And I have one really tiny one
that I'm still working on.
And that'll be 13, I think.
I don't really know if 13 was
a number that has any
relevance to me.
But I just don't need to
work on them anymore.
And I can't take it, also.
It becomes really painful
painting the same one over and
over again.
And in terms of--
I'm not even really working
on them that much anymore.
I did the first lot of them.
But hen you can just show
people how to do them.
And you work on them
with them.
And basically, what the
assistants enable me to do is
that I can work on multiple
things at once.
Maybe I'll fiddle with stuff
or think about stuff.
Or, I don't know.
And I stay here all night.
And I go home in the morning,
and I come back.
I mean I'm in here everyday,
messing around with
something or other.
The bird shit, the kiss, and the
gum all kind of come from
the same place.
I just started trying to pursue
other ideas of making
paintings or using a canvas.
INTERVIEWER: It's
real gum, right?
DAN: It's all real gum.
This is just moving them from
one canvas to another.
I'm just messing around.
I don't really touch
them at all.
I just like them to look
as random as possible.
So I just have them transfer
them between canvases.
I try to get them to
do it really quick.
And then I come over
and finesse it
a little bit, maybe.
It's pretty idiotic.
You want me to try to talk about
why I make them, and--
INTERVIEWER: Yeah, absolutely.
Yeah.
DAN: I don't really have
[INAUDIBLE] like that.
But on the rocks, the rocks were
about, they looked like
these things that you come up to
walking through the woods.
And teenagers would set
up camp around there.
And drink beer.
And so there's spray paint
all over them.
And people stick gum
on rocks and trees.
So that's were it came from,
from rocks and trees, or
underneath desks, all
that kind of stuff.
INTERVIEWER: Can I stick
my gum to this one now?
DAN: Yeah, go for it.
INTERVIEWER: All
right, awesome.
Anywhere?
DAN: Anywhere you want.
INTERVIEWER: Cool.
Thanks.
DAN: Thank you.
INTERVIEWER: How do you
go about making this?
Do you look at a lot of bird
shit photos, or something?
DAN: I actually would
walk around Chelsea,
underneath the High Line.
Because you know all the birds
hang out over there.
And take lots of pictures.
I've made a lot of them,
like 150 maybe.
Some look really real.
Some remind people of these kind
of paintings, and others,
abstract paintings.
You learn new techniques, but
you're just throwing paint at
the canvas, basically.
INTERVIEWER: So this kiss
one, is this one
person, or many people?
DAN: This is one person.
I thought they had
really close to a
perfect set of lips.
INTERVIEWER: That must have
taken them forever.
DAN: Took her a long time.
INTERVIEWER: And
it's lipstick?
A lot of lipstick?
DAN: Yeah, it's all lipstick.
INTERVIEWER: How many tubes?
DAN: She wears a little
wrestling
mask so that she doesn't--
she was getting these horrible
rashes on her nose and chins.
But after she did this she said
she would never ever do
it again, which is too bad,
because I really, really like
this painting a lot.
I think this is really pretty.
And I feel like I never really
make straightforwardly stuff
that [INAUDIBLE] beautiful.
But it still has enough dirty
implications to satisfy that
side of me.
This is a Jewish prayer shawl.
It's called a tallit, and it's
hanging off a boner.
It just came to me, randomly.
Not through--
it's pretty easy for somebody
to think lots of different
thoughts about it.
But I didn't have one
particular one.
INTERVIEWER: Well, you're
Jewish, right?
DAN: I'm Jewish, yeah.
INTERVIEWER: Did you get
any feedback to it?
DAN: People in Berlin
reacted to it.
And they were all ripped
down really quick.
But you don't know if it's
Jews ripping it down, or
neo-Nazis ripping it down.
I couldn't say.
Nobody's said anything in
depth to me about it.
Some people think it's silly.
And some people think
it's funny.
I don't know.
INTERVIEWER: I see another
Jewish biblical theme.
DAN: Yeah.
I am who I am.
But I still like--
there's something really
straightforward about it where
it's like, you know,
a bunch of animals
bummed on Noah's ark.
But beyond that, I don't
have anything I can
really say about it.
But there's tons of
religious things.
Even with like something
like the candle.
When I first saw the image,
I'm thinking something
God-like about that.
This is actually just
a giant Constable
painting that I copied.
And I put in all the
signs and stuff.
I'm not a spiritual person,
necessarily, but I think about
stuff like that sometimes.
So it will come up in my work.
There are millions of people
running around the world
talking about some God.
I'm curious about where he
is, and stuff like that.
I'd like to find him.
INTERVIEWER: What do you think
about the art world?
Do you like the art world?
DAN: I'm collected seriously.
I'm in really big, important
shows, especially
for somebody my age.
I work a lot, so I
produce a lot.
And people seem to
like it, too.
But I feel like writers and
people like that would rather
like not take me seriously.
But I don't know exactly why.
And, yeah, you could speculate
something about--
because my lifestyle is fun, or
stupid, or whatever, that
they think that I don't take
my work seriously.
Or maybe they're just
unhappy themselves.
Whatever.
There's things about the
art world that I
don't really like.
There's lots of stupid shit with
market, or collectors, or
curators, or bullshit
like that.
But I try not to think about
it, and just make my work.
I don't see a point in
constantly bashing it or being
bummed out on it.
Because I'd be depressed
all the time.
So I just pay attention
and make my work.
And sometimes I'll go to
a party where I have
to deal with them.
And I find a way to have fun.
I think that if I was walking
around bummed about the art
world all time, I wouldn't be
able to be a part of it.