Well, I'm singing 'Valerie' today,
by Amy Winehouse, and I'm just singing it
because it's one of my favourite
songs to sing.
I sing it in different family occasions
for, like, weddings and parties
and different things.
And my granddad really loves this song
so, whenever I sing it, it makes him happy.
So it's a big day for you, today.
Yep.
This could be the big break.
Exactly.
The first day of the rest of your life.
Dec: Is this mum?
Karen: That's me.
Ant: Look at that face, he's not worried.
Dec: Hiya, mum. You alright?
Karen: That's me.
Ant: Look at that face, he's not worried.
Dec: Hiya, mum. You alright?
Karen: Yeah, fine.
Ant: Look at that face, he's not worried.
Dec: Hiya, mum. You alright?
Karen: Yeah, fine.
Ant: He's not worried.
Dec: Hiya, mum. You alright?
So, let's see if this little boy can make
his and his mum's dreams come true.
Hello
My name's Shaheen Jafargholi.
OK, what're you gonna sing?
I'm gonna sing 'Valerie' by Amy Winehouse.
Are you?
OK, good luck.
#  'Valerie' as performed by Amy Winehouse  #
You got this really wrong.
What do you sing apart from that?
'Who's Loving You' by Michael Jackson.
You wanna give that a go?
OK
#  'Who's Loving You'  #
#  as performed by Michael Jackson  #
Dec: Wow.
#  'Who's Loving You'  #
#  as performed by Michael Jackson  #
Look at Simon. [inaudible]
#  'Who's Loving You'  #
#  as performed by Michael Jackson  #
That is amazing.
#  'Who's Loving You'  #
#  as performed by Michael Jackson  #
Wow!
OK,
Simon.
Er, this is how one song can change your life.
And this may be
the start of something special for you,
young man.
Really.
Piers
Shaheen.
Well, you have just shown
that Wales has got talent.
Thank you.
Doesn't happen to me very often,
but I get... I do the goosebump test.
I got it with Paul Potts,
I got it with George Sampson,
and I got it with you.
Piers, yes or no?
It's a definite 'yes' from me, Shaheen.
Oh, it's a no-brainer.
Yes!
Thank you.
Shaking
I know, I'm shaking, I'm really nervous.
Shaheen,
you just got three very large yesses.
Thank you!
Love him...
love him!
Well done!
Thank you.
Well done, that was amazing.
That's a really hard song to sing, that.
I mean really hard.
What did it feel like at the end, there?
Everybody stood up,
the three judges were on their feet.
It was (just) amazing.
I never knew I could make somebody do that.
It's just... ah. Can't describe it –
words can't describe it.
It was really good.