UNIDENTIFIED MALE: I`m President Barack Obama.
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: Vice President Joe Biden.
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: I`m Governor Mitt Romney.
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: And I`m Paul Ryan.
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: And this is our election
in Middle School in Charleston, West Virginia,
and this is -- CNN Student News.
(cheers)
CARL AZUZ, CNN ANCHOR: Oh-ho, man, that was
awesome. Thanks to everyone at Oresman (ph)
Middle for getting things going today with
that I- Report.
From your mock debate, we are going to jump
right into the presidential debate.
Last night was the third and final face-off
between Barack Obama and Mitt Romney. This
debate was held at Lynn University in Boca
Raton, Florida, and it focused on foreign
policy. So we are talking about ways in which
the United States interacts with the rest
of the world. Election day is exactly two
weeks away. Candidates will still be out at
events on the campaign trail. But last night
was the last chance they had to present some
of their ideas to a large audience all at
once. Here is some of what happened.
(BEGIN VIDEOTAPE)
MITT ROMNEY, REPUBLICAN PRESIDENTIAL CANDIDATE:
I absolutely believe that America has a responsibility
and the privilege of helping defend freedom
and promote the principles that make the world
more peaceful, and those principles include
human rights, human dignity, free enterprise,
freedom of expression, elections because when
there are elections people tend to vote for
peace. They don`t vote for war. So we want
to promote those principles around the world.
We recognize that there are places of conflict
in the world. We want to end those conflicts
to the extend humanly possible. But in order
to be able to fulfill our role in the world,
America must be strong.
BARACK OBAMA, PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED STATES
OF AMERICA: America remains the one indispensable
nation and the world needs a strong America
and it is stronger now than when I came into
office. Because we ended the war in Iraq we
were able to refocus our attention on not
only the terrorist threat, but also beginning
a transition process in Afghanistan. It also
allowed us to refocus on alliances, relationships
that have been neglected for a decade. And
Governor Romney, our alliances have never
been stronger. In Asia, in Europe, in Africa,
with Israel where we have unprecedented military
and intelligence cooperation, including dealing
with the Iranian threat.
(END VIDEOTAPE)
AZUZ: One of the topics that came up during
last night debate was outsourcing. It`s when
a company has a different business do some
kind of work. So, instead of doing it themselves,
companies pay someone else to do it. Outsourcing
can help companies save money and maybe help
keep cost down on the products that they sell.
But if U.S company outsources work to a different
country, it means those jobs aren`t being
done by American workers. Maggie Lake has
more on the impact of outsourcing and the
presidential candidates` plans to do something
about it.
(BEGIN VIDEOTAPE)
MITT ROMNEY: Thank you.
PAUL RYAN: Thank you.
MAGGIE LAKE, CNN CORRESPONDENT: Whether on
the campaign trail ...
ROMNEY: If there is an outsourcer-in-chief,
it`s the president of the United States.
LAKE: Or amid the barrage of
political ads on TV.
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: Mitt Romney`s firms were
pioneers at helping companies outsource their
manufacturing to countries including China.
LAKE: Outsourcing is a hot button issue again
in presidential politics. In states like Ohio,
Pennsylvania and Michigan where scores of
factory jobs have been lost, it is a deeply
emotional issue.
JOE KLEIN, TIME MAGAZINE: They do a lot of
focus grouping, and polling and testing. And
what they find is, that this is very resonant.
LAKE: In recent years, the manufacturing sector
of the U.S. has been hit particularly hard.
Over five and a half million jobs lost between
2000 and 2009. A million alone to China. But
that tide maybe turning as companies rethink
their commitment to lower wage countries.
HAL SIRKIN, BOSTON CONSULTING GROUP: Wages
in China are, you know, topping $3 an hour.
Wages will probably be something around $6
an hour or so in 2015. It starts to become
competitive with the U.S., you have the intellectual
property risk, and being far away from (ph)
consumer means you are not on top of the trends.
LAKE: General Electric and Caterpillar are
just a few of the companies who have recently
brought some of their production back to the
U.S. Economists warn the manufacturing revival
has a long way to go, but both candidates
are pledging they can get the job done.
Mitt Romney continues to call for lower taxes
for businesses, just for investment. And tougher
trade relations with China.
President Obama is also calling for tax incentives
for companies that bring jobs back to the
U.S. and touting the auto industry bailout
which Romney opposed. Maggie Lake, CNN, New York.
(END VIDEOTAPE)
AZUZ: All right, next stop: Lance Armstrong.
He won cycling`s most famous race, seven times
in a row, but you can`t call him a Tour de
France champion anymore. Yesterday, the International
Cycling Union said it was wiping out Armstrong`s
titles and banning him from the sport.
This was in response to a report from the
U.S. Anti-Doping Agency. It says there is
overwhelming evidence that Armstrong used
banned performance enhancing drugs during
his career. Armstrong has always denied that.
In addition to losing his Tour de France titles,
Armstrong is being asked to return nearly
$4 million that he won for those seven Tour
victories.
Cheerleaders, they`ve got spirit? Yes, they
do. But they do a lot more than just chant
and clap and try to get the home crows excited.
We are talking about pyramids, flips, tosses.
Cheerleading involves some pretty serious
acrobatic stance, and that`s got some doctors
concerned about some pretty serious injuries.
The American Academy of Pediatrics just put
out a new policy on cheerleading injuries.
The group says that injury rate in cheerleading
is low compared to other sports, but the number
of catastrophic injuries, like brain and spinal
cord injuries in cheering is going up. The
new policy suggests that cheerleaders limit
their stance and avoid doing them on hard
surfaces, and that they should be checked
for concussions if they have a head injury.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: Today "Shoutout" goes
out to Ms. Kreicker in the Cougar Culture
Club at South Middle School in Lawrence, Kansas.
"Which of these positions is the leader of
a marching band? Here we go, is it: the field
marshal, drill instructor, drum major or concertmaster?
You`ve got three seconds, go!
A marching band is led by its drum major.
That`s your answer and that`s your "Shoutout."
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: At the University of Missouri, the drum
major leads a marching band of more than 300
members. It`s one of the largest college marching
bands in the country. Now, its current head
drum major says he wanted the job so that
people could look up to him in difficult times,
but he wasn`t just talking about the marching
band. Dr. Sanjay Gupta explains what we mean.
(BEGIN VIDEOTAPE)
DR. SANJAY GUPTA, CNN CORRESPONDENT: As a
drum major for marching Missou (ph), the University
of Missouri`s famed marching band, Paul Heddings
is living his dream.
It`s a new dream, because his original dream
of playing professional baseball was disappearing.
PAUL HEDDINGS, UNIV. OF MISSOURI DRUM MAJOR:
September Seventh, 2007, just (inaudible)
my junior high school ...
GUPTA: The 17-year old woke up, and his world
was changing.
HEDDINGS: Everything was just a little blurry,
it didn`t seem like anything was wrong.
GUPTA: But something was terribly wrong. His
retinas had detached and started to tear apart
in both eyes.
HEDDINGS: I didn`t know how my life would
change, what I`d be able to do, what I wouldn`t
be able to do. I could potentially go completely
blind ...
GUPTA: Paul says this was not caused by disease
or trauma, but by genetics.
HEDDINGS: This has happened to my mom, my
grandma and a couple of uncles. Even my little
sister is having some more issues.
GUPTA: They didn`t lose much vision. Paul,
on the other hand, is now legally blind. Sight
in his best eye can`t be corrected beyond
2200. He says family, friends and music saved
his life. He joined his high school drum line,
taking the music home, magnifying it, memorizing
it.
HEDDINGS: Here we go, be flat!
I just, you know, strapped up my boots and
went to work.
GUPTA: He made the Missou (ph) drum line first
playing cymbals and then after an extensive
interview process clinched the coveted drum
major spot. Most in the band didn`t even know
he was legally blind.
Heddings hopes his time on the letter will
change the perception of visually impaired
people.
HEDDINGS: I want to be able to say when I
leave here that I did something special, and
that I didn`t let this hold me back.
(END VIDEOTAPE)
AZUZ: Great story. Finally today, we have
a cavalcade of costume canines (ph). It may
look like a dog, but this is guy is a real
turkey. Gobbling up for bunch of attention
at a Halloween parade for pooches. A hot dog
costume for a dog? Come on, that`s too easy.
Hello, if he falls behind on the parade, he`ll
have to catch-up. It may seem out of the ordinary
to see a dog dressed up like a former first
lady of Argentina, but it`s just a sign of
the season. After all, we are right around
the corner from Halloween. We`ve reached the
tail in the today show but we will be bark
tomorrow, more CNN STUDENT NEWS. I hope to
see you all then.