[SPEAKING JAPANESE]
MITSUO: Stand up, first.
CHRIS GARVER: I know a lot of
people are like, oh, I'd love
to go work at Three Tides.
They're are a world
famous shop.
It's got great artists.
It's going to go down in
history as one of those
legendary shops.
I tattooed at Three Tides
several times.
I went out there for the first
time with Juan Puente after
they had that 1999 first tattoo
convention in Tokyo.
The first Tokyo convention in
1999, that was a pretty
groundbreaking thing, especially
for Japan.
Because in Japan tattooing
is not as open.
There wasn't, at that
time, too much
communication between artists.
[INAUDIBLE] it was known that
there was going to be a really
big International convention
there.
That was a really big move.
When so many foreigners came
over to Japan, and a lot of
people wanted to stay.
So a lot of the tattooers
were invited to work
at different shops.
And I got invited to work
at Three Tides.
When I went there the first
time, it was Horitomo.
He was Washo then.
Mutsuo was an apprentice.
He hadn't started
tattooing yet.
I had tattooed Washo in
1991 in Philadelphia.
He didn't speak any
English yet.
He came up to me and he asked
me if I would tattoo
a monster on him.
And that was basically the
only thing he could say.
He's a mind blowing artist.
He's one of my favorites.
I think he's probably one of
the best in the world.
Mossa, he doesn't tattoo.
But he is really good
at running a shop.
It's a little bit strange for
a tattoo artist to work at a
shop where the owner isn't
a tattoo artist.
But I think in Three Tides
it really works.
He loves tattooing.
And I think he wanted
to elevate the art.
Three Tides was one of
the first Western
style shop in Osaka.
It wasn't a street level shop.
It had like a little sign,
and it was in an alley.
So was about as out in
the open a shop has
ever been in Japan.
[SPEAKING JAPANESE]
CHRIS GARVER: Yeah, I think
there was quite a few foreign
artists that went there.
I know Running Bear went
there, Charlie Roberts.
Well they learned firsthand how
American tattooers act.
They had so many coming out.
I had a great time.
All those guys at Three Tides
are super cool dudes.
And used to make
them get drunk.
They get really red.
When I was at Three Tides, I was
drinking more alcohol than
I ever have in my life.
And I was probably getting
really crazy and belligerent.
Mutsuo always took it so good.
No matter how much I was like,
get him in a headlock and give
him nuggies and stuff,
he would always be
cool the next day.
He would never be like, Garver,
you're an asshole.
I think Mutsuo, he's just like
a super nice dude, you know.
He's quiet.
He's driven.
I think that's one of the things
I admire about him.
He's just persistent.
When he started off, he wasn't
great at drawing.
But whenever somebody wasn't
telling him to clean this,
break that down, he would
be drawing all day long.
He didn't really ask
for anything.
But I think everybody willingly
would critique his--
people, everybody critiqued
his stuff.
The way he came across, the way
he was, it made you want
to help him.
You could tell that
he was going to be
a good tattoo artist.
He wasn't going to give up.
By the time I left he
started tattooing.
And he picked it up so fast.
[SPEAKING JAPANESE]
CHRIS GARVER: Chris
Trevino, he just
does really epic tattoos.
He would put so much of his
energy into every piece.
There would be a million
outlines.
The shop didn't open until noon,
but he would go in and
open up at--
he would go in there
at 9 o'clock.
I think Mutsuo had to
go and let him in.
He was a huge influence
on Mutsuo.
He definitely put a lot
of teaching into him.
I think, as far as how many
good artists there are--
I think Mutsuo--
I don't even know if at the time
he realized that he was
in the perfect spot
at the right time.
A lot of the guys,
I was surprised--
I don't think they knew that
they had that great
opportunity.
But he's the one that actually
stuck it out.
[SPEAKING JAPANESE]
CHRIS GARVER: The last time I
went to Japan, I went down to
Osaka just to see those guys.
And a lot of things
are different.
But a lot of things are
still the same.
They got artwork from everybody
that's worked there.
Got my old paintings.
I'm like, maybe I should send
them some new ones.
I asked Mutsuo to tattoo
me, and he was super
stoked about it.
He tattooed this frog
on my wrist.
It's kind of smoking.
It's got the Three Tides
logo on there.
I could see it was like, whoa,
the apprentice came back.
And his hand was kind
of like [INAUDIBLE].
He tattooed.
It was awesome, though.
I've got tons of pictures
of that.