CHRIS ROACH: I see it taking a
different image than lately,
kind of more skateboard
influenced.
People are going to start
doing some shit.
I think for sure that people
were milking snowboarding
because snowboarding is fucking
easy, and they were
making money off of nothing
doing nothing.
And I think it was
starting to show.
And those people that got cut
for that shouldn't have been
making money anyway, you know?
My main influence in
snowboarding was
probably Mike Ranquet.
I met Mike.
Once I met Mike, we had the
same kind of backgrounds.
And we felt the same way
about snowboarding.
We didn't take it as seriously
as a lot of the
other people did.
We didn't care about contests.
We just felt like, I guess,
skateboarding on the snow.
We weren't trying to win
everything or whatnot.
And Mike just ripped.
To this day, I think Mike's
one of the best
snowboarders out there.
He just does so many
great things.
MIKE RANQUET: God, I think
I met Roach in Colorado
on some Sims trip.
And we just hit it off.
We were like two
peas in a pod.
We had the same ideals
of snowboarding.
When you go to Europe in
1989, you're the only
person in soft boots.
It's like me and Craig Kelly
and Palmer and a
couple other guys.
We were the only people
in soft boots.
Everyone was in ski boots,
you know what I mean?
And meeting Roach was like a
breath of fresh air, because
it was like he dressed proper.
And he was concerned
with style.
Whereas other people just wanted
to do method airs and
get their arm up like that
and stuff like that.
We wanted to grab the board
behind your foot or right in
front of your foot, and not
gay it out, you know?
CHRIS ROACH: We went to the
Sim's camp together, I think.
And everybody was training
or something.
And me and Mikey were just like,
dude, we can do cabs.
We can go switch and
do switch tricks.
And I remember talking with
Shaun later, he's like what
the fuck dude, you guys are
doing cabs now on snow
and all this shit.
It was just like skateboarding
all over again.
It's so early in snowboarding
that going fakey or whatever
was like a new step
in snowboarding.
It was just a new progression,
I guess.
But crazy they weren't
doing it before.
I'm sure they were, though,
Terry and all those guys.
But I think we started doing
different tricks.
Yeah, I think-- well,
I don't know.
Mikey was pretty on
top of everything.
He probably brought it to
me first, to be honest.
TODD RICHARDS: Who is my
favorite snowboarder?
I would say it was, back
in that time, it
was Roach, for sure.
I mean, he was definitely--
between Roach and Ranquet
because those were two guys
that both skated.
And as far as doing tricks and
things, they were grabbing and
holding longer than
anybody else.
It was insane to see that coming
from like-- you know,
we weren't doing half cabs
and all that stuff.
We were kind of just doing
this weird like kick out
things off mobiles.
And then I remember I was
at the US Open in 1990--
or no, '89.
And we were riding up the
gondola at Stratton.
And I looked down, and it was
Roach, Ranquet, Keith Wallace,
Tucker Fransen, and some other
random dudes that were from
like Tahoe-- maybe Monte,
Chris's brother, were all
riding under the gondola,
like just half
cabbing off the knolls.
And we were just like, what?
We had never seen that before.
And that's all we tried to do
after that day, was like
imitate that, you know?
MIKE RANQUET: Yeah, we just
started doing like out of the
end of the pipe in Breckenridge
and at the US
Open that year.
Just switch tricks basically,
what is now switch tricks.
But it was only me and Roach.
It wasn't like a couple
other people.
It was like maybe Duck
Boy was in there.
But he was way more into like
the pipe, whereas I started to
look at the whole mountain.
Like Roachy and I, it felt like
we were the only ones
carrying the flag of the
skateboarding, you know?
And then just having Noah then
Cardiel kind of come
on board, you know.
It helped legitimize it in
skating too because up to that
point, I wouldn't even really
admit I was a snowboarder
among certain circles.
It might come out, but then, OK,
not all snowboarders are
gay by birth, you know.
Because at that time, I won't
name names, but just goofy
outfits, jester hats, and
might as well have been
juggling up there or something,
you know?
Like neon, and it was
just bad, you know?
CHRIS ROACH: I don't
know because I
wasn't really a skier.
And that was isn't background.
And I don't know where all
the DayGlo came from.
Wave Rave didn't help
that situation.
But it just didn't fit with
me and where I was.
I mean, black looked better on
snow than bright yellow did.
And that was more my attitude
and how I felt.
But I think a lot of guys make
good money off wearing DayGlo.
Damian did very well
for himself.
So whatever, that's
good for him.
There was plenty of guys that
would wear the DayGlo, so
there was no shortage of that.
JP WALKER: Just his fashion
at the time,
too, was pretty sick.
Like with those big--
I don't know if they were Oakley
Frogskins or something,
rainbow, tan, and big bleached
hair, and all
grown out and stuff.
And just the way he even talked,
too, was so like
snowboard speak, like decent
pokes in the pipe.
I don't know, Brushie used
to talk like that, too.
But I don't know, it was
pretty sick, his whole
everything.
DAVE SEOANE: And, I don't know
if you guys know this, but I
think it was like Tucker
Fransen and
Chris Roach who actually--
the traditional method airs,
when you pull it out and you
poke your leg way out,
traditionally that was called
the grasser.
And that was because of Chris
Roach and Tucker Fransen.
The grasser.
CHRIS ROACH: I coined it up
here because a lot of my
friends, we're all from
Grass Valley here.
And like I said, Shaun and Terry
did the best backside
airs known to man.
And so we all did them mimicking
those two guys.
And we called it the grasser
because everybody from Grass
Valley had to do it
like those guys.
So now it's like the
grasser, you know?
You know who knows how to do a
backside air and who doesn't.
I mean, even to this day, you
can see someone do a fucking
method air, and I wouldn't
call it a backside air or
grasser either way.
I mean, that's one of the good
things, is if you have to
explain it, then you're
not doing it.
So either you know you're doing
it right, or you're not.
You do whatever feels good.
If the method feels good, so
be it, and thanks for not
doing the grasser.
Jamie does grassers.
He knows the feelings.
JAMIE LYNN: You know, when I'm
in Tahoe, I'm doing grassers.
Any place else, I'm kicking
out a method.
Those guys grew up watching
Kidwell at the Tahoe Donner
quarter pipe kicking out
killer skate methods.
And they were the generation
kind of just a
nick before I was.
So Roach had one of the
sickest grassers ever.
He was a big influence.
He probably doesn't get as much
credit as he deserves for
being influential on
a backside method.
Grasser.
Thanks, Chris.
CHRIS ROACH: My favorite trick
right now is grasser reverts.
Made it up.
I don't know.
No one else does it.
It's pretty cool.
-How does it work?
CHRIS ROACH: You go backside
wall, do a grasser, then keep
rotating it.
Over-rotate it and land fakey.
It's pretty cool.
And you poke to fakeys
over-rotating,
those are good, too.
JP WALKER: Yeah, grasser
reverts.
I made them up.
No one's doing but me, or
something like that.
I didn't even notice
it back then.
But it seems like if somebody
said something like that now,
they'd just be so crucified
by everyone
else, like what a claimer.
You know what I mean?
So it's kind of funny because
I just watched that
not too long ago.
And I was laughing so hard
about what he was
saying about that.
It was pretty sick.
CHRIS ROACH: We were filming
for Dogger's movies up in
Mount Hood.
And Dogger's the kind of guy
who's like yeah, that's pretty
sick, but I know you
got more in you.
You know?
You got to start bringing
that thing around or
do something else.
And I was like, well, dude,
what about backside 360s?
We'll do grasser and
turn it around.
He's like do it, do it.
So that's when it started
up in Mount Hood.
And during the summer, we
started doing those.
I think I was the only one
doing them that day.
Obviously, Noah and all those
guys started doing
them right away too.
But I think Dogger pushed me
into doing them that day.
It was good when Santa Cruz
called and said they were
going to make snowboards,
you know, super excited.
Joel Gomez was the
team manager.
Me, Mike Ranquet, and John
Cardiel were the first riders.
And to me, that was
an all time team.
I was so excited to have
that as a team.
And I remember telling Joel, I
was like man, whatever we do,
we've got to keep this
team together.
This is a great, great team for
this time in the sport.
There's not that much skateboard
influence, and we
could take this long way.
And it fell apart right away.
Santa Cruz just didn't have the
money, or didn't want to
pay those boys what they
needed to make.
And I stayed, and was happy to
stay, but I sure would have
liked to have them on as
teammates a couple more years
or whatever.
MIKE RANQUET: I rode for
Sessions at the time.
And so did Roach.
And Sessions didn't
even close then.
It was like the coolest
shop sponsor to have.
And Santa Cruz hired Joel
as a team manager.
And yes, so it just
made sense.
Santa Cruz snowboards sponsor
Roach and Ranquet, you know?
And that to us was so cool
because Santa Cruz was
so cool back then.
But their snowboard division
got taken over by the
Europeans, and all of a sudden,
the snowboarding side
of Santa Cruz wasn't as
cool as we thought it
would be, you know?
So we're not dealing with NHS,
like Independent Trucks, Santa
Cruz skateboards.
We're not dealing with that.
We're dealing with some hotshot
racer guys from Europe.
And so when we got kicked out
of Japan, that was over the
top for them.
They were just like,
fuck that.
-Easter man.
-Or Ted Martin?
Is that the guy?
JERRY DUGAN: Yeah, so
Ranquet rode for
pretty much the shitsters.
They were the worst.
I mean, they're the two that
got kicked out of Japan.
And they were together,
just like bad news.
A food fight happened
in an area that
shouldn't have happened.
And it was stupid.
They were just drunk
and being dumb.
But it wasn't like they got
their hands slapped.
They basically got kicked off
the property, kicked out of
Japan, and sent home.
Yeah, the Japanese had a little
different understanding
of what should be appropriate
or not appropriate behavior.
DAMIAN SANDERS: They were pretty
serious over there.
And it's funny how they can kick
you out of their country.
Like around here, they
might put you in jail
or give you a ticket.
But they rounded them up and
actually escorted them to the
airport and got them on a
plane and said see ya.
[LAUGHTER]
-You got to film getting
on the bus, dude.
You got to walk out, Mike.
-Where's Roach?
-The rubber frog
incident, bro.
Gonna miss you.
-Bye, guys!
-I love you.
MIKE RANQUET: I mean, it
wasn't any part due to
anything Joel did or said.
He was just the messenger,
you know what I mean?
He felt bad for both sides
because he saw that you can
capitalize on these kids, but
he also saw that in their
eyes, we blew it, 100%.
We got kicked off the World
Cup tour forever.
We get kicked out of Japan.
And I also knew, and I tried
to tell Chris at the time,
like Santa Cruz ain't
going to back you.
They're not at all.
They're going to brush
you under the rug.
And they did.
But Roach, out of pride,
just like NorCal, dude.
You know?
Like, Santa Cruz.
And I wish I could still feel
that then, because I kind of
did, only because of the
camaraderie of Roach and I.
But the other thing was I found
I could hang out with
Roach more.
Because at the end of Santa
Cruz, they didn't want us
hanging out together.
They wouldn't put us
on trips together.
You know what I mean?
And all of a sudden,
I was like, killer.
I can go hang out with Roach.
There's no weird
binding thing.
But it was just kind of like too
bad to watch Roach at the
height of his riding and kind
of image just get a wet
blanket put over him
by his sponsor.
They gave him a pro model, but
they didn't promote it.
You know what I mean?
So Roach probably sold one board
for every five of mine,
which then Noah sold probably 10
for every one of mine, you
know what I mean?
So me and Noah had these
successful pro models.
And Roach's was successful, but
they didn't promote it.
It's like a band having
a record contract.
And then all of a sudden, the
record company ain't going to
promote their record.
It's going to sell, but not as
well as with advertising,
blah, blah, blah.
CHRIS ROACH: You know, I kind of
went full circle, and now I
have another model with them.
And I get to still be involved
in Santa Cruz.
So Santa Cruz definitely has
given me a good life.
And they've always been behind
me, and I appreciate that.
MIKE RANQUET: After the Japan
incident where we both got
kicked out, I went back to
Japan the next year.
He never went back.
But he was fine with that.
He was cool just
not traveling.
He just didn't care, you know?
He was like, dude, I just want
to kick it at home in Tahoe,
go to Grass Valley, smoke pot.
You know?
That's pretty funny.
This guy's got the opportunity
to go anywhere in the world,
he's like eh, you know?
Like, yawn.
CHRIS ROACH: If you're a
professional snowboarder and
you got to just do videos,
I think that in
itself was a statement.
You know, you didn't
have to deal with
the pressure of contests.
You didn't have to go to all the
shitty resorts and spend
your time doing that.
You could chase the snow
and the weather and
be with your friends.
And that atmosphere, it was
obviously a lot funner.
There's always pressure to try
to get footage and stuff.
But it's a different
kind of pressure.
It's more enjoyable.
I think Montana was one of my
funnest ones with Ranquet and
Graham, and probably
Seoane too.
Just the snow was so good.
It snowed so much up there
in big sky Montana.
That was a super fun trip.
And I don't remember too
much of any of those.
I don't remember any of
my own highlights
in any of the movies.
JASON BORGSTEDE: You know
you were watching
people's whole season.
They were hour, hour and a half
long movies, you know?
What I remember more than
anything is getting a Santa
Cruz towel, riding
down the hill.
And in those days, you just
emulated in your head.
You thought, OK, I'm basically
this guy this run.
You know?
And him and Noah and people like
that were those guys for
me a lot of times.
I remember, of course, his
broken leg in critical
condition, and all that stuff.
CHRIS ROACH: Yeah, we were at
Snowbird, and there's a blind
little drop.
And Tucker went off at first,
and I yelled at him, how fast?
He goes, as fast as you want.
And I was like, all
right, cool.
Not that it's Tucker's fault
by any means, but we were
setting up, and I just went off
it I guess too fast and
jumped right into little trees
and hooked up into them, and
just started rag dolling
had over and stopped.
And my femur got wrapped around
a tree and broke and
sat in the fucking snow for
probably an hour or whatever
because we were out of bounds
and with my shirt up and snow
down my back and got dragged
out of there and waited for
the helicopter.
As soon as the morphine kicked
in, I was all right.
Took the helicopter ride into
the hospital, and that
hospital treated me really well
for a few weeks until I
flew home and got healed up.
Two and a half months into it,
I went to Chile with Dave
Seoane just to see-- and Noah
Salasnek-- to see how my knee
was, or my femur.
And the only thing that hurt
was my knee where they tied
that rod to my knee.
And I was stoked to be back on
the snow two and a half months
after that.
-What's up, dude?
We're in Chile.
We're having fun.
[INAUDIBLE].
A lot of nice girls come from
different countries.
-OK, OK.
Stop.
CHRIS ROACH: Portillo's
in Chile.
And yeah, I went there with I
think the same guys, Noah and
Dave Seoane and Shawn Farmer.
That was just the
funnest trip.
You go up there in the summer,
it's like Tahoe weather.
It snowed for probably three
days, and was probably 60
degrees during the day.
And then it's like a little
resort for maybe the Brazilian
people who come down or whoever
comes down and spends
their summertimes or whatever.
So it's a night life
thing too.
You don't have to leave
the mountain.
Everything's right there
at the resort.
-The strobe lights are going.
So they can't really
see my moves.
CHRIS ROACH: I don't
know, man.
I found one little
troll thing.
And I think Noah had some
fun with maybe one other
one, and you know.
The girls, we couldn't
speak their language.
They couldn't speak ours.
So it was kind of one
of those fun things.
You know, you just
mess around.
-That's right, that's right.
Come one.
-I hate you.
-She hates me.
-But I love him.
CHRIS ROACH: I think we were
in Colorado, one of those
mountains, just because
Colorado, they think they have
the best mountains, but
there's nothing there.
It's just all fucking
ski slopes.
So you stay in bounds.
And there's nothing else
to do there besides do
blood slides and shit.
So we did those for a week and
learned how to press the board
up shitty hill and trying to
progress snowboarding.
What can we have fun
doing, you know?
Nothing to jump and
nothing to do.
I don't know, man.
I don't know.
I don't like the--
Whatever, you know how it is.
Just, I guess, having fun
and riding sideways.
I don't know.
I didn't do anything for anybody
that I didn't give it.
I don't know.
If I did something for younger
kids, and I like to give my
boards away as well at contests,
and that was it.
I didn't try to snowboard for
anybody or any other reasons
than for me.
And if I help people enjoy it
more, then that's cool.
But nothing more than that.
I wouldn't change anything
I ever did.
I mean, shit, I went through my
snowboarding career pretty
much just partying
and having fun.
I mean, snowboarding was on the
back burner almost to me.
And that's unfortunate, but
that's the way it was.
You know, you do what you can,
but you know what I mean.
And you would do shit a little
smarter, maybe put a little
bit more money in the
bank and shit.
But you know, I mean,
what do you do?
You know, you're out getting
paid to travel the world and
ride ski lifts.
I mean, that's incredible.
I mean, who doesn't dream
about that kind
of shit, you know?
That's insane.