SPEAKER 1: I've come to
show you something.
That's what I wanted
to show you.
[LAUGHTER]
LAL HARDY: Look at that!
He's got a picture of me
tattooed, the idiot.
[LAUGHTER]
LAL HARDY: Fucking hell, man.
Go and get it and bring
it out here.
SPEAKER 2: That's the only
reason he got it done.
LAL HARDY: I didn't even know
he'd had that done.
That's pretty freaky,
you know?
VALERIE VARGAS: I think when
we first started, Dad
introduced us to him because
Lal's a pretty really level
headed kind of guy.
He's own a shop for
a long time.
He's been in the business
for a long time.
He's pretty much the perfect
guy to ask anything to.
It's something really strange
that kind of happens with Lal
and people like even
[INAUDIBLE]
and they've been in this
game for so long.
And they're still so stoked
on tattooing.
They're not burnt out at all.
They don't hate people.
They don't hate customers.
They don't hate tattooing.
He's super open, super nice
and I really like
his sense of humor.
He's got a really cheeky sense
of humor which I like.
LAL HARDY: This flipper belonged
to a tattooist who
was killed by a shark.
And then we had another one
which was a customer that
didn't pay so we cut their
nipple off as a punishment.
Somebody asks me-- they didn't
have enough money for a
tattoo-- so they said, could
they pay with this.
That's what we want.
Every shop needs a musket.
There's another one.
My name's Lal Hardy.
I'm a tattoo artist in Muzzle
Hill, which is a suburb of
North London.
And I've been tattooing now--
well I probably got involved in
the industry around 1975.
And the rest is history,
really.
Been in this shop ever since.
Tattooing in the 1980s in
London was quite an
interesting time.
A few things happened
in this country.
Punk rock came along.
And I started to tattoo a
lot of the punk rockers.
And they'd bring in
record sleeves.
And I was doing that and got
a bit of publicity for it.
And I'd written a thing for
Ed Hardy's tattoo in Time
Magazine and I was getting
some recognition.
I used to have my hair all
different colors and I just
used to love punk rock girls
and skinhead girls.
You know?
That was just--
I loved it.
I like the kind of nonconformist
way that they
used to look.
And that was kind of an
interesting time to grow up to
in the punk rock era.
There was a whole movement,
wasn't it?
And now it's just rubbish,
really, when
you think about it.
It's like everything.
You know?
You think you're going to
change the world but
ultimately you don't.
SPEAKER 3: When I went to Good
Time Charlie's, one of the
biggest kicks I got
was seeing Jeff
Harp's Sid Vicious tattoo.
LAL HARDY: I've got a Sid
Vicious done on me as well.
But really--
SPEAKER 3: Where's
your Sidney?
LAL HARDY: Sid's under there.
I mean, when I think back to
people still coming in and
just saying, mate, you were so
crazy when you were younger.
In a way, the old time
tattooist had to
be a bit of a showman.
Like just get on the counter
and do a dance or something
ridiculous.
Come downstairs dressed
in a pantomime outfit.
Just crazy silly things.
But that's because back
then, you had to
fight for your work.
You had to A, be doing stuff
that was a bit different, but
you wanted people to come for
the experience as well.
I've got to say, I've got
a million and one
stories and lived it.
I feel that for some of the
young people, they've got
their own way of entertainment
now, but they ain't had a guy
turn up in an army tank stark
naked, fire a distress flare
up the street.
We had a big tree up here.
Another guy'd take all his
clothes off, climb up the
tree, sitting up there
just because he
thought he was funny.
Even in my shop, here, I
was mad on greyhounds.
SPEAKER 4: Yeah.
LAL HARDY: I had a running
machine, electric roadway,
that I used to stand a dog on so
that the dog could get fit
when I was tattooing.
There used to be a massive
psychiatric hospital across
the road as well.
So sometimes, you'd get people
coming in that you had to sort
of direct out the shop.
It keeps you young at heart if
you let it, this business.
That's one of the funny things
about tattooing.
You can either become a
crotchety grumpy old tattooist
or you can sort of go with the
flow a bit, and pick up on
some of these things and draw
from what's being offered from
talented young people
coming in there.
When you get to a certain age
in tattooing, you've had a
good run at it.
You've had a good time.
I think that you should promote
other people, people
that are deserving of that.
People that actually
inspire you.
It doesn't have to be someone
who's been tattooing 50 years.
They could tattooing 50 days.
If they know what they're doing
and she's one of those
people, you know, and
Stewart as well.
So I just--
I don't know.
It's kind of like they're your
little adopted tattoo children
that you want to see out there
doing it and you want them to
succeed and do well.
VALERIE VARGAS: Oh,
they're coming in.
STEWART ROBSON: You done?
LAL HARDY: Nope.
We're talking about you.
Do you mind if we come in?
STEWART ROBSON: No.
Wielding your sword.
VALERIE VARGAS: Get
your sword out.
LAL HARDY: I don't very
much like her work.
Rubbish.
SPEAKER 4: He said you guys
were his tattoo children.
VALERIE VARGAS: Aw.
STEWART ROBSON: Sweet.