ROCCO CASTORO: There is a place
in Russia where people
have discovered the secret of
living in perfect harmony.
A place where the children run
free, where the Earth provides
everything you need, and where
money is meaningless.
Welcome to the Church of
the Last Testament.
This is Petropavlovka, a small
settlement located deep within
the Taiga Forest of Siberia,
over 100 miles away from the
nearest town.
It looks like an elf village at,
like, a putt-putt course.
About 20 years ago a handful
of disciples came here to
worship and live with Vissarion,
or "the teacher,"
as he is commonly known.
Today, Vissarion's Church of
the Last Testament has over
5,000 followers from all
around the world.
About 2,000 live here and in
the surrounding areas.
[SINGING IN RUSSIAN]
ROCCO CASTORO: I came here in
hopes of meeting the man
himself, who hasn't granted an
interview to the media in at
least three years.
VISSARION: [SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
ROCCO CASTORO: Two decades ago,
that man was known as
Sergey Anatolyevitch Torop, a
29-year-old patrol officer who
suddenly had a revelation that
his was the word of God.
VISSARION: [SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
ROCCO CASTORO: Conveniently,
this realization happened
right around the time
the Soviet Union, a
self-proclaimed nation of
atheists, began to crumble,
and religion became an
acceptable topic of
discussion in Russia.
He soon began writing the Last
Testament, a 12-volume
follow-up of sorts to the New
Testament, which details the
religion's major tenets and
provides answers to some of
life's most mundane questions,
such as which brand of
detergent you should use.
Labeled a dangerous cult by
some, it has been reported
that Vissarion and his followers
believe in aliens,
think suicide is A-OK, and
believe that the end of the
world is imminent.
There are rules here that
I was warned about--
no cussing, no tobacco,
no alcohol, no meat.
I believe it's all vegan.
I've got to watch my mouth
because I have a dirty mouth.
And I like meat, I like
drugs, sometimes.
There's none of that here, so
it's going be good to dry up.
I was invited here by one of
the church's more recent
converts, a 24-year-old woman
named Tamriko, who worked as a
lawyer in Moscow before moving
here three months ago.
She now works the German House,
a sort of guest house
for the spiritually curious.
Why don't you give me a little
history of how you got here?
TAMRIKO DGEBUADZE: When I first
heard about the teacher,
it was me like this kind
of thing that-- wow.
It was like, this is the only
source of all information, of
all answers, and this is a
real teacher of the truth
about the world.
And so--
ROCCO CASTORO: Something
feels--
TAMRIKO DGEBUADZE: And sometimes
you need answers.
You need, just, answers.
ROCCO CASTORO: Answers, yeah.
TAMRIKO DGEBUADZE: And somebody
will explain you,
like, everything.
He will explain your life.
Why are you doing this.
Why you have some problems--
problems with your health,
problems with your life.
For what purpose, actually,
you are living.
ROCCO CASTORO: I see.
And one of the things that a
lot of people have said is
like, oh, it's a cult.
You know?
How do you feel about that?
It has a bad connotation.
TAMRIKO DGEBUADZE: Usually,
I don't think
anything about this.
Do you know why?
Because I think that if some
people find that this person
can help them, and they
want to pray to
this person, why not?
ROCCO CASTORO: OK, yeah.
TAMRIKO DGEBUADZE: Why
not, it's very good.
ROCCO CASTORO: Is there anything
that you perhaps
disagree with here, with--
TAMRIKO DGEBUADZE: Here?
ROCCO CASTORO: --the teaching.
With teachings, you know?
TAMRIKO DGEBUADZE:
No, no, no, no.
ROCCO CASTORO: OK.
Disagreeing with Vissarion's
teachings is rare, which
became very apparent after
meeting Tanya, a patron of the
local girls school--
a place where young ladies go to
learn "the discipline," as
she put it.
Is part of the lesson
plan set aside for
study of the teacher?
TANYA DENISOVA:
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
ROCCO CASTORO: So, do you ever
have strong girls that maybe
resist, and they're not so with
that line of thinking?
TANYA DENISOVA:
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
ROCCO CASTORO:
TANYA DENISOVA:
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
ROCCO CASTORO: As tempting as
brainwashing my girlfriend
into misogynistic slavery
sounded, I had mountains to
climb and deities to meet.
I had been invited to celebrate
the Holiday of Good
Fruits at the Abode of Dawn, a
small mountaintop community
where Vissarion and his closest
followers live.
I stopped at the general store
to get supplies for the hike.
So I have the luxury, after a
40-hour trip, of eating a CCC
pop, We just bought provisions
for two days.
This is kind of the
treat before--
I don't even know if
I'm supposed to be
eating this, to be honest.
I don't know what Vissarion's
stance is on
candy and ice pops.
But it's hot, so.
Mmm.
I climbed into a Soviet-era
bread loaf and begin the bumpy
drive up the hill.
And we've got a good crew, just
materialized here at the
base of the mountain.
Looks like we're about
ready to go.
My hiking companions had
traveled from Germany,
Slovenia, Sweden, and beyond,
all in hopes of catching even
a glimpse of the elusive
Vissarion.
MALE SPEAKER 1:
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
ROCCO CASTORO: Along the way,
I met Maciek, a university
student from Poland.
What did you come
here seeking?
ROCCO CASTORO: [LAUGH].
We made it to what appeared to
be a border crossing, and the
attendant took down
our details.
MALE SPEAKER 2:
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
ROCCO CASTORO: Yes.
Our guide, Nina, led me to the
place where I'd be staying for
the next two nights--
the home of a lovely Russian
family who immediately offered
me cold vegetable
soup and bread.
FEMALE SPEAKER 1:
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
ROCCO CASTORO: Vissarion's
serene gaze watched over us as
we ate our blessed meal,
spiritually charging us for
the upcoming nighttime
liturgy.
We're going to go see what
worship is like here.
I feel like I'm kind of in a
different world, to be honest.
[SINGING IN RUSSIAN]
ROCCO CASTORO: The pre-holiday
liturgy didn't seem too
different from a
Christian Mass.
But I would come to find out
that things weren't that
simple here.
Still, all the followers had
been very pleasant so far.
Only a few seemed to have the
crazy stare of a cult member.
I ran into Maciek and asked him
how he was settling in.
So how have the accommodations
been?
MACIEJ RAFINSIC: What
accommodations--
very, very well.
I met nice people.
We had a nice conversation.
And then they asked me, when did
I accept the teacher and
his teachings.
And I said, well, I'm not
really a follower.
And then there was, like,
a minute of silence--
second of silence.
And it felt uneasy.
But they got over it.
But I think they felt a
little disappointed.
ROCCO CASTORO: [CHUCKLE], OK.
And are you--
they have our passports.
MACIEJ RAFINSIC: I know.
ROCCO CASTORO: [INAUDIBLE].
Are you a little concerned
about that?
MACIEJ RAFINSIC: I am.
It's like, you know--
yeah, so I don't want to be
insulting, but you come to the
place which is far away from
anywhere in the world.
You come to people who are known
to be members of a cult,
of a religious group of--
ROCCO CASTORO: [LAUGH]
MACIEJ RAFINSIC: --of
some sort, now.
Let's put it like this.
And then they take your
passport away
straight when you--
ROCCO CASTORO: And they
were pretty--
MACIEJ RAFINSIC: They are pretty
persistent about that.
ROCCO CASTORO: Yeah.
Physically and spiritually
exhausted from my long
journey, I turned in for the
night to rest up for the
Holiday of Good Fruits and our
first glimpse of Vissarion.
MALE SPEAKER 3:
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
ROCCO CASTORO: Today is August
18, which is the high holy day
of the year-- the Holiday of
Good Fruits, the Church of the
Last Testament's most
important holiday.
Basically, it's their Easter.
It was on this day in 1990 when
Vissarion first realized
his divine connection to God
and established his church.
It's the reason that thousands
of Vissarionites from around
the world have gathered
here today.
MALE SPEAKER 3:
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
ROCCO CASTORO: We began our
ritualistic procession up the
mountain, a five-hour
journey replete
with ceremonial washing--
that felt good--
mood music, and supremely
positive vibes.
[SINGING IN RUSSIAN]
ROCCO CASTORO: Looking back, I
think it was supposed to serve
as a sort of mental palate
cleanser for what lay ahead.
Up the mountain we go.
Part of the reason I wanted
to come here--
the world seems to be in a
pretty bad way right now.
This seems to be an idyllic
community, so maybe Vissarion
has some answers for
us on how we could
better live our lives.
Or maybe he's just
got it right, and
people should come here.
They're actually pretty
good musicians.
Oh wow, beautiful.
I found a little friend in this
hole here, watching us.
He looks very surprised,
like us.
Wide-eyed.
Stopping again for
another hymn.
Something happened to me while I
was walking up the mountain.
Was I experiencing the initial
stages of indoctrination?
Everything looked
so beautiful.
And the people seemed
so happy.
I began to wish that I could
be more like them.
Slava, another in a long line of
guides/minders, didn't want
me to miss the site where the
site where Vissarion literally
left his mark on
mother nature.
SLAVA TKACHENKO: The teacher,
when the first time on this
mountain, take your hands
on this stone.
And after we turned the stone,
we see this letter, it was the
first letter of his name--
Jesus.
In Russia, kha, letter kha.
You may see it.
ROCCO CASTORO: Yeah,
we should see.
Is it OK for me to touch?
SLAVA TKACHENKO: Russian kha.
ROCCO CASTORO: Kha.
SLAVA TKACHENKO: Christos.
In English, Jesus.
ROCCO CASTORO: Christos.
It's there.
[NERVOUS LAUGH]
While the rest of the followers
gathered around the
stage where Vissarion would soon
give his sermon, Slava
took us to visit the monastery
for young boys.
A trampoline.
[LAUGH]
SLAVA TKACHENKO: For jumping.
ROCCO CASTORO: I'll jump.
[LAUGH]
NINA: Andrei is the master
of those boys.
ROCCO CASTORO: Of
all the boys.
Why do you live here?
Why did you come here?
ANDREI ANATOLEVICH:
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
ROCCO CASTORO: We sat down with
17-year-old Ivan, who,
among other things, was learning
the "masculine
professions."
IVAN KOZLOVSKY:
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
ROCCO CASTORO: How long
have you been
living at the monastery?
IVAN KOZLOVSKY: Two years.
ROCCO CASTORO: Two years.
And how do like it?
IVAN KOZLOVSKY:
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
ROCCO CASTORO: What's your
favorite thing to
do during the day?
IVAN KOZLOVSKY:
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
ROCCO CASTORO: Are
you planning on
starting a family soon?
IVAN KOZLOVSKY: [LAUGHING].
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
[LAUGHTER]
ROCCO CASTORO: Do you
have in mind a,
maybe, a potential wife?
No?
[LAUGH], OK.
That's it.
We'll stop there.
[RUSSIAN].
IVAN KOZLOVSKY:
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
ROCCO CASTORO: [LAUGH]
Beautiful.
Wow, that's amazing.
You can see they're clearing
out this side over here.
Perhaps to build more housing.
Their numbers are continually
growing.
I see why people stay, though.
It's very beautiful.
People who are interested in
joining the community and
living here, is there anything
that one must do to become
part of the community?
Or can you just come
and live here?
ANDREI ANATOLEVICH:
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
ROCCO CASTORO: If I moved here,
I'm an editor and a
writer, so, I'd have
to learn Russian.
But perhaps I could
help with that?
NINA: [LAUGH], You
will be welcome.
ANDREI ANATOLEVICH:
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
ROCCO CASTORO: Hmm, a place
where negative characters
don't exist.
That sounded pretty
good to me.
Clean energy?
Healthy living?
Virgin brides?
I started wondering if the Abode
of Dawn could be that
place for me.
Here we go.
I'm going to hurt myself.
[LAUGHTER]
ROCCO CASTORO: And then,
finally, it was time for us to
get our first glimpse of
the teacher himself.
[SINGING IN RUSSIAN]
MALE SPEAKER 3: [SPEAKING
RUSSIAN OVER LOUDSPEAKER]
Any moment, now, Vissarion's
going to descend from the
stairs and address
everyone here.
And as you can see, everyone's
eagerly anticipating it.
I have not doubt in my mind that
they believe he is God.
And it's interesting and kind of
scary, too, to see so many
people have so much faith
in one man, or god.
MALE SPEAKER 3: [SPEAKING
RUSSIAN OVER LOUDSPEAKER]
[SINGING IN RUSSIAN]
ROCCO CASTORO: We had traveled
thousands of miles to the
middle of nowhere in Siberia
to see this man, Vissarion,
address his congregation on what
they call the Holiday of
Good Fruits.
It was sort of spooky.
[WHISPERING]
Vissarion's making his way
down now, very slowly.
Very Christ-like.
[SINGING CONTINUES]
ROCCO CASTORO: And just as
Vissarion was about to share
some infallible nuggets
of wisdom--
VISSARION: [SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
ROCCO CASTORO: --they made
us turn off the camera.
After giving a short sermon
in hushed tones, Vissarion
blessed bread made by the
community for the ensuing
feast and bid his followers
farewell.
CONGREGATION: [SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
ROCCO CASTORO: So we just
have finished the
sermon with the teacher.
And Nina's going to translate
a little bit for
us of what was said.
NINA: I remember exactly
his first phrase--
"I'm glad that you still
survive." Because everybody
was laughing.
And then he spoke about that
we, all of us, are pupils--
ROCCO CASTORO: Pupils, yeah.
NINA: --in the school of life.
ROCCO CASTORO: "We are
all peoples in
the school of life"?
I guess that's true.
But I'm not sure it provided
me with any answers.
We're going to see if we can
interview some pilgrims.
Some people that came to see
Vissarion from afar.
What is your feelings
about Vissarion?
FEMALE SPEAKER 3:
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
ROCCO CASTORO: Why did you make
the journey here today?
MALE SPEAKER 4:
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
ROCCO CASTORO: How did you first
hear about the teacher?
MALE SPEAKER 5:
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
ROCCO CASTORO: Compared
to years past,
does he seem happy?
Does he seem in good spirits?
MALE SPEAKER 6:
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
ROCCO CASTORO: After the
liturgy, we ran into our
Polish friend, Maciek.
ROCCO CASTORO: How
do you feel?
I mean, do you feel that there's
something about him
that's beyond human?
MACIEJ RAFINSIC: I don't
want to insult anybody,
but I don't, no.
I feel it's an interesting
place and
an interesting person.
And I think these people
around me want
to live a good life.
And I do appreciate that.
But I don't perceive
him as divine.
ROCCO CASTORO: After mingling
with some members of the
congregation, I headed to bed
to rest up for the next day
and my big interview
with Vissarion.
There's a lot of
stars tonight.
I was talking with Slava about
the beautiful and clear
nighttime sky, when he told me
that stars weren't the only
things up there.
ROCCO CASTORO: You've
seen UFOs?
ROCCO CASTORO: What
did it look like?
ROCCO CASTORO: Three spheres.
Yeah, OK.
ROCCO CASTORO: See it too?
The next morning, we got up
bright and early and took a
secret path to Vissarion's
home.
So we're finally here at
the teacher's house.
And we're going to interview a
man that many people believe
to be the word of god.
I suddenly became very
anxious about my
meeting with the teacher.
What if I actually had an
audience with someone who is
the word, and perhaps
flesh, of god?
[INAUDIBLE]
Why did you agree to an
interview with me?
Because I know that you haven't
for quite a bit.
VISSARION: [SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
ROCCO CASTORO: [LAUGH]
Are you regretting it now?
OK.
I want to know about Russia.
Was it a coincidence, or was it
just happenstance that this
community came to be around the
same time as the fall of
the Soviet Union?
VISSARION: [SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
ROCCO CASTORO: I think I
understood what he was saying.
But I was struggling with how
to tactfully ask someone who
looks like Jesus if he's the Son
of God without coming out
and saying it.
You're very Christ-like
in your appearance.
I'll say it this way-- do you
have memories of Christ from
2,000 years ago?
Do you carry on in that
way, in that lineage?
VISSARION: [SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
ROCCO CASTORO: That's probably
as close to a yes as I was
going to get.
It seems like the world is--
there's lots of riots.
There's uprisings.
Is the turmoil and conflict in
the world right now worse than
you've experienced?
VISSARION: [SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
ROCCO CASTORO: Was Vissarion
talking about Armageddon?
Naturally, I was curious as
to when that might happen.
Is that coming soon?
VISSARION: [SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
ROCCO CASTORO: Talk about
dancing around the subject.
I switched gears, and,
remembering Slava's
extraterrestrial encounter,
asked him about the church's
stance on what they call
"the outer space mind."
VISSARION: [SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
ROCCO CASTORO: I have to admit,
Vissarion lost me
somewhere in between the end
times and soulless aliens.
Still, I could see how his
followers could really get
into this stuff.
It's a hell of a lot more
interesting than Adam and Eve
and the crucifixion.
The teacher's handlers
signalled that it was
time to wrap up.
But I was determined to slip
in a few simple questions
that, with any luck, would
be answered in a
straightforward manner.
How about food.
What's your favorite
dish to eat?
VISSARION: [SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
ROCCO CASTORO: A man
without penchant--
which apparently extended to
answering questions in a
fashion that I could
understand.
But this was my last shot.
At the very least, maybe I could
glean something about
the purity of my own being.
Just meeting me briefly,
can you tell me
anything about myself?
VISSARION: [SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
ROCCO CASTORO: [LAUGH]
I'd say--
So last question.
If you could tell one piece of
advice that our viewers here
could follow relatively easily,
what would it be?
VISSARION: [SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
ROCCO CASTORO: OK.
I'm not sure if I was supposed
to or not, but there is no way
I was leaving without a photo.
So I hopped right in there.
[RUSSIAN].
So we've finished our journey
here, and going back to New
York City, and pollution,
and terrible people.
In other words, all the things
that I find weirdly
comforting.
What can I say?
I'm a man of modern
convenience.
But if it ever gets too much
for me, if the scum of
humanity becomes so sticky and
viscous that I can't scrub it
off, I know there's a place
where I can drop
out and be at peace.
And the next time someone
complains to me that
everything sucks, or our
problems are unsolvable, I'll
just tell them--
there's this place you can go
in Siberia where they'll
accept you with open arms.
A place where the children run
free, where the earth provides
everything you need.
And where money--
[SINGING IN RUSSIAN]