squash it with another biscuit. From here,
dip in some chocolate.
This recipe is in honour of our YouTube friends;
Grace, Mamrie and Hannah and they did a fantastic
film - Camp Takota. So it's all about camp
fire cooking.
S'mores is all about getting a stick, melting
up that marshmallow, getting it nice and soft
and sandwiching that into a biscuit. Now in
America you guys have the Graham crackers.
We don't have them here in the UK but what
we do have is digestive biscuits. Brilliant
biscuit! Or you could use a rich tea biscuit.
and very simply squash it with another biscuit
and that's the whole thing. Now you can put
other things in it. I've got some jam here,
you can put a little bit of that in there.
I've got some beautiful salted caramel here.
I'm gonna dip my S'mores in a little chocolate.
And by the way this is naughty. You will get
no nutritional value out of this, but it makes
people happy so every now and again this is
what life's all about. What I've done, if
you can find anything metal, a pan, you could
use anything. Half fill it with water. You
could put it next to the fire and then you
can pop another little plate or tin. And I've
got chocolate, just smashed up chocolate in
there. You can melt pretty much any chocolate
bar. And from here you can kinda have a little
bit of a dip session. So we can go in with
some chocolate here and then we come out,
shake off the excess. You can just rub that
up the side like that. And then you can have
that landing in something. You can have it
landing in coconut, desiccated coconut, you
can toast it off beforehand if you want. But
that is gonna be bad ass! Here's my first
attempt of an Essex S'mores. Ok, so there's
number one, let's go in with a second. I'm
gonna keep a little bit un-chocolated in the
middle and then I'm just gonna twiddle my
rim around the nuts. Essex S'mores number
two! Look at that, even a hole in the middle.
Dip and a little bit of a roll up. Enjoy your
campfire cooking. If you wanna find out more
about Camp Takota then click on that chocolate
and there will be a link through to our friends.
Tell us what different sprinkles or what flavours
you do with you S'mores. Share your ideas
in the comments box. If you like this, like
it. If you wanna share it, share it on your
social media. And of course, if you haven't
joined Food Tube, with a whole array of wonderful
chefs from all around the world, then click
subscribe because we'll love to look after
you. So there you go guys, a little bit of
Essex S'mores dedicated to the guys at Camp
Takota. Lot's of love.
How to make S'mores Essex style take two!
Word up Food Tubers, Jamie Oliver here in
the mouth of an oven.
It allows you to enjoy cooking over fire,
which is very, very nice.
Arghhhhhhhhhhhhh!
It lifts the spirits, it allows you.... Oh My God!
You *BLEEP*
Take five! Does it matter that I've snapped it?
Simplest recipe known to man.