Maybe the cool Uncle
can succeed
where the father has failed.
You're not his Uncle.
That is a minor technicality.
You're not cool.
Okay, now you're just
being ridiculous.
What are you guys
gonna do?
Oh, I don't know,
maybe shop for purses,
go to a knitting class,
water ballet.
What do you think?
We're just gonna hang out,
you know,
like guys do.
If it's okay with him,
it's okay with me,
as long as you stay
out of trouble.
If you're referring
to Kevin's birthday party,
the ad said entertainer.
How was I supposed to know
she was that kind
of entertainer?
Hey, Martin.
Morning, Suzanne.
You're out of corn flakes.
Hey, baby.
Good morning.
Mom, can I borrow
your credit card?
What for?
I want to buy the sweater
that Michelle Obama's going
to wear at her next speech.
You can only get it online.
The first time,
I took too long.
The second time,
I didn't even have enough money.
This time,
I'm ready.
But I need a credit card.
No.
Why not?
Because every time I ask you
to help me with something,
you give me attitude.
So why should I help you
get what you want
when you won't help me?
These dishes have been
sitting here since last night.
But I've been busy.
Besides, I didn't dirty
all these dishes.
That's exactly the attitude
I'm talking about.
But--
but nothing.
I can't hear you.
My plates are screaming,
"clean me."
No,
they're screaming,
"let Lindsey
use the credit card."
My plates aren't stupid.
♪ Are we there yet? ♪
The Michele Obama Sweater
S01x08 Original Air Date on June 23, 2010
♪ tell me, tell me, tell me ♪
♪ tell me,
are we there yet? ♪
-- sync, corrected by elderman --
-- for www.addic7ed.Com --
hello.
Hi.
[Sighs]
[Sighs loudly]
What's up, Lindsey?
I want to buy the sweater
that Michelle Obama's wearing
at her next speech.
Have you saved up
your money?
Yeah.
Where do you get it?
At J. Crew.
Well, why don't you just
go to the mall and get it?
Anybody can go
to J. Crew.
It's not like
it's rodeo drive.
They never make it
to the store.
Everyone buys them online,
and they sell out.
It's easier
to get Michelle Obama
than it is to get
a Michelle Obama sweater.
Did you forget
that I used to own
a sports collectible shop
that specialized in acquiring
hard-to-find items?
Kind of.
I am the master
of getting hard-to-find items.
I got Kobe Bryant's
8 Jersey,
a Plaxico Burress
gun holster.
I even got a pair
of Michael Phelps' floaties.
So...
So you're doing it
the wrong way.
Let me show you
how a professional does it.
Can I use your credit card?
Yeah.
That's not a problem.
And because you're family,
I'll offer you my services
free of charge.
I wasn't gonna pay you.
That's also
why it's free of charge.
So let me get this straight.
A man offered you money
to get him a signed bat
A-Rod used in a game,
so you sent letters
to a children's foundation
pretending to be an orphan
whose dream was to have
a signed A-Rod bat.
Yes.
But now someone
from the children's foundation
is coming here
to meet that kid,
so you want me
to be that fake kid,
lie to them
and my dad,
who just thinks
we're going to hang out?
Well, when you say it
like that,
it sounds negative.
Yeah, it doesn't seem right.
That's 'cause you left out
the good, wholesome part
of the story.
That guy is gonna give me
500 bucks for that bat,
and I'll give you $50.
You're right.
That does make it
seem better.
It's a deal.
All right,
sit down.
Okay, this is everything
I could find online
about A-Rod, okay?
I need you
to study these stats
in case it comes up
in conversation,
talking rbis,
slugging percentage,
girlfriend history,
both celebrity
and noncelebrity, okay?
And these are letters.
I need you
to take a look at these,
because, well,
you wrote them.
What's a crack whore?
Unfortunately,
your mom.
Mmm.
I smell cinnamon toast.
No, you smell cinnamon.
The toast is gone.
Oh, I'm starved.
I didn't eat dinner
last night.
Why didn't you eat dinner?
Because
I'm in between boyfriends,
and I didn't have anyone
to take me out.
So why don't you just
go to the grocery store?
I'm not gonna be without
a boyfriend for that long.
Besides, I spend my money
on looking good
so other people
will buy me food.
But for now,
I'll have to depend
on me, myself, and I.
I'm hungry.
What do you have
for me to eat?
[Sighs]
Are you gonna watch
Michelle Obama's speech
this afternoon?
Yeah, of course.
Why?
Well, Lindsey wants
whatever J. Crew sweater
she's gonna be wearing,
and apparently,
so does every other girl
in the country.
Really?
Girls care
about J. Crew sweaters?
If Michelle Obama wore it.
But, you know, she wanted
to use my credit card,
but I wouldn't let Lindsey,
because she hasn't been
helping me around the house.
You know, if those sweaters
are that popular,
maybe I can sell one online
and it'll help tide me over
while I'm in between boyfriends.
Did you know
gas is over $3 a gallon?
Yes.
Anyway, I think
you should help Lindsey.
Housework will be here
every week.
Michelle Obama sweaters are here
for a limited time only.
Toaster waffles, huh?
How do you make these?
Okay.
In what year was A-Rod
drafted by the Mariners?
Uh, 1993?
Correct.
When was A-Rod born?
July 27...1975.
Correct.
What's A-Rod's middle name?
Emmanuel.
Correct.
I can't believe you.
What are you
talking about?
I was actually thinking
about giving you my credit card.
But you just don't get it,
Lindsey.
This basket of clothes
has been in there all day.
You could have folded them.
You could have
put them away.
But no, you left them there
to remind me
that you don't do anything
to help me around this house.
You know what?
Michelle Obama did not
get to be the first lady
by being lazy.
She didn't get there
by folding clothes either.
Now you're definitely
not getting it.
Bam!
You ready to get this?
Okay, so how does
all this stuff work?
We got to see
Michelle Obama
the second
she walks out onstage,
and I mean
the first second,
not the second second.
Look, all these screens
are a different shot,
so I got all the angles.
I got East,
West, North, South,
northwest, northeast,
southwest, southeast, eastwest.
Eastwest?
When I say
all the angles,
I mean all the angles.
Look, I've already pulled up
the possible websites
where we can buy it,
so as soon as you identify
the color and style
of the sweater,
bam!
Oh, my God.
There she is.
What's the color?
Pink.
Bam!
What kind of pink?
Fuchsia, salmon, coral?
Salmon.
Bam!
What's the sleeve?
3/4.
Bam!
What's the length?
Short waist.
Button-down?
Bam!
What's the size?
I don't know
what size she wears.
Not her size,
your size.
Small.
Bam!
Credit card on file.
Both: Bam!
Express shipping.
Submit order.
Both: Bam!
Order confirmation.
Wait for it.
Both: Bam!
[Screams]
We did it.
I told you.
Both: ♪ I am
the pink sweater master ♪
♪ you are
both: ♪ we are
the pink sweater masters ♪
[doorbell rings]
"Lindsey Kingston-Persons."
Wow.
Was somebody
at the front door?
Why?
Were you expecting somebody?
No.
Why?
Because you asked.
That's why.
Lindsey, I just saw
a delivery truck.
Did you get your sweater yet?
What sweater?
This sweater.
Bam!
Give me. Give me.
Ooh, this is ni--
oh, my God.
If they had this
in triple "x"...
Mm.
That's nice.
That's cashmere.
Oh, feel it.
Watch this.
Oh, bam!
[Laughs]
What's wrong with you?
Lindsey, sit down.
Nick, did you help Lindsey
get this sweater?
Yes, I did.
♪ Because I am
the pink sweater master ♪
♪ I am
♪ I am the... ♪
You have no idea
what's going on, do you?
Um, no.
You got played.
I told your daughter
she couldn't get this sweater
because she hasn't been
helping me around the house.
Is this true?
Well...
You used my powers
for evil?
I'm sorry, dad.
Why are you apologizing
to him?
He just got tricked.
I got disrespected.
But I was--
but, ah.
Here's what's gonna happen,
Lindsey.
You are gonna march
down to the mall,
and you're gonna return
this sweater.
But I was--
are you still talking?
Go upstairs.
I'm sorry, baby.
I didn't know.
It doesn't make
any difference.
You shouldn't be making
decisions like this without me.
Wait.
How am I supposed to know
what decisions
to check with you about?
That's easy.
Before you decide,
check with me.
Fine.
From now on, I don't do anything
without asking you first.
Oh.
Excuse me.
Can I leave?
Actually, it's "may" you,
and yes, you may.
[Door clicks open]
Candace, this is the kid
I wrote to you--
I mean, the poor child
who wrote to you
about his love of A-Rod.
We're in a mentor program
together.
It's great to meet you,
Kevin.
Give me a pound, yo.
Huh?
She wants you
to shake her hand.
Shake?
Shake.
Yeah.
[Growls playfully]
So I'm sorry
to get you out of bed so early.
I'm sure after holding down
a corner all night,
you must be exhausted.
I don't know how you do it
on the drug time.
Drug time?
What--
actually, Kevin doesn't get
much sleep at the group home.
You know how it is
with the constant fighting
and the stabbings
and whatnot.
Right, and all the gunshots
and ghetto birds.
Ghetto birds?
She means helicopters.
Ah, Boyz n the Hood,
domino.
You know,
we at the foundation
were shocked when we found out
that Kevin is a baseball fan.
Why is that?
Well, most kids
in Kevin's situation
are more inclined
to be basketball fans.
Ah.
You know,
pass me the rock.
Hitting the tre.
And one.
I'm open, homey.
I'm open.
Pass it.
We get it.
Yeah.
Well, Kevin here
is definitely a baseball fan,
especially
when it comes to A-Rod.
Am I right, Kevin?
Right.
I am definitely
a fan of A-Rod,
who was drafted by the Mariners
in 1993.
Yeah.
And I love baseball.
Oh, he is so articulate.
I understood
every word he said.
Who are your other favorites,
Kevin?
Uh, b-rod
and his brother c-rod
and his other brother d-rod.
Ah, you're a comedian.
Yes.
Yes, he is.
He's like a little
Original Kings of Comedy.
Get you a nine-button
purple suit
and a hat,
put you on tour?
Okay, listen,
we know your time is valuable.
You probably have
some rally to attend.
So if I could just
get that bat from you
for little Kevin here.
Oh, well,
that is exactly
what I came
to talk to you about.
We talked
to A-Rod's people
and told them
Kevin's story,
and he has agreed
to let you
come to the game today
as his special guest,
where he'll sign the bat for you
in person.
Isn't that great?
So you don't have
the bat?
No, well, I was worried
about bringing it here.
But he'll sign it at the game
in person.
Isn't that great?
Yeah, wonderful,
mm-hmm.
Do I really
have to go?
Oh, don't worry.
There are no metal detectors.
What?
You can wear your bling.
Suzanne!
Yeah?
I need you to help me find
the J. Crew sweater
Michelle Obama
was wearing the other day.
What?
What are you talking about?
Well, after you told me
how valuable they were,
I posted one online
for sale,
and the bidding price
is skyrocketing.
But you don't actually
have one to sell.
Right,
I thought I could just
go down to the store
and buy one,
but those things
are impossible to find.
That's why
they're so valuable.
Well, I know that now.
I'm gonna change the channel
from Sportscenter.
Is that okay?
Yes.
Can I say hi
to Gigi?
Yes.
Hi, Gigi.
Hi.
You know what?
You should have let Lindsey
get that sweater.
Why?
Because then
you could have told her
she couldn't have it,
and then you could have
given it to me.
As a matter of fact,
Lindsey did buy the sweater,
and I did tell her
she couldn't have it.
Great.
Can I have it?
No.
I'm making her take it back.
Well, how do you take
something back to the Internet?
She's taking it back
to the mall.
Can I watch
a cool thing about cheetahs
on the Discovery Channel?
Yes.
You know what?
You can't take that sweater
back to the mall.
I'll buy it from you.
With what?
I'll give you a cut.
How you gonna
give me a cut
of something you don't have?
Besides, Gigi,
it's not about the money.
It's about the principle.
Oh, please.
I've said that before,
and believe me,
it's about the money.
How much?
I'm not selling you
the sweater.
Can I put my feet up
on the coffee table?
Yes.
I can't believe
you're gonna sacrifice
hundreds of dollars
just to teach
your daughter a lesson
when you could teach her
two lessons.
One: Do not
disobey your mother.
Two:
Even you can earn money
in the comfort and privacy
of your own home.
No.
Three: It's better to give
than to receive.
Sometimes.
No.
You're lucky all you do
is bobble, Chuck.
Oh, you know,
I'm sorry.
I probably
shouldn't be talking to you.
I didn't ask permission.
[Knocking]
Hey.
Hey, honey.
What are you doing?
Breathing.
Oh, is that okay?
Nick, I shouldn't have
blamed you for what Lindsey did.
I was angry,
and I'm sorry.
Thank you.
Come here, babe.
Look, Lindsey saved up
for a sweater
Michelle Obama was wearing.
She wants to dress
like the first lady.
I could think
of a lot worse things.
She could be looking up
to Amy Winehouse,
Heidi Montag,
Courtney Love,
the Real Housewives
of Orange County,
you know, white women.
You're right.
Hey, where's Kevin?
I haven't seen him all day.
I told him
he could hang out with Martin.
Why would Martin want
to hang out with a ten-year-old?
He said he wanted
to teach him guy stuff.
Well, he could have just
stayed here with you
and watched baseball.
[Crowd cheering]
Ladies and gentlemen,
this is a truly
heartwarming story.
A-Rod is dedicating
this at bat
to young Kevin Martin,
an orphan
whose drug-addicted parents
gave him up
for an eight ball.
Gave him up
for an eight ball?
That is awful.
Oh, my God!
That's Kevin!
What?
Poor kid.
Kevin Martin's
cracked-out parents
should be ashamed
of themselves.
Crack?
I'm not on crack!
Kevin Martin?
Did Martin have something
to do with this?
And A-Rod steps up
to the plate
and points to the bleachers.
Oh, he's gonna hit a home run
for poor little Kevin.
First pitch,
and it's a swing
and a miss.
Strike one.
[Groans]
You suck, A-Rod.
Come on, man.
A-Rod steps back
to the plate.
Here's the windup
and the pitch,
and it's fouled away.
Both: What is wrong
with you, man?
A-Rod just can't
catch a break.
Here comes the pitch.
And it's a bunt.
A bunt?
A surprise bunt
for young Kevin Martin.
And A-Rod's thrown out
at first,
just like young Kevin
was thrown out of life.
You do realize
I'm gonna kill your friend.
Hey.
Thank you
for cleaning up the kitchen.
I'm sorry
for disrespecting you
and lying to dad.
I just really wanted
that sweater.
I know.
Can we do this?
Yeah.
Bam!
Really?
Mm-hmm.
[Gasps]
Thank you, mom.
You're welcome.
[Giggles]
She did a good job.
Yeah, look at this.
Oh, hey, guys.
Hey.
Kevin, did you have
a good time with Martin?
It was cool.
What did you do?
We went
to the Mariners-Yankees game.
You don't say.
Oh, yeah.
I even got this bat signed
by one Alex Rodriguez.
Mm.
I'll take that.
Thank you.
Be careful with that.
It's worth $1,000.
$1,000?
I thought you said
it was worth $500.
Yeah, I lied.
What else
did you lie about, Martin?
Are you the one
who told millions of people
that my child
was a crack baby?
I never said that Kevin
was a crack baby.
I said his mother
was a crack whore.
[Doorbell rings]
You've got three seconds
to tell her
I had nothing to do with this.
All right, fine.
I admit it.
It was all my doing.
I mean, you know Nick,
Suzanne.
Does he seem
like he could come up
with a plan
this complicated?
Fortunately,
no one was harmed.
So can I get my bat,
please?
Your bat?
You got this using my child
under false pretenses.
Yeah.
That's why I said
I was sorry.
This is my bat.
What?
Never trust a crack whore.
Suzanne,
I'm in big trouble.
What's wrong?
I sold that
Michelle Obama sweater online,
and now the winning bidder
is threatening to sue me.
Here.
Maybe A-Rod can help you.
What am I gonna do
with this?
Sell it to Martin
for $1,000.
I'll give you $500.
I still need
to make a profit on this.
$750.
You still get $250
out of it.
$650,
and I don't tell Suzanne
what you said about her ankles.
I know my friend,
and she didn't say anything
about my ankles.
$850.
Fine, deal.
What about my $100 buck?
$100. We agreed on $50.
That's when you said
it was worth $500.
You're dead to me.
Kevin... you were in on this?
I only did it for the money.
-- sync, corrected by elderman --
-- for www.addic7ed.Com --