Launch (ph).
(END VIDEO CLIP)
CARL AZUZ, CNN ANCHOR: A big thanks to Mr.
Merrill students for getting things started
today, we have a packed show, so let`s go
ahead and get to it.
First up, hearings on Capitol Hill. Now, you
are not going to see any pictures from these
hearings, and you are not going to hear anything
that was said in them, either. That is because
these are closed hearings. That means no members
of the media, no members of the public are
allowed in.
We do know what they are about, though. This
-- the attack on the U.S. facility in Benghazi,
Libya. It happened just over two months ago,
the members of Congress who are running the
hearings have questions about how the attacks
happened and what happened afterward. And
they are hoping to get answers. Martha Shade
has more on who`ll be at the hearings and
what issues are expected to come up.
(BEGIN VIDEOTAPE)
MARTHA SHADE, CNN CORRESPONDENT: Several of
Washington`s power players will be on Capitol
Hill, expecting to be grilled about the deadly
consulate attack in Benghazi, Libya. U.S.
ambassador Chris Stevens and three other Americans
were killed in the September 11th assault.
Former CIA director David Petraeus is scheduled
to address this Senate House Intelligence
Committee, his testimony was in question after
his sudden resignation last week.
REP. PATRICK MEEHAN, (R ), PENNSYLVANIA: He
is necessary, he understands and was there
during the time when the Benghazi events occurred.
SHADE: Some Republicans have been going after
U.N. ambassador Susan Rice. After the violence,
she said intelligence pointed to a spontaneous,
not pre-planned attack. Senator John McCain
said Rice was deceptive, while Lindsey Graham
just doesn`t trust her.
SEN. LINDSEY GRAHAM, (R ), SOUTH CAROLINA:
And the reason I don`t trust her, is because
I think she knew better, and if she didn`t
know better she shouldn`t be the voice of
America.
SHADE: President Barack Obama had a message
to the senators in Rice`s defense.
BARACK OBAMA, PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED STATES
OF AMERICA: If Senator McCain and Senator
Graham and others want to go after somebody,
they should go after me, and I`m happy to
have that discussion with them.
SHADE: The senators oppose Rice possibly being
nominated to secretary of state to replace
Hillary Clinton, and say they will do whatever
they can do to block it.
Senator Rand Paul says he is no fun of Rice,
but there are bigger issues at play.
SEN. RAND PAUL, (R ), KENTUCKY: But I think
the more important question is, why were there
no Marines guarding our ambassador.
SHADE: Who made that decision, is likely to
be discussed during these hearings. I`m Martha
Shade reporting.
(END VIDEOTAPE)
AZUZ: Next stop, we are looking at a fine,
not just any old fine, the largest criminal
fine in U.S. history: it`s $1.2 billion, and
the company that`s paying it, is BP. You might
remember this: an explosion in 2010 in a BP
oil rig in the Gulf of Mexico. A massive oil
spill that leaked more than 200 million gallons
of oil into the water. And the serious environmental
problems when some of that oil washed up along
the U.S. Gulf coast. Yesterday, BP reached
the settlement with the U.S. government. The
company will pay $4.5 billion. That includes
the record fine, and it covers other criminal
charges and government penalties. BP has already
agreed to pay 20 billion to cover damages
from the spill, and nearly 8 billion to private
victims. For perspective in a two year since
the oil spill happened, BP has made $43 billion
in profits.
You`ve heard this talk about this fiscal cliff.
It`s a series automatic government spending
cuts and tax increases that could hit Americans
next year, if Congress and President Obama
don`t figure out a way around them. Here is
a look at how the fiscal cliff could impact
education: school districts nationwide would
have less money, so after school programs,
enrichment programs, sports could be cut.
More teachers could lose their jobs or get
paid less. And many schools wouldn`t be able
to make needed repairs, upgrade computers
or get new textbooks. Because so many schools
have been struggling with less money after
the recession hit, this fiscal cliff could
make things worse: and that`s why so many
people in education are paying attention to
what happens as Congress and the president
try to find the solution.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: See, if you can ID me.
I`m a country that`s been around for centuries,
but I established my current Communist form
of government in 1949. I`m one of the world`s
largest nations in size. And I`m the largest
in population.
I`m China and I`m home to more than 1.3 billion
people.
(END VIDEOCLIP)
AZUZ: There`s been a change at the top of
China`s Communist Party. In the U.S., presidential
candidates are out in public all the time.
That`s not how things work in China. When
that country`s leadership goes through a transition,
it all happens behind closed doors. These
seven men are those new leaders. They make
up the most powerful committee in the Chinese
government. And the one who is front and center,
is Xi Jinping, he is the new head of China`s
Communist Party and is expected to lead the
country for the next ten years. A lot of other
nations are wondering, what to expect from
Xi in this committee. That`s because in addition
to having the world`s biggest population,
China also has the world`s second biggest
economy. That means it has a lot of influence
on the world`s economic issues.
Back into U.S., 13 deaths have been reported
to the FDA, the Food and Drug Administration.
The reports say that those 13 people died
after using a supplement called "5-hour Energy."
The FDA launched an investigation, it`s required
to by law. But it also says, that a report
by itself doesn`t mean that a product is responsible
for health issue. So far, connection between
the deaths and 5-hour Energy hasn`t been established.
One thing the FDA is likely looking at is
caffeine. One 5-hour Energy has 207 milligrams
of caffeine. To compare, a cup of coffee can
have anywhere from 95 to 200 milligrams. A
regular can of Red Bull has about 80 milligrams.
Dr. Sanjay Gupta is CNN`s chief medical correspondent.
He was talking to a colleague recently, and
this other doctor brought up an issue that
he described as the biggest manmade epidemic
in the United States. He was talking about
accidental death from overdoses. But not from
illegal drugs, from prescription drugs. Accidental
overdoses are the number one cause of accidental
death in America. We talked to Dr. Gupta about
ways to prevent this, and some of the surprising
numbers associated with the issue.
(BEGIN VIDEOTAPE)
DR. SANJAY GUPTA, CNN CORRESPONDENT: Carl,
I think the statistics that gets everyone`s
attention here, is that every 90 minutes in
this country, someone dies from an accidental
overdose of prescription drugs. You keep that
in mind, and I think that tells you a large
tale. And also, if you look at the world,
and you think about young people and old people
alike, 80 percent of the world`s pain pills
are taken in the United States. We prescribe
enough to give every man, woman and child
a doze every 4 hours for three weeks. So,
look, we are talking a lot about this, but
best advice: if you have pain pills in your
medicine cabinet, get rid of them.
People have a preconceived notion of who this
people are that are dying, but oftentimes
it`s your friends, your families, your neighbors,
it`s not people who you would think of as
addicts. There are people who have legitimate
pain that need to have those pain concerns
addressed. Don`t misuse these pills, and ask
yourself, every time you are given a prescription,
do I really need this? Hopefully, that`s going
to help a lot of people, Carl. Back to you.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: Today "Shoutout" goes
out to Mr. Love`s journalism technology student
at Sandpoint High School in Sand Point, Idaho.
Francis Scott Key wrote the lyrics o which
of these songs? You know what to do, is it
"My Country "Tis of Thee." "America the Beautiful,"
God Bless America" or the "Star-Spangled Banner."
You`ve got three seconds, go!
Key wrote the lyrics to the "Star-Spangled
Banner" during the war of 1812. That`s your
answer and that`s your "Shoutout."
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: You might expect to hear the "Star-Spangled
Banner" before a sports event, that tradition
is connected to some controversy in part of
Pennsylvania. The commissioner in charge of
high school hockey emailed teams and suggested
that they not sing the anthem. He says it`s
not a question of patriotism, it`s a concern
about costs.
High school hockey rents ice time for games,
so every game is carefully timed. When time
runs out, the game ends, even if the clock
hasn`t hit zero. If the singer takes longer
with the national anthem, it eats into that
game time. Some people aren`t happy with the
idea of skipping the national anthem. They`ve
suggested extending the time for the game
or cutting time somewhere else. One person
suggested using a pre- recorded rendition
of the anthems, so you always know how long
it will be.
Tile, linoleum, marble, carpet, hardwood,
there are a lot of types of floors. But the
owner of this business in Pittsburgh went
a different route: she paid pennies for her
flooring, actually, she didn`t pay them, she
used them. 250,000 pennies took her and some
volunteers about 300 hours to lay it all down,
but she said it`s actually a lot cheaper than
paying for tile. So, how do you make a floor
from all these? I guess, you lay the pennies
down and then start linking them together.
Suppose, if you don`t want to be ordinary
that`s certainly on the way to change. You
imagine when the customers walking and see
it, though. They are going to be floored.
They might not be able to make sense of it,
but I know just how to ask them for their
opinions. Penny for your thoughts? All right,
that`s all the puns we can handle for now.
I hope you have a great weekend.