EXPLORES THE MOTIVE...
GENOCIDE NEVER HAPPENS
AS A SURPRISE.
AND EXPLODES THE MYTH...
THESE PEOPLE HAD
TO BE ELIMINATED.
BEHIND A CRIME...
IT WAS CRUELTY
THAT OVERCAME US,
ME AND MY FELLOW CRIMINALS.
GENOCIDE IS
ALWAYS POLITICS.
THAT'S WORSE THAN WAR.
CAPTIONING MADE POSSIBLE BY
FRIENDS OF NCI
"WORSE THAN WAR" WAS MADE
POSSIBLE BY...
THE PERSHING SQUARE
FOUNDATION...
AND THE EINHORN FAMILY
CHARITABLE TRUST.
ADDITIONAL FUNDING WAS
PROVIDED BY...
[BIRD CHIRPING]
Man: SO ALL THE PEOPLE HERE
MURDERED OTHER PEOPLE?
[TRANSLATOR SPEAKS
NATIVE LANGUAGE]
YES. YOU CAN'T BE HERE
IF YOU HAVEN'T KILLED.
[BIRD CHIRPING]
CAN YOU SHOW ME HOW YOU--
HOW THE PERSON WAS HACKED?
[TRANSLATOR SPEAKS
NATIVE LANGUAGE]
I'VE BEEN THINKING
AND WRITING ABOUT GENOCIDE
FOR NEARLY 30 YEARS,
IT'S SOMETHING PEOPLE DON'T
MUCH LIKE TO TALK ABOUT
AND ABOUT WHICH
MOST OF US REMAIN
DANGEROUSLY MISINFORMED.
Woman: GOOD EVENING.
A NEW BOOK CALLED "HITLER'S
WILLING EXECUTIONERS,"
A HIGHLY CONTROVERSIAL
ACCOUNT OF THE HOLOCAUST...
Man: THE AMERICAN
DANIEL GOLDHAGEN SAYS
THE EXCUSE OF ONLY
OBEYING ORDERS WON'T WASH.
[MAN SPEAKS
NATIVE LANGUAGE]
Jane Pauley:
A CONTROVERSIAL BOOK
ABOUT THE HOLOCAUST,
RAISING A TROUBLING
NEW QUESTION:
WERE NAZI KILLERS HELPED
BY HUNDREDS OF THOUSANDS
OF ORDINARY GERMANS?
THEY SUBJECTED THE VICTIMS
TO GRATUITOUS BRUTALITY,
INCESSANT CRUELTY,
SO THE PICTURE THAT EMERGES
IS NOT OF RELUCTANT PEOPLE
WHO ARE COMPELLED TO DO
WHAT THEY DID,
BUT PEOPLE WHO AGREED WITH
THE PROGRAM, WHO BELIEVED
THAT THE DEATH OF THE JEWS
WAS NECESSARY AND JUST.
Goldhagen: I'VE SPENT
MY PROFESSIONAL LIFE TRYING
TO DISPEL THE MANY MYTHS
THAT CLOUD PEOPLE'S JUDGMENT
AND PREVENT US FROM DOING
SOMETHING EFFECTIVE
TO STOP THE KILLING.
GENOCIDES HAPPEN
IN EVERY CORNER OF THE WORLD,
THROUGH EVERY TYPE OF PEOPLE.
THE NUMBERS IN THE PAST
100 YEARS ARE STAGGERING.
THE TURKS SLAUGHTERED
MORE THAN A MILLION ARMENIANS
DURING WORLD WAR I.
IN THE 1930s AND 1940s,
THE JAPANESE KILLED
MILLIONS ACROSS ASIA.
IN THE SOVIET UNION,
THE ESTIMATED NUMBER
OF DEATHS IN THE GULAG CAMPS
AND BEYOND IS
MORE THAN 8 MILLION.
THE GERMANS SLAUGHTERED
6 MILLION JEWS
AND MILLIONS MORE
DURING WORLD WAR II.
IN THE 1950s AND 1960s,
THE COMMUNIST CHINESE KILLED
AN ESTIMATED 30 MILLION,
AND DURING THE 1970s,
THE KHMER ROUGE KILLED
1.7 MILLION CAMBODIANS--
FULLY 20% OF THEIR
COUNTRY'S POPULATION.
BOSNIA,
RWANDA,
CONGO,
DARFUR.
ALL TOLD, IN OUR TIME
THERE HAVE BEEN MORE THAN
100 MILLION INNOCENT VICTIMS
OF GENOCIDE--
MORE THAN ALL THE COMBAT DEATHS
IN ALL THE WARS FOUGHT
DURING THAT TIME
EVERYWHERE IN THE WORLD.
BASED ON THE HUMAN TOLL ALONE,
GENOCIDE AND MASS SLAUGHTER
ARE WORSE PROBLEMS PLAGUING
HUMANITY THAN WAR.
WE NEED TO UNDERSTAND WHY.
Man: IT IS
A GREAT, DIFFICULT
TASK YOU'RE FACING
TO CONVEY HUMAN BEINGS
WHOSE BEHAVIOR SEEMS
TO DEFY UNDERSTANDING,
AND THEY WERE
BEYOND BELIEF.
Goldhagen, voice-over:
IN MY WORK, I HAVE BENEFITED
FROM THE WISDOM
OF A VALUED MENTOR,
A SCHOLAR OF GENOCIDE,
AND SURVIVOR OF THE HOLOCAUST.
BUT, YOU KNOW,
AT THIS POINT,
THOUGH--
BUT LET ME JUST
REMIND YOU...
HE ALSO HAPPENS
TO BE MY FATHER.
WHEN THE FIRST NEWS
OF THE GAS CHAMBERS CAME,
THE JEWISH COMMUNITY WAS
VERY SKEPTICAL OF IT.
RIGHT, BUT WE'RE
IN A DIFFERENT
TIME NOW.
NOBODY DISBELIEVES
THAT THESE THINGS
HAPPENED.
THAT'S QUITE TRUE.
WHAT THEY HAVE
DIFFICULTY
UNDERSTANDING--
IS WHY IT HAPPENED, YES.
AND ACCEPTING NOTIONS
THAT VIOLATE THEIR OWN
COMMON-SENSE
UNDERSTANDINGS
OF THE WORLD.
THERE'S
A CERTAIN PARADOX HERE
BECAUSE SOMETIMES
ONE ACCEPTS VERY HIGHLY,
SEEMINGLY ORIGINAL,
PROFOUND THEORIES,
AND SOMETIMES
THE EXPLANATION IS
RELATIVELY SIMPLE.
I THINK THE ACTUAL
EXPLANATIONS ARE--
ARE THREATENING AND
UNSETTLING TO PEOPLE.
THE NOTION THAT ORDINARY
PEOPLE WOULD WILLFULLY
BUTCHER OTHER PEOPLE,
TORTURE THEM,
INCLUDING CHILDREN,
SLAUGHTER THEM,
IS A VERY DISTURBING
NOTION TO PEOPLE,
PARTICULARLY IF THEY'RE
LOOKING UPON PEOPLE
WITH WHOM THEY IDENTIFY.
SO THEY SEEK
EXPLANATIONS
WHICH ARE MORE--
I WOULDN'T SAY MORE
COMFORTING, BUT LESS
THREATENING TO THEM...
Goldhagen, voice-over:
AS EARLY AS I CAN REMEMBER
THINKING SERIOUS THOUGHTS,
MY FATHER AND I HAVE BEEN
TALKING ABOUT THESE THINGS.
AS A SCHOLAR, HE JOURNEYED
INTO THE DARKEST CHAPTERS
OF THE HUMAN EXPERIENCE,
SEEKING TO UNDERSTAND
NOT ONLY WHAT HAPPENED,
BUT WHY.
NOW I AM CONTINUING
THE JOURNEY HE BEGAN,
A JOURNEY THAT IN A SENSE,
I HAVE BEEN ON MY ENTIRE LIFE.
PEOPLE NEED TO UNDERSTAND
THAT NOTHING IS INEVITABLE
ABOUT GENOCIDE.
IT BOILS DOWN
TO A SERIES OF CHOICES.
LEADERS CHOOSE
TO INITIATE THE KILLING,
ORDINARY PEOPLE MAKE
A CONSCIOUS CHOICE
TO PARTICIPATE...
AND THOSE WITH THE POWER
TO PREVENT OR STOP IT
CHOOSE TO DO NOTHING.
I STUDY GENOCIDES
BECAUSE I BELIEVE
THE MORE WE KNOW ABOUT HOW
AND WHY GENOCIDES HAPPEN,
THE MORE WE CAN
GET POLITICAL LEADERS
AND ORDINARY PEOPLE
TO MAKE DIFFERENT CHOICES.
IMAGINE IF ONE DAY,
PEOPLE IN YOUR NEIGHBORHOOD
WERE DRAGGED OUT OF THEIR HOMES
AND KILLED IN THE STREET.
YOU WOULD WANT THE KILLERS
STOPPED AND PUNISHED,
AND YOU WOULD WANT
TO KNOW THAT IT WOULD
NEVER HAPPEN AGAIN.
WHY SHOULD IT BE ANY DIFFERENT
WHEN THE VICTIMS
ARE SOMEWHERE ELSE?
LIKE THE PEOPLE
IN YOUR COMMUNITY,
EACH GENOCIDE VICTIM
IS AN INDIVIDUAL.
A FATHER, A MOTHER,
A DAUGHTER, A SON.
AS A SCHOLAR, I SPEND MOST
OF MY TIME IN ARCHIVES
AND LIBRARIES.
BUT OVER THE PAST YEAR,
I TRAVELED TO THESE
"SOMEWHERE ELSES,"
THE SITES OF SOME OF
THE WORST MASS MURDERS
OF OUR TIME.
[BIRDS CHIRPING]
[DOOR CLANGS]
IT'S BEEN DECADES STUDYING NAZIS
AND THE HOLOCAUST, GENOCIDE,
BUT I'VE NEVER BEEN IN
A GAS CHAMBER BEFORE.
I STARTED MY JOURNEY MINDFUL
THAT THERE HAS NEVER BEEN A TIME
DURING THE PAST CENTURY
WHEN OUR PLANET WAS FREE
OF MASS MURDER,
INCLUDING NOW.
Woman: FOR 5 LONG YEARS,
DARFUR HAS BEEN A SCENE
OF DEVASTATION AND DESTRUCTION.
300,000 PEOPLE HAVE DIED
AND 2.5 MILLION HAVE FLED
THEIR HOMES
AS THE SUDANESE GOVERNMENT HAS
TRIED TO CRUSH A REBELLION
AGAINST ITS RULE.
Goldhagen: THE PLIGHT OF DARFUR
HAS MOVED PEOPLE OF CONSCIENCE
AROUND THE WORLD
AND HAS ONLY INTENSIFIED
MY DESIRE TO KNOW MORE...
TO SEE THE PLACES WHERE
THE HORRORS HAVE HAPPENED,
MEET THE PEOPLE WHO WERE THERE,
AND ASK THE KINDS OF QUESTIONS
YOU HAVE TO ASK,
EVEN THOUGH SOMETIMES
YOU MAY DREAD HEARING
THE ANSWER.
Goldhagen:
WHEN THE GENOCIDE BEGAN,
WHAT HAPPENED TO YOU?
[TRANSLATOR SPEAKING
NATIVE LANGUAGE]
AND HER FAMILY.
SHE SAID HER DAD
WAS KILLED LIKE--
HE WAS, YOU KNOW,
CHOPPED. HE WAS CUT
WITH A MACHETE.
AND THE MOM WAS CHOPPED.
THAT WHAT SHE'S SAYING
IS SHE WAS CHOPPED
WITH A MACHETE.
AND THE BROTHER WAS,
ALSO.
WHO KILLED HER FAMILY?
WERE THESE
JUST LOCAL PEOPLE
WHO LIVE THROUGH HERE?
[TRANSLATOR SPEAKS
NATIVE LANGUAGE]
SHE SAYS THEY WERE
NEIGHBORS.
MOST OF THAT, THEY WERE
EVEN FRIENDS
TO THE FAMILY.
[COW BELLOWS]
Goldhagen: IN GENOCIDE
AFTER GENOCIDE,
THESE ARE THE QUESTIONS
THAT CONTINUE TO BE ASKED:
HOW DO NEIGHBORS END UP
TURNING AGAINST NEIGHBORS?
WHY DO THE KILLERS KILL?
HERE IN RWANDA,
MORE THAN 800,000 MEN,
WOMEN, AND CHILDREN
WERE KILLED OVER
THE COURSE OF 3 MONTHS.
MOST WERE ETHNIC TUTSI,
MURDERED BY MEMBERS
OF THE HUTU MAJORITY,
FACE TO FACE WITH MACHETES,
CLUBS, AND GUNS.
HITLER'S GAS CHAMBERS
DID NOT KILL WITH SUCH
DEADLY EFFICIENCY.
Goldhagen: WHEN PEOPLE
KILLED THE VICTIMS,
DID THEY TRY TO KILL THEM
AS PAINLESSLY AS POSSIBLE
OR DID THEY TRY
TO MAKE THEM SUFFER?
[TRANSLATOR SPEAKING
NATIVE LANGUAGE]
Goldhagen: I FIND IT HARD
TO UNDERSTAND, AND I WANT
TO UNDERSTAND,
HOW PEOPLE COULD
APPROACH OTHER PEOPLE,
WHO ARE BEGGING
FOR THEIR LIVES AND
SCREAMING IN PAIN,
AND CHOP THEM.
IT'S A VERY TOUGH
QUESTION TO ANSWER
BECAUSE THEY HAVE
THE SAME FLESH,
LIKE YOURS.
ELIE'S WORD--CRUELTY--
COULD NOT BE MORE ACCURATE.
CRUELTY IS AT
THE HEART OF GENOCIDE.
THE KILLERS DON'T JUST ERADICATE
THE TARGETED PEOPLE,
BUT BRUTALIZE THEM
IN WAYS THAT FAR EXCEED
WHAT IS NEEDED TO KILL THEM.
I SEE THE EVIDENCE
OF SUCH CRUELTY
EVERYWHERE I GO.
I CAME TO GUATEMALA,
WHERE A MASSIVE EFFORT
HAS BEEN UNDERWAY
TO LITERALLY UNCOVER THE TRUTH
ABOUT THE GOVERNMENT'S
MASS SLAUGHTER
OF 200,000 INDIGENOUS MAYA
DURING THE 1980s.
OUTSIDE GUATEMALA, FEW PEOPLE
EVEN KNOW ABOUT THE GENOCIDE.
Suasnavar:
BUENOS DIAS.
Goldhagen: DO WE KNOW--IS THIS
A FAMILY OR TWO FAMILIES?
ARE THERE ADULTS?
Goldhagen: IN THESE HILLS,
THE GUATEMALAN MILITARY
CONDUCTED A SCORCHED-EARTH
CAMPAIGN
AGAINST MAYA
AND LEFTIST INSURGENTS.
THE MAYAN PEOPLE, THEY SAID,
WERE INHERENTLY SUBVERSIVE
AND AN IMPEDIMENT TO PROGRESS.
THE GOVERNMENT STRATEGY
WAS SUMMED UP
IN A GRIM APHORISM
OF THE TIME--
"TO KILL THE FISH,
YOU HAVE TO DRAIN THE POND."
HERE, IN THE MOUNTAIN HAMLET
OF PLAN DE SANCHEZ,
THEY DRAINED THE POND
ON JULY 18, 1982.
Woman: THE MILITARY WOULD
SEPARATE THE WOMEN AND THE MEN.
SOMETIMES THEY WOULD TAKE
THE INFANTS OUT OF
THE WOMEN'S ARMS
AND SIMPLY SMASH THEM
ON THE GROUND,
KILL THEM RIGHT THERE
IN FRONT OF EVERYBODY.
THEY CUT TONGUES OUT.
THEY OPENED
PREGNANT WOMEN'S BELLIES
AND DASHED FETUSES
AGAINST TREES.
THEY BURNED PEOPLE ALIVE.
WE KNOW THIS BECAUSE
THERE WERE PEOPLE
WHO, EVEN IN THE MIDST
OF THIS MAYHEM AND MASS KILLING,
SOMEHOW MANAGED TO HIDE--
BEHIND A DOOR,
UNDERNEATH A PILE
OF CORN HUSKS--
AND WATCH.
Goldhagen: ONLY ONCE I GOT
TO GUATEMALA DID I REALIZE
HOW REMOTE
THESE MOUNTAIN VILLAGES
REALLY ARE.
GOVERNMENT LEADERS CALL
THESE SUBSISTENCE FARMERS
A THREAT TO THE WELL-BEING
OF THE COUNTRY,
BUT THEY DID NOT POSE
A THREAT TO ANYONE.
THE GUATEMALAN PERPETRATORS
OBLITERATED ONE SUCH COMMUNITY
AFTER ANOTHER.
Goldhagen:
EVERYWHERE I GO, THE FACES
OF CHILDREN HAUNT ME THE MOST.
I HAVE CHILDREN, TOO,
AND IT'S HARD NOT TO THINK
ABOUT THEM AS I HEAR STORIES
OVER AND OVER ABOUT THE CRUELTY
CHILDREN SUFFERED.
...WHEN THEY KILLED
ABOUT 177 PEOPLE,
MOST OF THEM
CHILDREN AND
THE OTHERS WOMEN.
SO THERE WASN'T
A SINGLE ADULT MALE,
SO WHICH CAN--
YOU KNOW,
YOU CAN SAY
LETS YOU UNDERSTAND
THAT THESE ARE NOT
COMBAT DEATHS.
OH, NO. YEAH, YOU KNOW,
IT'S VERY COMMON
IN MASS MURDERS
FOR THE PERPETRATORS
TO DO THIS TO CHILDREN...
YEAH.
AFTER RWANDA
AND THE HOLOCAUST.
Goldhagen, voice-over:
FREDY PECCERELLI, A GUATEMALAN
NATIVE RAISED IN AMERICA,
IS IN CHARGE OF COLLECTING
AND CATALOGUING THE BONES.
THEY PORTRAY A MESSAGE.
WHEN THEY DO THIS,
THEY ARE ALSO KILLING
THE SEED OF EVIL,
ACCORDING TO THEM,
WHETHER IT BE
IN NAZI GERMANY
OR WHETHER IT BE
IN GUATEMALA
IN THE 1980s.
BUT THIS IS THE BONE LAB
OF THE FORENSIC
ANTHROPOLOGY LABORATORY.
FREDY IS AMASSING
A RECORD OF THE ATROCITIES
COMMITTED BY THE GUATEMALAN
PERPETRATORS...
BUT THE FIRST STAGE
AFTER THE...
AND PROVIDING THE VICTIMS'
FAMILIES WITH THE REMAINS
TO BURY PROPERLY.
Peccerelli:
THE BONES HOLD THE STORY
OF WHAT HAPPENED TO
A PERSON DURING THEIR LIFE
AND MIGHT EVEN TELL US
WHAT HAPPENED TO THEM
DURING THE EVENT
OF THEIR DEATH
AND EVEN WHAT HAPPENED
TO THEM AFTER DEATH.
SO HERE, FOR EXAMPLE,
WE CAN SEE...HOW...
AND IF YOU WANT, I'LL
ALLOW YOU TO FEEL THE
DIFFERENCE SO YOU CAN SEE.
THIS IS A VERY SHARP CUT,
AND IF YOU RUN YOUR HAND
THROUGH IT,
IT'S VERY, VERY SMOOTH.
MM-HMM.
YOU SEE, THAT WAS CAUSED
BY A MACHETE STRIKING
THE RIGHT SIDE OF THE HEAD
AND ALSO CUTTING THE ATLAS.
AND, YOU SEE,
WHEN YOU MATCH IT UP
ANATOMICALLY,
YOU CAN SEE THAT
THIS TRAUMA HERE...
RIGHT.
IS RELATED
TO THIS STRIKE HERE,
AND BASICALLY WHAT
THEY TRIED TO DO HERE IS
DECAPITATE THE PERSON.
NOW, WHAT WE'VE SEEN
USUALLY IS THAT
THESE PEOPLE WERE NOT
VERY KNOWLEDGEABLE
OF ANATOMY,
SO THE DECAPITATIONS,
AS YOU'D EXPECT,
WERE NOT ALWAYS SUCCESSFUL,
SO YOU HAVE REPEATED BLOWS
TO THE HEAD.
SOMEBODY'S TRYING
TO SEPARATE THE HEAD
FROM THE BODY.
THEY'RE VERY TYPICAL
OF OVERKILL AND SOMETIMES
OF EVEN CRIMES OF PASSION.
Goldhagen: "OVERKILL"--
THERE'S A WORD
I DON'T THINK I'LL EVER HEAR
THE SAME WAY AGAIN.
IF THE KILLERS WERE
SIMPLY DOING THEIR DUTY
TO WIPE OUT AN INSURGENCY,
AS THEY CLAIM,
THEY WOULD EXECUTE THEIR VICTIMS
QUICKLY AND BE DONE WITH IT.
YOU HAVE TO WONDER WHY
WE SEE SO MUCH EVIDENCE
OF SUCH MURDEROUS PASSION,
ESPECIALLY AGAINST
WOMEN AND CHILDREN.
THIS IS A CHILD HERE,
A VERY YOUNG CHILD.
I WOULDN'T EVEN DARE
TO TELL YOU THE AGE
UNLESS WITH
THE ANTHROPOLOGIST
WORKING ON THE CASE,
AND YOU CAN COMPARE--
THIS IS THE FIRST RIB.
WOW.
SO...AND IF
YOU COMPARE THIS
TO THAT ONE,
YOU CAN SEE THE DIFFERENCE.
I MEAN, THE FIRST RIB IS
ABOUT THAT BIG, SO THIS
IS A VERY, VERY SMALL--
MAY I SEE THIS?
JUST HOLDING THE
TINY LITTLE BONE.
YOU KNOW...
YEAH.
SEE, I DON'T KNOW.
I DON'T THINK
THERE'S A--A WAY OF...
HUMANLY
UNDERSTANDING THIS
BECAUSE IT GOES
BEYOND WHAT I BELIEVE
HUMANS CAN DO,
BUT OBVIOUSLY--I MEAN,
THE MORE I SAY THAT,
THE MORE I TEND TO--
IT'S HARD FOR ME
TO BELIEVE
THAT YOU'RE
SAYING THIS,
GIVEN WHAT YOU--
BECAUSE I WANT TO BELIEVE
THAT WE'RE NOT CAPABLE
OF THESE THINGS,
EVEN THOUGH--
I WANT TO BELIEVE
THAT THIS IS WRONG.
SO DOING THIS
HAS TO BE WRONG.
IF I ACCEPTED THIS
AS RIGHT AND IF
I EXCUSE IT,
THEN I CAN'T
DO THIS ANYMORE.
FREDY IS NOT ALONE.
MOST OF US FIND IT HARD
TO COME TO TERMS
WITH THE CAPACITY
OF HUMAN BEINGS TO DO
SUCH HORRIBLE THINGS TO OTHERS.
BUT WE HAVE TO MAKE SENSE OF IT.
AS IRRATIONAL AS THEY SEEM,
THESE ARE NOT THE ACTS
OF CRAZED INDIVIDUALS.
THESE ARE PEOPLE WHO KNOW
WHAT THEY ARE DOING,
BELIEVE IT'S RIGHT, AND MAKE
A CONSCIOUS CHOICE TO ACT.
UH, HELLO.
JA.
ICH BIN DANIEL GOLDHAGEN.
[SPEAKING GERMAN]
Goldhagen: LIKE MOST GERMANS,
OTTO-ERNST DUSCHELEIT GREW UP
WITH THE WORLD VIEW
IN WHICH HE SAW HIMSELF
AS A MEMBER OF THE MASTER RACE,
WHILE MANY OTHERS FELL INTO
THE CATEGORY OF SUB-HUMANS
OR UNTERMENSCHEN.
[MEN SINGING IN GERMAN]
Goldhagen:
WHEN YOU WERE IN SCHOOL...
YES?
WHEN YOU WERE IN
THE HITLER YOUTH,
WHAT DID YOU LEARN,
FOR EXAMPLE, ABOUT
UNTERMENSCHEN?
WHAT DID THAT WORD
MEAN TO YOU?
JA, UNTERMENSCHEN.
Goldhagen: IT'S STRIKING
THAT IT IS A FORMER SS MAN,
INVOKING ANNE FRANK,
WHO MAKES THIS POINT.
IT IS AN IMPORTANT ONE.
IT IS THAT FAILURE TO SEE
THE HUMANITY IN OTHERS
WHICH MAKES IT POSSIBLE
FOR THE KILLERS TO COMMIT
THEIR CRIMES.
I WOULD ADD
THAT IT'S THE BELIEF
THAT THOSE OTHERS
ARE DANGEROUS ENEMIES
WHICH INSPIRES THE PERPETRATORS
TO KILL WITH SUCH ZEAL.
YEARS AGO, I ENCOUNTERED
AN EPISODE OF THE HOLOCAUST
WHICH SPOKE VOLUMES
ABOUT THE WILLFULNESS
AND DEDICATION OF THE KILLERS,
AND I GOT TO KNOW ONE OF
THE SURVIVORS, LILLI SILBIGER.
I HAVE A MAP HERE
WITH ME WHICH ACTUALLY
OUTLINES THE ROUTE
FROM HELMBRECHT
TO VOLARY...
Goldhagen, voice-over:
IN THE LAST MONTHS
OF WORLD WAR II,
AS THE ALLIED FORCES NEARED
THE CONCENTRATION CAMPS
HOUSING JEWS AND OTHERS,
GERMANS EMPTIED THEIR CAMPS
AND DROVE THEIR PRISONERS
ON FORCED MARCHES
THROUGH THE NEARBY TOWNS
AND COUNTRYSIDE.
[SILBIGER SPEAKING GERMAN]
Goldhagen: THE DEATH MARCHES
LEFT A TRAIL OF CORPSES
IN THEIR WAKE,
AND THE MARCHING PRISONERS WERE
DESCRIBED BY MORE THAN
ONE WITNESS
AS "THE WALKING DEAD."
THESE ARE ACTUAL PHOTOS
OF THE YOUNG WOMEN
WHO WERE WITH LILLI
ON THE MARCH.
ON THE SUMMER DAY
LILY REVISITED THE ROUTE
OF A DEATH MARCH WITH ME,
THE COUNTRYSIDE WAS BEAUTIFUL.
BUT IN THE SPRING OF 1945,
IT WAS COLD AND BLEAK.
LILY'S GUARDS ACTUALLY HAD
RECEIVED EXPLICIT ORDERS
NOT TO KILL ANY MORE JEWS,
BUT THEY WILLFULLY DEFIED
THEIR SUPERIORS.
THEY DROVE HER AND THE OTHERS,
STARVING, WEARING NOTHING
MORE THAN RAGS,
DAY AFTER DAY THROUGH
THE FRIGID COUNTRYSIDE.
SOMETIMES WE WOULDN'T
EVEN GET FOOD FOR
24 HOURS, FOR 48 HOURS.
PEOPLE RESORTED
TO ANYTHING
THAT WAS FOUND
OR ANYTHING ROTTEN THAT
WAS--YOU KNOW, YOU JUST
GRABBED AT ANYTHING.
AND YOU WERE 16
AT THE TIME?
YEAH.
AND IN ONE PLACE,
SOMEONE BROKE
INTO A PANTRY
OR SOMEPLACE WHERE
WE ARRIVED AND STOLE
SOME LOAFS OF BREAD.
AND FOR THAT,
THEY SELECTED 50 GIRLS
AND KILLED THEM
OVER THE MASS GRAVE
THERE.
WE HAD TO COME BACK
AND COVER THEM,
AND THERE WERE MANY
OF THEM STILL ALIVE
WHEN WE HAD TO DO THAT.
SO THEY--YOU HAD
TO HELP BURY THEM ALIVE?
WE HAD TO DO--
WE HAD TO PUT--
YES, THE EARTH,
COVER THEM WITH EARTH.
SO THIS WAS
THE BIGGEST HORRIBLE...
[VOICE CRACKS]
YEAH....
PERIOD.
[DISTANT ROLLING THUNDER]
ONE OF THE ASTONISHING THINGS
IS THAT THEY WERE MARCHING
THE JEWISH PRISONERS
LITERALLY THE LAST DAY
OF THE WAR.
INSTEAD OF RUNNING AWAY
TO AVOID CAPTURE, THEY
STAYED WITH THE PRISONERS,
THEY CONTINUED
TO DENY THEM FOOD...
ABSOLUTELY.
THEY CONTINUED TO BEAT THEM,
THEY CONTINUED TO KILL THEM,
THEY CONTINUED TO DO IT
TO THE VERY END.
WE KNEW THE RUSSIANS
WERE CLOSING IN THERE,
AND THEN WE HEARD
ARTILLERY,
SOME PLANES FLYING
OVERHEAD,
HEARD SOME BOMBINGS
IN THE DISTANCE,
SO WE KNEW
THEY WERE VERY CLOSE.
[EXPLOSIONS, GUNFIRE]
THEY MANAGED FOR SUCH
A LONG TIME TO KEEP
AHEAD OF THE ALLIES,
GOING NOWHERE, YOU KNOW,
TO--A PLACE--TO NOWHERE.
JUST TO DRAG US,
JUST TO...
JUST GO IN CIRCLES,
ACTUALLY. THAT'S WHAT
WAS HAPPENING.
THEY DIDN'T KNOW
THEMSELVES WHAT THEY
WERE DOING.
THEY COULD HAVE EASILY
LEFT US WHEREVER WE WERE
AND JUST DISAPPEAR,
AND THEY DIDN'T.
THEY BELIEVED THE JEWS
WERE EVIL INCARNATE,
AN ENEMY OF HUMANKIND,
A THREAT TO
THE WELL-BEING AND FUTURE
EXISTENCE OF GERMANY.
AND IF YOU BELIEVE THAT,
JUST AS IF YOU BELIEVE
SOMEONE'S ABOUT
TO ATTACK YOUR CHILD,
YOU WILL DO
ANYTHING YOU CAN.
YEAH.
[CAR HORN HONKS]
EACH OF US TRIES TO MAKE SENSE
OF THE HORRORS IN HIS
OR HER OWN WAY.
OVER THE YEARS, I HAVE TALKED
WITH MANY WHO GRAPPLE
OVER THESE ISSUES,
BUT NEVER ONE MORE THOUGHTFUL
THAN A MAN I MET IN RWANDA--
THARCISSE KARUGARAMA,
THE COUNTRY'S MINISTER
OF JUSTICE.
Goldhagen:
HERE WE'RE SPEAKING NOW
AS TWO PEOPLE TRYING
TO UNDERSTAND
A VERY DIFFICULT SET
OF CIRCUMSTANCES:
THE WAYS IN WHICH VICTIMS
WERE NOT JUST KILLED
IN, IF WE CAN CALL IT,
THE LEAST PAINFUL WAY,
BUT WERE HACKED TO DEATH,
WERE TORTURED;
THE ZEAL AND PASSION
WITH WHICH THE PERPETRATORS
SOUGHT OUT THE VICTIMS.
IT'S NOT EASY TO FIND PEOPLE
HIDING IN THE COUNTRYSIDE.
MASS HYSTERIA...
IS VERY DIFFICULT
TO EXPLAIN.
PEOPLE HIT A PERIOD
WHEN THEY'RE INVOLVED
IN MASS HYSTERIA,
WHEN THEY CAN NO LONGER
BE ACCOUNTABLE FOR
THEIR ACTIONS.
BUT YOU CERTAINLY
DON'T WANT TO TAKE THAT AS
A LEGAL POSITION, DO YOU?
NO, DEFINITELY NOT.
DEFINITELY NOT.
I'M JUST TRYING
TO EXPLAIN BECAUSE
I'VE BEEN AROUND
IN THIS JUDICIAL
FOR SOME TIME NOW,
AND I'VE MADE ALL SORTS
OF CONTRADICTIONS.
SO THE ONE
YOU'RE TALKING ABOUT IS
A MAJOR CONTRADICTION.
THE BRUTALITY
WITH WHICH THEY DID
THE KILLING IS SHOCKING.
WHAT...ONCE PEOPLE
HAD STEPPED BEYOND
THE FIRST STEP
OF ACTUALLY KILLING--
THROWING A CHILD DOWN
AND HACKING THEM
TO DEATH,
OPENING THE WOMB
OF PREGNANT--
THERE'S NOTHING THAT WAS
IF--THAT HE COULDN'T DO
BECAUSE THEY WERE BEING
TOLD BY THE PETITIONS
WHO WERE GIVING THEM
THE ALCOHOL
THAT "IF YOU DON'T
DESTROY THESE PEOPLE,
THESE ANIMALS, THESE--
THEY'RE COMING
TO FINISH YOU. NONE
OF YOU WILL SURVIVE."
AND THEY HAD BEEN MADE
TO BELIEVE IT.
I DON'T WANT TO BE
A--TO GIVE AN EXCUSE
FOR THEM.
THEY ARE WILLING
KILLERS. THERE'S
NO DOUBT IN MY MIND.
BUT, SEE, AT THE BACK
OF THEIR MIND, THE RADIO
IS TELLING THEM,
"THEY'RE COMING
TO FINISH YOU.
"IF YOU DON'T KILL THEM
YOURSELVES,
THEIR PLAN...
IS TO FINISH YOU."
Goldhagen: IN MASSACHUSETTS,
I LIVE JUST A FEW MILES
FROM A LARGE COMMUNITY
OF CAMBODIAN AMERICANS.
MANY OF THEM ARE SURVIVORS
OF THE GENOCIDE THAT TOOK
THE LIVES
OF 20% OF CAMBODIA'S POPULATION
DURING THE 1970s--
ONE IN 5 CAMBODIANS.
[MEN SINGING IN NATIVE LANGUAGE]
Goldhagen:
IT IS A CHILLING STATISTIC.
IN THE SPRING OF 1975,
A COMMUNIST REBEL GROUP,
THE KHMER ROUGE, CONQUERED
THE COUNTRY.
THEY WANTED TO TURN CAMBODIA
INTO A MARXIST AGRARIAN UTOPIA,
WHICH, TO THEM, MEANT DESTROYING
VIRTUALLY ALL VESTIGES
OF MODERN CIVILIZATION.
Man: FIRST DAY WHEN
THEY MARCH INTO THE CITY,
AND WE'RE SO HAPPY
THAT THE WAR IS ENDED.
WE WERE JOYFUL AND WE SAW
THE SOLDIER CAME,
THE PEACE COME,
AND NO MORE FIGHTING,
NO MORE WAR,
AND THEN SUDDENLY
EVERYTHING JUST DISAPPEARED.
I SAW A LOT OF SOLDIERS
IN BLACK UNIFORMS CLOSE
TO MY HOME.
[WHISTLE BLOWS]
THESE SOLDIERS SPRAYED
EVERYWHERE, SHOOTING GUNS
IN THE AIR
AND ASK, "LET'S GO, LET'S GO."
[DISTANT MACHINE GUNFIRE]
Goldhagen: WITHIN 3 DAYS,
KHMER ROUGE CADRES EMPTIED
CAMBODIA'S CITIES,
FORCING MILLIONS
INTO THE RURAL CAMPS
THEY CALLED COOPERATIVES,
BUT WHICH CAME TO BE KNOWN
TO THE OUTSIDE WORLD
AS THE KILLING FIELDS.
Uong: THINK OVER TWO MILE
PER DAY, 3 MILE PER DAY
THAT WE COULDN'T MOVE
BECAUSE OF SO MANY PEOPLE.
AND ALONG THE ROAD ARE BODIES
ALONG THE ROAD EVERYWHERE.
THEY JUST--
THE SCENE IS JUST AWFUL.
Goldhagen: THE EXTENT
OF THEIR VIOLENT TRANSFORMATION
OF CAMBODIAN SOCIETY
STILL BOGGLES THE MIND.
AND IT WAS ALL BEGUN
BY ONE MAN, KNOWN AS POL POT,
SUPPORTED BY
A SMALL INNER CIRCLE.
GENOCIDE IS ALWAYS
THE DECISION OF ONE LEADER
OR A SMALL GROUP
OF LEADERS.
THESE INDIVIDUALS MAKE A CHOICE
TO INITIATE THE KILLING,
WHICH, IN EVERY CASE, MEANS
THEY COULD HAVE ALSO
CHOSEN NOT TO.
THE LEADERS' GOALS VARY,
DEPENDING ON THE TIME,
PLACE, AND CIRCUMSTANCES:
POL POT WANTED TO RADICALLY
TRANSFORM CAMBODIAN SOCIETY;
THE TURKISH LEADER MEHMED TALAAT
WANTED TO SECURE TURKEY'S
DECAYING EMPIRE;
ADOLF HITLER WANTED TO CREATE
A VAST POLITICAL EMPIRE
RULED BY THE GERMAN MASTER RACE;
COLONEL THEONISTE BAGOSORA
AND HIS FELLOW HUTU LEADERS
WANTED TO SECURE POLITICAL POWER
IN RWANDA FOR THE HUTU;
AND IN THE BALKANS,
SLOBODAN MILOSEVIC
WANTED TO PERMANENTLY REDRAW
THE POLITICAL MAP OF THE REGION.
GENOCIDE IS ALWAYS
POLITICS.
OF COURSE, THERE ARE
POLITICAL GOALS.
THOSE POLITICAL GOALS
CAN BE REACHED
IN DIFFERENT WAYS.
SOME PEOPLE THINK THAT
EXTERMINATING A GROUP
WILL HELP THEIR GOALS,
SO THAT'S WHY
THEY DO IT.
SLOBODAN MILOSEVIC
THOUGHT AT THAT TIME,
THAT HE COULD, BECAUSE
OF THE OVERWHELMING
MILITARY POWER,
MAKE SOME TERRITORIAL
GAINS IN CROATIA AND
BOSNIA, SO HE ATTACKED.
[MEN SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
Silajdzic:
THE FULFILLING
OF THEIR MISSION...
[EXPLOSION]
WAS...TO MAKE A GREATER SERBIA.
IN ORDER TO MAKE GREATER SERBIA,
YOU HAD TO EXTERMINATE
PEOPLE IN YOUR WAY.
Man: SERBIA'S RIGHT THERE
ACROSS THE DRINA RIVER,
AND LOTS OF SERB-CONTROLLED
TERRITORY IN THE CENTRAL PART
OF THE COUNTRY,
THEY WANTED TO LINK
THOSE TWO ZONES, RIGHT?
BUT IF YOU HAD LARGE--
A SIGNIFICANT NUMBER OF MUSLIMS
ALONG THE WESTERN BANKS
OF THAT RIVER,
YOU HAD A KIND OF BARRIER
BETWEEN THOSE TWO SERBIAN AREAS,
SO THESE PEOPLE HAD
TO BE ELIMINATED.
Silajdzic: THESE THINGS
ARE DONE IN COLD BLOOD.
THIS IS A DESIGN.
THIS IS A PLAN.
THIS IS A CALCULATION,
OF COURSE.
THIS IS NOT A REACTION
TO SOMETHING.
THIS IS--THIS,
UNFORTUNATELY, HERE IS
A PLANNED GENOCIDE,
AS IS ANY OTHER GENOCIDE
BECAUSE IT'S NOT
POSSIBLE TO KILL
A BIG NUMBER OF PEOPLE
WITHOUT
PRIOR PREPARATION:
MENTAL PREPARATION,
INTELLECTUAL
PREPARATION,
MILITARY PREPARATION.
Goldhagen:
PRESIDENT SILAJDZIC IS RIGHT.
THERE'S A MISCONCEPTION
THAT GENOCIDES ERUPT
SPONTANEOUSLY
OUT OF DEEP-SEATED PASSIONS
OR ETHNIC CONFLICTS.
BUT THERE IS NOTHING SPONTANEOUS
ABOUT GENOCIDE.
IN THIS VILLA IN
THE SUBURBS OF BERLIN,
THE NAZI LEADERSHIP DISCUSSED
THEIR DETAILED PLANS
TO EXTERMINATE THE JEWS
OF EUROPE.
THESE TYPEWRITTEN MINUTES
DOCUMENT THE MEETING
AND LIST COUNTRY BY COUNTRY
THE 11 MILLION JEWS
THEY PLAN TO KILL.
ONE OF THOSE WAS
ERICH GOLDHAGEN,
THE 10-YEAR-OLD BOY
IN WHAT WAS THEN ROMANIA,
NOW UKRAINE,
WHO WOULD GROW UP
TO BECOME MY FATHER.
THE NAZI VICTORY
WOULD HAVE BEEN
TANTAMOUNT, EVEN WORSE,
THAN--IT WOULD BE LIKE
A NUCLEAR WAR, ALMOST.
THE DESTRUCTION
WOULD BE...
MM-HMM.
IT IS PERHAPS EASIER
TO RECOVER FROM
A NUCLEAR ASSAULT
THAN IT WOULD BE
FROM A NAZI VICTORY.
Goldhagen: I'VE ASKED HIM
TO JOIN ME ON PART OF
MY JOURNEY
TO RETURN TO WHERE HE LIVED
DURING THE HOLOCAUST.
SO HAVE YOU TALKED
TO MOM ABOUT OUR TRIP
TO CZERNOWITZ?
YES.
SHE IS VERY
ENTHUSIASTIC ABOUT IT. SHE
ENCOURAGES ME TO GO.
YOU KNOW, MOM IS ALWAYS SOMEONE
IN BELIEVING--
SHE BELIEVES
THAT THE PAST HAS TO BE
PRESERVED AND REMEMBERED,
AND SHE HAS
HELPED ME OVERCOME MY
NATURAL RELUCTANCE TO GO.
YOU KNOW,
WHEN I TOLD HER THAT
SHE HAD TO WORK ON YOU,
SHE SAID SHE NEVER WORKS
ON YOU. HA HA!
BUT I KNEW I HAD
AN ALLY.
IN A VERY SUBTLE WAY,
YOU KNOW, SHE WORKS ON ME.
ALL YOU HAVE TO DO IS
TO ENVISION
WHAT WOULD HAVE HAPPENED
IF HITLER HAD WON THE WAR.
THERE WOULD BE
MASS GRAVES EVERYWHERE,
VAST CONCENTRATION CAMPS,
AND WHAT I CALL
IN GREEK A NECROPOLIS,
A CITY OF DEATH.
AND EVEN GERMANY ITSELF
WOULD HAVE BEEN TRANSFORMED,
BUT MOST GERMANS
UNDERSTAND THIS,
THAT HITLER WOULD HAVE
DONE TO GERMANY THINGS
WHICH EVEN THE WORST ENEMY
OF GERMANY WOULDN'T HAVE DONE.
HE WOULD HAVE DESTROYED
THE CHRISTIAN CHURCHES,
DESTROYED THE CHURCHES,
KILLED THE INSANE,
AND ABOVE ALL, AND THIS IS
THE IMPORTANT POINT,
HE WOULD HAVE CONVERTED
THE YOUNGER GENERATION
INTO A RACE OF BARBARIANS.
Goldhagen: THERE IS
A WIDELY HELD MISCONCEPTION
THAT THE GERMANS' EFFICIENCY
AND TECHNOLOGY--
THE TRAINS
AND THE GAS CHAMBERS--
MADE IT POSSIBLE FOR THEM
TO KILL SO MANY SO QUICKLY.
AS WE'VE SEEN IN RWANDA
AND ELSEWHERE,
LEADERS DO NOT NEED
SOPHISTICATED TECHNOLOGY
TO KILL ON A VAST SCALE.
[MEN SHOUTING
IN NATIVE LANGUAGE]
IT IS THE WILL,
AND NOT THE WAY,
THAT IS CRITICAL.
[MEN SINGING]
IN RWANDA, THE HUTU LEADERS DID
WHAT ALL GENOCIDAL LEADERS DO.
THEY TAPPED INTO THE PREJUDICES
AND BELIEFS THAT PEOPLE
ALREADY HELD.
GENERATIONS OF HUTU HAD
GROWN UP BEING TAUGHT
THAT THE TUTSI ARE
DANGEROUS AND INHUMAN.
[RADIO STATIC]
[MAN SPEAKING NATIVE LANGUAGE]
[MEN SINGING
IN NATIVE LANGUAGE]
Goldhagen: IT WAS EASY
TO MOBILIZE HUTU FOR
THE KILLING.
[MAN SHOUTS IN BOSNIAN]
Silajdzic: IN BOSNIA,
THERE WAS DELIBERATELY
A PARANOID CULTURE
CREATED PRIOR
TO THE WAR,
ABOUT 5 OR 6, 7 YEARS.
THERE WAS
A PROPAGANDA OF...
THE SERBS
BEING THREATENED
BY EVERYBODY ELSE.
AND I KNOW PEOPLE
WHO, BECAUSE OF
THIS PROPAGANDA,
GOOD PEOPLE,
WHO GENUINELY BELIEVED
THAT THEY ARE
SOMEHOW THREATENED,
SO THEY HAVE TO ATTACK
IN ORDER TO DEFEND
THEMSELVES.
[CROWD CHANTS]
Goldhagen:
AS HUTU LEADERS DID IN RWANDA,
THE SERB LEADER,
SLOBODAN MILOSEVIC,
PLAYED ON BELIEFS
HIS FOLLOWERS ALREADY HELD.
HIS RALLYING CRY WAS ONE
THAT MOST SERBS WOULD
EASILY EMBRACE:
UNDER HIS LEADERSHIP,
SERBS WOULD RECLAIM THE LAND
THAT THEY BELIEVED WERE
HISTORICALLY THEIRS,
INCLUDING THE PREDOMINANTLY
MUSLIM COUNTRY OF
BOSNIA HERZEGOVINA.
HE EXPLOITED CENTURIES-OLD
ANIMOSITIES TOWARD MUSLIMS,
WHOM THE CHRISTIAN SERBS SAW
AS THEIR ETERNAL ENEMIES.
WHAT THEY'RE BEING TOLD
ABOUT BOSNIA'S--
ABOUT MUSLIMS,
THEY ARE A THREAT TO THEM.
WHY DOES THIS
MAKE SENSE TO THEM?
BECAUSE
IT'S IN HARMONY WITH
THE NATIONALIST MYTH
THAT MANY OF THEM
HAVE BEEN FED
FOR GENERATIONS,
AND THE LABELINGS
OF THE VICTIMS
THAT THEY VIOLATED
DURING THIS ACTIVITY
FIT THAT MYTH.
[CROWD CHANTING]
Goldhagen: WHEN THOSE HARBORING
POWERFUL HATREDS FINALLY ARE
GIVEN THE CHANCE TO KILL,
THEIR EUPHORIA IS UNMISTAKABLE.
[WHISTLE BLOWING]
Goldhagen: IN BOSNIA,
THE SERBS' PLAN WAS
COMPREHENSIVE.
IT WAS DESCRIBED WIDELY
AS ETHNIC CLEANSING,
A EUPHEMISM THAT TRIVIALIZES
THEIR BRUTAL ACTS.
THEY ROUNDED UP MUSLIM MEN
AND PUT THEM
IN CONCENTRATION CAMPS
OR MURDERED THEM OUTRIGHT.
THEY EXPELLED FAMILIES
FROM THEIR HOMES
AND FROM REGIONS
WHICH THEY WANTED
EXCLUSIVELY FOR SERBS.
AND IN THE CAPITAL CITY,
SARAJEVO,
THEY ATTACKED
THE CIVILIAN POPULATION
FROM THE SURROUNDING HILLS.
[GUNFIRE]
[EXPLOSION]
[SIREN]
Man: THE BOSNIAN SERBS FIRED
12 MORTAR AND ARTILLERY ROUNDS
LAST NIGHT
INTO A PART OF THE CITY
CROWDED WITH YOUNG PEOPLE.
[GUNFIRE]
Sudetic:
THE SNIPING ACTIVITY
HERE WAS NOTORIOUS.
PEOPLE WALKING DOWN
THE STREET WERE
HUNTED LIKE ANIMALS.
SO WHAT WOULD HAVE
HAPPENED TO US
IF WE HAD BEEN HERE?
WE WOULD HAVE BEEN SHOT
FROM THOSE BUILDINGS
OVER THERE.
THAT FAR AWAY?
I MEAN, THE ROOF--
NO, THAT'S NOT FAR AT ALL.
I MEAN, A SNIPER
COULD HAVE HIT US
RIGHT HERE?
OH, YEAH, YEAH.
DEFINITELY.
IT'S NOT
A HARD SHOT FROM--
FOR A TRAINED SNIPER.
AND THESE WERE
TRAINED PEOPLE.
THEY WERE NOT, UH,
THEY WERE NOT YAHOOS
WITH 12-GAUGES.
[GUNSHOT]
THESE WERE HIGH-POWERED
HUNTING RIFLES.
THEY USED HIGH-POWERED
SNIPER RIFLES
WITH VERY SOPHISTICATED
SIGHT EQUIPMENT ON THEM.
AND IT'S--
YOU'D BE BANGED
WITH A HEAD SHOT.
[GUNSHOT]
YOU COULD WALK
ACROSS THIS STREET
IN BROAD DAYLIGHT
AND NOTHING WOULD
HAPPEN, BUT THEN--
[MACHINE GUNFIRE]
LIKE BAGGING PREY.
WERE THEY JUST AS LIKELY
TO SHOOT WOMEN?
YES.
AND CHILDREN?
YEAH.
SO IT HAD NOTHING
TO DO WITH YOU BEING
A SOLDIER, PER SE.
NO.
SO WHAT WAS--
I MEAN, WHAT WAS
THE FUNCTION?
I MEAN, WHY WERE
THEY
DOING THIS?
TERROR.
[EXPLOSION, GUNFIRE]
GET RID
OF THE MUSLIMS.
YEAH.
AND SO
TERRORIZE THEM,
KILL AS MANY
AS POSSIBLE--
YES.
PUSH AS MANY OF THEM INTO
AS SMALL AN AREA AS POSSIBLE
SO THEY COULD TAKE THE REST.
THEY KNEW EVERYTHING.
THEY PREPARE EVERYTHING.
IT WAS REALLY ACTUALLY
PLANNED AND SYSTEMATIC.
ACTUALLY SYSTEMATICALLY
PLANNED, THE WAR,
OF ACTUALLY ESTABLISHING
CONCENTRATION CAMPS,
KILLING, RAPING, EVERYTHING.
RAPING'S ONE
OF THE WORST CRIMES.
IT NOT ONLY HUMILIATES
THE PERSON,
IT DESTROYS THE FAMILY.
MM-HMM.
THERE IS SO MANY CASES
OF UNWANTED CHILDREN.
THE MOTHER DOESN'T
RECOGNIZE HER SON
OR DAUGHTER
THAT CAME
FROM THESE RAPINGS.
Goldhagen: THE SERBS' WIDESPREAD
RAPING OF BOSNIAN WOMEN
WAS NOT THE KIND OF THING,
AS MANY THINK,
THAT HAPPENS INEVITABLY
IN WAR ZONES.
Muratcaus: THEY DID
NOTHING, ACTUALLY...
Goldhagen, voice-over:
LIKE KILLING,
THE SERBS USE RAPE
AND RAPE CAMPS AS
AN INTEGRAL COMPONENT
OF THEIR CAMPAIGN
TO RID THE COUNTRY OF
ITS MUSLIM POPULATION.
Muratcaus:
WE WILL NEVER FIND OUT
HOW MANY WOMEN WERE RAPED
ALL OVER BOSNIA.
THEY ACTUALLY POSED US
IN SOME BIG ROOMS
WITH MAYBE 14 BEDS.
THEY ARE YELLING AT US,
"YOU WILL HAVE SERBIAN BABIES,
SERBIAN CHILDREN."
THEY WERE BEATEN,
HORRIBLY BEATEN
WITH FACE, WITH, ACTUALLY,
THEIR LEGS AND...
HORRIBLE.
[COMPUTER KEYBOARD KEYS TAPPING]
THERE'S A LOT
TO MAKE SENSE OF HERE.
IT SEEMS TO ME WE'VE BEEN
MISSING A CRITICAL POINT
IN UNDERSTANDING THESE HORRORS.
THE MASTERMINDS OF GENOCIDE
USE DIFFERENT MEANS
IN VARYING COMBINATIONS
TO GET RID OF UNWANTED PEOPLE.
THEY EXPEL VICTIMS
FROM THEIR COUNTRIES,
THEY HERD THEM INTO CAMPS,
THEY RAPE WOMEN
IN AN ORGANIZED WAY,
AND OF COURSE,
THEY SYSTEMATICALLY SLAUGHTER.
[COMPUTER KEYBOARD KEYS TAPPING]
SO WHAT WE OFTEN THINK OF
AS GENOCIDE IS NEVER JUST
ABOUT KILLING.
WHAT THE PERPETRATORS WANT
MOST OF ALL
IS TO ELIMINATE
A SUBSTANTIAL PART OR ALL
OF THE TARGETED GROUP.
TERMS LIKE "GENOCIDE"
OR EVEN "MASS MURDER"
ARE INADEQUATE TO DESCRIBE
THE PHENOMENON WE HAVE
REPEATEDLY WITNESSED.
AS A POLITICAL SCIENTIST,
I LIVE AND WORK IN A WORLD
OF ISMS.
THIS ONE WE SHOULD CALL
ELIMINATIONISM.
REFRAMING THE WAY WE THINK
ABOUT THESE DEEDS IS NOT JUST
AN INTELLECTUAL EXERCISE.
IT'S A CRITICAL COMPONENT
OF UNDERSTANDING
THAT GENOCIDE IS ONE PART
OF A LARGER PHENOMENON
THAT WE MUST COMBAT.
WE NEED TO BE ON ALERT
WHEN WE SEE ANY FORM OF
ELIMINATIONIST POLITICS,
WHETHER IT INITIALLY
INCLUDES KILLING OR NOT.
EVERYWHERE IT IS PRACTICED,
ELIMINATIONISM TAKES
DIFFERENT FORMS.
RWANDA WAS DIFFERENT
FROM BOSNIA,
CAMBODIA WAS
DIFFERENT FROM TURKEY.
THE GERMANS' ASSAULT ON THE JEWS
WAS ALSO DIFFERENT.
IT WAS THE ONLY CASE
WHEN PERPETRATORS TARGETED
EVERY ADULT AND CHILD,
WITHOUT EXCEPTION,
FOR ANNIHILATION,
AND WHERE THAT MURDEROUS POLICY
EXTENDED TO COUNTRY
AFTER COUNTRY,
INCLUDING JEWS
HALF A CONTINENT AWAY.
Goldhagen: SO IT'S
64 YEARS SINCE YOU'VE
BEEN BACK, RIGHT?
YES, THAT'S RIGHT, YES.
AND--
AND I FEEL THE SADNESS
AS I COME BACK
TO THIS PLACE
WHERE I WAS
ALMOST KILLED,
WHERE A GREAT PART OF
MY FAMILY LIES BURIED.
HAD YOU--HAD YOU EVER--
HAD YOU PLANNED ONE DAY
TO COME BACK ON YOUR OWN?
NO, NEVER.
REALLY NOT.
UH, I PROBABLY WOULD
HAVE NEVER COME BACK
HAD IT NOT BEEN
THAT YOU WERE MAKING
THIS FILM.
SO ARE YOU A RELUCTANT,
IF WILLING, PARTICIPANT?
AN AMBIVALENT
PARTICIPANT,
I WOULD SAY.
Goldhagen: THE JEWS IN
THE REGION WHERE MY FATHER LIVED
WERE KILLED, IN MOST CASES,
BY THE EINSATZGRUPPEN--
MOBILE KILLING SQUADS CHARGED
WITH EXTERMINATING EVERY JEW
IN THE SOVIET TERRITORY
CONQUERED BY THE GERMANS.
THEY KILLED
WITH BRUTAL ABANDON.
Goldhagen: IS THERE ANY--
IS THERE A POSITIVE SIDE
FOR YOU TO GO BACK?
SHOWING ME THE PLACES
YOU WERE--
YES, SHOWING YOU
THE PLACES
BECAUSE YOU HAVE BEEN
SORT OF AN ACADEMIC,
VERY SECLUDED,
NEVER...
FOR THE FIRST TIME--
YOU HAVE STUDIED
THIS PHENOMENON
FROM A DISTANCE,
THROUGH DOCUMENT.
COME NOW, YOU HAVE SEEN
THE MASS GRAVES
IN GUATEMALA.
AND YOU CERTAINLY
SHOULD HAVE A LOOK
AT THE MASS GRAVE
OF SOME OF
YOUR RELATIVES,
GRAVE OF MY PARENTS.
Goldhagen: THERE WERE 2,000 JEWS
IN THIS TOWN WHEN MY FATHER USED
TO VISIT HIS RELATIVES HERE.
NOW THERE ARE 3.
MOST LIE IN A MASS GRAVE
NEAR WHAT IS NOW
A POPULAR PICNIC SITE.
[BOYS SHOUTING]
[SPEAKING
NATIVE LANGUAGE]
Goldhagen: LIKE MY FATHER,
I HAVE ALWAYS ENDEAVORED
TO SEPARATE MY EMOTIONS
FROM MY SCHOLARLY WORK
ON GENOCIDE.
BUT HERE WE ARE, AT A MOMENT
THAT I NEVER IMAGINED.
A LOCAL MAN HAS AGREED
TO GUIDE US TO THE SITE
WHERE GERMANS MURDERED
MY FATHER'S RELATIVES
AND 2,000 OTHERS.
I SEE, I SEE.
OH, HERE
WE CAN GO CLOSE.
Goldhagen: THE SCHOLAR'S JOB IS
TO STAND BACK AND ANALYZE,
BUT THE SURVIVOR AND THE SON
HAVE NO CHOICE BUT TO DRAW NEAR.
"TO THE ETERNAL MEMORY
OF THE JEWS OF KOSOV..."
"WHO WERE MURDERED
"BY THE NAZI MURDERERS
AND THEIR HELPERS."
SO...
HOW MANY...PEOPLE
FROM YOUR FAMILY
ARE LYING IN
THIS MASS GRAVE--
I WOULD ESTIMATE IT
OVER A DOZEN PEOPLE.
WERE YOU CLOSE
TO THEM?
I WAS VERY CLOSE TO THEM.
I VISITED THEM HERE,
AND IT EVOKES
SOME CERTAIN EMOTIONS.
THE IMAGES OF SOME,
OF ELDERS APPEAR BEFORE ME.
I SEE THEM NOW.
AS I SPEAK TO YOU
NOW, I SEE THEM.
SOMETIMES--AS YOU
MAY REMEMBER WHEN I
GAVE THE COURSE
ON THE HOLOCAUST
AT HARVARD--
I EXPERIENCE SOMETIMES
A SENSE OF GUILT
AT THE FACT THAT
I SPEAK SO COOLLY
AND ANALYTICALLY
OVER THEIR DEATH.
I'M YOUR SON
IN MANY WAYS,
AND YOUR DISPASSION
IS MY OWN.
HOW--HOW DID
THEY DIE?
WHAT HAPPENED HERE?
WELL, THEY BROUGHT
THEM UP HERE
AND KILLED THEM
BY GUNFIRE.
ONE GROUP FELL
INTO THE GRAVE.
THEN ANOTHER GROUP
WAS LINED UP,
THEY FELL
INTO THE GRAVE.
WHEN THEY WERE SHOT?
WHEN THEY WERE SHOT
UNTIL--AND MANY
OF THEM WERE PROBABLY
NOT KILLED,
MANY OF THEM WERE
PROBABLY NOT DEAD.
THEY WERE ALIVE
AS THEY FELL
INTO THE GRAVE,
AND UKRAINIAN GROUPS
WERE MADE TO COVER
THE GRAVES.
YOU KNOW, AS WE'VE
OFTEN SPOKEN BEFORE,
IT'S SHOCKING TO ME
TO REFLECT ON HOW
DETACHED I AM, TOO,
FROM THIS,
THAT I DIDN'T
EVEN MAKE
THIS OBVIOUS
CONNECTION THAT
WE WERE GOING HERE
WHEN I WAS
IN A MASS GRAVE
IN GUATEMALA,
BUT NOW THAT
WE'RE HERE,
I REALIZE
THAT SUDDENLY
MY RELATIVES
MURDERED
SIT BELOW US,
LIE BELOW US
UNMARKED, UNKNOWN,
BARELY REGISTERED
IN ANY WAY,
THEIR NAMES ABSENT,
SOON TO BE FORGOTTEN
COMPLETELY.
SHOULD WE GET SOME
STONES, TATI?
PERHAPS WE BETTER
PUT THEM ON EACH.
[INDISTINCT CHATTER]
[DRUMS BEATING]
[SINGING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
Woman: WELL, CERTAINLY,
WE THOUGHT THAT WE WERE SAYING,
"NEVER AGAIN," BUT WE KEEP
SAYING, "NEVER AGAIN,"
OVER AND OVER
AND OVER AGAIN.
WELL, THERE ARE TWO
DIFFERENT ISSUES.
WHY DOES THIS KEEP
HAPPENING AGAIN,
AND WHY DOESN'T
ANYBODY DO ANYTHING
TO STOP IT FROM
HAPPENING AGAIN?
AND IT KEEPS
HAPPENING BECAUSE
THERE ARE POLITICAL
REGIMES THAT
FIND IT USEFUL
TO DEAL WITH THEIR
SELF-DEFINED
PROBLEMS,
AND IT'S
A VERY USEFUL TOOL.
THEY DO IT BECAUSE
THEY KNOW THEY HAVE
BASICALLY IMPUNITY,
AND THERE HAS BEEN
VERY LITTLE CALLING
TO ACCOUNT,
AND THEY GET AWAY
WITH IT TIME
AND TIME AGAIN.
SO QUITE CLEARLY,
THE STATUS QUO
IS CATASTROPHIC,
AND WHEN I SAY
CATASTROPHIC,
I MEAN LITERALLY
CATASTROPHIC
BECAUSE IT TAKES
THE LIVES OF TENS
OF THOUSANDS,
HUNDREDS
MILLIONS UPON
MILLIONS OF PEOPLE,
AND SO "NEVER AGAIN"
IS A HOLLOW PHRASE.
IT'S WELL-MEANT,
BUT IN THE WORLD
OF WHAT ACTUALLY
HAPPENS,
IT'S BEEN
A HOLLOW PHRASE,
A MOCKERY OF ITSELF.
THE INACTION OF WORLD LEADERS
IN THE FACE OF MASS SLAUGHTER
GOES BACK WELL
BEFORE THE HOLOCAUST,
AND GENOCIDAL LEADERS
HAVE TAKEN NOTE.
STARTING IN 1915,
THE TURKISH GOVERNMENT KILLED
AT LEAST A MILLION ARMENIANS
AND EXPELLED
HUNDREDS OF THOUSANDS MORE.
THE STORY
OF THE ARMENIAN GENOCIDE
WAS COVERED ON THE FRONT PAGE
OF THE "NEW YORK TIMES,"
AND TURKEY'S LEADERS WERE
EXPLICITLY WARNED
BY THE U.S. AND OTHERS
THAT THEIR NATION
WOULD BE CONDEMNED BY THE WORLD,
BUT THE MASTERMINDS
OF GENOCIDE WERE UNDETERRED.
THE TURKS BRAZENLY
DESTROYED COMMUNITIES,
KILLED, RAPED, AND DROVE
THE ARMENIAN PEOPLE
INTO THE DESERT,
WHERE THEY STARVED TO DEATH.
FOR A CENTURY,
TURKEY HAS REFUSED
TO ACKNOWLEDGE THE GENOCIDE,
AND REMARKABLY,
MANY AROUND THE WORLD,
INCLUDING THE U.S. GOVERNMENT,
HAVE ALLOWED THEM TO DO SO.
Man:
THE ARMENIAN GENOCIDE
IS THE ONLY GENOCIDE
THAT WE HAVE TROUBLE
RECOGNIZING,
AND IT'S BECAUSE
THE CAMPAIGN OF DENIAL
CONTINUES TO THIS DAY.
Woman: OUR GOVERNMENT IS
FLAT OUT WRONG
IN THEIR REFUSAL TO RECOGNIZE
THE ARMENIAN GENOCIDE.
WE MUST CALL GENOCIDE
BY ITS NAME.
Schiff: WE CAN'T
HAVE THE KIND
OF LEADERSHIP
THAT WE NEED
IN STOPPING GENOCIDE
GOING ON TODAY
IF WE'RE EQUIVOCAL
ABOUT THE MURDER
OF OTHER PEOPLE
BECAUSE IT MIGHT
OFFEND AN ALLY.
I SHOULD THINK THAT
IT WOULD BE A NO-BRAINER
THAT A RESOLUTION BE PASSED
TO ACKNOWLEDGE THIS.
WHAT'S THE PROBLEM?
WELL, IT SHOULD BE
A NO-BRAINER.
AS IT IS, IT'S
AN ENORMOUSLY
DIFFICULT CHALLENGE.
WHEN THE GENOCIDE
RESOLUTION WAS IN
COMMITTEE LAST FALL,
THE PRESIDENT
OF THE UNITED STATES
WAS ON THE PHONE,
CALLING COMMITTEE
MEMBERS AT THEIR HOME
TO URGE THEM TO VOTE
AGAINST IT.
FOR THIS RESOLUTION?
FOR THIS RESOLUTION.
WE ALL DEEPLY REGRET
THE TRAGIC SUFFERING
OF THE ARMENIAN PEOPLE
THAT BEGAN IN 1915.
THIS RESOLUTION IS NOT
THE RIGHT RESPONSE
TO THESE HISTORIC MASS KILLINGS.
THE PROBLEM THAT WE HAVE
IS THAT THIS IS CLEARLY
A VERY SENSITIVE SUBJECT
FOR ONE OF OUR CLOSEST ALLIES.
YOU HAD MEMBERS
OF THE JOINT CHIEFS OF
STAFF CALLING MEMBERS,
YOU HAD
THE SECRETARY OF
STATE CALLING MEMBERS.
I'VE NEVER SEEN
A FULL-COURT PRESS LIKE
THIS ON ANY RESOLUTION.
I DON'T THINK
WE STRENGTHEN
OUR RELATIONSHIP
EVEN WITH AN ALLY
WHEN WE TURN A BLIND EYE
TO SOME
OF THE WORST CHAPTERS
IN HUMAN HISTORY.
Goldhagen: OUR POLITICIANS
MAY FAIL TO LEARN FROM HISTORY,
BUT THERE IS AMPLE EVIDENCE
THAT MASS MURDERERS
HAVE LEARNED QUITE WELL.
Man: SUDANESE PRESIDENT
OMAR AL-BASHIR
HAS BEEN ACCUSED
OF MASTERMINDING
A CAMPAIGN
OF GENOCIDE IN DARFUR.
Goldhagen: 20 YEARS BEFORE
THE RECENT CRISIS IN DARFUR,
THE SAME SUDANESE GOVERNMENT
KILLED AND EXPELLED
EVEN MORE PEOPLE
IN SOUTHERN SUDAN.
AFTER KILLING TWO MILLION THEN,
THE SUDANESE LEADER
OMAR AL-BASHIR LEARNED
THAT THE INTERNATIONAL COMMUNITY
WOULD LET HIM DO IT AGAIN.
WHY DOES THE INTERNATIONAL
COMMUNITY FAIL TO INTERVENE
TIME AND TIME AGAIN?
JUST TELL ME.
Madeleine Albright:
AS OUR REPORT EMPHASIZES,
THE CHOICE WE FACE IN TRYING
TO PREVENT GENOCIDE
IS RARELY A CASE
OF ALL OR NOTHING.
THERE IS A BROAD RANGE
OF FOREIGN POLICY OPTIONS
BETWEEN STANDING ASIDE
AND ORDERING IN THE MARINES.
Goldhagen: THE CO-CHAIR
OF A RECENT TASK FORCE
ON THE SUBJECT,
FORMER SECRETARY OF STATE
MADELEINE ALBRIGHT
SERVED AS U.S. AMBASSADOR
TO THE UNITED NATIONS
DURING THE BOSNIAN
AND RWANDAN GENOCIDES.
[ELEVATOR PINGING]
Goldhagen: YOU KNOW,
IF ONE IS SIMPLY NAIVE,
ONE SEES A WORLD
OF POWERFUL COUNTRIES
USUALLY LOOKING ON
WITH SOME INEPTITUDE
AT BEST AT COUNTRIES
THAT ARE POOR
AND NOT VERY POWERFUL
IN WHICH THEIR LEADERSHIP
IS SLAUGHTERING PEOPLE,
AND YOU WONDER
HOW CAN THIS BE?
IF YOU GO TO PEOPLE
AND YOU SAY,
"YOU CAN PREVENT
MASS MURDER,"
THEN MOST PEOPLE
WILL THINK,
"OK. I'LL DO
THE BEST I CAN."
THE PROBLEM IS
THAT WORLD LEADERS
OR LEADERS GENERALLY
ARE DISTRACTED.
THERE'S SO MUCH
TO DO.
IT ISN'T AS IF
THEY'RE NOT
DOING ANYTHING.
THERE'S NO WAY
TO DESCRIBE
TO SOMEONE
THAT HAS NEVER BEEN
IN THE U.S. GOVERNMENT
OR ANY GOVERNMENT
HOW MANY THINGS ARE
HAPPENING EVERY HOUR
AND REQUIRE ATTENTION
AND REQUIRE WILL
AND REQUIRE RESOURCES.
THE QUESTION
IS WHETHER YOUR
GOVERNMENTAL SYSTEM
IS SET UP IN A WAY
THAT YOU DON'T HAVE TO
START FROM SCRATCH.
WE CAN TALK
ABOUT RWANDA,
WHERE THERE WERE MANY
DIFFERENT PLAYERS INVOLVED
AND PEOPLE HAD
DIFFERENT DEGREES
OF KNOWLEDGE
AT DIFFERENT TIMES
ABOUT WHAT WAS GOING ON.
IT SEEMS THAT THERE WAS
A CLEAR LACK OF WILL--
NOT GOODWILL IN THE SENSE
OF COURSE PEOPLE DIDN'T WANT
THE PEOPLE THERE
TO BE SLAUGHTERED,
BUT WILL ACTUALLY
TO TAKE THE SACRIFICE
OR MAKE THE SACRIFICE
THAT WAS NECESSARY
SEE, I DISAGREE
WITH YOU.
THE BELGIANS PULLED OUT,
DALLAIRE WAS--
YOU KNOW THE STORY.
DALLAIRE WAS
CRYING OUT
FOR MORE SUPPORT.
MAYBE NOT EVERYONE
COULD HAVE BEEN SAVED,
BUT A LOT OF PEOPLE
COULD HAVE BEEN SAVED.
I MEAN, THIS IS
AN ISSUE THAT WEIGHS
VERY HEAVY
ON ALL OUR HEARTS.
WE WERE AT THE SAME
TIME DEALING
WITH SOMALIA,
BOSNIA, HAITI,
A FEW OTHER THINGS
THAT WERE GOING ON,
AND I THINK THAT
PEOPLE DID NOT
FULLY UNDERSTAND
ALL THE HUTU-TUTSI
RIVALRY
AND THE INTERNAL
THINGS THAT WERE
BUILDING UP.
THAT, I THINK, WAS
SOMETHING THAT HAD
NOT BEEN PAID
ENOUGH ATTENTION TO.
IT IS MUCH EASIER
EX POST FACTO
TO SAY WE KNEW THESE
KINDS OF THINGS
WERE GOING ON,
BUT AT THE TIME
I WAS AMBASSADOR AT
THE UNITED NATIONS,
AND I CAN TELL YOU
THAT THE INFORMATION
WAS NOT THERE.
Goldhagen: I DON'T KNOW
WHAT KIND OF INFORMATION
ALBRIGHT NEEDED,
BUT EVEN MORE THAN
DURING THE ARMENIAN GENOCIDE,
INFORMATION
ABOUT THE RWANDAN GENOCIDE
WAS AVAILABLE TO ANYONE
WITH ACCESS TO TV OR NEWSPAPER,
AS THERE WERE MULTIPLE
SOURCES OF INFORMATION
COMING STRAIGHT FROM RWANDA,
WHERE EVERYONE KNEW.
AS SOON AS THE KILLING BEGAN,
MANY TUTSI,
INCLUDING EMMANUEL GATARI,
MADE THEIR WAY
TO A TECHNICAL SCHOOL,
WHICH WAS BEING PROTECTED
BY U.N. PEACEKEEPERS.
AS THE LIVES OF EMMANUEL
AND THE OTHERS WITH HIM
HUNG IN THE BALANCE,
THE U.S. AND OTHER
FOREIGN GOVERNMENTS
BEGAN TO EVACUATE
THEIR CITIZENS FROM RWANDA.
[EMMANUEL SPEAKING
NATIVE LANGUAGE]
[MACHINEGUNS FIRING]
Karugarama: AND THERE WERE SO
MANY PEOPLE HAD RUN TO THE U.N.
FOR SECURITY, FOR PROTECTION,
AND THEY WITHDREW
AND LEFT THEM THERE
TO BE MASSACRED
IN COLD BLOOD.
THIS IS REALLY SOMETHING
THAT THE U.N.
SHOULD BE ABLE TO EXPLAIN.
HOW DO YOU WITHDRAW PEOPLE WHO
ARE SUPPOSED TO PROTECT PEOPLE
AT A TIME THAT IS
SO CRITICAL,
AT A TIME WHEN YOU SEE
THE KILLINGS HAD
ALREADY STARTED?
Goldhagen: A LACK OF INFORMATION
IS NOT THE REASON
WORLD LEADERS FAIL TO INTERVENE
TO STOP GENOCIDES.
THE PROBLEM IS A LACK OF WILL.
FOR MORE THAN HALF A CENTURY,
PEOPLE AROUND THE WORLD
HAVE EXPECTED THE MEN AND WOMEN
HERE AT THE UNITED NATIONS
TO PROTECT THEM,
AND TIME AND AGAIN,
THE U.N. HAS LET
THOSE PEOPLE DOWN.
I LOOK AROUND AT THE MANY STATES
HERE THAT HAVE TERRORIZED,
OPPRESSED, AND ELIMINATED
THEIR OWN PEOPLE,
AND I THINK, "WHY WOULD ANYONE
LOOK TO THIS BODY
TO COMBAT THESE EVILS
AROUND THE WORLD?"
IN 1948,
THE UNITED NATIONS ADOPTED
AN ANTIGENOCIDE CONVENTION
THAT LEGALLY DEFINED GENOCIDE
AND AUTHORIZED ITS MEMBER STATES
TO STOP AND PUNISH ACTS
OF MASS MURDER.
THE DOCUMENT IS NOBLE-SOUNDING
BUT TOTALLY INEFFECTIVE.
IT HAS NEVER ONCE BEEN INVOKED
TO PREVENT THE DEATH
OF A SINGLE PERSON.
THERE'S A FUNDAMENTAL
PROBLEM HERE.
THE U.N. EXISTS LARGELY
TO PROTECT STATE SOVEREIGNTY,
A STATE'S RIGHT TO BE IMMUNE
FROM OTHER COUNTRIES
INTERVENING IN ITS
INTERNAL AFFAIRS.
SO HOW CAN WE EXPECT TO
ALSO PROMOTE INTERVENTION
WHEN A SOVEREIGN STATE
AND ITS PEOPLE
ARE ELIMINATING, KILLING,
RAPING, AND EXPELLING GROUPS
OF ITS OWN CITIZENS?
Man: I DON'T SEE
SOVEREIGNTY NEGATIVELY
AS A CONCEPT OF BARRICADING
YOURSELF AGAINST THE WORLD
WHILE YOUR PEOPLE
ARE SUFFERING.
I SEE IT
AS A POSITIVE CONCEPT
OF THE STATE DISCHARGING
ITS RESPONSIBILITIES
TOWARDS ITS OWN CITIZENS,
PROVIDING THEM
WITH PROTECTION
AND ASSISTANCE,
AND IF FOR LACK
OF CAPACITY,
YOU CANNOT DO IT,
CALL ON THE INTERNATIONAL
COMMUNITY TO COME
AND HELP YOU
DO WHAT IS YOUR
RESPONSIBILITY
IN THE FIRST PLACE.
YOU KNOW, I APPLAUD
WHAT YOU DO,
AND I AGREE,
AND I ALSO
VERY MUCH LIKE
RECONCEPTUALIZING
CONCEPTS THE WAY
YOU HAVE
WITH SOVEREIGNTY,
BUT YOU'RE
IN A MINORITY THERE,
AS YOU WELL KNOW...
ABSOLUTELY.
AND EVEN IN THIS
HALL IN PARTICULAR,
YOU WOULD BE
IN A MINORITY
IF YOU WERE TO
STAND UP AND TO GIVE
AND SPEECH HERE,
AND IT SEEMS TO ME
THAT SOVEREIGNTY
IS AN IMPORTANT
PRINCIPLE,
BUT WE SHOULD
MAKE CLEAR THAT IT
DOES NOT GO SO FAR
AS TO ALLOW
GOVERNMENTS TO
SLAUGHTER THEIR PEOPLE
AND THAT THAT IN ITSELF,
THOSE ACTS IN ITSELF
ABRIDGE SOVEREIGNTY.
AND IF YOU DO NOT DISCHARGE
YOUR RESPONSIBILITY
AND YOU DON'T
WELCOME HELP,
YOU HAVE NO WILL,
WE WILL TAKE
OTHER MEASURES.
AND THESE OTHER MEASURES
WE NEED TO DEVELOP
TO BE A CREDIBLE THREAT,
BUT MEANWHILE,
I'M JUST DOING WHAT IS
IN MY CAPACITY TO DO.
AND YOU'RE DOING
IT WELL.
Goldhagen, voice-over:
THERE ARE WELL-MEANING PEOPLE
HERE TO BE SURE,
BUT I'M AFRAID THEY'RE PART
OF AN INSTITUTION
THAT IS SET UP TO FAIL.
THE U.N. IS NOT THE SOLUTION,
AS ITS APPALLING RECORD SHOWS,
BUT I DO THINK WE CAN
DESIGN A SYSTEM
THAT WILL EFFECTIVELY STOP
OR PREVENT FUTURE GENOCIDES.
THE FIRST COMPONENT MUST BE
SWIFT DIPLOMATIC INTERVENTION.
A RECENT EPISODE HERE IN KENYA
MAY OFFER A PROMISING MODEL
FOR THE FUTURE.
Man: WHAT WAS ONCE ONE
OF AFRICA'S MOST
STABLE DEMOCRACIES
IS RIGHT NOW ONE OF THE MOST
VIOLENT PLACES IN THE WORLD.
EXTREME CHAOS FOLLOWING
A DISPUTED ELECTION IN KENYA,
MOBS TORCHING A CHURCH
WITH HUNDREDS
OF REFUGEES INSIDE.
WITNESSES SAY DOZENS OF PEOPLE,
INCLUDING CHILDREN,
WERE BURNED ALIVE OR HACKED
TO DEATH WITH MACHETES,
AND THERE ARE NEW FEARS TODAY
THAT KENYA IS IN DANGER
OF BECOMING THE NEXT RWANDA.
Goldhagen: IN JANUARY 2008,
A SPATE OF KILLINGS
FOLLOWED THE REELECTION
OF KENYAN PRESIDENT MWAI KIBAKI.
Man: CLEARLY, I THINK,
THE IMMEDIATE TRIGGER
FOR THAT VIOLENCE WAS
THE DISPUTED ELECTION
RESULTS THAT HAPPENED,
BUT BEYOND THAT, I THINK
THERE WERE ALSO
OTHER UNDERLYING ISSUES
THAT CAME TO THE FORE,
ISSUES OF DISCONTENTMENT,
ISSUES OF MARGINALIZATION,
RIFTS BETWEEN ETHNIC GROUPS
IN THE COUNTRY,
ISSUES OF LAND,
ISSUES OF HISTORICAL
INJUSTICES.
SO ALL THESE THINGS
CAME UP TOGETHER,
AND I THINK THAT
THE ELECTION RESULTS,
THE WAY IT WAS HANDLED,
THE PROCESS,
WAS REALLY LIKE THE MATCH
THAT WAS THROWN
INTO A BARREL OF OIL.
[SINGING IN NATIVE LANGUAGE]
Goldhagen: IN THE RIFT VALLEY,
MEMBERS OF THE PRESIDENT'S
TRIBE, THE KIKUYU,
WERE TARGETED.
1,500 OR MORE WERE KILLED,
HUNDREDS OF THOUSANDS
WERE EXPELLED FROM THEIR HOMES.
IF THE KIKUYU HAD
TRIED TO HOLD
THEIR GROUND,
WOULD THE VIOLENCE
HAVE ESCALATED
TO PRODUCE DEATHS
ON A MASSIVE SCALE?
ABSOLUTELY.
I THINK THE KILLINGS
WOULD HAVE
DEFINITELY INCREASED.
I THINK IT WOULD HAVE
DRAWN IN, ALSO,
MORE COMMUNITIES.
Goldhagen: WITHIN DAYS,
FORMER U.N. SECRETARY GENERAL
KOFI ANNAN HAD FLOWN TO NAIROBI
ALONG WITH REPRESENTATIVES
OF OTHER AFRICAN COUNTRIES.
I THINK IT IS IMPORTANT
THAT ALL KENYANS
RESPOND WITH SYMPATHY
AND UNDERSTANDING
AND NOT TRY TO REVENGE.
Goldhagen:
THE U.S. SECRETARY OF STATE
CONDOLEEZZA RICE ARRIVED
SOON AFTER.
THEY CAME TO MEDIATE,
TO PRESSURE,
AND WITH THREATS OF SANCTIONS.
Kiai: I DON'T THINK
I'VE EVER SEEN IN AFRICA
SUCH INTENSE
INTERNATIONAL ENGAGEMENT
ON AN ISSUE,
AND THAT REALLY HELPED.
Goldhagen: THE LONG-TERM EFFECTS
OF THE DIPLOMATIC INTERVENTION
IN KENYA REMAIN TO BE SEEN.
THE VIOLENCE STOPPED,
BUT THE RACISTS
AND POLITICAL ROOTS
OF THE CONFLICT RUN DEEP,
AND KENYAN POLITICAL LEADERS
COULD START UP
THE VIOLENCE AGAIN,
BUT THE IMMEDIATE RESPONSE
OF WORLD LEADERS
WAS A POWERFUL STATEMENT
AND THE KIND OF RAPID REACTION
THAT COULD SAVE MANY LIVES
IN THE FUTURE.
DIPLOMACY OF COURSE
DOES NOT ALWAYS WORK.
Christiane Amanpour:
THE U.N. IS ACCUSING
THE SUDANESE GOVERNMENT
OF RESUMING BOMBING RAIDS
AGAINST REBELS IN SOUTH DARFUR,
AND IT ALSO SAYS THAT
DISPLACED VILLAGERS LIKE THESE
ARE STILL BEING ATTACKED
BY JANJAWEED MILITIA.
Goldhagen: WHEN THE SUDANESE
GOVERNMENT WAS MURDERING
ITS OWN PEOPLE IN THE WESTERN
REGION OF DARFUR,
WORLD LEADERS SENT ENVOYS
TO KHARTOUM.
BUT THE OIL-RICH REGIME CARES
LITTLE ABOUT WORLD OPINION.
THEY CONTINUE TO KILL,
AND THE WORLD HAS DONE
NOTHING MEANINGFUL TO STOP THEM.
WE NEED TO STOP PROVING
TO POLITICAL LEADERS
THAT WE WILL STAND BY AS THEY
SLAUGHTER THEIR OWN PEOPLE.
IF DIPLOMACY FAILS, COUNTRIES
COMMITTING MASS ELIMINATIONS
SUCH AS SUDAN HAVE TO BE KICKED
OUT OF THE U.N.
AND ALL INTERNATIONAL
ORGANIZATIONS,
AND ALL TRADE MUST BE CUT OFF.
LEADERS THAT CONTINUE TO KILL
MUST KNOW THAT WE WILL
SWIFTLY AND FORCEFULLY DESTROY
THEIR MILITARY CAPABILITY.
Felde: SOME PEOPLE HAVE
TALKED ABOUT SOME KIND
OF RAPID RESPONSE FORCE.
I WOULD OF COURSE
BE FOR INTERVENTION,
MILITARY INTERVENTION
WHEN PEOPLE ARE
BEING SLAUGHTERED.
IT SEEMS QUITE OBVIOUS
THAT HAVING SOME KIND
OF FORCE
THAT COULD INTERVENE
RAPIDLY AND EFFECTIVELY
IN MANY OF THE COUNTRIES
WHERE IT DOESN'T TAKE
A GREAT DEAL OF FORCE
TO STOP THESE THINGS
IS AN ABSOLUTE MORAL
AND POLITICAL NECESSITY.
SOME WOULD SAY THAT IF
WE'RE GOING TO INTERVENE
MILITARILY IN DARFUR
WHAT ABOUT CONGO?
CERTAINLY, MORE PEOPLE
HAVE DIED THERE
IN THE PAST 10 YEARS.
SO PERHAPS THEN
YOU'RE SUGGESTING
WE SHOULD INTERVENE
THERE, AS WELL.
THESE KINDS
OF ARGUMENTS I ALSO
FIND UNPERSUASIVE.
IT IS QUITE TRUE THAT
THE UNITED STATES IS NOT
THE POLICEMAN
OF THE WORLD,
EVEN THOUGH IT IS
THE GUARANTOR
OF MUCH OF ORDER
IN THE WORLD.
IT REMAINS THAT,
BUT THAT DOESN'T MEAN
THAT IF INTERVENING
IN DARFUR IS
THE RIGHT THING TO DO
TO SAVE LIVES
THAT WE SHOULD NOT DO IT
BECAUSE WE CAN'T
INTERVENE EVERYWHERE.
I DON'T FIND
THE ARGUMENTS AGAIN
PERSUASIVE THAT,
WELL, YOU SHOULDN'T
DO SOMETHING BECAUSE
YOU CAN'T DO EVERYTHING.
OUR PROBLEM IS THAT WE
DO LITTLE OR NOTHING
AT ALL.
Silajdzic:
THE INTERNATIONAL
COMMUNITY MUST HAVE
A MECHANISM THAT
WILL QUICKLY REACT
TO GENOCIDE.
THERE IS NO
WAITING THERE,
OTHER CONSIDERATION.
HUMAN LIFE
MUST BE SAVED.
WE MUST ALL AGREE
TO THIS.
IF THERE IS
MASS KILLING
SOMEWHERE,
THE INTERNATIONAL
COMMUNITY HAS
THE RIGHT
TO INTERVENE.
YOU KNOW, WHEN IT
BECOMES TOO LATE,
IT'S TOO LATE.
Man: IN MANY INSTANCES,
DIPLOMATIC EFFORTS
ARE GONNA BE
UNSUCCESSFUL,
PARTICULARLY ONCE
THE KILLING STARTS.
THE ONLY WAY YOU ARE
GONNA STOP THAT
IS THROUGH THE USE
OF MILITARY FORCE,
BUT IT'S GONNA BE
VERY DIFFICULT
TO GET A WIDE CONSORTIUM
OF COUNTRIES TO AGREE
THAT THERE'S
AN AUTOMATIC TRIGGER
FOR MILITARY
INTERVENTION.
IN DARFUR, YOU NEED
AFRICAN GOVERNMENTS
ON BOARD,
YOU NEED MIDDLE EASTERN
GOVERNMENTS ON BOARD.
THIS HAS PROVED
VERY DIFFICULT
TO ACCOMPLISH.
YOU KNOW, I'M NOT A DIPLOMAT,
AND I SAY WHY?
WHY DO WE NEED THEM
ON BOARD?
I MEAN, YOU HAVE
HUNDREDS OF THOUSANDS
OF PEOPLE BEING SLAUGHTERED.
WHY DO WE NEED TO GET
MIDDLE EASTERN GOVERNMENTS
OR AFRICAN GOVERNMENTS
ON BOARD?
WHY NOT CREATE
A NO-FLY ZONE,
WHY NOT BOMB THEIR
MILITARY INSTALLATIONS?
FORGET ABOUT THE DIPLOMACY
FOR A MINUTE.
WOULD IT BE EFFECTIVE,
AND THEN HOW DO WE WEIGH
IF IT WOULD BE
THE MORALITY OF IT
VERSUS THE DIPLOMACY OF IT?
FROM THE MORAL
PERSPECTIVE, YOU'RE
ABSOLUTELY RIGHT.
I MEAN, WE DO HAVE
A MORAL OBLIGATION.
IF WE'RE
IN A POSITION TO ACT
AND WE HAVE THE ACTUAL
CAPABILITY TO DO SO,
THEN I THINK WE SHOULD,
BUT IF YOU HAVE
A SITUATION WHERE YOU'RE
NOT ABLE TO GET SUPPORT
OF OTHER GOVERNMENTS,
IT MAY BE
COUNTERPRODUCTIVE.
Goldhagen: GETTING THE SUPPORT
OF OTHER GOVERNMENTS
SOUNDS GOOD,
BUT AS HARIS SILAJDZIC
EXPERIENCED DURING THE DAYS
OF THE BOSNIAN GENOCIDE,
CONVINCING LEADERS
TO INTERVENE MILITARILY
IS EXTRAORDINARILY DIFFICULT.
WHAT WAS IT LIKE
FOR YOU TRYING TO MOBILIZE
THE INTERNATIONAL COMMUNITY,
THE POLITICAL LEADERS
OF THE EUROPEAN COUNTRIES,
OF THE UNITED STATES,
THE U.N., AND SO ON
TO DO SOMETHING?
WELL, THAT IS
VERY FRUSTRATING,
THE POWERLESSNESS,
VERY FRUSTRATING.
IT'S HARD TO MOVE
THE INTERNATIONAL
COMMUNITY
TO REALLY DO SOMETHING.
IT'S THE PHILOSOPHY
OF, UH...
THE LEAST RESISTANCE.
"LET'S DO THE EASIEST
THING IN THE WORLD,
SO LET'S WAIT.
MAYBE IT WILL
GO AWAY."
Goldhagen: AS WE HAVE SEEN
TIME AND AGAIN,
WHEN WE WAIT TO INTERVENE,
PROBLEMS DON'T GO AWAY.
THEY ONLY GET WORSE.
THIS IS THE STORY
OF ANOTHER MASS MURDER
THAT DIDN'T HAVE TO HAPPEN.
BY THE TIME IT DID,
THE ELIMINATION
OF BOSNIA'S MUSLIMS
HAD BEEN GOING ON FOR 3 YEARS.
THE OUTSIDE WORLD KNEW WHAT
THE SERBS WERE UP TO,
WE KNEW WE COULD STOP IT,
AND DAY AFTER DAY,
WE CHOSE NOT TO TAKE
EFFECTIVE MEASURES.
IN 1995, THE CITY
OF SREBRENICA,
DESIGNATED A SAFE HAVEN
FOR BOSNIAN MUSLIMS
BY THE UNITED NATIONS,
FELL TO SERB FORCES.
WITHIN DAYS,
THE SERBS KILLED 8,000.
EACH YEAR, SOME OF THE VICTIMS
EXHUMED FROM MASS GRAVES
ARE POSITIVELY IDENTIFIED
AND GIVEN A PROPER BURIAL
ON THE ANNIVERSARY
OF THE MASSACRE.
AS SREBRENICA FELL,
THE MUSLIMS SOUGHT REFUGE
SEVERAL MILES AWAY
AT THIS FACTORY COMPLEX,
WHICH SERVED AS THE HEADQUARTERS
OF A SMALL U.N.
PEACEKEEPING FORCE.
Sudetic: YOU HAD
25,000 PEOPLE,
MANY OF THEM ELDERLY,
WOMEN, AND CHILDREN
GATHERED IN THE YARD
AROUND THIS BASE,
SEEKING PROTECTION.
AND I THINK AT THAT TIME
THERE WERE APPROXIMATELY
300 DUTCH TROOPS THERE,
FAR, FAR BELOW ANYTHING
THAT WOULD HAVE BEEN
A CREDIBLE DETERRENT
TO ANY KIND
OF MILITARY ACTION
ON THE GROUND.
Goldhagen: AFTER THEY
CAPTURED SREBRENICA,
SERB SOLDIERS UNDER THE COMMAND
OF THE NOTORIOUS MASS MURDERER
GENERAL RATKO MLADIC ARRIVED
AT THE U.N. BASE TO DEAL
WITH THE MUSLIM REFUGEES.
[CHILDREN CRYING]
Sudetic: AFTER A NIGHT
OF TERROR,
THE SERBS ANNOUNCED THAT
THEY WERE GOING TO BE
TRANSPORTED
TO FRIENDLY LINES
IN BUSES, DON'T BE AFRAID.
THEY BROUGHT COOKIES
FOR CHILDREN.
[SPEAKING NATIVE LANGUAGE]
THE SERBS SEPARATE
THE MILITARY AGE MEN.
WHAT THAT MEANT WAS
PRETTY MUCH ANYBODY
12 AND ABOVE TO ONE SIDE,
AND THEN THE WOMEN
AND CHILDREN
AND THE OLDER PEOPLE
TO THE OTHER.
Goldhagen: THIS IS HOW EASY
IT WOULD HAVE BEEN
TO SAVE THE LIVES
OF SABAHETA'S SON
AND 8,000 OTHERS
IN SREBRENICA.
Woman: EARLY MORNING RAIDS
OF MORE THAN 60 AIRCRAFT
FROM AS MANY AS 5 NATIONS
POUNDED AIR DEFENSE MISSILES...
Goldhagen: IN AUGUST 1995,
TWO MONTHS AFTER THE EXPULSION
AND MASS MURDER IN SREBRENICA
AND 3 YEARS
AFTER THE GENOCIDE BEGAN,
NATO FORCES BEGAN
A BOMBING CAMPAIGN
AGAINST SERBIAN
MILITARY TARGETS.
IN JUST 3 WEEKS,
THE BOMBING CHANGED
MILOSEVIC'S CALCULATIONS.
IN SHORT ORDER,
SLOBODAN MILOSEVIC WAS
AT THE NEGOTIATING TABLE,
DISCUSSING THE PEACE TREATY
THAT WOULD END
HIS DEPREDATIONS IN BOSNIA.
THE BOSNIAN GENOCIDE WAS OVER.
LET'S TURN
THE CLOCK BACK.
WHAT HAPPENS IF
IN 1992 NATO
STARTED TO BOMB
AND NOT WAITED
UNTIL 1995 TO DO SO?
OH, THAT WOULD HAVE
STOPPED EVERYTHING
DEFINITELY.
WE WOULD HAVE SAVED
THE LIVES OF 100,000 PEOPLE?
NOT ONLY THAT.
THE CREDIBILITY
OF THE INTERNATIONAL
ORDER,
THE CREDIBILITY
OF JUSTICE,
OF HUMANITY.
THAT WOULD HAVE
BEEN SAVED.
Goldhagen: THE PERPETRATORS
OF ELIMINATION
ALMOST ALWAYS ACT
WITH TOTAL IMPUNITY.
HERE IN GUATEMALA,
A GENOCIDAL MASTERMIND
WALKS FREELY.
IN FACT, HE CONTINUES TO SERVE
IN THE COUNTRY'S CONGRESS.
[SPEAKS SPANISH]
Goldhagen, voice-over:
AT THE TIME THIS KILLER
COMMITTED HIS CRIMES,
HE BELIEVED HE WOULD GET
AWAY WITH MURDER.
SO FAR, HE'S BEEN PROVEN RIGHT.
JOS EFRAN ROS MONTT
LED THIS COUNTRY
FOR NEARLY TWO TERRIFYING YEARS,
DURING WHICH HE WAS RESPONSIBLE
FOR A WIDESPREAD CAMPAIGN
OF TERROR AND SLAUGHTER.
I WANTED TO GET A LOOK
AT THIS MAN IN PERSON,
AND I HOPED
OTILIA LUX DE COTI
A MEMBER
OF GUATEMALA'S CONGRESS,
WOULD HELP.
HI. NICE TO MEET YOU.
Doyle: THE ROS MONTT
PLAN FOR 1982 WAS
CALLED VICTORIA.
THESE ARE PLANS
THAT LAY OUT
THE BROAD STRATEGY
OF HOW THE ARMY WAS
GOING TO DESTROY
COMMUNISM
AND WIPE OUT
THE GUERRILLAS,
AND THE PLANS ARE
VERY EXPLICIT
ABOUT THE NEED
TO GO INTO
THE MAYAN COMMUNITIES
AND DESTROY THEM.
THEY CONTAIN
OPERATIONAL ORDERS
TO GO INTO
CERTAIN VILLAGES,
WHICH WERE, IN FACT,
MASSACRED AND RAZED,
AND AFTER ACTION REPORTS
IN WHICH THE COMMANDERS
OF THOSE UNITS SAY,
"DUTY DONE.
WE'VE, UH--WE'VE
"COMPLETED
THE OPERATION,
AND THE VILLAGE IS"--
UM, WHAT ARE SOME
OF THE WORDS THEY USED?
"ELIMINATED."
"THE VILLAGE
IS ELIMINATED.
THE VILLAGE IS
NEUTRALIZED."
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
Goldhagen: OTILIA LUX DE COTI
IS TAKING ME
INTO THE HALLS OF CONGRESS,
WHERE THE FORMER DICTATOR
MAINTAINS A POWERFUL PRESENCE.
IN THE ROUGH AND TUMBLE
OF POLITICS,
THE CONGRESSWOMAN WORKS
SIDE BY SIDE
WITH THE MAN RESPONSIBLE
FOR THE MURDER
OF NEARLY 200,000 OF HER PEOPLE.
SEEING ROS MONTT
IN THIS SETTING IS SURREAL.
IT'S LIKE ENCOUNTERING HITLER
IN THE BUNDESTAG.
I HAVE STUDIED MASS MURDERERS
FOR MORE THAN 3 DECADES,
BUT IT NEVER OCCURRED TO ME
THAT I MIGHT ONE DAY STAND
BEFORE A GENOCIDAL MASTERMIND
FACE TO FACE.
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
MAY I ASK YOU
A QUESTION?
WAS THERE GENOCIDE
IN GUATEMALA,
AND WERE YOU RESPONSIBLE?
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
THE U.N. LAWS
AND INTERNATIONAL CODES
HAVE A CONCEPT
FOR GENOCIDE.
IT'S CLEARLY DEFINED.
WHEN YOU'RE GOING
TO ELIMINATE
AN ETHNICAL GROUP...
WHEN YOU'RE GOING
TO ELIMINATE
A RELIGIOUS GROUP...
OR A SPECIFIC GROUP
OF PEOPLE.
THE DEFINITION
CLEARLY STATES IT'S
ELIMINATING SOMETHING.
THE DEFINITION
STATES, ELIMINATING
IN WHOLE OR IN PART
AN ETHNIC GROUP,
WHICH THE MAYAN
PEOPLE WERE.
HE AGREES WITH THAT.
AND SO WERE YOU
RESPONSIBLE
FOR THIS?
HE WOULD BE IN JAIL
IF HE WAS RESPONSIBLE
FOR THAT.
Goldhagen, voice-over:
I DON'T KNOW WHAT
I WAS EXPECTING
BUT NOT THIS.
THE FORMER DICTATOR
WAS EVASIVE AND COMBATIVE,
BUT REMARKABLY,
HE STAYED TO TALK
FOR MORE THAN 20 MINUTES.
DO YOU ACCEPT
THE HISTORICAL
COMMISSION'S FINDING
THAT 200,000
INDIGENOUS MAYANS
WERE KILLED
WHILE YOU WERE
PRESIDENT
BY YOUR MILITARY?
HE SAID THAT YOU
SHOULD TAKE PROOF
AND CONVINCE HIM
IN A COURT OF LAW.
STARING INTO THE EYES
OF THIS KILLER,
I FEEL OUTRAGE AND DISGUST,
BUT MORE THAN ANYTHING,
I AM REMINDED
THAT ALL OF THIS COMES
DOWN TO A CHOICE.
MORE THAN 25 YEARS AGO
AS THE POLITICAL LEADER
OF HIS COUNTRY,
THIS MAN CONSIDERED
HIS POLITICAL GOALS,
WEIGHED HIS OPTIONS,
DECIDED HE COULD
GET AWAY WITH IT,
AND MADE A CALCULATED DECISION
TO MURDER AND EXPEL
HUNDREDS OF THOUSANDS
OF HIS COUNTRY'S PEOPLE.
THE QUESTION IS CAN WE GET
FUTURE LEADERS TO MAKE
A DIFFERENT DECISION?
I THINK WE CAN.
Woman: YOU KNOW, DANNY,
YOU MIGHT BE SUGGESTING
WE CAN PREVENT ONE
OF THE FEW THINGS
IN THE WORLD
THAT PEOPLE SAY
ARE UNSTOPPABLE
OR THAT WE HAVEN'T
SEEMED TO BE ABLE
TO STOP.
DO YOU THINK PEOPLE
WILL JUST SAY,
"COME ON, DANNY.
THAT'S--THAT'S
NOT GONNA HAPPEN.
"IT'S NOT JUST
ONE PERSON.
"WE'VE BEEN SCREAMING
ABOUT THESE ISSUES
FOR A LONG TIME,
AND THE LEADERS
OF THE WORLD
HAVEN'T LISTENED."
THE POLITICAL LEADERS
WHO KILL OTHER PEOPLE
ARE OFTEN HATE-FILLED,
POSSESSED BY IDEOLOGIES
THAT LEAD THEM TO SEE
GROUPS OF PEOPLE
AS NECESSARY
TO SLAUGHTER,
BUT THEY ARE NOT CRAZY.
THEY ARE
RATIONAL CALCULATORS
OF COSTS AND BENEFITS.
AFTER ALL,
THESE PEOPLE HAVE RISEN
TO THE PINNACLE OF POWER
IN THEIR COUNTRIES,
AND SO WHAT WE NEED
TO DO IS THINK
ABOUT THEIR
COST-BENEFIT CALCULUS.
LIKE ROS MONTT,
ALL POLITICAL LEADERS
WHO INITIATE
GENOCIDES AND ELIMINATIONS
KNOW THAT
THE INTERNATIONAL COMMUNITY
IS UNLIKELY TO INTERFERE
WITH THEIR DEADLY PLANS.
Woman: THIS IS CASE NUMBER
IT-95-5/18-I,
THE PROSECUTOR
VERSUS RADOVAN KARADZIC.
Goldhagen: WE HAVE
INTERNATIONAL COURTS,
AND THEY DO SOME GOOD,
BUT THEY ARE UNBEARABLY
SLOW AND INEFFECTIVE...
Man: GOOD AFTERNOON,
YOUR HONOR.
AND THE KILLING CONTINUES.
SO WHAT SHOULD WE DO?
FROM THE TRAGEDIES
IN RWANDA AND ELSEWHERE,
WE'VE SEEN THAT
THE INSTITUTIONS WE RELY ON
TO COMBAT GENOCIDE DON'T WORK,
AND IT'S CLEAR THAT AS IN KENYA
TIMELY INTERVENTION
CAN GET POLITICAL LEADERS
TO STOP
THE ELIMINATIONIST ASSAULT.
IN DEALING WITH A RECALCITRANT
GENOCIDAL LEADER IN DARFUR,
WE'VE LEARNED THAT
TO BE EFFECTIVE
INTERVENTION MUST OFTEN
BE FORCEFUL
AND THAT, AS WAS
THE CASE IN BOSNIA,
RELATIVELY LITTLE FORCE CAN
ACHIEVE EXTRAORDINARY RESULTS,
AND WE KNOW ABOVE ALL
THAT GENOCIDES ARE POLITICAL
AND THEY ARE INITIATED
BY A FEW LEADERS
WHOSE COST-BENEFIT CALCULATIONS
CAN BE CHANGED.
WE NEED TO CHANGE
THAT CALCULATION.
Goldhagen: DO WE NEED TO
HAVE A NEW INTERNATIONAL
ORIENTATION
TOWARDS INTERVENTION
AND GENOCIDE?
DEFINITELY.
HOW WOULD YOU REWRITE
THE RULES
OF THE INTERNATIONAL
COMMUNITY ON THIS?
FIRST, GENOCIDE
NEVER HAPPENS
AS A SURPRISE.
NEVER.
THE SIGNS ARE
USUALLY AVAILABLE
AND APPARENT,
AND SO THERE SHOULD
BE A DEBATE
AT THE U.N.
SECURITY COUNCIL,
AT THE LEVEL
OF THE EUROPEAN
UNION,
AT THE LEVEL
OF AFRICAN UNION,
OR OTHER
POWERBROKERS
TO SET UNDER
WHICH CIRCUMSTANCES
INTERVENTION WOULD
BE DEEMED NECESSARY.
SO YOU DON'T
WAIT UNTIL IT
HAS HAPPENED.
THERE MUST BE
PREVENTIVE MEASURES.
SO I THINK WE
SHOULD GO BACK TO
THE DRAWING BOARD.
Goldhagen, voice-over: BACK
TO THE DRAWING BOARD INDEED.
GIVEN EVERYTHING I'VE
SEEN AND STUDIED,
THIS MUCH IS CLEAR.
INSTEAD OF THE U.N.,
WE NEED AN INTERNATIONAL
WATCHDOG ORGANIZATION
MADE UP OF DEMOCRATIC NATIONS
THAT WILL ENFORCE
A ZERO TOLERANCE POLICY
ON GENOCIDE AND ELIMINATIONISM.
EACH OF THE MEMBERS MUST HAVE
THE RIGHT TO INTERVENE
INDIVIDUALLY OR COLLECTIVELY
TO STOP CAMPAIGNS
OF ELIMINATION,
BUT INTERVENTION,
EVEN FORCEFUL INTERVENTION,
IS NOT ENOUGH.
BY THE TIME WE INTERVENE,
TENS OF THOUSANDS
CAN BE DEAD OR HOMELESS.
WE NEED AN EFFECTIVE SYSTEM
OF PREVENTION.
WE'VE GOT TO STOP GENOCIDES
BEFORE THEY HAPPEN
BY SHOWING POLITICAL LEADERS
THAT THE COSTS TO THEM
WILL FOR SURE
FAR OUTWEIGH THE BENEFITS.
THE U.S. HAS A BOUNTY PROGRAM
FOR GETTING PEOPLE
TO HUNT DOWN TERRORISTS.
WHY NOT HAVE
DEMOCRATIC COUNTRIES DO THE SAME
FOR LEADERS WHO PERPETRATE
GENOCIDES AND ELIMINATIONS?
LET'S SAY FOR EXAMPLE,
THE INTERNATIONAL COMMUNITY
DECLARED THE LEADERS
OF COUNTRIES
THAT COMMIT GENOCIDE
TO BE OUTLAWS.
THEY CAN BE HUNTED DOWN
UNTIL THEY EITHER
GIVE THEMSELVES UP
OR UNTIL THEY'RE KILLED.
WOULD MILOSEVIC
UNDER THESE CIRCUMSTANCES
HAVE EVER INITIATED
THE SLAUGHTER OF BOSNIANS?
I DON'T THINK
HE WOULD.
HE COUNTED
WITH POWERFUL
FRIENDS
AND MOST OF ALL
WITH THE FACTUAL
SITUATION
ON THE GROUND,
KNOWING THAT
THE INTERNATIONAL
COMMUNITY IS IN LOVE
WITH THE STATUS QUO.
WE MUST SHOW
THAT IT DOESN'T PAY.
IF PEOPLE KNEW
THAT AT THE END
OF THE DAY
THEY'D BE
THE LOSERS,
THEY WOULD
NEVER INVEST
IN A LOSING
ENTERPRISE.
IT'S BECAUSE
GENOCIDE IS
A POLITICAL GAME,
IT'S A POWER PLAY,
IT'S WORSE,
IT'S EVERYTHING.
IF PEOPLE INVOLVED
IN KNEW AT THE END
OF THE DAY
THEY'D BE
THE LOSERS,
THEY WOULD NOT
PLAY THE GAME,
THAT'S FOR SURE.
Goldhagen: WHAT IS
THE ALTERNATIVE TO DEALING
FORCEFULLY
WITH GENOCIDAL LEADERS?
THE STATUS QUO,
MORE MASS MURDER,
MORE LIVES DESTROYED.
THE KEY TO STOPPING GENOCIDE
IS TO FOCUS ON THE LEADERS.
THE KEY TO GETTING US TO ACT IS
TO IDENTIFY WITH THE VICTIMS,
TO THINK OF EACH ONE
AS IF HE OR SHE WERE
YOUR DAUGHTER OR SON,
YOUR SISTER OR BROTHER,
YOUR MOTHER
OR YOUR FATHER.
WE'RE GONNA "T"
INTO CAR--CAR--
CARMEN--
I DON'T KNOW
HOW TO READ IT.
Goldhagen, voice-over:
MY JOURNEY ENDS WITH MY FATHER
AT THE PLACE WHERE HIS BEGAN.
SHORTLY AFTER THE GERMANS
AND THE ROMANIAN ALLIES
ENTERED MY FATHER'S TOWN,
THEY SLAUGHTERED 800 JEWS.
MY FATHER AND HIS FAMILY
WERE NEARLY EXECUTED
ON A DIRT ROAD
BEHIND THEIR HOUSE
SOMEWHERE IN THIS NEIGHBORHOOD.
DO YOU SEE
ANY TRACKS?
THEY SHOULD BE
STRAIGHT AHEAD.
IF WE END HERE,
THE TRACKS SHOULD
BE RIGHT DOWN HERE.
HERE THEY ARE.
TATI, SEE
THE TRACKS?
I DON'T KNOW.
DO YOU SEE THEM?
YES, THEY'RE
RIGHT THERE.
OH, I SEE.
YEAH. THAT WAS HERE.
I LIVED RIGHT HERE.
I RAN OUT WITH MY
FATHER BEYOND
FROM THERE.
OUT THE OTHER SIDE?
YES. I REMEMBER WE
RAN OVER A FENCE,
AND AS WE WERE
RUNNING, A SOLDIER
SPIED US
AND BEAT MY FATHER
VERY SEVERELY
WITH THE BUTT
OF HIS RIFLE
AND PUT US AGAINST--
SAID, "WAIT HERE,"
PUT US AGAINST--
OF COURSE THERE
WAS A FENCE--
AGAINST THE FENCE,
AND THEN HE TOLD ME
TO TELL THE FAMILY
TO COME--
TO COME OUT.
SO HE SENT YOU BACK
TO THE HOUSE?
HE SENT ME
BACK TO THE HOUSE,
AND WE SAW NEIGHBORS
STANDING BEYOND
THIS RAILWAY,
AND WE REALIZED
THAT THEY'RE
LOOKING AT US
IN A CERTAIN WAY
THAT THEY--
IN AN OMINOUS WAY.
THEY--WHICH DIDN'T--
WHICH DIDN'T BODE WELL,
TO SAY THE LEAST.
NOW THAT WE'RE HERE,
IS THIS--HAS IT
CHANGED YOUR VIEW?
YOU SEE, THE POINT IS
THAT THE SCHOLARLY ELEMENT--
THE SCHOLAR WITHIN ME
IMMEDIATELY TAKES OVER THE--
AND OVERSHADOWS
THE EMOTIONS
OF THE SURVIVOR
WHO REVISITS THE SCENE
OF HIS NEAR DEATH.
SO AS I TALK TO YOU,
I BEGIN TO REFLECT,
DRAW HISTORICAL ANALOGIES,
AND SO ON,
SO THEREFORE,
IT HAS A CERTAIN
TEMPERING EFFECT
UPON MY EMOTIONS
AS I CONFRONT
THIS HOUSE WHERE I LIVED,
THIS STREET
WHERE I WALKED,
AND REFLECTED ON MY BLOOD
LYING IN THE DUST HERE,
BUT WHEN I REMEMBER
THAT MOMENT
AS I WALKED
AND I JUST COULDN'T
BELIEVE--
YES, I DID REFLECT
UPON HOW I WOULD LIE DEAD.
WHAT DOES IT MEAN
TO BE DEAD
AND TO LIE
IN YOUR BLOOD?
I REMEMBERED VIVIDLY
THIS IMAGERY THAT I HAD
AS I WALKED, AND...
Goldhagen, voice-over:
WHAT MUST IT FEEL LIKE
FOR A 10-YEAR-OLD BOY
TO CONTEMPLATE HIS OWN
IMMINENT, VIOLENT DEATH
OR A 16-YEAR-OLD GIRL
OR A 19-YEAR-OLD MAN?
WHAT MUST IT FEEL LIKE
TO BE IMPRISONED IN A RAPE CAMP
OR TO WATCH HELPLESSLY
AS MEMBERS OF YOUR FAMILY
ARE KILLED
OR AS YOUR PEOPLE
ARE DECIMATED?
WHAT MUST IT HAVE BEEN LIKE
FOR THE MEN OF SREBRENICA
WHO WERE HERDED
INTO THIS WAREHOUSE
OR FOR THE OTHERS
FORCED AT GUNPOINT
INTO NEARBY FIELDS
TO BE EXECUTED?
[SPEAKING
NATIVE LANGUAGE]
[GUNSHOT]
[RAPID GUNSHOTS]
[GUNFIRE CONTINUING]
Goldhagen: WE CAN'T
STAND BY ANYMORE.
PEOPLE ARE DYING EVERY DAY.
A FEW POLITICAL LEADERS
START GENOCIDES.
CAN STOP THEM.
THE PRESIDENTS
AND PRIME MINISTERS WE ELECT
HAVE THE POWER TO END IMPUNITY
AND CHANGE THE CHOICES
POTENTIAL MASS KILLERS MAKE.
WE MUST HOLD OUR LEADERS
ACCOUNTABLE AND DEMAND
THAT THEY BRING AN END
TO GENOCIDE AND ELIMINATIONISM.
[INDISTINCT CHATTER]
THANK YOU. HOW DO
YOU SAY THANK YOU?
I NEVER REMEMBER
ANYTHING.
[MAN SPEAKS
NATIVE LANGUAGE]
[REPEATS PHRASE]
EVERYONE.
Goldhagen, voice-over:
I HAD BEEN WORKING
ON "WORSE THAN WAR"
FOR ABOUT 10 YEARS BEFORE
THE FILM PROJECT BEGAN.
WHEN I WRITE A BOOK,
I CAN PRETTY MUCH SAY
WHATEVER I WANT TO,
AND IF I DECIDE SOMETHING
NEEDS 20 PAGES OF ELABORATION,
THEN I DO IT.
EVEN THOUGH I HAD THOUGHT
AT THE BEGINNING,
"WELL, I KNOW WHAT
THIS FILM SHOULD SAY,"
IT TURNED INTO SOMETHING
QUITE DIFFERENT
AND INFINITELY BETTER
THAN ANYTHING
I WOULD HAVE PRODUCED
HAD I BEEN THE FILMMAKER
BECAUSE I PROBABLY WOULD HAVE
PRODUCED A NICE TWO-HOUR LECTURE
OF SOME KIND WITH VISUALS
INSTEAD OF A FILM THAT IS
VISUALLY ARRESTING
AND EMOTIONALLY EVOCATIVE
AND, AS POWERFUL AS THE BOOK IS,
IN SOME WAYS
OBVIOUSLY MORE POWERFUL.
WHEN MY FATHER AND I WENT
TO WHERE HE HAD LIVED
DURING THE HOLOCAUST,
SARAH MY WIFE
AND GIDEON OUR SON CAME WITH US.
GIDEON AT THE TIME
WAS 7 YEARS OLD,
AND HE WAS DEEPLY INTERESTED.
HE'S VERY CLOSE MY PARENTS.
THEY LIVE NEARBY.
HE WAS DEEPLY INTERESTED IN
GOING TO WHERE GRANDPA WAS FROM.
SO THEY CAME
ON THE TRIP WITH US,
AND IT WAS SOMETHING THAT MADE
MY FATHER ENORMOUSLY HAPPY.
THAT ONE OF HIS GRANDCHILDREN
COULD SEE WHERE
MY FATHER CAME FROM
AND WHERE HE SUFFERED
AND WHERE HIS FAMILY SUFFERED
MADE THE TRIP,
IF ONE CAN SAY SUCH A THING,
TWICE AS MOVING AND MEMORABLE
AND MEANINGFUL FOR HIM.
THERE'S NO DOUBT THAT
MY FATHER INFLUENCED
MY INITIAL DIRECTION
OF WORKING ON THE HOLOCAUST,
BUT IT'S LESS BECAUSE
HE WAS A SURVIVOR
THAN HE WAS A PROFESSOR
WHO STUDIED THIS,
AND I GREW UP
WITH THIS MATERIAL IN MY HOME
ALWAYS WITH THE PURPOSE
NOT OF TELLING A TALE OF WOE,
WHICH IT IS,
BUT OF UNDERSTANDING
AND EXPLAINING.
THIS WAS ALWAYS MY ORIENTATION
FROM THE TIME I CAN REMEMBER
KNOWING OR THINKING ABOUT IT
OR DISCUSSING IT,
BUT IT CHANGES YOU
TO SEE THE PLACES.
THE CLICH "A PICTURE'S
WORTH A THOUSAND WORDS"
ONLY BEGINS TO CONVEY
WHAT BEING IN A PLACE
AND SITTING
ACROSS FROM THE VICTIMS
AND SEEING THE LOCATIONS
WHERE PEOPLE WERE SLAUGHTERED
AND BEING IN A FORENSIC LAB
WITH THE REMAINS OF VICTIMS
OR BEING IN A MASS GRAVE
OR STANDING ACROSS
FROM A MASTERMIND OF GENOCIDE
SUCH AS ROS MONTT.
IT CHANGES YOU.
IT IS MORE THAN WORTH
A THOUSAND WORDS.
IT'S WORTH ENDLESS,
ENDLESS VOLUMES OF WORDS.
IN RWANDA, WE GAINED ACCESS
TO ONE OF THE PRISON CAMPS.
IT'S ACTUALLY A WORK CAMP
FOR PRISONERS WHO CONFESSED
TO THEIR CRIMES,
OR AT LEAST SOME CRIMES,
TO CONFESS TO HAVING
PARTICIPATED IN THE GENOCIDE.
IF YOU CAN BELIEVE THAT,
THERE ARE ABOUT 1,000 PEOPLE
IN THIS PRISON.
THERE WERE NO GUARDS.
SO WE INTERVIEWED
THE PERPETRATORS IN THE FIELD.
THE WARDEN JUST BROUGHT
PEOPLE TO US.
WE HAD NO IDEA
WHO WE'D BE TALKING TO,
AND ALSO, WE WALKED AMONG THEM.
THEY WERE TILLING
THE GROUND WITH HOES
AND PICKS AND MACHETES,
CLEARING IT,
AND YOU'RE WALKING AMONG THEM
WITHIN FEET OF ROWS OF THEM
WIELDING THESE IMPLEMENTS,
AND YOU CAN'T BUT THINK
THESE ARE THE IMPLEMENTS
THEY USED TO SLAUGHTER
THEIR VICTIMS
DURING THE GENOCIDE
BY THE INDIVIDUALLY,
BY THE TENS, BY THE HUNDREDS,
BY THE THOUSANDS ULTIMATELY.
OK.
TELL ME WHEN.
SHAKING THE HAND OF A KILLER
BEFORE I EVEN KNOW ANYTHING ELSE
ABOUT HIM EXCEPT
FOR WHAT HIS NAME IS,
IS A STRANGE THING.
IT'S AN ACT OF POLITENESS.
IT'S A TIME
OF HUMAN SHARING,
AND YET THAT SAME HAND--
I SHAKE THE HAND.
I THINK THE SAME HAND ACTUALLY
WAS WIELDING A MACHETE
AND STRIKING AND KILLING
AND HACKING TO DEATH
OTHER PEOPLE,
AND YOU CAN'T FLINCH,
AND YOU CAN'T SAY,
"I DON'T WANT TO DO IT,"
AND YOU HAVE TO DO IT
BECAUSE IT'S PART
OF WHAT YOU NEED TO DO
WHEN YOU INTERVIEW SOMEBODY,
AND THAT'S JUST THE BEGINNING
OF SITTING ACROSS FROM SOMEONE
WHO THEN BEGINS TO TELL YOU
OF THE HORRIBLE THINGS,
THE HORRIFYING THINGS
THAT HE DID,
THE WAYS THAT HE DID IT.
AND SO THERE I AM,
A WHOLE JUMBLE OF EMOTIONS
AND THOUGHT AND DIFFERENT
ORIENTATIONS AT THE SAME TIME--
THE INTERVIEWER,
THE SCHOLAR THINKING
ABOUT WHAT HE SAYS,
THE ANALYST,
THE HUMAN BEING SITTING
ACROSS FROM A MASS MURDERER,
FEELING A DEGREE OF SYMPATHY
OR EVEN OF LIKING FOR SOMEONE,
BECAUSE SOME SEEM LIKEABLE,
AND ALSO ALWAYS KEEPING IN MIND
THAT THESE ARE MASS MURDERERS.
TO BE ABLE IN MAKING THIS FILM
TO GO TO ANY NUMBER OF COUNTRIES
AND TO TALK TO THE VICTIMS,
TO TALK TO THE PERPETRATORS,
JUST TO SEE THE PLACES
I'D READ ABOUT
WAS TRANSFORMATIVE,
AND I THINK BACK ON THE PEOPLE
QUITE OFTEN I TALKED TO.
THEY RESONATE WITH ME.
THEIR FACES I SEE.
IN THE FILM, MY FATHER
AND SOME OTHERS TALKED
ABOUT SEEING FACES.
THEY'RE HAUNTED BY THEM,
OR THEY REMEMBER THEM,
THE FACES OF THE PEOPLE
WHO DIED.
WELL, THE FACES OF THE PEOPLE
I SPOKE WITH AND THEIR WORDS
ARE WITH ME
IN THE WAY THAT
THE TESTIMONY IN DOCUMENTS
AND COURT TESTIMONY
AND SO ON NEVER ARE WITH ME.
I HEAR THEM, I SEE THEM,
I THINK ABOUT THEM.
I ABSORBED AND INTERNALIZED
THINGS INTO MY BEING
THAT WERE NEVER THERE
AND THAT WILL NEVER LEAVE ME.
Announcer: "WORSE THAN WAR"
WAS MADE POSSIBLE BY...
AND...
ADDITIONAL FUNDING
WAS PROVIDED BY...
CAPTIONING MADE POSSIBLE BY
FRIENDS OF NCI
CAPTIONED BY THE NATIONAL
CAPTIONING INSTITUTE
--www.ncicap.org--
"WORSE THAN WAR"
CONTINUES ONLINE.
FOR MORE RESOURCES,
INFORMATION ABOUT
THE PHENOMENON OF GENOCIDE,
AND EXCERPTS
FROM DANIEL GOLDHAGEN'S BOOK,
VISIT PBS.ORG.
THE "WORSE THAN WAR" PROGRAM
IS AVAILABLE ON DVD
FOR $24.95 PLUS SHIPPING.
THE COMPANION BOOK IS AVAILABLE
FOR $29.95 PLUS SHIPPING.
TO ORDER, CALL 1-800-336-1917.