BRYAN IGUCHI: Yeah, so you know
if the rest of you guys
split we can all just
partnership with Trav, film,
and like, these jumps
are already built.
So it's really just a matter
of going out and just
sessioning.
And these guys are pros.
That's why, my gut feelings is
just to stick with our plan
and not try to start
from scratch again.
Because, I think we've
been out there.
We know the snow's good.
And we know what's going on.
We're confident in what
we can do, at least.
And then just to reset a whole
new plan, right now, I think,
would be counterproductive.
PAT BRIDGES: Probably around
the time that Subjekt
Haakonsen and those movies, he
moved to Jackson Hole, which
is like the big mountain mecca,
as far as the lower 48
states goes.
Here's a guy who consciously
went against what was
marketable about him, what his
sponsors expected of him, but
he did what he had to
do as a snowboarder.
DAVE DOWNING: I know we went to
Jackson Hole, actually, I
remember the trip.
It was with Standard Films.
We were filming for this, I
think it was TV5, and we had a
really sick week in
Jackson Hole.
It was super sick.
Like powder, epic.
We were filming on the
resort and stuff.
And I think he just fell in love
with the place, you know?
And he just made a decision to
just live there, and just
became a mountain man.
KEVIN JONES: And I believe
that next year, I believe
that's when, I think, Burton
dropped him, basically for
moving to Jackson Hole,
of all things.
It's like, oh you could never
be a professional
snowboarder out there.
He was so ahead of his time.
And I think that he really found
himself, in a lot of
ways, and what his snowboarding
was going to be about.
MIKE RANQUET: He moved there at
a time when his career was
pretty high.
And he didn't just move there,
he disappeared there.
And he didn't go there
for fame and glory.
He went there for mountains
and snow.
BRYAN IGUCHI: I was at
a point where I felt
stagnant in my riding.
And I saw the only progression
as be a big mountain,
freestyle, snowboarder.
And that was the way, where
I saw the sport going.
And that's why I wanted my film
parts to be able to get
these tricks off cliffs, or
off natural kickers in the
back country.
And that's what I saw
as my progression.
WILLIE MCMILLON: He was
a pretty big deal.
Jackson was still pretty
low key at that time.
And I've always been pretty
protective of this place.
So when he moved here, I don't
know if I was threatened by
some big name coming here.
Or just kind of worried
about him blowing this
place out, or something.
But I kind of gave him
a pretty hard time
when he moved here.
I don't even know if he even
knew I was vibing him.
But I was just kind
of a dick to him.
BRYAN IGUCHI: I had a
realization, I think, that I
was this professional
snowboarder and I didn't
really know anything about
the mountains.
You know?
I knew how to ride
a snowboard.
I knew how to do tricks.
But I didn't know
anything about
avalanches, or what was possible.
Or how to get around the
mountain safely.
The reality sank in that, man,
this is a dangerous pursuit.
And I've got to get to
know what I'm riding.
And I wanted to explore more
of the back country.
WILLIE MCMILLON: He
played it so cool.
He didn't come into town and
just bring all these crews in,
and do all this shit,
whatever.
He like, laid really low and
just kind of naturally became
part of the scene.
We're like, this guy's got to
be pretty cool if he gave up
all this fame and stuff, in
California, to come out here
and just hideout,
and ride powder.
BRYAN IGUCHI: It was kind
of like a career
suicide, in a sense.
It was taking myself out of
everything that I had built,
the snowboard park, freestyle
snowboarding thing.
And just going exactly
opposite.
I wanted to keep snowboarding
fun for myself, not for
necessarily my sponsors.
I saw a different
way to progress.
PAT BRIDGES: He was the first
rider to sit there and put his
money where his mouth was.
A lot of people are like, oh
yeah, I'm going to go and I'm
going to work on big mountain
freestyle, and make it
technical in the
big mountains.
He really laid it
all on the line.
And for a while, I mean, he
kind of paid the price.
Because it wasn't what
his sponsors, at the
time, wanted from him.
So he was kind of in
the wilderness, as
far as that's concerned.
But I mean, he was
riding every day.
WILLIE MCMILLON: He was
here for a while.
I think his sponsors were
cool with it, whatever.
And then it just seemed like
at one point it was just a
domino effect of his sponsors
dropping him.
You know?
And at one point he was
printing t-shirts for
Bluebird, getting like
$10 an hour.
He was just back in the working
class, dealing with
like, what the fuck
do I do now?
BRYAN IGUCHI: I just
kept snowboarding.
Because whether I was making
good money or not, I was still
doing whatever I had
to do to snowboard.
I started apprenticing as a
sushi chef, and working at the
local sushi bar.
And I just kept riding, though,
regardless of what was
going on with my sponsors, or
with my career, I guess.
It was just more about
the riding.
WILLIE MCMILLON: And it was just
kind of a crazy winter.
Because you would just kind of
see this aftermath of that
crew up on the mountain.
And that's kind of when I
started to maybe really have a
lot of respect for him.
You didn't see those guys hit
anything, but you just saw
their lines.
And people would be like, oh
yeah, Guch did this today, and
Johann did that.
I was kind of bummed, at that
point, that I was like such a
dick to him, because I was like,
I want to go shred with
those dudes, you know?
TRAVIS RICE: We were out
at Teton Village
riding here, in Jackson.
One day were out there in the
morning, and they used to have
this tram tower that had a clock
with a bell on it, and
it would ring like every hour.
It was like gong, gong.
My buddy and I were walking
along the path, going up to
the ski resort.
We're rolling out.
My buddy stops me and we both
look up, and here's Johan and
Bryan Iguchi like walking.
And it was so weird.
I remember it so specifically
to this day.
Right at that moment, dude,
the hour clock gonged.
And it was like, I think
it was nine gongs long.
It was like right at the
beginning of the day.
And just, gong, this thing was
like, it was slow motion.
And sure enough,
Bryan and Johan
Olofsson go walking along.
BRYAN IGUCHI: As a snowboarder
that was only way I was going
to progress.
It was going to be doing another
rotation off a jump.
I wasn't really that interested
in continuing to
keep spinning into oblivion.
I wanted to be able to ride a
big mountain, and be able to
ride a steep line.
And be able to do tricks
within that line.
And basically, Travis Rice is
exactly what I wanted to be.
That's kind of funny.
I might not have achieved
it, but it was cool
seeing him do it.
TRAVIS RICE: Seeing Guch,
every now and then, even
though he was a resident at
that point, it was kind of
like seeing an albino Buffalo,
or something rare.
Something mystical, perhaps, I
don't know, some type of horse
with a horn coming
straight out.
He's a mystical creature
that lived in Jackson.
You never saw him though.
He's like an owl.
BRYAN IGUCHI: My riding's
evolved.
And it's still evolving.
I'm progressing more on trying
to educate myself and get in
my head wrapped around
the mountains.
And trying to do what I
do, and do it safely.
And it's all timing
in the mountains.
And you've got to get out
there when it's good.
And you've got to know
when to pull back.
TRAVIS RICE: So yeah, years went
on, years went on, and
the Guch actually took me
into the back country
for the first time.
Later that year, the same
filmer, Rich Goodwin, actually
invited me down to tag along
with Lance Pitman and Bryan
Iguchi go down to go to
Superpark, which was this big
event that they do in Mammoth
Lakes, California.
Which is like this big
park they built.
They invite all the pros in
the world, come shred.
And I went down there, I wasn't
invited but Guch was
able to have some kind words
with the guys that were
putting the event on.
And got me in.
And I ended up, after like five
or six days, getting MPV
Superpark, which is kind
of how I got started in
snowboarding.
BRYAN IGUCHI: These photos are
taken by Ari Marcopoulos in, I
think, 1997.
Yeah, this is kind of the first
years here in Jackson.
And you had like Jamie Lynn,
and Terry, Johan.
Johan actually lived here for
a little bit then, in '97.
Spent two season's
out here with me.
Grillo lived with me, as well.
And my buddy, Tim.
We grew up together
in California and
moved out here together.
Kind of came here for a season,
to Jackson Hole, and
ended 16 years later
still doing it.
PAT BRIDGES: It wasn't
coincidence that he was out
there on the hill when the
cameras came back to find him
in Jackson, because he would
be riding, no matter what.
He would be rolling
sushi at night and
riding during the day.
That's what Guch did.
Anybody who went to Jackson,
for the last 15 years, you
knew you could find him
in the lift line.
That's what he did.
And unlike a lot of other people
in his peer group from
that first big early '90s,
freestyle movement, a lot of
those guys maybe they wanted
to do what Guch did.
Maybe they tried, but they
didn't have the patience that
he had, for the sport to
catch back up on him.
WILLIE MCMILLON: He wasn't
even like getting paid or
anything to snowboard.
He started shooting with the
Grenade and somehow he just
like carved his way
back in with this
eternal legend status.
There's like this or three year
period where he was just
working his ass off, filming
every single day, just like
stepping up his riding,
everything.
Before you knew it, he was just
like, back in the mags,
back in videos.
Volcom picks him back up.
All this great stuff started
happening for me.
And now he's where
he's at now.
And he's like the dude that
everybody calls when
they come to town.
DAVE DOWNING: Yeah, some people
could say, Bryan's
making a comeback.
Or he's a sponsored
snowboarder again.
And that's true.
But I don't think Bryan
really went anywhere.
He was still snowboarding.
He just wasn't doing it
in front of a camera.
WILLIE MCMILLON: And him and
Lance Pitman just started
exploring all these mountains.
And I'd probably say that Guch
and Lance found 90% of the
spots that people are
filming at now.
Now Guch brings--
he's got to show the
Volcom crew around,
and all that stuff.
But it's kind of like, well he
kind of found all these spots.
TRAVIS RICE: He came
in, fresh eyes.
He's like, there's mountains
360 degrees
around Jackson Hole.
That's why it's called a hole.
Wonder what's up there,
or up there?
So he set off on a quest
to go to discover what
the hell was up there.
And I was lucky enough to get
on board years later.
And he kind of showed
me the ropes.
WILLIE MCMILLON: It's kind of
the place where when people
just get over the nonsense,
they come out here.
And now there's like enough
cool people out here, that
it's accepted.
Like, I'm moving to Jackson,
and your sponsors
are like, right on.
BRYAN FOX: For like a kid in
Southern California to see
someone from Southern California
leave and turn into
a back country, more or less
like wilderness snowboarder
type of guys, that's definitely
inspiring.
WILLIE MCMILLON: I think
Harrison Ford is
kind of like the Guch.
You know, like, Harrison Ford
made it cool for Hollywood
people to move out here.
And Guch made it cool for pro
snowboarders to move out here.
-Oh, good.
We got all the dirt on you
now. dirt on you now.
BRYAN IGUCHI: Oh, no.
WILLIE MCMILLON: I talked so
much shit, dude, it wasn't
even funny.
No, I kept it clean.
-Your career is over.
BRYAN IGUCHI: Damn it.
You spoiled it.
WILLIE MCMILLON: No.
We kept it family style.