SHANE SMITH: Hi, I'm
Shane Smith.
And we're here in the Vice
offices in Brooklyn, New York.
As a thank you for hitting 1
million subscribers on our
Vice YouTube channel, we wanted
to take you in, show
you around, on how we
hit that million.
So come on, let's go inside.
In here is editorial, where
people write all the stuff and
come up with all the stories.
This Alex Pasternack, who
runs Motherboard.
What stories are
you working on?
ALEX PASTERNACK: We're doing
something right now about 3D
printed guns.
SHANE SMITH: 3D printed guns?
Do they work?
Can you shoot them?
[HIGH-PITCHED SHOTS]
ALEX PASTERNACK: Yeah,
they sure do.
SHANE SMITH: 3D printed
guns, it's the future.
So this is all the writing,
editorial.
And then we go through here.
These are all edit suites, where
we edit all the stories.
What are you working on?
TRAVIS WOOD: Working on
a Fringes episode.
It's called Gaddafi Wiki.
SHANE SMITH: Fringes
is a series on?
YouTube.
Corruption, dictators, Muammar
Gaddafi, you're going to watch
it on YouTube.
Everybody editing.
That looks interesting.
I don't know what it is.
Let's go upstairs.
Hi, this is Matt Schoen.
He's our art director.
He makes us seem smart.
So now we'll go in here.
This is production.
So this is where the stories,
like scopolamine, which is the
"World's Scariest Drug", or the
world's freakiest drug,
snake venom, or cannibals,
interview with a cannibal, or
when I went to Liberia to hang
out with cannibal warlords,
any of that stuff,
it happens here.
These are the producers that
come up with the ideas and
deal with the red tape
to get us in.
And this year, we will be
working on stories coming out
of Afghanistan, Iran, Iraq,
South America, West Africa.
We have a lot of breaking
news stories, a lot
of interesting stuff.
We wanted to say, thank
you from Vice
for the first million.
On the second million, I'll
do the whole tour naked.
Thank you very much,
1 million subs.
Stay tuned, the best
is yet to come.
Bang-o.