STEPHANIE IZARD: All right,
cheers to me.
Holy shit, I am not drinking
that whole thing.
Beautiful.
It's just fun in here.
It is like a party
all the time.
For me, it's just all about
flavor and it's having people
take a bite and then
they're like whoa.
And there's just so much flavor
going on in their mouths.
My name is Stephanie Izard, I'm
the chef and owner of Girl
& The Goat.
I went to University of Michigan
for undergrad first.
I was a sociology major.
I started working at the Olive
Garden, that was my first
industry job.
Their bread sticks are pretty
damn tasty, I'm
not going to lie.
After college I ended up going
to culinary school.
My dad was like, you know, you
haven't found anything you
love in college as much as you
love cooking, so you should go
to culinary school.
And I think at the time I
really thought that you
graduate culinary school
and you're like a chef.
I didn't get that you graduate
culinary school and you make
$7 an hour and you make salads,
but I was super
excited anyway.
So my dad's like, you're going
to make $7 an hour?
I was like yeah, I'm going
to make some salads.
It's going to be awesome.
The restaurant I was working at
closed for renovations, and
I came out to Chicago to visit
some friends for a few days.
While I was out here, it was
June when it's actually
beautiful here.
And there were just nice
people and cute boys
everywhere and I was like,
I'm moving to Chicago.
I make decisions just
sort of last minute
without telling anybody.
So these are my two not a lot
of hair Jared friends.
I've actually known this not a
lot of hair Jared for longer.
When did we meet, like
four years ago?
JARED VAN CAMP: Four or
five years ago, yeah.
STEPHANIE IZARD: I was dating
his friend who's
a chef in the city.
JARED VAN CAMP: Yeah,
I remember it.
STEPHANIE IZARD: And this is
Jared I met like, what did we
decide, two months ago?
JARED ROUBEN: I think so.
JARED VAN CAMP: So, we got cotto
salami, finocchiona,
toscano salami, chorizo,
sopressata, a little pastrami,
pate de compagne, some toast,
picalilly, and some assorted
pickles and olives.
STEPHANIE IZARD: Yeah, I was
actually thinking about this
this afternoon, because I was
thinking about meeting up with
you and we're going
to go find Koren.
All of our chefs that are--
and I was like are we the
young generation?
I was like, we're kind of like
the medium-age generation.
But it's sort of like
our generation.
Nothing against the slightly--
JARED VAN CAMP: Older?
STEPHANIE IZARD: Just ahead of
our time, but people we all
worked for like Shawn McClain,
and Paul Kahan, and Rick
Bayless and Charlie Trotter,
and all the people that--
JARED VAN CAMP: Yeah,
for sure.
STEPHANIE IZARD: And now we're
just sort of the people that
worked for them.
And now we're all just
buddy buddies, let's
make Chicago awesome.
JARED VAN CAMP: It's one of the
coolest things about being
in Chicago, is the camaraderie
in the industry.
STEPHANIE IZARD: We just want
the city to get better.
We want to open fun, cool
restaurants and support local
and do as many charities
as we can.
And all do it together because
you can't do it by yourself.
I think chefs all love hanging
out with each other because we
also learn from each other.
So I guess the more stuff I can
get out there and do while
still keeping this place
running, the better.
So then I take both Jareds, both
non-hair Jareds, over to
Avec because it's my favorite
restaurant in the city.
Yeah, whenever I'm asked what's
the favorite restaurant
in the city, Avec, Avec, Avec.
Going to Avec is going and
hanging with your friends and
drinking and eating and
exactly what we
try to capture here.
Koren's just cool.
We became friends a couple
of years ago.
I mean, maybe a little bit of
it is like oh, cool, another
cool chick chef that I
can hang out with.
But we hang out at events
together, we're just sort of
into supporting the
same things.
Brandade, brandade, and--
JARED VAN CAMP: No, no,
Stephanie, it's OK.
No, really, I'm sorry.
KOREN GRIEVESON:
Grammer pizza.
STEPHANIE IZARD: Queso, fresco,
green figs, Serrano,
and de coto.
JARED VAN CAMP: I like that.
STEPHANIE IZARD: So
just delisio?
STEPHANIE IZARD: Delisio
ricotta--
KOREN GRIEVESON: A little
truffle oil.
STEPHANIE IZARD: A little
truffle oil in between
flatbread that's sliced
really thin, and
it's freaking delicious.
You're probably my only close,
female friend chef.
STEPHANIE IZARD: Anything.
JARED ROUBEN: Boom.
KOREN GRIEVESON: Let's
put it out there.
STEPHANIE IZARD: In this city
though, I don't have any other
chick chef friends.
I think that most women
just decide to either
go one way or another.
They're going to go have a
family and have children, or
stick with a career.
Maybe that's why there's
not so many.
It always comes up
in conversation.
Why are there so few females?
And I don't know, maybe more
chicks should be doing this I
guess would be my answer.
STEPHANIE IZARD: It is.
I mean, for anyone.
It's suddenly taking
a toll on me.
Yesterday, I honestly, to leave
work early, and I just
slept for 12 hours straight.
For some reason there are just
more men in the industry.
And I think part of it's
also when I started
working on the industry--
I'm not easily offended and
nothing that guys can say in
the kitchen is going to
bother me whatsoever.
If they want to talk about
picking up chicks, or I'm not
going to get into the
things that get
talked about in kitchens.
But if you're easily offended
it's not going to work well
for you, I'll just say
that for women.
I love the brandade.
Salty, creamy goodness with
little teeny specks of [BLEEP]
crunchy.
JARED ROUBEN: It is
so delicious.
STEPHANIE IZARD: I know.
JARED VAN CAMP: Hold on.
Salty, creamy goodness
with little [BLEEP]
specks of
STEPHANIE IZARD: A teeny
spice of crunchy.
JARED VAN CAMP: You should put
it on the menu as that.
STEPHANIE IZARD: After Avec, we
walked down the street with
our new little posse of
chefs, walking back
to Girl & The Goat.
We were doing this "Elle"
magazine shoot a few weeks
ago, and they wanted us to look
like we were after work
eating lamb shanks together
and stuff.
And I was like, why don't
we do that after work?
That's pretty sweet.
So it's basically grilled
octopus with a fish sauce
vinaigrette.
Fava beans, yellow wax beans, a
little bit of the house wine
[INAUDIBLE], and some lemon
pistachio vinaigrette.
It's one of my favorite
things I make.
ALL: Cheers!
STEPHANIE IZARD: One of my
bartenders one day, I got to
work, he's like what's
the deal?
He's like, you work
18 hours a day--
18, 19, 20, 21, 22--
drink four and sleep two,
if that adds up to 24.
I'm not even sure right now.
MALE SPEAKER: I'm getting paid
and I'm eating food?
This is awesome.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Cheers
to you, [INAUDIBLE].
MALE SPEAKER: I'm going to get
out of here before we've got
to clean up, for sure.
I'm hopping on the bike
and I'm gone.
JARED ROUBEN: Here's to being
better-looking than that table.
ALL: Woo!
FEMALE SPEAKER: Yeah!
STEPHANIE IZARD: I mean, I don't
think you need to go out
and party until 4:00 AM with
your chefs all the time--
sometimes I do that.
Even if I hang out with them,
and party with them, and take
them to events and have a good
time, they still will listen
when I'm like, you're not
plating that right.
I guess there's different ways
of getting respect from people
that work for you.
And maybe there's some people
that work here that think I am
just a crazy party girl and
they're like great boss lady.
But I think for the most part
we've just created this really
fun atmosphere to work in.
I've worked places where I go
into other kitchens and it's
absolute dead silence.
And I've worked in a
kitchen where I got
in trouble for laughing.
And, I don't know, I laugh
a lot, I sing and
dance with my cooks.
It's all about having fun.
Eating's about having fun,
so cooking should be
about having fun.
JARED VAN CAMP: There we go!
ALL: Woo hoo!