waiting all day to talk to you, so I want
to get right to it.
Governor Romney, as you know, you won the
coin toss, so the first question will go to
you. And I want to turn to a first-time voter,
Jeremy Epstein, who has a question for you.
QUESTION: Mr. President, Governor Romney,
as a 20-year-old college student, all I hear
from professors, neighbors and others is that
when I graduate, I will have little chance
to get employment. What can you say to reassure
me, but more importantly my parents, that
I will be able to sufficiently support myself
after I graduate?
ROMNEY: Thank you, Jeremy. I appreciate your
— your question, and thank you for being
here this evening and to all of those from
Nassau County that have come, thank you for
your time. Thank you to Hofstra University
and to Candy Crowley for organizing and leading
this — this event.
Thank you, Mr. President, also for being part
of this — this debate.
Your question — your question is one that’s
being asked by college kids all over this
country. I was in Pennsylvania with someone
who had just graduated — this was in Philadelphia
— and she said, “I’ve got my degree.
I can’t find a job. I’ve got three part-
time jobs. They’re just barely enough to
pay for my food and pay for an apartment.
I can’t begin to pay back my student loans.”
So what we have to do is two things. We have
to make sure that we make it easier for kids
to afford college.
ROMNEY: And also make sure that when they
get out of college, there’s a job. When
I was governor of Massachusetts, to get a
high school degree, you had to pass an exam.
If you graduated in the top quarter of your
airlines, we gave you a John and Abigail Adams
scholarship, four years tuition free in the
college of your choice in Massachusetts, it’s
a public institution.
I want to make sure we keep our Pell grant
program growing. We’re also going to have
our loan program, so that people are able
to afford school. But the key thing is to
make sure you can get a job when you get out
of school. And what’s happened over the
last four years has been very, very hard for
America’s young people. I want you to be
able to get a job.
I know what it takes to get this economy going.
With half of college kids graduating this
year without a college — excuse me, without
a job. And without a college level job, that’s
just unacceptable.
And likewise you’ve got more and more debt
on your back. So more debt and less jobs.
I’m going to change that. I know what it
takes to create good jobs again. I know what
it takes to make sure that you have the kind
of opportunity you deserve. And kids across
this country are going to recognize, we’re
bringing back an economy.
It’s not going to be like the last four
years. The middle-class has been crushed over
the last four years, and jobs have been too
scarce. I know what it takes to bring them
back, and I’m going to do that, and make
sure that when you graduate — when do you
graduate?
QUESTION: 2014.
ROMNEY: 2014. When you come out in 2014, I
presume I’m going to be president. I’m
going to make sure you get a job. Thanks Jeremy.
Yeah, you bet.
CROWLEY: Mr. President?
OBAMA: Jeremy, first of all, your future is
bright. And the fact that you’re making
an investment in higher education is critical.
Not just to you, but to the entire nation.
Now, the most important thing we can do is
to make sure that we are creating jobs in
this country. But not just jobs, good paying
jobs. Ones that can support a family.
OBAMA: And what I want to do, is build on
the five million jobs that we’ve created
over the last 30 months in the private sector
alone. And there are a bunch of things we
can do to make sure your future is bright.
Number one, I want to build manufacturing
jobs in this country again. Now when Governor
Romney said we should let Detroit go bankrupt.
I said we’re going to bet on American workers
and the American auto industry and it’s
come surging back.
I want to do that in industries, not just
in Detroit, but all across the country and
that means we change our tax code so we’re
giving incentives to companies that are investing
here in the United States and creating jobs
here.
It also means we’re helping them and small
businesses to export all around the world
to new markets.
Number two, we’ve got to make sure that
we have the best education system in the world.
And the fact that you’re going to college
is great, but I want everybody to get a great
education and we’ve worked hard to make
sure that student loans are available for
folks like you, but I also want to make sure
that community colleges are offering slots
for workers to get retrained for the jobs
that are out there right now and the jobs
of the future.
Number three, we’ve got to control our own
energy. Now, not only oil and natural gas,
which we’ve been investing in; but also,
we’ve got to make sure we’re building
the energy source of the future, not just
thinking about next year, but ten years from
now, 20 years from now. That’s why we’ve
invested in solar and wind and biofuels, energy
efficient cars.
We’ve got to reduce our deficit, but we’ve
got to do it in a balanced way. Asking the
wealthy to pay a little bit more along with
cuts so that we can invest in education like
yours.
And let’s take the money that we’ve been
spending on war over the last decade to rebuild
America, roads, bridges schools. We do those
things, not only is your future going to be
bright but America’s future is going to
bright as well.
CROWLEY: Let me ask you for more immediate
answer and begin with Mr. Romney just quickly
what — what can you do? We’re looking
at a situation where 40 percent of the unemployed
have been unemployed have been unemployed
for six months or more. They don’t have
the two years that Jeremy has.
What about those long term unemployed who
need a job right now?
ROMNEY: Well what you’re seeing in this
country is 23 million people struggling to
find a job. And a lot of them, as you say,
Candy, have been out of work for a long, long,
long time. The president’s policies have
been exercised over the last four years and
they haven’t put Americans back to work.
We have fewer people working today than we
had when the president took office. If the
— the unemployment rate was 7.8 percent
when he took office, it’s 7.8 percent now.
But if you calculated that unemployment rate,
taking back the people who dropped out of
the workforce, it would be 10.7 percent.
We have not made the progress we need to make
to put people back to work. That’s why I
put out a five-point plan that gets America
12 million new jobs in four years and rising
take-home pay. It’s going to help Jeremy
get a job when he comes out of school. It’s
going to help people across the country that
are unemployed right now.
And one thing that the president said, which
I want to make sure that we understand, he
said that I said we should take Detroit bankrupt.
And that’s right. My plan was to have the
company go through bankruptcy like 7-Eleven
did and Macy’s and Condell (ph) Airlines
and come out stronger.
And I know he keeps saying, you want to take
Detroit bankrupt. Well, the president took
Detroit bankrupt. You took General Motors
bankrupt. You took Chrysler bankrupt. So when
you say that I wanted to take the auto industry
bankrupt, you actually did.
And I think it’s important to know that
that was a process that was necessary to get
those companies back on their feet, so they
could start hiring more people. That was precisely
what I recommended and ultimately what happened.
CROWLEY: Let me give the president a chance.
Go ahead. OBAMA: Candy, what Governor Romney
said just isn’t true. He wanted to take
them into bankruptcy without providing them
any way to stay open. And we would have lost
a million jobs. And that — don’t take
my word for it, take the executives at GM
and Chrysler, some of whom are Republicans,
may even support Governor Romney. But they’ll
tell you his prescription wasn’t going to
work.
And Governor Romney’s says he’s got a
five-point plan? Governor Romney doesn’t
have a five-point plan. He has a one-point
plan. And that plan is to make sure that folks
at the top play by a different set of rules.
That’s been his philosophy in the private
sector, that’s been his philosophy as governor,
that’s been his philosophy as a presidential
candidate.
You can make a lot of money and pay lower
tax rates than somebody who makes a lot less.
You can ship jobs overseas and get tax breaks
for it. You can invest in a company, bankrupt
it, lay off the workers, strip away their
pensions, and you still make money.
That’s exactly the philosophy that we’ve
seen in place for the last decade. That’s
what’s been squeezing middle class families.
And we have fought back for four years to
get out of that mess. The last thing we need
to do is to go back to the very same policies
that got us there.
CROWLEY: Mr. President, the next question
is going to be for you here.
And, Mr. Romney — Governor Romney — there’ll
be plenty of chances here to go on, but I
want to…
ROMNEY: That — that Detroit — that Detroit
answer…
CROWLEY: We have all these folks.
ROMNEY: … that Detroit answer…
CROWLEY: I will let you absolutely…
ROMNEY: … and the rest of the answer, way
off the mark.
CROWLEY: OK. Will — will — you certainly
will have lots of time here coming up.
Because I want to move you on to something
that’s sort of connected to cars here, and
— and go over. And we want to get a question
from Phillip Tricolla.
QUESTION: Your energy secretary, Steven Chu,
has now been on record three times stating
it’s not policy of his department to help
lower gas prices. Do you agree with Secretary
Chu that this is not the job of the Energy
Department?
OBAMA: The most important thing we can do
is to make sure we control our own energy.
So here’s what I’ve done since I’ve
been president. We have increased oil production
to the highest levels in 16 years.
Natural gas production is the highest it’s
been in decades. We have seen increases in
coal production and coal employment. But what
I’ve also said is we can’t just produce
traditional source of energy. We’ve also
got to look to the future. That’s why we
doubled fuel efficiency standards on cars.
That means that in the middle of the next
decade, any car you buy, you’re going to
end up going twice as far on a gallon of gas.
That’s why we doubled clean — clean energy
production like wind and solar and biofuels.
And all these things have contributed to us
lowering our oil imports to the lowest levels
in 16 years. Now, I want to build on that.
And that means, yes, we still continue to
open up new areas for drilling. We continue
to make it a priority for us to go after natural
gas. We’ve got potentially 600,000 jobs
and 100 years worth of energy right beneath
our feet with natural gas.
And we can do it in an environmentally sound
way. But we’ve also got to continue to figure
out how we have efficiency energy, because
ultimately that’s how we’re going to reduce
demand and that’s what’s going to keep
gas prices lower.
Now, Governor Romney will say he’s got an
all-of-the-above plan, but basically his plan
is to let the oil companies write the energy
policies. So he’s got the oil and gas part,
but he doesn’t have the clean energy part.
And if we are only thinking about tomorrow
or the next day and not thinking about 10
years from now, we’re not going to control
our own economic future. Because China, Germany,
they’re making these investments. And I’m
not going to cede those jobs of the future
to those countries. I expect those new energy
sources to be built right here in the United
States.
That’s going to help Jeremy get a job. It’s
also going to make sure that you’re not
paying as much for gas.
CROWLEY: Governor, on the subject of gas prices?
ROMNEY: Well, let’s look at the president’s
policies, all right, as opposed to the rhetoric,
because we’ve had four years of policies
being played out. And the president’s right
in terms of the additional oil production,
but none of it came on federal land. As a
matter of fact, oil production is down 14
percent this year on federal land, and gas
production was down 9 percent. Why? Because
the president cut in half the number of licenses
and permits for drilling on federal lands,
and in federal waters.
So where’d the increase come from? Well
a lot of it came from the Bakken Range in
North Dakota. What was his participation there?
The administration brought a criminal action
against the people drilling up there for oil,
this massive new resource we have. And what
was the cost? 20 or 25 birds were killed and
brought out a migratory bird act to go after
them on a criminal basis.
Look, I want to make sure we use our oil,
our coal, our gas, our nuclear, our renewables.
I believe very much in our renewable capabilities;
ethanol, wind, solar will be an important
part of our energy mix.
But what we don’t need is to have the president
keeping us from taking advantage of oil, coal
and gas. This has not been Mr. Oil, or Mr.
Gas, or Mr. Coal. Talk to the people that
are working in those industries. I was in
coal country. People grabbed my arms and said,
“Please save my job.” The head of the
EPA said, “You can’t build a coal plant.
You’ll virtually — it’s virtually impossible
given our regulations.” When the president
ran for office, he said if you build a coal
plant, you can go ahead, but you’ll go bankrupt.
That’s not the right course for America.
Let’s take advantage of the energy resources
we have, as well as the energy sources for
the future. And if we do that, if we do what
I’m planning on doing, which is getting
us energy independent, North America energy
independence within eight years, you’re
going to see manufacturing jobs come back.
Because our energy is low cost, that are already
beginning to come back because of our abundant
energy. I’ll get America and North America
energy independent. I’ll do it by more drilling,
more permits and licenses.
We’re going to bring that pipeline in from
Canada. How in the world the president said
no to that pipeline? I will never know.
This is about bringing good jobs back for
the middle class of America, and that’s
what I’m going to do. CROWLEY: Mr. President,
let me just see if I can move you to the gist
of this question, which is, are we looking
at the new normal? I can tell you that tomorrow
morning, a lot of people in Hempstead will
wake up and fill up and they will find that
the price of gas is over $4 a gallon.
Is it within the purview of the government
to bring those prices down, or are we looking
at the new normal?
OBAMA: Candy, there’s no doubt that world
demand’s gone up, but our production is
going up, and we’re using oil more efficiently.
And very little of what Governor Romney just
said is true. We’ve opened up public lands.
We’re actually drilling more on public lands
than in the previous administration and my
— the previous president was an oil man.
And natural gas isn’t just appearing magically.
We’re encouraging it and working with the
industry.
And when I hear Governor Romney say he’s
a big coal guy, I mean, keep in mind, when
— Governor, when you were governor of Massachusetts,
you stood in front of a coal plant and pointed
at it and said, “This plant kills,” and
took great pride in shutting it down. And
now suddenly you’re a big champion of coal.
So what I’ve tried to do is be consistent.
With respect to something like coal, we made
the largest investment in clean coal technology,
to make sure that even as we’re producing
more coal, we’re producing it cleaner and
smarter. Same thing with oil, same thing with
natural gas.
And the proof is our oil imports are down
to the lowest levels in 20 years. Oil production
is up, natural gas production is up, and,
most importantly, we’re also starting to
build cars that are more efficient.
And that’s creating jobs. That means those
cars can be exported, ‘cause that’s the
demand around the world, and it also means
that it’ll save money in your pocketbook.
OBAMA: That’s the strategy you need, an
all-of-the-above strategy, and that’s what
we’re going to do in the next four years.
ROMNEY: But that’s not what you’ve done
in the last four years. That’s the problem.
In the last four years, you cut permits and
licenses on federal land and federal waters
in half.
OBAMA: Not true, Governor Romney.
ROMNEY: So how much did you cut (inaudible)?
OBAMA: Not true.
ROMNEY: How much did you cut them by, then?
OBAMA: Governor, we have actually produced
more oil –
ROMNEY: No, no. How much did you cut licenses
and permits on federal land and federal waters?
OBAMA: Governor Romney, here’s what we did.
There were a whole bunch of oil companies.
(CROSSTALK)
ROMNEY: No, no, I had a question and the question
was how much did you cut them by?
OBAMA: You want me to answer a question –
ROMNEY: How much did you cut them by?
OBAMA: I’m happy to answer the question.
ROMNEY: All right. And it is –
OBAMA: Here’s what happened. You had a whole
bunch of oil companies who had leases on public
lands that they weren’t using. So what we
said was you can’t just sit on this for
10, 20, 30 years, decide when you want to
drill, when you want to produce, when it’s
most profitable for you. These are public
lands. So if you want to drill on public lands,
you use it or you lose it.
ROMNEY: OK, (inaudible) –
OBAMA: And so what we did was take away those
leases. And we are now reletting them so that
we can actually make a profit.
ROMNEY: And production on private — on government
land –
OBAMA: Production is up.
ROMNEY: — is down.
OBAMA: No, it isn’t.
ROMNEY: Production on government land of oil
is down 14 percent.
OBAMA: Governor –
ROMNEY: And production on gas –
(CROSSTALK)
OBAMA: It’s just not true.
ROMNEY: It’s absolutely true. Look, there’s
no question but the people recognize that
we have not produced more (inaudible) on federal
lands and in federal waters. And coal, coal
production is not up; coal jobs are not up.
I was just at a coal facility, where some
1,200 people lost their jobs. The right course
for America is to have a true all-of-the-above
policy. I don’t think anyone really believes
that you’re a person who’s going to be
pushing for oil and gas and coal. You’ll
get your chance in a moment. I’m still speaking.
OBAMA: Well –
ROMNEY: And the answer is I don’t believe
people think that’s the case –
OBAMA: — (inaudible).
ROMNEY: That wasn’t the question.
OBAMA: OK.
ROMNEY: That was a statement. I don’t think
the American people believe that. I will fight
for oil, coal and natural gas. And the proof,
the proof of whether a strategy is working
or not is what the price is that you’re
paying at the pump. If you’re paying less
than you paid a year or two ago, why, then,
the strategy is working. But you’re paying
more. When the president took office, the
price of gasoline here in Nassau County was
about $1.86 a gallon. Now, it’s $4.00 a
gallon. The price of electricity is up.
If the president’s energy policies are working,
you’re going to see the cost of energy come
down. I will fight to create more energy in
this country, to get America energy secure.
And part of that is bringing in a pipeline
of oil from Canada, taking advantage of the
oil and coal we have here, drilling offshore
in Alaska, drilling offshore in Virginia where
the people want it. Those things will get
us the energy we need.
CROWLEY: Mr. President, could you address,
because we did finally get to gas prices here,
could you address what the governor said,
which is if your energy policy was working,
the price of gasoline would not be $4 a gallon
here. Is that true?
OBAMA: Well, think about what the governor
— think about what the governor just said.
He said when I took office, the price of gasoline
was $1.80, $1.86. Why is that? Because the
economy was on the verge of collapse, because
we were about to go through the worst recession
since the Great Depression, as a consequence
of some of the same policies that Governor
Romney’s now promoting.
So, it’s conceivable that Governor Romney
could bring down gas prices because with his
policies, we might be back in that same mess.
What I want to do is to create an economy
that is strong, and at the same time produce
energy. And with respect to this pipeline
that Governor Romney keeps on talking about,
we’ve — we’ve built enough pipeline
to wrap around the entire earth once.
So, I’m all for pipelines. I’m all for
oil production. What I’m not for is us ignoring
the other half of the equation. So, for example,
on wind energy, when Governor Romney says
“these are imaginary jobs.” When you’ve
got thousands of people right now in Iowa,
right now in Colorado, who are working, creating
wind power with good-paying manufacturing
jobs, and the Republican senator in that — in
Iowa is all for it, providing tax breaks (ph)
to help this work and Governor Romney says
I’m opposed. I’d get rid of it.
That’s not an energy strategy for the future.
And we need to win that future. And I intend
to win it as President of the United States.
CROWLEY: I got to — I got to move you on
–
ROMNEY: He gets the first –
CROWLEY: — and the next question –
ROMNEY: He actually got –
CROWLEY: — for you –
ROMNEY: He actually got the first question.
So I get the last question — last answer
–
CROWLEY: (Inaudible) in the follow up, it
doesn’t quite work like that. But I’m
going to give you a chance here. I promise
you, I’m going to.
And the next question is for you. So if you
want to, you know, continue on — but I don’t
want to leave all –
ROMNEY: Candy, Candy –
CROWLEY: — sitting here –
ROMNEY: Candy, I don’t have a policy of
stopping wind jobs in Iowa and that — they’re
not phantom jobs. They’re real jobs.
CROWLEY: OK.
ROMNEY: I appreciate wind jobs in Iowa and
across our country. I appreciate the jobs
in coal and oil and gas. I’m going to make
sure –
CROWLEY: OK.
ROMNEY: — we’re taking advantage of our
energy resources. We’ll bring back manufacturing
to America. We’re going to get through a
very aggressive energy policy, 31/2 million
more jobs in this country. It’s critical
to our future.
OBAMA: Candy, it’s not going to –
CROWLEY: We’re going to move you along –
OBAMA: Used to being interrupted.
CROWLEY: We’re going to move you both along
to taxes over here and all these folks that
have been waiting.
Governor, this question is for you. It comes
from Mary Follano — Follano, sorry.
ROMNEY: Hi, Mary.
QUESTION: Governor Romney, you have stated
that if you’re elected president, you would
plan to reduce the tax rates for all the tax
brackets and that you would work with the
Congress to eliminate some deductions in order
to make up for the loss in revenue.
Concerning the — these various deductions,
the mortgage deductions, the charitable deductions,
the child tax credit and also the — oh,
what’s that other credit? I forgot.
OBAMA: You’re doing great.
QUESTION: Oh, I remember.
The education credits, which are important
to me, because I have children in college.
What would be your position on those things,
which are important to the middle class?
ROMNEY: Thank you very much. And let me tell
you, you’re absolutely right about part
of that, which is I want to bring the rates
down, I want to simplify the tax code, and
I want to get middle- income taxpayers to
have lower taxes.
And the reason I want middle-income taxpayers
to have lower taxes is because middle-income
taxpayers have been buried over the past four
years. You’ve seen, as middle-income people
in this country, incomes go down $4,300 a
family, even as gasoline prices have gone
up $2,000. Health insurance premiums, up $2,500.
Food prices up. Utility prices up.
The middle-income families in America have
been crushed over the last four years. So
I want to get some relief to middle-income
families. That’s part — that’s part
one.
Now, how about deductions? ‘Cause I’m
going to bring rates down across the board
for everybody, but I’m going to limit deductions
and exemptions and credits, particularly for
people at the high end, because I am not going
to have people at the high end pay less than
they’re paying now.
The top 5 percent of taxpayers will continue
to pay 60 percent of the income tax the nation
collects. So that’ll stay the same.
Middle-income people are going to get a tax
break.
And so, in terms of bringing down deductions,
one way of doing that would be say everybody
gets — I’ll pick a number — $25,000
of deductions and credits, and you can decide
which ones to use. Your home mortgage interest
deduction, charity, child tax credit, and
so forth, you can use those as part of filling
that bucket, if you will, of deductions.
But your rate comes down and the burden also
comes down on you for one more reason, and
that is every middle-income taxpayer no longer
will pay any tax on interest, dividends or
capital gains. No tax on your savings. That
makes life a lot easier.
If you’re getting interest from a bank,
if you’re getting a statement from a mutual
fund or any other kind of investment you have,
you don’t have to worry about filing taxes
on that, because there’ll be no taxes for
anybody making $200,000.00 per year and less,
on your interest, dividends and capital gains.
Why am I lowering taxes on the middle-class?
Because under the last four years, they’ve
been buried. And I want to help people in
the middle-class.
And I will not — I will not under any circumstances,
reduce the share that’s being paid by the
highest income taxpayers. And I will not,
under any circumstances increase taxes on
the middle-class. The president’s spending,
the president’s borrowing will cost this
nation to have to raise taxes on the American
people. Not just at the high end. A recent
study has shown the people in the middle-class
will see $4,000.00 per year in higher taxes
as a result of the spending and borrowing
of this administration.
I will not let that happen. I want to get
us on track to a balanced budget, and I’m
going to reduce the tax burden on middle income
families. And what’s that going to do? It’s
going to help those families, and it’s going
to create incentives to start growing jobs
again in this country.
CROWLEY: Thanks, Governor.
OBAMA: My philosophy on taxes has been simple.
And that is, I want to give middle-class families
and folks who are striving to get into the
middle-class some relief. Because they have
been hit hard over the last decade. Over the
last 15, over the last 20 years.
So four years ago I stood on a stage just
like this one. Actually it was a town hall,
and I said I would cut taxes for middle- class
families, and that’s what I’ve done, by
$3,600.00. I said I would cut taxes for small
businesses, who are the drivers and engines
of growth. And we’ve cut them 18 times.
And I want to continue those tax cuts for
middle-class families, and for small business.
But what I’ve also said is, if we’re serious
about reducing the deficit, if this is genuinely
a moral obligation to the next generation,
then in addition to some tough spending cuts,
we’ve also got to make sure that the wealthy
do a little bit more.
So what I’ve said is, your first $250,000.00
worth of income, no change. And that means
98 percent of American families, 97 percent
of small businesses, they will not see a tax
increase. I’m ready to sign that bill right
now. The only reason it’s not happening
is because Governor Romney’s allies in Congress
have held the 98 percent hostage because they
want tax breaks for the top 2 percent.
But what I’ve also says is for above $250,000,
we can go back to the tax rates we had when
Bill Clinton was president. We created 23
million new jobs. That’s part of what took
us from deficits to surplus. It will be good
for our economy and it will be good for job
creation.
Now, Governor Romney has a different philosophy.
He was on 60 Minutes just two weeks ago and
he was asked: Is it fair for somebody like
you, making $20 million a year, to pay a lower
tax rate than a nurse or a bus driver, somebody
making $50,000 year? And he said, “Yes,
I think that’s fair.” Not only that, he
said, “I think that’s what grows the economy.”
Well, I fundamentally disagree with that.
I think what grows the economy is when you
get that tax credit that we put in place for
your kids going to college. I think that grows
the economy. I think what grows the economy
is when we make sure small businesses are
getting a tax credit for hiring veterans who
fought for our country. That grows our economy.
So we just have a different theory. And when
Governor Romney stands here, after a year
of campaigning, when during a Republican primary
he stood on stage and said “I’m going
to give tax cuts” — he didn’t say tax
rate cuts, he said “tax cuts to everybody,”
including the top 1 percent, you should believe
him because that’s been his history.
And that’s exactly the kind of top-down
economics that is not going to work if we
want a strong middle class and an economy
that’s striving for everybody.
CROWLEY: Governor Romney, I’m sure you’ve
got a reply there.
(LAUGHTER) ROMNEY: You’re absolutely right.
You heard what I said about my tax plan. The
top 5 percent will continue to pay 60 percent,
as they do today. I’m not looking to cut
taxes for wealthy people. I am looking to
cut taxes for middle-income people.
And why do I want to bring rates down, and
at the same time lower exemptions and deductions,
particularly for people at the high end? Because
if you bring rates down, it makes it easier
for small business to keep more of their capital
and hire people.
And for me, this is about jobs. I want to
get America’s economy going again. Fifty-four
percent of America’s workers work in businesses
that are taxed as individuals. So when you
bring those rates down, those small businesses
are able to keep more money and hire more
people.
For me, I look at what’s happened in the
last four years and say this has been a disappointment.
We can do better than this. We don’t have
to settle for, how many months, 43 months
with unemployment above 8 percent, 23 million
Americans struggling to find a good job right
now.
There are 3.5 million more women living in
poverty today than when the president took
office.
We don’t have to live like this. We can
get this economy going again. My five-point
plan does it. Energy independence for North
America in five years. Opening up more trade,
particularly in Latin America. Cracking down
on China when they cheat. Getting us to a
balanced budget. Fixing our training programs
for our workers. And finally, championing
small business.
I want to make small businesses grow and thrive.
I know how to make that happen. I spent my
life in the private sector. I know why jobs
come and why they go. And they’re going
now because of the policies of this administration.
CROWLEY: Governor, let me ask the president
something about what you just said.
The governor says that he is not going to
allow the top 5 percent, believe is what he
said, to have a tax cut, that it will all
even out, that what he wants to do is give
that tax cut to the middle class. Settled?
OBAMA: No, it’s not settled.
Look, the cost of lowering rates for everybody
across the board, 20 percent. Along with what
he also wants to do in terms of eliminating
the estate tax, along what he wants to do
in terms of corporates, changes in the tax
code, it costs about $5 trillion.
Governor Romney then also wants to spend $2
trillion on additional military programs even
though the military’s not asking for them.
That’s $7 trillion.
He also wants to continue the Bush tax cuts
for the wealthiest Americans. That’s another
trillion dollars — that’s $8 trillion.
Now, what he says is he’s going to make
sure that this doesn’t add to the deficit
and he’s going to cut middleclass taxes.
But when he’s asked, how are you going to
do it, which deductions, which loopholes are
you going to close? He can’t tell you.
The — the fact that he only has to pay 14
percent on his taxes when a lot of you are
paying much higher. He’s already taken that
off the board, capital gains are going to
continue to be at a low rate so we — we’re
not going to get money that way.
We haven’t heard from the governor any specifics
beyond Big Bird and eliminating funding for
Planned Parenthood in terms of how he pays
for that.
Now, Governor Romney was a very successful
investor. If somebody came to you, Governor,
with a plan that said, here, I want to spend
$7 or $8 trillion, and then we’re going
to pay for it, but we can’t tell you until
maybe after the election how we’re going
to do it, you wouldn’t take such a sketchy
deal and neither should you, the American
people, because the math doesn’t add up.
And — and what’s at stake here is one
of two things, either Candy — this blows
up the deficit because keep in mind, this
is just to pay for the additional spending
that he’s talking about, $7 trillion – $8
trillion before we even get to the deficit
we already have. Or, alternatively, it’s
got to be paid for, not only by closing deductions
for wealthy individuals, that — that will
pay for about 4 percent reduction in tax rates.
You’re going to be paying for it. You’re
going to lose some deductions, and you can’t
buy the sales pitch. Nobody who’s looked
at it that’s serious, actually believes
it adds up.
CROWLEY: Mr. President, let me get — let
me get the governor in on this. And Governor,
let’s — before we get into a…
ROMNEY: I — I…
CROWLEY: …vast array of who says — what
study says what, if it shouldn’t add up.
If somehow when you get in there, there isn’t
enough tax revenue coming in. If somehow the
numbers don’t add up, would you be willing
to look again at a 20 percent…
ROMNEY: Well of course they add up. I — I
was — I was someone who ran businesses for
25 years, and balanced the budget. I ran the
Olympics and balanced the budget. I ran the
— the state of Massachusetts as a governor,
to the extent any governor does, and balanced
the budget all four years. When we’re talking
about math that doesn’t add up, how about
$4 trillion of deficits over the last four
years, $5 trillion? That’s math that doesn’t
add up. We have — we have a president talking
about someone’s plan in a way that’s completely
foreign to what my real plan is.
ROMNEY: And then we have his own record, which
is we have four consecutive years where he
said when he was running for office, he would
cut the deficit in half. Instead he’s doubled
it. We’ve gone from $10 trillion of national
debt, to $16 trillion of national debt. If
the president were reelected, we’d go to
almost $20 trillion of national debt. This
puts us on a road to Greece. I know what it
takes to balance budgets. I’ve done it my
entire life. So for instance when he says,
“Yours is a $5 trillion cut.” Well, no
it’s not. Because I’m offsetting some
of the reductions with holding down some of
the deductions.
And…
CROWLEY: Governor, I’ve gotta — gotta
— actually, I need to have you both (inaudible).
(CROSSTALK)
CROWLEY: I understand the stakes here. I understand
both of you. But I — I will get run out
of town if I don’t…
(CROSSTALK)
ROMNEY: And I just described — I just described
to you, Mr. President — I just described
to you precisely how I’d do it which is
with a single number that people can put — and
they can put they’re — they’re deductions
and credits…
(CROSSTALK)
CROWLEY: Mr. President, we’re keeping track,
I promise you. And Mr. President, the next
question is for you, so stay standing.
OBAMA: Great. Looking forward to it.
And it’s Katherine Fenton, who has a question
for you.
QUESTION: In what new ways to you intend to
rectify the inequalities in the workplace,
specifically regarding females making only
72 percent of what their male counterparts
earn?
OBAMA: Well, Katherine, that’s a great question.
And, you know, I was raised by a single mom
who had to put herself through school while
looking after two kids. And she worked hard
every day and made a lot of sacrifices to
make sure we got everything we needed. My
grandmother, she started off as a secretary
in a bank. She never got a college education,
even though she was smart as a whip. And she
worked her way up to become a vice president
of a local bank, but she hit the glass ceiling.
She trained people who would end up becoming
her bosses during the course of her career.
She didn’t complain. That’s not what you
did in that generation. And this is one of
the reasons why one of the first — the first
bill I signed was something called the Lily
Ledbetter bill. And it’s named after this
amazing woman who had been doing the same
job as a man for years, found out that she
was getting paid less, and the Supreme Court
said that she couldn’t bring suit because
she should have found about it earlier, whereas
she had no way of finding out about it. So
we fixed that. And that’s an example of
the kind of advocacy that we need, because
women are increasingly the breadwinners in
the family. This is not just a women’s issue,
this is a family issue, this is a middle-class
issue, and that’s why we’ve got to fight
for it.
It also means that we’ve got to make sure
that young people like yourself are able to
afford a college education. Earlier, Governor
Romney talked about he wants to make Pell
Grants and other education accessible for
young people.
Well, the truth of the matter is, is that
that’s exactly what we’ve done. We’ve
expanded Pell Grants for millions of people,
including millions of young women, all across
the country.
We did it by taking $60 billion that was going
to banks and lenders as middlemen for the
student loan program, and we said, let’s
just cut out the middleman. Let’s give the
money directly to students.
And as a consequence, we’ve seen millions
of young people be able to afford college,
and that’s going to make sure that young
women are going to be able to compete in that
marketplace.
But we’ve got to enforce the laws, which
is what we are doing, and we’ve also got
to make sure that in every walk of life we
do not tolerate discrimination.
That’s been one of the hallmarks of my administration.
I’m going to continue to push on this issue
for the next four years.
CROWLEY: Governor Romney, pay equity for women?
ROMNEY: Thank you. And important topic, and
one which I learned a great deal about, particularly
as I was serving as governor of my state,
because I had the chance to pull together
a cabinet and all the applicants seemed to
be men.
And I — and I went to my staff, and I said,
“How come all the people for these jobs
are — are all men.” They said, “Well,
these are the people that have the qualifications.”
And I said, “Well, gosh, can’t we — can’t
we find some — some women that are also
qualified?”
ROMNEY: And — and so we — we took a concerted
effort to go out and find women who had backgrounds
that could be qualified to become members
of our cabinet.
I went to a number of women’s groups and
said, “Can you help us find folks,” and
they brought us whole binders full of women.
I was proud of the fact that after I staffed
my Cabinet and my senior staff, that the University
of New York in Albany did a survey of all
50 states, and concluded that mine had more
women in senior leadership positions than
any other state in America.
Now one of the reasons I was able to get so
many good women to be part of that team was
because of our recruiting effort. But number
two, because I recognized that if you’re
going to have women in the workforce that
sometimes you need to be more flexible. My
chief of staff, for instance, had two kids
that were still in school.
She said, I can’t be here until 7 or 8 o’clock
at night. I need to be able to get home at
5 o’clock so I can be there for making dinner
for my kids and being with them when they
get home from school. So we said fine. Let’s
have a flexible schedule so you can have hours
that work for you.
We’re going to have to have employers in
the new economy, in the economy I’m going
to bring to play, that are going to be so
anxious to get good workers they’re going
to be anxious to hire women. In the — in
the last women have lost 580,000 jobs. That’s
the net of what’s happened in the last four
years. We’re still down 580,000 jobs. I
mentioned 31/2 million women, more now in
poverty than four years ago.
What we can do to help young women and women
of all ages is to have a strong economy, so
strong that employers that are looking to
find good employees and bringing them into
their workforce and adapting to a flexible
work schedule that gives women opportunities
that they would otherwise not be able to afford.
This is what I have done. It’s what I look
forward to doing and I know what it takes
to make an economy work, and I know what a
working economy looks like. And an economy
with 7.8 percent unemployment is not a real
strong economy. An economy that has 23 million
people looking for work is not a strong economy.
An economy with 50 percent of kids graduating
from college that can’t finds a job, or
a college level job, that’s not what we
have to have. CROWLEY: Governor?
ROMNEY: I’m going to help women in America
get good work by getting a stronger economy
and by supporting women in the workforce.
CROWLEY: Mr. President why don’t you get
in on this quickly, please?
OBAMA: Katherine, I just want to point out
that when Governor Romney’s campaign was
asked about the Lilly Ledbetter bill, whether
he supported it? He said, “I’ll get back
to you.” And that’s not the kind of advocacy
that women need in any economy. Now, there
are some other issues that have a bearing
on how women succeed in the workplace. For
example, their healthcare. You know a major
difference in this campaign is that Governor
Romney feels comfortable having politicians
in Washington decide the health care choices
that women are making.
I think that’s a mistake. In my health care
bill, I said insurance companies need to provide
contraceptive coverage to everybody who is
insured. Because this is not just a — a
health issue, it’s an economic issue for
women. It makes a difference. This is money
out of that family’s pocket. Governor Romney
not only opposed it, he suggested that in
fact employers should be able to make the
decision as to whether or not a woman gets
contraception through her insurance coverage.
That’s not the kind of advocacy that women
need. When Governor Romney says that we should
eliminate funding for Planned Parenthood,
there are millions of women all across the
country, who rely on Planned Parenthood for,
not just contraceptive care, they rely on
it for mammograms, for cervical cancer screenings.
That’s a pocketbook issue for women and
families all across the country. And it makes
a difference in terms of how well and effectively
women are able to work. When we talk about
child care, and the credits that we’re providing.
That makes a difference in whether they can
go out there and — and earn a living for
their family.
These are not just women’s issues. These
are family issues. These are economic issues.
And one of the things that makes us grow as
an economy is when everybody participates
and women are getting the same fair deal as
men are.
CROWLEY: Mr. President…
OBAMA: And I’ve got two daughters and I
want to make sure that they have the same
opportunities that anybody’s sons have.
That’s part of what I’m fighting for as
president of the United States.
CROWLEY: I want to move us along here to Susan
Katz, who has a question.
And, Governor, it’s for you. QUESTION: Governor
Romney, I am an undecided voter, because I’m
disappointed with the lack of progress I’ve
seen in the last four years. However, I do
attribute much of America’s economic and
international problems to the failings and
missteps of the Bush administration.
Since both you and President Bush are Republicans,
I fear a return to the policies of those years
should you win this election. What is the
biggest difference between you and George
W. Bush, and how do you differentiate yourself
from George W. Bush?
ROMNEY: Thank you. And I appreciate that question.
I just want to make sure that, I think I was
supposed to get that last answer, but I want
to point out that that I don’t believe…
OBAMA: I don’t think so, Candy.
ROMNEY: … I don’t believe…
OBAMA: I want to make sure our timekeepers
are working here.
ROMNEY: The time — the time…
CROWLEY: OK. The timekeepers are all working.
And let me tell you that the last part, it’s
for the two of you to talk to one another,
and it isn’t quite as (inaudible) you think.
But go ahead and use this two minutes any
way you’d like to, the question is on the
floor.
ROMNEY: I’d just note that I don’t believe
that bureaucrats in Washington should tell
someone whether they can use contraceptives
or not. And I don’t believe employers should
tell someone whether they could have contraceptive
care of not. Every woman in America should
have access to contraceptives. And — and
the — and the president’s statement of
my policy is completely and totally wrong.
OBAMA: Governor…
ROMNEY: Let me come back and — and answer
your question.
President Bush and I are — are different
people and these are different times and that’s
why my five point plan is so different than
what he would have done.
I mean for instance, we can now, by virtue
of new technology actually get all the energy
we need in North America without having to
go to the — the Arabs or the Venezuelans
or anyone else. That wasn’t true in his
time, that’s why my policy starts with a
very robust policy to get all that energy
in North America — become energy secure.
Number two, trade — I’ll crack down on
China, President Bush didn’t. I’m also
going to dramatically expand trade in Latin
America. It’s been growing about 12 percent
per year over a long period of time. I want
to add more free trade agreements so we’ll
have more trade.
Number three, I’m going to get us to a balanced
budget. President Bush didn’t. President
Obama was right, he said that that was outrageous
to have deficits as high as half a trillion
dollars under the Bush years. He was right,
but then he put in place deficits twice that
size for every one of his four years. And
his forecast for the next four years is more
deficits, almost that large. So that’s the
next area I’m different than President Bush.
And then let’s take the last one, championing
small business. Our party has been focused
too long. I came through small business. I
understand how hard it is to start a small
business. That’s why everything I’ll do
is designed to help small businesses grow
and add jobs. I want to keep their taxes down
on small business. I want regulators to see
their job as encouraging small enterprise,
not crushing it.
And the thing I find the most troubling about
Obama Care, well it’s a long list, but one
of the things I find most troubling is that
when you go out and talk to small businesses
and ask them what they think about it, they
tell you it keeps them from hiring more people.
My priority is jobs. I know how to make that
happen. And President Bush has a very different
path for a very different time. My path is
designed in getting small businesses to grow
and hire people.
CROWLEY: Thanks, Governor.
Mr. President?
OBAMA: Well, first of all, I think it’s
important to tell you that we did come in
during some tough times. We were losing 800,000
jobs a month when I started. But we had been
digging our way out of policies that were
misplaced and focused on the top doing very
well and middle class folks not doing well.
Now, we’ve seen 30 consecutive — 31 consecutive
months of job growth; 5.2 million new jobs
created. And the plans that I talked about
will create even more. But when Governor Romney
says that he has a very different economic
plan, the centerpiece of his economic plan
are tax cuts. That’s what took us from surplus
to deficit. When he talks about getting tough
on China, keep in mind that Governor Romney
invested in companies that were pioneers of
outsourcing to China, and is currently investing
in countries — in companies that are building
surveillance equipment for China to spy on
its own folks.
That’s — Governor, you’re the last person
who’s going to get tough on China. And what
we’ve done when it comes to trade is not
only sign three trade deals to open up new
markets, but we’ve also set up a task force
for trade that goes after anybody who is taking
advantage of American workers or businesses
and not creating a level playing field. We’ve
brought twice as many cases against unfair
trading practices than the previous administration
and we’ve won every single one that’s
been decided.
When I said that we had to make sure that
China was not flooding our domestic market
with cheap tires, Governor Romney said I was
being protectionist; that it wouldn’t be
helpful to American workers. Well, in fact
we saved 1,000 jobs. And that’s the kind
of tough trade actions that are required.
But the last point I want to make is this.
You know, there are some things where Governor
Romney is different from George Bush. George
Bush didn’t propose turning Medicare into
a voucher. George Bush embraced comprehensive
immigration reform. He didn’t call for self-deportation.
George Bush never suggested that we eliminate
funding for Planned Parenthood, so there are
differences between Governor Romney and George
Bush, but they’re not on economic policy.
In some ways, he’s gone to a more extreme
place when it comes to social policy. And
I think that’s a mistake. That’s not how
we’re going to move our economy forward.
CROWLEY: I want to move you both along to
the next question, because it’s in the same
wheelhouse, so you will be able to respond.
But the president does get this question.
I want to call on Michael Jones.
QUESTION: Mr. President, I voted for you in
2008. What have you done or accomplished to
earn my vote in 2012? I’m not that optimistic
as I was in 2012. Most things I need for everyday
living are very expensive.
OBAMA: Well, we’ve gone through a tough
four years. There’s no doubt about it. But
four years ago, I told the American people
and I told you I would cut taxes for middle
class families. And I did. I told you I’d
cut taxes for small businesses, and I have.
I said that I’d end the war in Iraq, and
I did. I said we’d refocus attention on
those who actually attacked us on 9/11, and
we have gone after Al Qaeda’s leadership
like never before and Osama bin Laden is dead.
OBAMA: I said that we would put in place health
care reform to make sure that insurance companies
can’t jerk you around and if you don’t
have health insurance, that you’d have a
chance to get affordable insurance, and I
have.
I committed that I would rein in the excesses
of Wall Street, and we passed the toughest
Wall Street reforms since the 1930s. We’ve
created five million jobs, and gone from 800
jobs a month being lost, and we are making
progress. We saved an auto industry that was
on the brink of collapse.
Now, does that mean you’re not struggling?
Absolutely not. A lot of us are. And that’s
why the plan that I’ve put forward for manufacturing
and education, and reducing our deficit in
a sensible way, using the savings from ending
wars, to rebuild America and putting people
back to work. Making sure that we are controlling
our own energy, but not only the energy of
today, but also the energy of the future.
All of those things will make a difference,
so the point is the commitments I’ve made,
I’ve kept.
And those that I haven’t been able to keep,
it’s not for lack of trying and we’re
going to get it done in a second term. But,
you should pay attention to this campaign,
because Governor Romney has made some commitments
as well. And I suspect he’ll keep those
too. You know when members of the Republican
Congress say, “We’re going to sign a no
tax pledge, so that we don’t ask a dime
for millionaires and billionaires to reduce
our deficit so we can still invest in education,
and helping kids go to college. He said, “Me
too.”
When they said, “We’re going to cut Planned
Parenthood funding.” He said, “Me too.”
When he said, “We’re going to repeal Obamacare.
First thing I’m going to do,” despite
the fact that it’s the same health care
plan that he passed in Massachusetts and is
working well. He said, “Me too.” That
is not the kind of leadership that you need,
but you should expect that those are promises
he’s going to keep.
(CROSSTALK)
CROWLEY: Mr. President, let me let…
OBAMA: …the choice in this election is going
to be whose promises are going to be more
likely to help you in your life? Make sure
your kids can go to college. Make sure that
you are getting a good paying job, making
sure that Medicare and Social Security…
(CROSSTALK)
CROWLEY: Mr. President. Thank you.
OBAMA: …will be there for you.
CROWLEY: Thank you. Governor?
ROMNEY: I think you know better. I think you
know that these last four years haven’t
been so good as the president just described
and that you don’t feel like your confident
that the next four years are going to be much
better either.
I can tell you that if you were to elect President
Obama, you know what you’re going to get.
You’re going to get a repeat of the last
four years. We just can’t afford four more
years like the last four years.
He said that by now we’d have unemployment
at 5.4 percent. The difference between where
it is and 5.4 percent is 9 million Americans
without work.
I wasn’t the one that said 5.4 percent.
This was the president’s plan. Didn’t
get there.
He said he would have by now put forward a
plan to reform Medicare and Social Security,
because he pointed out they’re on the road
to bankruptcy. He would reform them. He’d
get that done. He hasn’t even made a proposal
on either one.
He said in his first year he’d put out an
immigration plan that would deal with our
immigration challenges. Didn’t even file
it.
This is a president who has not been able
to do what he said he’d do. He said that
he’d cut in half the deficit. He hasn’t
done that either. In fact, he doubled it.
He said that by now middle-income families
would have a reduction in their health insurance
premiums by $2,500 a year. It’s gone up
by $2,500 a year. And if Obamacare is passed,
or implemented — it’s already been passed
— if it’s implemented fully, it’ll be
another $2,500 on top.
ROMNEY: The middle class is getting crushed
under the policies of a president who has
not understood what it takes to get the economy
working again. He keeps saying, “Look, I’ve
created 5 million jobs.” That’s after
losing 5 million jobs. The entire record is
such that the unemployment has not been reduced
in this country. The unemployment, the number
of people who are still looking for work,
is still 23 million Americans.
There are more people in poverty, one out
of six people in poverty.
How about food stamps? When he took office,
32 million people were on food stamps. Today,
47 million people are on food stamps. How
about the growth of the economy? It’s growing
more slowly this year than last year, and
more slowly last year than the year before.
The president wants to do well. I understand.
But the policies he’s put in place from
Obamacare to Dodd-Frank to his tax policies
to his regulatory policies, these policies
combined have not let this economy take off
and grow like it could have.
You might say, “Well, you got an example
of one that worked better?” Yeah, in the
Reagan recession where unemployment hit 10.8
percent, between that period — the end of
that recession and the equivalent of time
to today, Ronald Reagan’s recovery created
twice as many jobs as this president’s recovery.
Five million jobs doesn’t even keep up with
our population growth. And the only reason
the unemployment rate seems a little lower
today is because of all the people that have
dropped out of the workforce.
The president has tried, but his policies
haven’t worked. He’s great as a — as
a — as a speaker and describing his plans
and his vision. That’s wonderful, except
we have a record to look at. And that record
shows he just hasn’t been able to cut the
deficit, to put in place reforms for Medicare
and Social Security to preserve them, to get
us the rising incomes we need. Median income
is down $4,300 a family and 23 million Americans
out of work. That’s what this election is
about. It’s about who can get the middle
class in this country a bright and prosperous
future and assure our kids the kind of hope
and optimism they deserve.
CROWLEY: Governor, I want to move you along.
Don’t — don’t go away, and we’ll have
plenty of time to respond. We are quite aware
of the clock for both of you. But I want to
bring in a different subject here.
Mr. President, I’ll be right back with you.
Lorraine Osorio has a question for you about
a topic we have not…
OBAMA: This is for Governor Romney?
CROWLEY: It’s for Governor Romney, and we’ll
be right with you, Mr. President. Thanks.
ROMNEY: Is it Loraina?
QUESTION: Lorraine.
ROMNEY: Lorraine?
QUESTION: Yes, Lorraine.
ROMNEY: Lorraine.
QUESTION: How you doing?
ROMNEY: Good, thanks.
QUESTION: Mr. Romney, what do you plan on
doing with immigrants without their green
cards that are currently living here as productive
members of society?
ROMNEY: Thank you. Lorraine? Did I get that
right? Good. Thank you for your question.
And let me step back and tell you what I would
like to do with our immigration policy broadly
and include an answer to your question.
But first of all, this is a nation of immigrants.
We welcome people coming to this country as
immigrants. My dad was born in Mexico of American
parents; Ann’s dad was born in Wales and
is a first-generation American. We welcome
legal immigrants into this country.
I want our legal system to work better. I
want it to be streamlined. I want it to be
clearer. I don’t think you have to — shouldn’t
have to hire a lawyer to figure out how to
get into this country legally. I also think
that we should give visas to people — green
cards, rather, to people who graduate with
skills that we need. People around the world
with accredited degrees in science and math
get a green card stapled to their diploma,
come to the U.S. of A. We should make sure
our legal system works.
Number two, we’re going to have to stop
illegal immigration. There are 4 million people
who are waiting in line to get here legally.
Those who’ve come here illegally take their
place. So I will not grant amnesty to those
who have come here illegally.
What I will do is I’ll put in place an employment
verification system and make sure that employers
that hire people who have come here illegally
are sanctioned for doing so. I won’t put
in place magnets for people coming here illegally.
So for instance, I would not give driver’s
licenses to those that have come here illegally
as the president would.
The kids of those that came here illegally,
those kids, I think, should have a pathway
to become a permanent resident of the United
States and military service, for instance,
is one way they would have that kind of pathway
to become a permanent resident.
ROMNEY: Now when the president ran for office,
he said that he’d put in place, in his first
year, a piece of legislation — he’d file
a bill in his first year that would reform
our — our immigration system, protect legal
immigration, stop illegal immigration. He
didn’t do it.
He had a Democrat House, a Democrat Senate,
super majority in both Houses. Why did he
fail to even promote legislation that would
have provided an answer for those that want
to come legally and for those that are here
illegally today? What’s a question I think
the — the president will have a chance to
answer right now.
OBAMA: Good, I look forward to it.
Was — Lorranna — Lorraine — we are a
nation of immigrants. I mean we’re just
a few miles away from Ellis Island. We all
understand what this country has become because
talent from all around the world wants to
come here. People are willing to take risks.
People who want to build on their dreams and
make sure their kids have an even bigger dreams
than they have.
But we’re also a nation of laws. So what
I’ve said is we need to fix a broken immigration
system and I’ve done everything that I can
on my own and sought cooperation from Congress
to make sure that we fix the system.
The first thing we did was to streamline the
legal immigration system, to reduce the backlog,
make it easier, simpler and cheaper for people
who are waiting in line, obeying the law to
make sure that they can come here and contribute
to our country and that’s good for our economic
growth.
They’ll start new businesses. They’ll
make things happen to create jobs here in
the United States.
Number two, we do have to deal with our border
so we put more border patrol on the — any
time in history and the flow of undocumented
works across the border is actually lower
than it’s been in 40 years.
What I’ve also said is if we’re going
to go after folks who are here illegally,
we should do it smartly and go after folks
who are criminals, gang bangers, people who
are hurting the community, not after students,
not after folks who are here just because
they’re trying to figure out how to feed
their families. And that’s what we’ve
done. And what I’ve also said is for young
people who come here, brought here often times
by their parents. Had gone to school here,
pledged allegiance to the flag. Think of this
as their country. Understand themselves as
Americans in every way except having papers.
And we should make sure that we give them
a pathway to citizenship.
And that’s what I’ve done administratively.
Now, Governor Romney just said, you know he
wants to help those young people too, but
during the Republican primary, he said, “I
will veto the DREAM Act”, that would allow
these young people to have access.” His
main strategy during the Republican primary
was to say, “We’re going to encourage
self-deportation.” Making life so miserable
on folks that they’ll leave. He called the
Arizona law a model for the nation. Part of
the Arizona law said that law enforcement
officers could stop folks because they suspected
maybe they looked like they might be undocumented
workers and check their papers.
You know what? If my daughter or yours looks
to somebody like they’re not a citizen,
I don’t want — I don’t want to empower
somebody like that. So, we can fix this system
in a comprehensive way. And when Governor
Romney says, the challenge is, “Well Obama
didn’t try.” That’s not true. I have
sat down with Democrats and Republicans at
the beginning of my term. And I said, let’s
fix this system. Including Senators previously
who had supported it on the Republican side.
But it’s very hard for Republican’s in
Congress to support comprehensive immigration
reform, if their standard bearer has said
that, this is not something I’m interested
in supporting.
CROWLEY: Let me get the governor in here,
Mr. President. Let’s speak to, if you could…
ROMNEY: Yes.
CROWLEY: …the idea of self-deportation?
ROMNEY: No, let — let — let me go back
and speak to the points that the president
made and — and — and let’s get them
correct.
I did not say that the Arizona law was a model
for the nation in that aspect. I said that
the E-Verify portion of the Arizona law, which
is — which is the portion of the law which
says that employers could be able to determine
whether someone is here illegally or not illegally,
that that was a model for the nation. That’s
number one.
Number two, I asked the president a question
I think Hispanics and immigrants all over
the nation have asked. He was asked this on
Univision the other day. Why, when you said
you’d filed legislation in your first year
didn’t you do it? And he didn’t answer.
He — he doesn’t answer that question.
He said the standard bearer wasn’t for it.
I’m glad you thought I was a standard bearer
four years ago, but I wasn’t.
Four years ago you said in your first year
you would file legislation.
In his first year, I was just getting — licking
my wounds from having been beaten by John
McCain, all right. I was not the standard
bearer.
My — my view is that this president should
have honored his promise to do as he said.
Now, let me mention one other thing, and that
is self-deportation says let people make their
own choice. What I was saying is, we’re
not going to round up 12 million people, undocumented
illegals, and take them out of the nation.
Instead let people make their own choice.
And if they — if they find that — that
they can’t get the benefits here that they
want and they can’t — and they can’t
find the job they want, then they’ll make
a decision to go a place where — where they
have better opportunities.
But I’m not in favor of rounding up people
and — and — and taking them out of this
country. I am in favor, as the president has
said, and I agree with him, which is that
if people have committed crimes we got to
get them out of this country.
ROMNEY: Let me mention something else the
president said. It was a moment ago and I
didn’t get a chance to, when he was describing
Chinese investments and so forth.
OBAMA: Candy?
Hold on a second. The…
ROMNEY: Mr. President, I’m still speaking.
(CROSSTALK)
ROMNEY: Mr. President, let me finish.
ROMNEY: I’ve gotta continue.
(CROSSTALK)
CROWLEY: Governor Romney, you can make it
short. See all these people? They’ve been
waiting for you. (inaudible) make it short
(inaudible).
ROMNEY: Just going to make a point. Any investments
I have over the last eight years have been
managed by a blind trust. And I understand
they do include investments outside the United
States, including in — in Chinese companies.
Mr. President, have you looked at your pension?
Have you looked at your pension?
OBAMA: I’ve got to say…
ROMNEY: Mr. President, have you looked at
your pension?
OBAMA: You know, I — I don’t look at my
pension. It’s not as big as yours so it
doesn’t take as long.
ROMNEY: Well, let me give you some advice.
OBAMA: I don’t check it that often.
ROMNEY: Let me give you some advice. Look
at your pension. You also have investments
in Chinese companies. You also have investments
outside the United States. You also have investments
through a Cayman’s trust.
(CROSSTALK)
CROWLEY: We’re way off topic here, Governor
Romney.
(CROSSTALK)
OBAMA: I thought we were talking about immigration.
OBAMA: I do want to make sure that…
CROWLEY: If I could have you sit down, Governor
Romney. Thank you.
OBAMA: I do want to make sure that — I do
want to make sure that we just understand
something. Governor Romney says he wasn’t
referring to Arizona as a model for the nation.
His top adviser on immigration is the guy
who designed the Arizona law, the entirety
of it; not E-Verify, the whole thing. That’s
his policy. And it’s a bad policy. And it
won’t help us grow.
Look, when we think about immigration, we
have to understand there are folks all around
the world who still see America as the land
of promise. And they provide us energy and
they provide us innovation and they start
companies like Intel and Google. And we want
to encourage that.
Now, we’ve got to make sure that we do it
in a smart way and a comprehensive way, and
we make the legal system better. But when
we make this into a divisive political issue,
and when we don’t have bipartisan support
— I can deliver, Governor, a whole bunch
of Democrats to get comprehensive immigration
reform done, and we can’t…
ROMNEY: I’ll get it done. I’ll get it
done. First year…
OBAMA: … we can’t — we have not seen
Republicans serious about this issue at all.
And it’s time for them to get serious on
it.
CROWLEY: Mr. President, let me move you on
here please. Mr. President, (inaudible).
OBAMA: This used to be a bipartisan issue.
(CROSSTALK)
CROWLEY: Don’t go away, though — right.
Don’t go away because I — I want you to
talk to Kerry Ladka who wants to switch the
topic for us.
OBAMA: OK.
Hi, Kerry.
QUESTION: Good evening, Mr. President.
OBAMA: I’m sorry. What’s your name?
QUESTION: It’s Kerry, Kerry Ladka.
OBAMA: Great to see you.
QUESTION: This question actually comes from
a brain trust of my friends at Global Telecom
Supply (ph) in Minneola yesterday.
OBAMA: Ah.
QUESTION: We were sitting around, talking
about Libya, and we were reading and became
aware of reports that the State Department
refused extra security for our embassy in
Benghazi, Libya, prior to the attacks that
killed four Americans.
Who was it that denied enhanced security and
why?
OBAMA: Well, let me first of all talk about
our diplomats, because they serve all around
the world and do an incredible job in a very
dangerous situation. And these aren’t just
representatives of the United States, they
are my representatives. I send them there,
oftentimes into harm’s way. I know these
folks and I know their families. So nobody
is more concerned about their safety and security
than I am.
So as soon as we found out that the Benghazi
consulate was being overrun, I was on the
phone with my national security team and I
gave them three instructions.
Number one, beef up our security and procedures,
not just in Libya, but at every embassy and
consulate in the region.
Number two, investigate exactly what happened,
regardless of where the facts lead us, to
make sure folks are held accountable and it
doesn’t happen again.
And number three, we are going to find out
who did this and we’re going to hunt them
down, because one of the things that I’ve
said throughout my presidency is when folks
mess with Americans, we go after them.
OBAMA: Now Governor Romney had a very different
response. While we were still dealing with
our diplomats being threatened, Governor Romney
put out a press release, trying to make political
points, and that’s not how a commander in
chief operates. You don’t turn national
security into a political issue. Certainly
not right when it’s happening. And people
— not everybody agrees with some of the
decisions I’ve made. But when it comes to
our national security, I mean what I say.
I said I’d end the war in Libya — in — in
Iraq, and I did.
I said that we’d go after al-Qaeda and bin
Laden, we have. I said we’d transition out
of Afghanistan, and start making sure that
Afghans are responsible for their own security,
that’s what I’m doing. And when it comes
to this issue, when I say that we are going
to find out exactly what happened, everybody
will be held accountable. And I am ultimately
responsible for what’s taking place there
because these are my folks, and I’m the
one who has to greet those coffins when they
come home. You know that I mean what I say.
CROWLEY: Mr. President, I’m going to move
us along. Governor?
ROMNEY: Thank you Kerry for your question,
it’s an important one. And — and I — I
think the president just said correctly that
the buck does stop at his desk and — and
he takes responsibility for — for that — for
the failure in providing those security resources,
and — and those terrible things may well
happen from time to time. I — I’m — I
feel very deeply sympathetic for the families
of those who lost loved ones. And today there’s
a memorial service for one of those that was
lost in this tragedy. We — we think of their
families and care for them deeply. There were
other issues associated with this — with
this tragedy. There were many days that passed
before we knew whether this was a spontaneous
demonstration, or actually whether it was
a terrorist attack.
ROMNEY: And there was no demonstration involved.
It was a terrorist attack and it took a long
time for that to be told to the American people.
Whether there was some misleading, or instead
whether we just didn’t know what happened,
you have to ask yourself why didn’t we know
five days later when the ambassador to the
United Nations went on TV to say that this
was a demonstration. How could we have not
known?
But I find more troubling than this, that
on — on the day following the assassination
of the United States ambassador, the first
time that’s happened since 1979, when — when
we have four Americans killed there, when
apparently we didn’t know what happened,
that the president, the day after that happened,
flies to Las Vegas for a political fund-raiser,
then the next day to Colorado for another
event, other political event.
I think these — these actions taken by a
president and a leader have symbolic significance
and perhaps even material significance in
that you’d hope that during that time we
could call in the people who were actually
eyewitnesses. We’ve read their accounts
now about what happened. It was very clear
this was not a demonstration. This was an
attack by terrorists.
And this calls into question the president’s
whole policy in the Middle East. Look what’s
happening in Syria, in Egypt, now in Libya.
Consider the distance between ourselves and
— and Israel, the president said that — that
he was going to put daylight between us and
Israel.
We have Iran four years closer to a nuclear
bomb. Syria — Syria’s not just a tragedy
of 30,000 civilians being killed by a military,
but also a strategic — strategically significant
player for America.
The president’s policies throughout the
Middle East began with an apology tour and
— and — and pursue a strategy of leading
from behind, and this strategy is unraveling
before our very eyes.
CROWLEY: Because we’re — we’re closing
in, I want to still get a lot of people in.
I want to ask you something, Mr. President,
and then have the governor just quickly.
Your secretary of state, as I’m sure you
know, has said that she takes full responsibility
for the attack on the diplomatic mission in
Benghazi. Does the buck stop with your secretary
of state as far as what went on here?
OBAMA: Secretary Clinton has done an extraordinary
job. But she works for me. I’m the president
and I’m always responsible, and that’s
why nobody’s more interested in finding
out exactly what happened than I do.
The day after the attack, governor, I stood
in the Rose Garden and I told the American
people in the world that we are going to find
out exactly what happened. That this was an
act of terror and I also said that we’re
going to hunt down those who committed this
crime.
And then a few days later, I was there greeting
the caskets coming into Andrews Air Force
Base and grieving with the families.
And the suggestion that anybody in my team,
whether the Secretary of State, our U.N. Ambassador,
anybody on my team would play politics or
mislead when we’ve lost four of our own,
governor, is offensive. That’s not what
we do. That’s not what I do as president,
that’s not what I do as Commander in Chief.
CROWLEY: Governor, if you want to…
ROMNEY: Yes, I — I…
CROWLEY: … quickly to this please.
ROMNEY: I — I think interesting the president
just said something which — which is that
on the day after the attack he went into the
Rose Garden and said that this was an act
of terror.
OBAMA: That’s what I said.
ROMNEY: You said in the Rose Garden the day
after the attack, it was an act of terror.
It was not a spontaneous demonstration, is
that what you’re saying?
OBAMA: Please proceed governor.
ROMNEY: I want to make sure we get that for
the record because it took the president 14
days before he called the attack in Benghazi
an act of terror.
OBAMA: Get the transcript.
CROWLEY: It — it — it — he did in fact,
sir. So let me — let me call it an act of
terror…
OBAMA: Can you say that a little louder, Candy?
CROWLEY: He — he did call it an act of terror.
It did as well take — it did as well take
two weeks or so for the whole idea there being
a riot out there about this tape to come out.
You are correct about that.
ROMNEY: This — the administration — the
administration indicated this was a reaction
to a video and was a spontaneous reaction.
CROWLEY: It did.
ROMNEY: It took them a long time to say this
was a terrorist act by a terrorist group.
And to suggest — am I incorrect in that
regard, on Sunday, the — your secretary
–
OBAMA: Candy?
ROMNEY: Excuse me. The ambassador of the United
Nations went on the Sunday television shows
and spoke about how –
OBAMA: Candy, I’m –
ROMNEY: — this was a spontaneous –
CROWLEY: Mr. President, let me –
OBAMA: I’m happy to have a longer conversation
–
CROWLEY: I know you –
OBAMA: — about foreign policy.
CROWLEY: Absolutely. But I want to — I want
to move you on and also –
OBAMA: OK. I’m happy to do that, too.
CROWLEY: — the transcripts and –
OBAMA: I just want to make sure that –
CROWLEY: — figure out what we –
OBAMA: — all of these wonderful folks are
going to have a chance to get some of their
questions answered.
CROWLEY: Because what I — what I want to
do, Mr. President, stand there a second, because
I want to introduce you to Nina Gonzalez,
who brought up a question that we hear a lot,
both over the Internet and from this crowd.
QUESTION: President Obama, during the Democratic
National Convention in 2008, you stated you
wanted to keep AK-47s out of the hands of
criminals. What has your administration done
or planned to do to limit the availability
of assault weapons?
OBAMA: We’re a nation that believes in the
Second Amendment, and I believe in the Second
Amendment. We’ve got a long tradition of
hunting and sportsmen and people who want
to make sure they can protect themselves.
But there have been too many instances during
the course of my presidency, where I’ve
had to comfort families who have lost somebody.
Most recently out in Aurora. You know, just
a couple of weeks ago, actually, probably
about a month, I saw a mother, who I had met
at the bedside of her son, who had been shot
in that theater.
And her son had been shot through the head.
And we spent some time, and we said a prayer
and, remarkably, about two months later, this
young man and his mom showed up, and he looked
unbelievable, good as new.
But there were a lot of families who didn’t
have that good fortune and whose sons or daughters
or husbands didn’t survive.
So my belief is that, (A), we have to enforce
the laws we’ve already got, make sure that
we’re keeping guns out of the hands of criminals,
those who are mentally ill. We’ve done a
much better job in terms of background checks,
but we’ve got more to do when it comes to
enforcement.
But I also share your belief that weapons
that were designed for soldiers in war theaters
don’t belong on our streets. And so what
I’m trying to do is to get a broader conversation
about how do we reduce the violence generally.
Part of it is seeing if we can get an assault
weapons ban reintroduced. But part of it is
also looking at other sources of the violence.
Because frankly, in my home town of Chicago,
there’s an awful lot of violence and they’re
not using AK-47s. They’re using cheap hand
guns.
And so what can we do to intervene, to make
sure that young people have opportunity; that
our schools are working; that if there’s
violence on the streets, that working with
faith groups and law enforcement, we can catch
it before it gets out of control.
And so what I want is a — is a comprehensive
strategy. Part of it is seeing if we can get
automatic weapons that kill folks in amazing
numbers out of the hands of criminals and
the mentally ill. But part of it is also going
deeper and seeing if we can get into these
communities and making sure we catch violent
impulses before they occur.
CROWLEY: Governor Romney, the question is
about assault weapons, AK-47s.
ROMNEY: Yeah, I’m not in favor of new pieces
of legislation on — on guns and taking guns
away or making certain guns illegal. We, of
course, don’t want to have automatic weapons,
and that’s already illegal in this country
to have automatic weapons. What I believe
is we have to do, as the president mentioned
towards the end of his remarks there, which
is to make enormous efforts to enforce the
gun laws that we have, and to change the culture
of violence that we have.
And you ask how — how are we going to do
that? And there are a number of things. He
mentioned good schools. I totally agree. We
were able to drive our schools to be number
one in the nation in my state. And I believe
if we do a better job in education, we’ll
— we’ll give people the — the hope and
opportunity they deserve and perhaps less
violence from that. But let me mention another
thing. And that is parents. We need moms and
dads, helping to raise kids. Wherever possible
the — the benefit of having two parents
in the home, and that’s not always possible.
A lot of great single moms, single dads. But
gosh to tell our kids that before they have
babies, they ought to think about getting
married to someone, that’s a great idea.
Because if there’s a two parent family,
the prospect of living in poverty goes down
dramatically. The opportunities that the child
will — will be able to achieve increase
dramatically. So we can make changes in the
way our culture works to help bring people
away from violence and give them opportunity,
and bring them in the American system. The
— the greatest failure we’ve had with
regards to — to gun violence in some respects
is what — what is known as Fast and Furious.
Which was a program under this administration,
and how it worked exactly I think we don’t
know precisely, where thousands of automatic,
and AK-47 type weapons were — were given
to people that ultimately gave them to — to
drug lords.
They used those weapons against — against
their own citizens and killed Americans with
them. And this was a — this was a program
of the government. For what purpose it was
put in place, I can’t imagine. But it’s
one of the great tragedies related to violence
in our society which has occurred during this
administration. Which I think the American
people would like to understand fully, it’s
been investigated to a degree, but — but
the administration has carried out executive
privilege to prevent all of the information
from coming out.
I’d like to understand who it was that did
this, what the idea was behind it, why it
led to the violence, thousands of guns going
to Mexican drug lords. OBAMA: Candy?
CROWLEY: Governor, Governor, if I could, the
question was about these assault weapons that
once were once banned and are no longer banned.
I know that you signed an assault weapons
ban when you were in Massachusetts, obviously,
with this question, you no longer do support
that. Why is that, given the kind of violence
that we see sometimes with these mass killings?
Why is it that you have changed your mind?
ROMNEY: Well, Candy, actually, in my state,
the pro-gun folks and the anti-gun folks came
together and put together a piece of legislation.
And it’s referred to as an assault weapon
ban, but it had, at the signing of the bill,
both the pro-gun and the anti-gun people came
together, because it provided opportunities
for both that both wanted.
There were hunting opportunities, for instance,
that haven’t previously been available and
so forth, so it was a mutually agreed- upon
piece of legislation. That’s what we need
more of, Candy. What we have right now in
Washington is a place that’s gridlocked.
CROWLEY: So I could — if you could get people
to agree to it, you would be for it?
ROMNEY: We have –
OBAMA: Candy?
ROMNEY: — we haven’t had the leadership
in Washington to work on a bipartisan basis.
I was able to do that in my state and bring
these two together.
CROWLEY: Quickly, Mr. President.
OBAMA: The — first of all, I think Governor
Romney was for an assault weapons ban before
he was against it. And he said that the reason
he changed his mind was, in part, because
he was seeking the endorsement of the National
Rifle Association. So that’s on the record.
But I think that one area we agree on is the
important of parents and the importance of
schools, because I do believe that if our
young people have opportunity, then they are
less likely to engage in these kinds of violent
acts. We’re not going to eliminate everybody
who is mentally disturbed and we have got
to make sure they don’t get weapons.
(AUDIO GAP)
OBAMA: because I do believe that if our young
people have opportunity, then they’re less
likely to engage in these kind of violent
acts.
We’re not going to eliminate everybody who
is mentally disturbed, and we’ve got to
make sure they don’t get weapons. But we
can make a difference in terms ensuring that
every young person in America, regardless
of where they come from, what they look like,
have a chance to succeed.
And, Candy, we haven’t had a chance to talk
about education much, but I think it is very
important to understand that the reforms we’ve
put in place, working with 46 governors around
the country, are seeing schools that are some
of the ones that are the toughest for kids
starting to succeed. We’re starting to see
gains in math and science.
When it comes to community colleges, we are
setting up programs, including with Nassau
Community College, to retrain workers, including
young people who may have dropped out of school
but now are getting another chance, training
them for the jobs that exist right now.
And in fact, employers are looking for skilled
workers. And so we’re matching them up.
Giving them access to higher education. As
I said, we have made sure that millions of
young people are able to get an education
that they weren’t able to get before.
Now…
CROWLEY: Mr. President, I have to — I have
to move you along here. You said you wanted
to…
(CROSSTALK)
CROWLEY: We need to do it here.
OBAMA: But — but it’ll — it’ll — it’ll
be…
(CROSSTALK)
OBAMA: … just one second.
CROWLEY: One…
OBAMA: Because — because this is important.
This is part of the choice in this election.
When Governor Romney was asked whether teachers,
hiring more teachers was important to growing
our economy, Governor Romney said that doesn’t
grow our economy.
When — when he was asked would class size…
(CROSSTALK)
CROWLEY: The question, Mr. President, was
guns here, so I need to move us along.
OBAMA: I understand.
CROWLEY: You know, the question was guns.
So let me — let me bring in another…
OBAMA: But this will make a difference in
terms of whether or not we can move this economy
forward for these young people…
CROWLEY: I understand.
OBAMA: … and reduce our violence.
CROWLEY: OK. Thank you so much.
I want to ask Carol Goldberg to stand up,
because she gets to a question that both these
men have been passionate about. It’s for
Governor Romney.
QUESTION: The outsourcing of American jobs
overseas has taken a toll on our economy.
What plans do you have to put back and keep
jobs here in the United States?
ROMNEY: Boy, great question and important
question, because you’re absolutely right.
The place where we’ve seen manufacturing
go has been China. China is now the largest
manufacturer in the world. It used to be the
United States of America. A lot of good people
have lost jobs. A half a million manufacturing
jobs have been lost in the last four years.
That’s total over the last four years.
One of the reasons for that is that people
think it’s more attractive in some cases
to go offshore than to stay here. We have
made it less attractive for enterprises to
stay here than to go offshore from time to
time. What I will do as president is make
sure it’s more attractive to come to America
again.
This is the way we’re going to create jobs
in this country. It’s not by trickle-down
government, saying we’re going to take more
money from people and hire more government
workers, raise more taxes, put in place more
regulations. Trickle-down government has never
worked here, has never worked anywhere.
I want to make America the most attractive
place in the world for entrepreneurs, for
small business, for big business, to invest
and grow in America.
Now, we’re going to have to make sure that
as we trade with other nations that they play
by the rules. And China hasn’t. One of the
reasons — or one of the ways they don’t
play by the rules is artificially holding
down the value of their currency. Because
if they put their currency down low, that
means their prices on their goods are low.
And that makes them advantageous in the marketplace.
We lose sales. And manufacturers here in the
U.S. making the same products can’t compete.
China has been a currency manipulator for
years and years and years. And the president
has a regular opportunity to label them as
a currency manipulator, but refuses to do
so.
On day one, I will label China a currency
manipulator, which will allow me as president
to be able to put in place, if necessary,
tariffs where I believe that they are taking
unfair advantage of our manufacturers.
So we’re going to make sure that people
we trade with around the world play by the
rules. But let me — let me not just stop
there. Don’t forget, what’s key to bringing
back jobs here is not just finding someone
else to punish, and I’m going to be strict
with people who we trade with to make sure
they — they follow the law and play by the
rules, but it’s also to make America the
most attractive place in the world for businesses
of all kinds.
That’s why I want to down the tax rates
on small employers, big employers, so they
want to be here. Canada’s tax rate on companies
is now 15 percent. Ours is 35 percent. So
if you’re starting a business, where would
you rather start it? We have to be competitive
if we’re going to create more jobs here.
Regulations have quadrupled. The rate of regulations
quadrupled under this president. I talk to
small businesses across the country. They
say, “We feel like we’re under attack
from our own government.” I want to make
sure that regulators see their job as encouraging
small business, not crushing it. And there’s
no question but that Obamacare has been an
extraordinary deterrent to enterprises of
all kinds hiring people.
My priority is making sure that we get more
people hired. If we have more people hired,
if we get back manufacturing jobs, if we get
back all kinds of jobs into this country,
then you’re going to see rising incomes
again. The reason incomes are down is because
unemployment is so high. I know what it takes
to get this to happen, and my plan will do
that, and one part of it is to make sure that
we keep China playing by the rules.
CROWLEY: Mr. President, two minutes here,
because we are then going to go to our last
question.
OBAMA: OK. We need to create jobs here. And
both Governor Romney and I agree actually
that we should lower our corporate tax rate.
It’s too high. But there’s a difference
in terms of how we would do it. I want to
close loopholes that allow companies to deduct
expenses when they move to China; that allow
them to profit offshore and not have to get
taxed, so they have tax advantages offshore.
All those changes in our tax code would make
a difference.
Now, Governor Romney actually wants to expand
those tax breaks. One of his big ideas when
it comes to corporate tax reform would be
to say, if you invest overseas, you make profits
overseas, you don’t have to pay U.S. taxes.
But, of course, if you’re a small business
or a mom-and-pop business or a big business
starting up here, you’ve got to pay even
the reduced rate that Governor Romney’s
talking about.
And it’s estimated that that will create
800,000 new jobs. The problem is they’ll
be in china. Or India. Or Germany.
That’s not the way we’re going to create
jobs here. The way we’re going to create
jobs here is not just to change our tax code,
but also to double our exports. And we are
on pace to double our exports, one of the
commitments I made when I was president. That’s
creating tens of thousands of jobs all across
the country. That’s why we’ve kept on
pushing trade deals, but trade deals that
make sure that American workers and American
businesses are getting a good deal.
Now, Governor Romney talked about China, as
I already indicated. In the private sector,
Governor Romney’s company invested in what
were called pioneers of outsourcing. That’s
not my phrase. That’s what reporters called
it.
And as far as currency manipulation, the currency
has actually gone up 11 percent since I’ve
been president because we have pushed them
hard. And we’ve put unprecedented trade
pressure on China. That’s why exports have
significantly increased under my presidency.
That’s going to help to create jobs here.
CROWLEY: Mr. President, we have a really short
time for a quick discussion here.
iPad, the Macs, the iPhones, they are all
manufactured in China. One of the major reasons
is labor is so much cheaper here. How do you
convince a great American company to bring
that manufacturing back here?
ROMNEY: The answer is very straightforward.
We can compete with anyone in the world as
long as the playing field is level. China’s
been cheating over the years. One by holding
down the value of their currency. Number two,
by stealing our intellectual property; our
designs, our patents, our technology. There’s
even an Apple store in China that’s a counterfeit
Apple store, selling counterfeit goods. They
hack into our computers. We will have to have
people play on a fair basis, that’s number
one.
Number two, we have to make America the most
attractive place for entrepreneurs, for people
who want to expand their business. That’s
what brings jobs in. The president’s characterization
of my tax plan…
(CROSSTALK)
ROMNEY: …is completely…is completely…
ROMNEY: …is completely false. Let me tell
you…
CROWLEY: Let me to go the president here because
we really are running out of time. And the
question is can we ever get — we can’t
get wages like that. It can’t be sustained.
OBAMA: Candy, there are some jobs that are
not going to come back. Because they are low
wage, low skill jobs. I want high wage, high
skill jobs. That’s why we have to emphasize
manufacturing. That’s why we have to invest
in advanced manufacturing. That’s why we’ve
got to make sure that we’ve got the best
science and research in the world. And when
we talk about deficits, if we’re adding
to our deficit for tax cuts for folks who
don’t need them, and we’re cutting investments
in research and science that will create the
next Apple, create the next new innovation
that will sell products around the world,
we will lose that race.
If we’re not training engineers to make
sure that they are equipped here in this country.
Then companies won’t come here. Those investments
are what’s going to help to make sure that
we continue to lead this world economy, not
just next year, but 10 years from now, 50
years from now, 100 years from now.
CROWLEY: Thanks Mr. President.
(CROSSTALK)
CROWLEY: Governor Romney?
ROMNEY: Government does not create jobs. Government
does not create jobs.
CROWLEY: Governor Romney, I want to introduce
you to Barry Green, because he’s going to
have the last question to you first?
ROMNEY: Barry? Where is Barry?
QUESTION: Hi, Governor. I think this is a
tough question. To each of you. What do you
believe is the biggest misperception that
the American people have about you as a man
and a candidate? Using specific examples,
can you take this opportunity to debunk that
misperception and set us straight?
ROMNEY: Thank you, and that’s an opportunity
for me, and I appreciate it.
In the nature of a campaign, it seems that
some campaigns are focused on attacking a
person rather than prescribing their own future
and the things they’d like to do. In the
course of that, I think the president’s
campaign has tried to characterize me as — as
someone who’s very different than who I
am.
I care about 100 percent of the American people.
I want 100 percent of the American people
to have a bright and prosperous future. I
care about our kids. I understand what it
takes to make a bright and prosperous future
for America again. I spent my life in the
private sector, not in government. I’m a
guy who wants to help with the experience
I have, the American people.
My — my passion probably flows from the
fact that I believe in God. And I believe
we’re all children of the same God. I believe
we have a responsibility to care for one another.
I — I served as a missionary for my church.
I served as a pastor in my congregation for
about 10 years. I’ve sat across the table
from people who were out of work and worked
with them to try and find new work or to help
them through tough times.
I went to the Olympics when they were in trouble
to try and get them on track. And as governor
of my state, I was able to get 100 percent
of my people insured, all my kids, about 98
percent of the adults. I was able also to
get our schools ranked number one in the nation,
so 100 percent of our kids would have a bright
opportunity for a future.
ROMNEY: I understand that I can get this country
on track again. We don’t have to settle
for what we’re going through. We don’t
have to settle for gasoline at four bucks.
We don’t have to settle for unemployment
at a chronically high level. We don’t have
to settle for 47 million people on food stamps.
We don’t have to settle for 50 percent of
kids coming out of college not able to get
work. We don’t have to settle for 23 million
people struggling to find a good job.
If I become president, I’ll get America
working again. I will get us on track to a
balanced budget. The president hasn’t. I
will. I’ll make sure we can reform Medicare
and Social Security to preserve them for coming
— coming generations. The president said
he would. He didn’t.
CROWLEY: Governor…
ROMNEY: I’ll get our incomes up. And by
the way, I’ve done these things. I served
as governor and showed I could get them done.
CROWLEY: Mr. President, last two minutes belong
to you.
OBAMA: Barry, I think a lot of this campaign,
maybe over the last four years, has been devoted
to this nation that I think government creates
jobs, that that somehow is the answer.
That’s not what I believe. I believe that
the free enterprise system is the greatest
engine of prosperity the world’s ever known.
I believe in self-reliance and individual
initiative and risk takers being rewarded.
But I also believe that everybody should have
a fair shot and everybody should do their
fair share and everybody should play by the
same rules, because that’s how our economy’s
grown. That’s how we built the world’s
greatest middle class.
And — and that is part of what’s at stake
in this election. There’s a fundamentally
different vision about how we move our country
forward.
I believe Governor Romney is a good man. Loves
his family, cares about his faith. But I also
believe that when he said behind closed doors
that 47 percent of the country considered
themselves victims who refuse personal responsibility,
think about who he was talking about.
Folks on Social Security who’ve worked all
their lives. Veterans who’ve sacrificed
for this country. Students who are out there
trying to hopefully advance their own dreams,
but also this country’s dreams. Soldiers
who are overseas fighting for us right now.
People who are working hard every day, paying
payroll tax, gas taxes, but don’t make enough
income.
And I want to fight for them. That’s what
I’ve been doing for the last four years.
Because if they succeed, I believe the country
succeeds.
When my grandfather fought in World War II
and he came back and he got a G.I. Bill and
that allowed him to go to college, that wasn’t
a handout. That was something that advanced
the entire country. And I want to make sure
that the next generation has those same opportunities.
That’s why I’m asking for your vote and
that’s why I’m asking for another four
years.
CROWLEY: President Obama, Governor Romney,
thank you for being here tonight.
On that note we have come to an end of this
town hall debate. Our thanks to the participants
for their time and to the people of Hofstra
University for their hospitality.
The next and final debate takes place Monday
night at Lynn (ph) University in Boca Raton,
Florida. Don’t forget to watch. Election
Day is three weeks from today. Don’t forget
to vote.
Good night.
(APPLAUSE)
END