[Music]
And a welcome to this episode of Genesis
Week, the weekly program of creationary
commentary on news, views and events
pertaining to the origins controversy,
exclusive right here on youtube.
Excellence in pirate broadcasting, we
bring you the information the
anti-creationists don't want you to see or
hear, and we  show the glory of God in the
Creation.
Remember if you get lost in cyberspace,
just punch in wazooloo.com or
genesisweek.com, and you will find us, or
click the ever-so-convenient subscribe
link up top. I'm your host, Ian Juby.
Live science carried an interview with Dr.
Jack Horner, famous paleontologist who
was a consultant and inspiration for the
characters in "Jurassic park".  Jack has
decided he wants to pull a Jurassic park
and make a modern day dinosaur.  But not
in the way the movie showed - nope.  He
wants to de-evolve a chicken back into a
dinosaur - cause after all, as we all know,
chickens are living dinosaurs.
[T-rex making chicken clucking sounds]
Bragawk!
I have great respect for Dr. Horner, but
his comments and the live science article
were filled with incredible amounts of
unfounded evolutionary propaganda and
assumptions.  The first and foremost
assumption being that birds evolved from
dinosaurs!
As I mentioned in passing last week, this
is a typical evolutionary claim - complete
with your average evolutionary thinker
citing feathered dinosaurs as proof that
dinosaurs evolved into birds. Until you
point out that based on the evolutionarily
assigned ages of the fossils, the
evolutionary timeline is reversed.
According to the evolutionary timeline,
the feathered dinosaurs were evolving
into un-feathered dinosaurs.  And let us
not forget the Nature article from a few
months back which ruffled a whole pile of
feathers after reporting a cretaceous
fossil duck!
Ya, ya, I know - Jurassic and Cretaceous
aren't the same time periods, but the
word "Cretaceous" doesn't lend itself to
humour.
and we find completely modern bird
fossils like protoavis in rocks that are
allegedly older than the dinosaurs birds
were supposed to have been evolved
from!
For these and many more reasons,
prominent evolutionists like Alan Feduccia
and Stors Olson do not believe birds
evolved from dinosaurs.
And this is ignoring other problems for
the dino to bird hypothesis such as the
fossil footprints from Nova Scotia -
allegedly 350 million years old  - which
sure look like fossil Ostrich tracks.
In spite of the fact that you cannot be
your Grandfather's father, among other
problems, Horner embraces the
dino-to-bird ancestry, and bases his
proposition on this assumption.
As Stephanie Pappas wrote in the
LiveScience article,
In other words, if chickens evolved from
the dinosaurs, then the "plans" for the
dinosaurs would still be left over in the
chicken's DNA, and he's just gotta figure
out how to throw the right switches to get
the chicken to make dinosaur parts
instead of chicken parts.
Just what would that take?  Well, first
you'd have turn off the switches that
control the genes that make the chicken's
bird-like hip, then you need to turn on the
gene that makes a lizard's hip.  And
doesn't it seem odd to you that the
evolutionists would claim that birds
evolved from the dinosaurs which have
lizard hips, rather than the dinosaurs
which have hips like a bird?  Like the
hadrosaurs - they lay eggs like a bird,
have bird-like hips, have a bill like a
duck's bill, yet the evolutionists claim the
birds evolved from the group of dinosaurs
which involves T-rex (which has lizard
hips), and the long necked, sauropod
dinosaurs which are lot more like an
elephant than anything!
Then Jack's gotta locate and turn off the
genes that produce feathers and turn on
the genes that make scales. He's also
gotta find the genes that turn off the wing
formation and turn on the arm formation,
find the genes that make the fourth digit
on the wing turn off and turn on the first
digit gene, etc...
All I can say is "Good luck with that, let
me know how it goes."
But Horner calls upon the erroneous,
long-discredited "science" of vestigial
organs or parts, and embryonic
recapitulation.  Haeckel's drawings were
shown to be fraudulent 150 years ago, yet
his drawings and false claims are simply
dressed up in a different, nicer looking
business suit and put in our textbooks.
Horner quotes a classic example of this
idea, specifically talking about the human
"tail", saying:
Hogwash!  It is nothing but a tall tale to
call that a tail! It is not a tail, but a somite
- developing organs, tissues, etc...
Describing it as a "tail" is nothing less
than evolutionary propaganda - in fact, it
is misleading.
David Coppedge over at Creation
Evolution Headlines had this to say about
the Horner and the live science article:
I might also add that Horner is not just
referring to Creationists as being
"misinformed", but other evolutionists
such as Alan Feduccia and Larry Martin.
Horner is also ignoring oodles of evidence
I have only mentioned in passing here, in
order to embrace the dino-to-bird
hypothesis.
Of course,  as Coppedge pointed out: If
you're going to de-evolve a chicken, why
stop at the dinosaur?  If Horner's
ludicrous assumptions were correct, then
you could de-evolve a chicken into an
amphibian, a fish, a worm, a protoplasm,
etc...
Stephanie Pappas also authored snother
live science article, "New Year brings New
attacks on evolution in schools."
That's right, more whining over the
introduction of legislative bills that either
allow teaching of creation or critique of
evolution in the public schools.  Eugenie
Scott, Executive director of the National
Center for Science Eradication was
quoted by live science regarding Indiana's
proposed bill to include creation science,
Let's get one thing straight here:
Evolutionism IS controversial.  The only
reason evolutionism has survived in the
schools is because it must hide behind
lawyers, judges, and school policies.
When was the last time you heard of a
physicist seeking court protection for his
theory to be taught in schools without
scrutiny?  You haven't heard of it because
it's moronic.  Either the theory stands or
falls under scrutiny. But yet, this is
precisely what evolution has required:
Court protection from scrutiny. Why?
Because evolution disintegrates under
even minor scrutiny.
Oh - and by the way, yes the supreme
court said it was unconstituntional to
force schools to teach creationary
theories, however they also ruled it was
not unconstitutional to permit such
teaching.
[Scary, dramatic music]
Wahoo! Mail for me?
The last episode of Genesis week was
launched into the #3 position of most
discussed videos in science and
technology within two days of posting it.
Over 600 hate-filled, rabid comments were
left which were quite revealing.  Feel the
LOVE!  First of all, why were the skeptics
so emotional? This is science - if I'm
wrong about something, then correct me.
Instead, what I got was a barrage of very
personal and venomous attack.
It seemed the only thing the skeptics
agreed upon was that I was a flagrant liar
for Jesus.  Besides being an incredibly
presumptuous accusation, they couldn't
seem to agree on what it was exactly that
I was lying about!  Well, that just speaks
volumes of the anti-creationist claims and
false accusations.
It was quite entertaining to watch the
skeptics contradict themselves, and each
other!  Go read the comments for
yourself!  Then to add to that, mutliple
people got downright angry at me for
saying that birds evolved from dinosaurs.
Uhhhh, hellloooo, it was an evolutionist
who said that, not me - I was merely
responding to the evolutionist.
This is a lesson I learned many years ago
when we held the skeptic's night at
Carleton University in Ottawa, the first
event of the week-long National Capital
Creation Conference.  It was standing
room only in the lecture hall, and for the
next week, I heard from lots of people
who had been to the skeptic's night -
including people who were not
creationists nor Bible believers - but they
all said the same thing.  The one thing
from the skeptic's night that convinced
them the most that maybe - just maybe,
the creationary thinkers were actually
right, was the extreme emotional,
irrational, and illogical behaviour and
comments of the atheists and
anti-creationists.  NObody does a better
job of making the anti-creationists look
bad than the anti-creationists do. And this
is precisely why I leave the comments
open on my videos, so the whooole world
can see exactly what they are saying.
This is typical of the quality of
argumentation from the anti-creationist
camp.  It's not difficult to point out the
glaring errors in their claims, and if you
pay attention, they themselves usually
point out their own glaring errors for you
- even contradicting themselves and each
other.
I'm not out to poke fun of people or just
"prove them wrong" - but rather I want to
search out and find the TRUTH - which I
have personally found to be Jesus Christ,
our Creator.  So why then such emotional
and personal reaction? I'm only talking
about scientific matters.  It's because
these scientific matters point to a Creator,
which these anti-creationists wish to
reject and hate.  So the hatred and
irrationality of rejecting their creator spills
over on to me - and I'm okay with that.
There's so much more I wanted to talk
about this week, but I'm out of time. Join
me next Thursday for the next episode of
Genesis week, and remember to rant
down below, and if you like the program
and want to support it, please do me a
favour - subscribe up above, and click
"share" down below to easily share with
all your friends on facebook, twitter and
google plus.  Thanks for watching, I'm
your host Ian Juby reminding you that
Jesus is the way, the TRUTH, and THE
LIFE - no one comes to the Father but
through Him!  See you on the flip side.