VIDEO CLIP)
CARL AZUZ, HOST: A big thanks to Jackson and
C.J. for getting things started today. They`re
ready to go and so are we.
It`s Friday, I`m Carl, and this is CNN STUDENT
NEWS.
Senkaku and Diaoyu -- two different names
for the same set of islands at the center
of some tension between China and Japan. You
can see those two countries on this map. And
right in between them, that`s where you`ll
find these islands in the East China Sea.
There`s not much to them. They`re rocky. They`re
not near much else. No one lives there.
So why is there tension?
Well, China and Japan each say the islands
belong to them. Yesterday, this was seen near
the islands -- a Chinese plane. China said
it was there to carry out a patrol.
Japan launched its own planes in response,
including eight fighter jets. The Chinese
plane was gone by the time the Japanese jets
showed up. And while China and Japan have
been kind of wrestling over these islands
for a while, this was the first time aircraft
were involved.
Next up, a story from Syria`s civil war. Some
of the images from this conflict are difficult
to watch. Some people might find them disturbing,
so we want to make you aware of that, because
this story includes footage of a Syrian woman
who had been shot by a sniper while she was
walking down the street.
We`re showing it to you because of what happened
next.
A Syrian teenager, 17 years old, crawled out
into the street to try to save her. He isn`t
her relative or neighbor. They`ve never met.
He crawled out through the gunfire and put
his own life at risk because he said he knew
he had to save the woman or die trying.
He was able to help get her out of the street.
He wasn`t able to save her life.
Later, he talked with CNN`s Arwa Damon.
(BEGIN VIDEOTAPE)
ARWA DAMON, CNN CORRESPONDENT: "We wanted
to save her, to get her to a hospital. I am
not a hero. I am just like anyone else."
(END VIDEO TAPE)
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: Is this legit -- decibels
are a measure of mass.
Not legit. Decibels measure the intensity
of sound, especially loud sounds.
AZUZ: All right, think about when you`re watching
a TV show. If you were measuring the speaker`s
dialogue with a decibel meter, it might look
something like this, a normal speaking voice.
But then a commercial comes on and suddenly
the volume jumps to this.
Take a look at that decibel meter now.
It`s not a problem you`d run into with our
show, but the U.S. government gets thousands
of complaints from people who say that the
advertisements they see are significantly
louder than the shows they`re watching.
Congress passed the Commercial Advertisement
Loudness Mitigation, or CALM Act, in 2010.
It basically says that TV stations, both network
and cable, have to have commercials that are
at the same volume as the shows they`re airing.
Now, not all business owners are on board
with this. They say the whole point of advertising
on TV is to get people`s attention and they`re
concerned that the CALM Act might make that
more difficult.
The fastest growing drug problem in the United
States, you`re looking at it -- prescription
drug abuse. According to the Centers for Disease
Control and Prevention, one American dies
from a drug overdose every 19 minutes. A pharmaceutical
industry representative says the problem here
is balancing those patients who abuse prescription
drugs with those who use them responsibly,
and, therefore, get the medical benefit from
them.
I spoke about this with CNN`s Dr. Sanjay Gupta
recently.
He had some suggestions for avoiding the dangers
of prescription drugs.
(BEGIN VIDEOTAPE)
AZUZ: Dr. Gupta, we`ve talked about the dangers
of prescription medications on CNN STUDENT
NEWS.
When are these things OK to take?
DR. SANJAY GUPTA, CNN CORRESPONDENT: There
are situations where your doctor is going
to prescribe you these types of medications,
uh, and, you know, presumably, in most cases,
that`s going to be OK to take. I think that
one of the points we try to make is that we
give a lot of pain medications out in this
country and we don`t always try other things
first.
So I think the doctor is going to make a judgment,
but you, as a patient, or whoever is watching,
needs to decide, as well, do I really need
to take narcotics?
Could this be something that could be helped
with something less powerful or -- or just,
you know, something like just stretching and
massage?
AZUZ: Let`s say a student does feel like he
needs it. Maybe he has a sports injury or
something that causes a lot of pain. Maybe
he`s given 10 pills, only needs three or four
of them.
What does he do with the remaining pills?
GUPTA: Well, you know, there is -- this is
a -- actually, a very interesting topic. The
medications themselves, you don`t want to
sort of get them out there in the general
supply, you don`t want them sitting around
in your medicine cabinet, you don`t want them
to flush down the toilet.
Uh, you -- the best thing you could -- you
could probably throw them away. But even better
than that, there are some what are known as
take- back programs, where the DEA will actually
come and take these medications back. Eventually,
they burn them, which is the right thing to
do with these types of medications.
But don`t leave them in your medicine cabinet.
People get tempted. Someone else may take
them and that can be a real problem.
AZUZ: The same hypothetical student who`s
injured has a brother who gets a similar injury.
Is it ever OK for the brother to take his
medication?
GUPTA: It`s -- it`s really not. And -- and,
you know, people do this all the time, I -- I
know. And people watching may say that happens
in our -- in our own home.
The problem is that, you know, everybody is
different. How the medication may react with
somebody could be different. If they`re taking
other medications, those medications could
interact. That could be a problem.
But I think psychologically, if you`re just
sort of getting some pills from another family
member, you may not take it as seriously.
These are -- these are potentially dangerous
pills, and, you know, so you have to treat
it as such.
AZUZ: Especially if they`re taken recreationally,
as some people might take them, to get a buzz.
What are the dangers of doing that?
GUPTA: The -- the biggest danger and these
types of medications, they -- they affect
a part of the brain that actually makes your
body breathe. We`re all breathing like this.
(breathing)
GUPTA: We don`t think about it much. But let`s
say you go to sleep and that part of your
brain has been tinkered with a little bit.
You may start to lose the urge to breathe
and that`s the concern -- you just stop breathing.
And when we say someone dies every 19 minutes,
that`s -- I -- I`ve just described most -- most
likely how it occurs.
The -- the biggest danger with something like
this is that you start to take more and more.
It just doesn`t work as well, so you`re taking
more and more. It`s not treating your pain
or whatever reason you took it for in the
first place, but it is still impairing your
breathing.
So all of a sudden you start to build up that
-- that potentially life-threatening effect
of these pills.
AZUZ: Dr. Gupta, thank you for helping us
understand these things better, helping us
understand how they can hurt us.
GUPTA: Hope it helps.
Thanks a lot.
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: Today`s Shout Out goes
out to Coach Bradley`s world history class
at Portland High School in Portland, Tennessee.
Wayne Rooney, Abby Wambach and Sergio Ramos
are all known for accomplishments in what
sport?
Here we go.
Is it baseball, soccer, horse racing or auto
racing?
You`ve got three seconds.
Go.
(clock ringing)
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: Rooney, Wambach and Ramos
all found fame on the soccer field.
That`s your answer and that`s your Shout Out.
AZUZ: This past Sunday, Lionel Messi did something
that none of those players have done. In fact,
it`s never been done at the top level of soccer
before. Messi, who plays professionally for
Barcelona and plays on Argentina`s national
team, kicked his 86th goal of 2012 -- 74 for
Barcelona, 12 for Argentina.
That broke a record that`s been around for
40 years. And Messi may not be done yet. Barcelona
still has a few more matches to play in 2012.
When Messi or any player scores in the future,
soccer officials want to make sure the ball
crossed the goal line.
Alex Zolbert looks at some technology that
could help out.
(BEGIN VIDEOTAPE)
ALEX ZOLBERT, CNN CORRESPONDENT: So this is
how the GoalRef technology works. Here`s the
soccer ball. Under the skin, you have three
coils around the ball.
On the goal post, you have a magnetic ring
around the goal post. When the ball goes through
the goal post on this watch that the ref wears,
you see goal.
From a confidence point of view, this system
will work during the next games, as we always
expected it and as we saw it during the tests.
ZOLBERT: Then there`s Hawk-Eye. It uses a
series of cameras to capture the ball`s path,
which can then be reviewed within seconds.
Tennis fans know the Hawk-Eye technology well.
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: And right near the sideline,
Karl Good (ph).
ZOLBERT: The technology doesn`t come cheap,
though. FIFA is spending roughly $1 million
U.S. to use the systems here in Japan before
giving the nod to one company for next year`s
Confederations Cup in Brazil, ahead of the
World Cup there in 2014.
(END VIDEO TAPE)
AZUZ: It`s almost time for us to run.
But before we do, it`s time for this little
guy to walk. Nothing like a little kiddy cardio
to get the blood pumping.
Obviously, it`s not an outdoor cat if it prefers
to be on a treadmill. When the pace picks
up, the cat does a pretty good job of keeping
up, although it does hop off for some quick
breaks in here.
It`s nice to see a pet support its owners
workout efforts. Otherwise, it might just
be milling around.
And if you`re thinking of forcing your pet
to get on for a few miles, you`d better make
sure it`s in a good mood, because otherwise,
I`d tread lightly.
It`s a long way to go for that one pun.
But a quick congratulations to Coronado High
School in Henderson, Nevada. A student there
got our social media question right.
We hope all of you have a great weekend.
For CNN STUDENT NEWS, I`m Carl Azuz.