Finland is a land of forests and seemingly
endless countryside. Although it's inhabited
by more
than 5 million people, more than a million
of them live in the country's capital and
largest city,
Helsinki. Helsinki is a unique and modern
city characterized by its artistry and its
world famous
designs, as even the most functional buildings
double as monuments to Finland's rich,
architectural history. It's an enchanting
and other-worldly place and its beauty is
striking.
But I didn't travel for over 24 hours just
to see what has to be the most stunning corner
of the
continent. I came to drift Bentleys on ice.
Eight years ago, Bentley began its Power on
Ice event— an outrageous excursion held
near the
Arctic Circle where Bentley owners meet with
skilled instructors and learn to power slide
Bentleys on an enormous frozen lake.
The lake is divided into different handling
tracks and the drivers get seat time in a
range of
Bentley Models, including the Continental
Supersports, Continental GT W12, Continental
GT
V8, and Continental Flying Spur Speed.
The objective is to learn how to get the best
performance from a Bentley in the toughest
of
natural driving conditions and to learn how
to effectively execute controlled power slides
in one
of the most exotic locations in the world.
My first ice-drifting lesson began with Kristian
Sohlberg, a Finnish Rally Driver who has scored
three World Rally Championship points during
his career. As he demonstrated what it takes
to
execute a power-slide in this environment,
it became immediately obvious that drifting
on ice is
much different than drifting on a high-friction
asphalt road surface. On ice, the
car begs to
oversteer and the driver's job is to patiently
wait for the back end to lose grip and spin
out before
gently applying throttle and counter-steer
to complete
the turn. Too much throttle and you'll spin
out or find yourself pointed perpendicularly
to the course. Too little throttle and you
won't make
it through the turn.
It's a controlled yet frenzied dance that
relies on your awareness of the vehicle's
weight transfer,
your ability to correctly place the car in
the corners, and your overall intuition. While
instructors
can provide a great deal of information to
support your success, there's an intangible
element that
can't be taught— the art of listening
to how the car feels, understanding its tendencies,
and
being able to anticipate its behavior on a
surface that offers absolutely no traction.
It's a complex skill to say the least, but
when performed correctly, drifting on ice
is possibly the
most exhilarating thrill you'll ever experience
in your car.
Throughout the day I
had the opportunity to work with different
rally drivers, like Mark Higgins,
a three-time British Rally Champion who served
as a stunt driver in the James Bond films
Quantum of Solace and Sky Fall.
I also spent time with Kris Meeke, a professional
rally driver and Intercontinental Rally
Challenge Champion, who recently put a Continental
GT Speed through its paces at the WRC
Rally GB on BBC Top Gear.
Each helped me better understand the complexities
of ice-driving and gave me the chance to see
the different ways professional drivers'
conceptualize this maneuver.
My afternoon concluded in the best possible
of ways, with Hot Laps with a Finnish rally
star
who's a four-time World Rally champion,
modern-day Bentley Boy, and
World Ice Speed
Record breaker, Juha Kankkunen.
After spending a truly surreal afternoon on
the lake, we headed back to the cabins to
prepare for
our evening adventure/outing which began with
a husky safari dog sledding ride. I spent
the
whole ride wondering if this was really happening,
and when we arrived at a reindeer farm,
things became even more dreamlike.
The reindeer farm was home to the Sami, a
distinct culture in Finland with a population
between
6 and 8 thousand people who speak different
dialects of the Sami language and who traditionally
herd reindeer. There, a man and his daughter
taught us about Sami culture and introduced
us to
their prized president reindeer. Then, it
was off to dinner, where we dined on Sami
foods and
reveled in the extraordinary experience we'd
had on the ice.
This event was one I will never forget. From
the majestic beauty of the countryside to
the sheer
thrill of drifting on ice and doing it in
one of the world's most exquisite vehicles,
this trip is by
far one of the most gratifying and memorable
experiences I've ever had. I learned more
than I
can yet describe, met so many amazing people,
and had the best time imaginable. And I did
it all
in temperatures that averaged 20 degrees below
zero.