so that you know how we approach
this work and how we approach
our partnership with you.
First of all, no one gets
anywhere on their own.
We have all had mentors.
And I have been really blessed
to have two terrific mentors
in my life among many others.
But two very special ones.
When I was a young college
student thinking about going to
law school, I talked my way into
a job as a paralegal in this
big law firm in Chicago.
And anyone who was foolish
enough to make eye contact with
me, I asked them what they did.
And there was a young attorney
who spent some time with me.
And invited me into her office.
Told me what she
did for a living.
Gave me an opportunity to
ask her some questions.
Basically, she invested in me.
And, and she saw something in
me that I didn't see in myself.
She later introduced
me to her fiance,
this hot shot young
lawyer named Barack Obama.
And I really can say that
having known the two of them as
long as I have, I am a better
professional, a better husband,
a better father from
their example and from
their mentorship.
And so I really try to go out
of my way personally to mentor
anyone that I have had
the opportunity to do so.
And I am surrounded by people
here at the White House who
have the same ethic and
who feel the same way.
And at a time of such
turmoil, such volatility,
such economic hardship,
mentoring is even more
important.
And, and you know that taking a
little bit of time in someone's
life, it doesn't just do
something for the person
that you have the
opportunity to mentor.
It does something for yourself.
Participating in your community,
making your community a better
place to live, it
helps all of us.
And so we have brought that
work into the White House.
We have had a great partnership
with you, Big Brothers,
Big Sisters.
We have started our own
mentoring program here.
The Boys Mentoring Program
about 20 young men,
high school age from the
Washington, D.C. area,
that are hooked up with White
House staffers as mentors.
They have done amazing things.
20 young women who are
from the Washington,
D.C. area participated in the
White House Mentoring Program.
I keep hearing from staffers
what a great opportunity
it is for them.
Mentor, mentees have got
a chance to do a couple
of cool things.
They have visited
the Supreme Court.
They have had a chance
to visit Air Force One.
They have hung out with Bo.
(laughter)
And they have met the
President and the First Lady
of the United States.
We just had a graduation
ceremony for those
who graduated.
And for, for the entire
program that graduated just
this past weekend.
We are about to bring on
another 40 young men and
women into the White House.
So we have, we have done this
ourselves because we know what,
what a privilege
it is to be here.
And our responsibility to
reach out and help others.
And so we have a lot of groups
that come into the White House
and sit down, and,
and, and talk with us.
And we are going to have a
parade of senior officials who
want to come in and meet
you and share a little bit
about what we are doing.
Because we know something else.
You all are leaders
in your community.
People follow you.
People listen to you.
You have credibility.
And so when you go
back home and just,
just tell them a
little bit about us.
You know, sometimes people
can get a bit cynical
about government.
Tell them what you saw.
Tell them what you learned.
Tell them what you
thought was great.
Tell them what you thought was
full of beans and all of that.
But just the fact that
you are engaging with us
I think is important.
It is important to us.
I hope it is important to you.
And it will be important
to, to the people back home.
So with that, I want to
turn this over to a, a,
a young attorney, who I first
met when he was a college
student at the
University of Illinois.
He graduated and went
on to the law school,
started his own practice.
He was doing pretty
well until I told him,
forget about all of that.
I need you to come
to Washington,
D.C. and take a
gigantic pay cut.
And, and come work with me.
He is the leader of
Disability Outreach.
And the leader of Disability
Policy for the Domestic Policy
Council, Kareem Dale.
Thanks, Kareem.
(applause)
I was going to give you
a different introduction.
But then I saw you
standing there.
So I knew you could hear me.
Thanks, everyone.
See you later.
(applause)
Kareem Dale:
All right.
Thanks.
Thanks, Mike.
And welcome to the White
House to everybody.
And we are certainly thrilled
to have all of you all here.
And for those who may be
watching on line on the live
stream, we are certainly pleased
to have all of you all watching
on line as well.
So we have a good agenda
for you all today.
Hopefully, everybody
has picked up the agenda
when you walked in.
I will kind of be back and forth
periodically to bridge the gap
between different folks and
to give you some additional
information about
what we are doing,
things we are doing here at the
White House that we think are,
we think was very
interesting to you all.
We think it is beneficial
for you all to know.
But we also think it is
beneficial from our stand point
to make sure that you know
what the President is doing,
what the President is up to,
what our administration is up
to, and what the White
House at large is up to.
So we obviously have coming up
next Tina Tchen who is the
First Lady's Chief of Staff.
And Tina will be here
in a few minutes.
And then we have George
Sheldon from the -- sorry.
Next after Tina
is Joshua DuBois.
Who is the head of our faith
office and then we also
have George Sheldon.
Then to be concluded by
the Attorney General.
So we have a good line-up
for you all today.
And so let me just talk about
a few things while we wait for
Tina to arrive in
the next few minutes.
As Mike said, I have
two, two roles here.
Well, actually I have
three roles here.
You have three roles plus
whatever else might come up
in the interim that
the administration,
that the President, or Valerie
or anybody else needs you to do.
So we have you know
some designed roles,
but we are the
jack of all trades,
particularly in the Office
of Public Engagement.
So as Mike said, I do
Disability Policy in the
Domestic Policy Council.
I also do in the Office of
Public Engagement which is
Valerie Jarrett, one of Valerie
Jarrett's offices I do outreach
to the disability community.
But I also do outreach
to lawyers and the
civil rights community.
I think I got stuck with that.
Actually, Tina is my former
boss in the Office of Public
Engagement before she went over
to the First Lady's office.
And she is a lawyer
from Chicago as well.
And so I think when she saw that
I was coming, she just decided,
well, I know you, you are
a lawyer from Chicago.
I am a lawyer from Chicago.
So you do lawyers.
So that is, that is how
I got stuck with that.
But, but it has been a good gig.
So within the Office
of Public Engagement,
we do a number of things.
And we are the front
door to the White House.
So it is our job to make sure
that you all know what is going
on here at the White House,
what the President is up to.
It is our job to make sure that
we are communicating to you all
as constituents about things
that are important to you,
and to your communities
across the country.
It is also our job
to listen to you.
And to bring you to events like
this and briefings so you can
hear from us, but that
also we can hear from you.
And you will, you will have a
chance to ask questions to
some of our, some of
our briefers today.
We want to have a
chance to hear from you.
And to make sure that we
understand where you
are coming from.
And this is something that we,
we do quite a bit here in the
Office of Public Engagement
bringing in constituents really
from around the country,
Democrats, Republican,
Independents.
It doesn't matter to us.
We want to hear from all
Americans to make sure that that
is, that you all are advising
us on what you think our policy
should be related to,
to your communities.
And so we have developed a
number of different tools
and so that we can do that.
And so that we
can hear from you.
And so that we can understand
where you are coming from.
But also so that, so that
you can hear from us.
Our new director,
our new director,
I guess he is no longer new.
I know he has been
here for maybe, gosh,
I think John has been here
since December or November now.
I lose track.
I have been here
since day one, so it,
it gets a little -- things
get a little run together.
But john has been
here several months,
John Carson is our Director of
the Office of Public Engagement
and so he has developed a number
of tools for us to communicate
with everybody
throughout the country.
And so let me just tell you
about -- let me make sure --
Catherine, Tina is
not here yet, right?
Catherine?
Catherine:
No, she is not.
Kareem Dale:
Okay.
All right. She is all right.
While we are, I am going to
tell you about a couple of these
tools that I think are
beneficial to you all,
that you all should know about.
One of those tools
is what is called a
Community Leaders Briefing.
And the Community
Leaders Briefing is,
it is actually not that much
different than what we are doing
today with you all.
What we do is we
bring in leaders,
community leaders from a
particular constituency or a
particular place in the country
or particular group of people
that are leaders in
their local communities.
That are doing great things,
that are leading their
communities across the country.
And we bring those community
leaders in and we have a
dialogue with White House
administration officials.
And while house officials and
administration officials from
particular agencies.
So we'll bring in those
community or we'll bring in 100
to 150 leaders, they will have
a chance to come here and hear
from administration officials
which is the part that is very
similar to what we
are doing here today.
You will have a
chance to hear from,
hear from administration
officials in
their relevant areas.
We'll do a briefing.
We'll do that here.
They will have a chance to ask
questions and then we'll have
break out sessions in the
afternoon where those,
those leaders break up into
you know four or five, six,
different break out groups and
have a chance to ask questions
of administration officials and
really kind of dig down deep
into some of the issues
that are concerning them in
their local communities.
And it is just another way
for us to reach out to
local communities.
Because, you know, we get kind
of tied up here in Washington
and we think the world
only exists in Washington.
But we realize we need to be
communicating and talking to
communities across the country.
So that is one way
that we do that.
So I say that to say that you
should go out and check out our
website, the Office of Public
Engagement website on the White
House website and you know
if you think that there is an
opportunity that community
leaders briefing,
that you think oh, these set
of or group of persons or a
particular constituency, might
be interested in having a
community, community
leaders briefing,
then you can email me and we'll,
we'll, we'll take a look at it.
And we'll consider it.
And we'll figure out if
there is a way to do it.
Obviously, we are doing this
already for Big Brothers,
Big Sisters.
So it will be
something different.
But that you might
be, I am sure you all,
all of you are involved in other
organizations and other groups
and things of that nature.
So that is one, one idea.
The second thing, second tool
that we have done in order to
highlight people that are doing
great things around the country,
we have created
Champions Of Change.
Let me ask, how many people
have actually heard of community
leaders briefing or
Champions Of Change?
Have any of you
all heard of that?
If you raise your
hands, I am blind,
if you didn't see the cane.
Please don't, don't
raise your hand you know.
You all are the ones
that look crazy, not me.
(laughter)
Because I know I am blind, so
if you all didn't see the cane,
you all want to look like oh,
duh, why did I raise my hand?
He can't see me.
So maybe just clap for
any of those that have,
that have heard of Community
Leaders Briefing or
Champions Of Change.
Okay.
A few of you all.
All right.
Not nearly enough, though.
So Champions Of Change was
something that we developed to
really highlight people
that are really doing great
things around the country.
I will give you an example.
We did a Champions Of Change
in my disability role.
for those persons who are doing
great things in STEM, science,
technology, engineering,
and math for people
with disabilities.
And we had some you
know great people.
Actually it was --
we had some really,
really great people and
there were stories done.
In various news outlets
or really across the country,
a lot of good publicity.
And we highlight generally about
12 to 14 people and we bring
them into the White
House, we highlight them,
we do a blog about
it, we tweet about it,
and we do a couple of
different panel discussions.
We do panel discussions with
the different champions to talk
about the issues.
And we invite you know a
hundred or so people to come in.
Their guests as well as
different people from that
particular community
to come in and listen to the
panel discussions.
We also give the champions
a tour of the White House,
and it is just a great way
to really signal that our,
our belief that it is not
only about government.
It is not government alone that
is going to make a difference
in our communities, but it is
people like you all that
are going to make a
difference everyday.
And it is a chance for us
to highlight some of those
champions that are really
doing phenomenal things.
If you take a look at
our Champions website,
you will see we have had
champions in business,
in environment.
We have had champions in, in,
I think teachers and just all
sorts of different areas where
we have had Champions Of Change.
And so if you take a look
at that and you think, wow,
I have an idea for a
Champions Of Change program.
You know, let us know.
And we will, we will
also consider that.
So to really those are
two really great tools for
us to get involved.
Let me, let me stop for a
second and take a few questions.
If anybody has questions that
they would want to ask about,
generally the Office of Public
Engagement, the work I do,
while, and then we'll just
have, we'll move into Tina as
soon as Tina gets here.
I have some other stuff I am
going to download for you all as
the briefing progresses.
So any questions right now?
If you have questions, just
you can just shout out.
I don't mind.
Any questions?
Audience Member:
Over here. Just quick question.
Big Brothers and Big
Sisters is pleased to have
the chance to be here.
Thank you very much
for hosting us.
Our local agencies
around the country,
are obviously consider
themselves and have been for
many years, for decades,
leaders in child safety and
in youth outcomes.
One of the things we need in
addition to resources
are more volunteers.
And as, through the Office
of Public Engagement,
are there ways that the White
House can encourage different
constituent groups to come
forward and serve as Big
Brothers, Big Sisters
around the country?
Kareem Dale:
Well, I think, I think
what we have tried to do
is while you know it is, it
gets a little complicated if you
start talking about you know
asking people to volunteer
for specific organizations.
I think what we have tried to do
is the President and the First
Lady have really highlighted
volunteerism and we have put
a big emphasis on that.
And the main emphasis
that has been through,
is through the Corporation For
National Community Service.
And really encouraging people
to get out and volunteer in
your local communities and
organizations that you
appreciate and that
you want to help out.
Now, obviously Big Brothers, Big
Sisters would be one of those
organizations where folks can
volunteer and do mentoring.
But there are obviously many
other organizations as well.
And so obviously I would, I
would encourage I think you all,
I assume you all probably have
a partnership in some capacity
with Corporation for
National Community Service.
If not, we can certainly
help facilitate that,
additional conversations
with the corporation.
But we, we, we believe as
you heard Mike talk about,
we certainly believe in
community service and we are
pushing individuals to volunteer
and get involved in their
communities because the
President and First Lady really
believe in that as well.
So we'll, you know, we can
certainly work on that.
Yup.
Other questions at this point?
Okay.
All right.
So let's, we'll give me a
couple of minutes and we'll
wait for Tina to arrive.
Oh, Tina is here.
Perfect timing.
You know, they have been raising
their hands and I told them I
couldn't see them, Tina.
Right at home.
So you heard me talk a little
bit about Tina earlier.
So without further adieu, the
First Lady's Chief Of Staff and
my former boss, Tina Tchen.
(applause)
Tina Tchen:
Thank you, Kareem.
Kareem is you have already
seen sort of one of our best
spokespersons and role models
and is just out you know on all
sorts of issues.
So he has been such a terrific
leader around the country.
And for young people.
I am delighted to be here.
I actually wear two hats
here at the White House.
I am Mrs. Obama's
Chief Of Staff.
And after having served
the first two years of the
administration as the Director
of the Office Of Public
engagement, so that
in former capacity,
I spent a lot of time with Big
Brothers Big Sisters as part of
our outreach efforts.
So I am a great admirer
of the all of the work
that all of you do.
My second hat is I am also the
Executive Director of the White
House Council on Women and
Girls which is chaired by
Valerie Jarrett.
And it is our council consisting
all of the agencies in the
federal government and all of
the major White House offices.
That really promotes pursuant to
the President's directive in the
executive order that he signed
when he created the council back
in March of '09 to make sure
that every part of the federal
government pays attention to
the needs of women and girls in
everything that we do.
And, certainly, making sure that
young women and girls really
reach their full potential in
things like STEM education,
in leadership capacities, in
much of what we all of you do I
know as, as mentors is part of
our mission here and what we do.
For the First Lady's office, as
many of you know from her own
personal history, mentorship
is a concept that she feels
quite strongly about.
Very often times when she
speaks to young people,
not just here in
the United States,
but a key part of many of her
foreign speeches when she,
whether it is in Brazil or in
India or more recently last
summer in South Africa she talks
to young people about her own
personal narrative and
about how, you know,
you can be anything you want
to be and how her own life
story demonstrates that.
And the importance then of
paying it forward and
of mentorship.
Her own personal story as you
all know, one where she after,
you know, graduating from
Princeton, Harvard Law School,
going to work at Sidley Austin
a big national law firm based in
Chicago, then made the decision
to leave that and you know to
work both in city government,
but importantly to work for
public allies.
To really be at the ground level
of that organization that really
promotes young adults working in
inner cities and on programs and
with disconnected youth and
providing that kind of up growth
and mentorship.
And she has seen herself very
much as a mentor to many of
those public allies folks.
And I now see it as we
travel around the country,
more often than not
when we are in a,
in an event and holding some
sort of grass roots rally or
something else, people will
come up having been high school
students that she mentored or
college students who are now
people who are administrators
or executives or work
for state government.
And we have tried to replicate
and model mentorship
here at the White House.
So from early on as many of
you may know, we have had the,
the First Lady started a White
House Mentorship Program.
We will in fact tomorrow hold
a graduation ceremony for our
second group of graduates
who will be graduating
from high school.
We, we started it when we first
got here and had a group of,
of at that point,
sophomores and juniors.
And we graduated that
first group that became
seniors last year.
And our second group this
year, and we have had a
new group come in.
And this year, we had
one for the girls,
because we organized
that from the East Wing.
This year, we told the West
Wing we'll let the boys come in
too and be part of the
graduation ceremony.
The President runs, his staff
runs a mentorship program for
boys as well.
And it is, it has been terrific.
It has been a labor of love
for many of us here
in the White House.
The mentors are a collection
of White House staffers.
And we also do then organize
group events for all of them.
We have had great participation
from places like George
Washington University who has
sent over many of their staff to
do Saturday morning writing
seminars for these kids and
career counseling.
And, you know, we have been able
to take them on visits to Air
Force One and to, to
the Capitol building.
And every year they come with us
to the Women Of Courage Awards
event that Secretary
Clinton gives, gives out.
We have been able to give them
previews of State Dinners.
So it has been, I hope
exciting for them.
It has been tremendously
rewarding for all of us.
Because as -- I don't have
to tell all of you, you know,
mentorship is a two way street.
You know, you get as much out of
it as a mentor as you give and
put in for these young people.
So that has been you know really
a constant theme that I think
the President and the First Lady
have promoted as part of their
overall message in support
of public service as a whole.
It is a theme that carried
through the recent report of
the Commission On Community
Solutions that just finished
it's work last week and
submitted a report to the
President on recommendations
for carrying the work forward to
stay involved with
disconnected youth.
You know, especially our older
youth who are not in school,
not employed, and how
we, we reach those kids.
And in our work that we
recently did in Chicago,
when we hosted the NATO Summit
there about three weeks ago and
what the First Lady
was able to do.
Every part of the summit has
a spousal program where the
spouses of the visiting
leaders participate in
a separate program.
And what we were able to do for
that event was to take those
spouses to the Gary Comer Youth
Center which is a youth center
that Gary Comer, the
founder of Lands End,
created in his old neighborhood
on the south side of Chicago
which is just a few blocks from
where the First Lady grew up.
And it is now a full service
center for youth both after
school and before school
and they started a
charter high school.
And really it is an embodiment
of how people in our community
can be engaged with youth.
And we were able to show that
to the NATO leader spouses.
The First Lady of Norway who is
quite an expert in these having
been to several summits actually
told me it was the best spousal
program they had ever had.
Because they are used to seeing
a lot of museums and lovely
places that are shown off
usually by, by Heads Of State.
They don't often get to see
actually really having an
engagement with the community.
And it is, it is a terrific
center and the kids were really
our tour directors you
know all throughout,
who were terrific spokes people.
And real examples of what
mentorship and what you all do
with Big Brothers
and Big Sisters.
The kinds of molding of
young lives that you,
you all do everyday.
So my message is I guess
you know just really very
brief and two fold.
And that is to thank you for
the work that I know all of
you do across the country
everyday with your mentors,
supporting them and recruiting
them with your mentees.
Supporting them in their lives.
And to make sure that you know
that you have great supporters
and partners in both the East
Wing and the West Wing of
the White House.
And really people throughout
the administration who know
what important work
it is that you do,
who are great supporters
of the work that you do.
And that, you know, we look
forward to continuing to expand
that work and to figure out
ways on which we can you know,
send along and continue
to promote the message of
mentorship throughout
everything that we do.
So thank you again.
With that, I am, you know, I can
take a couple of questions if
people have got some.
Yes.
Paul Bliss:
Yes, I am Paul bliss,
CEO of Big Brothers Big
Sisters in Washington, D.C.
and we have had the
privilege of hosting the Obama
family for approximately two
hours painting the school
for Martin Luther King Day.
And I know there is an
awful lot of Big Brother,
Big Sister agencies across
the country that would love to
be able to host the
President or the First Lady.
How would they go
about doing that?
Obviously, there is re-elections
and there is traveling
throughout the country.
I am certain that there
would be opportunities for us
to host the First Family.
Tina Tchen:
Well, and we have had a
wonderful time here in,
in the DC community.
Sure.
It is -- travel is always
a little challenging.
It is going to be particularly
challenging this year with the
remaining 149 days I gather that
there are now between now and
Novemeber 6 just to pick
a day off the calendar.
But, you know, we are certainly
you know in -- and Kareem you
know can be your contact at
public engagement if there are
particular invites
that you all have or
particular ideas for things.
Feel free to send them in and
send them along you know through
Kareem and his team and they
will get them over to us to,
to consider.
You know, we are happy,
happy to consider those.
But I will beg your indulgence
and your patience as we
work our ways through what
are, what are lots of requests.
But as I said, these are, these
are important issues to the
President and First Lady,
so we welcome any ideas.
Speaker:
Hi Tina.
Remember me.
Tina Tchen:
I do.
Speaker:
How are you?
Tina Tchen:
Okay. How are you?
Speaker:
We spent many years
together in Chicago at the
Department of Children and
Family Services and we won't
talk about that anymore.
(laughter)
It is one, it is just
great to see you.
And the second thing is
connecting with your office and
helping Big Brothers, Big
Sisters expose more of the
work that it is doing.
Particularly, I was very
interested in what Kareem
talked about, highlighting
some of the matches,
the longevity of those matches.
We just had a match that lasted
four children had 24 years of
mentoring from us.
All four went to college.
Two have graduated and two are
on their way to graduating.
That is the kind of community
story I would like to see on
the website or some way
that we can do that.
So if you don't
mind, may I call you?
Tina Tchen:
Of course, you can do that.
And Kareem really is, you
know, we rely on him
also as a contact.
But, you know, he can
get you through to me.
And, and I think, you know,
trying to really pass that word
along and highlight stories.
We are always looking
for, you know,
we call them real
person stories.
But those, those things
that really convey.
You know, we have found telling
an individual's story is
sometimes you know, the
most powerful thing.
You know, I should mention
one of the things I wanted in
particular to mention from the
First Lady's office that we have
spent the last year working on
and I know I think many of
your chapters have as
well, and that is our
Joining Forces Initiative.
So a year ago April the First
Lady started the second
of her initiatives.
The first one is our Let's Move
Initiative on childhood obesity.
But the second one is Joining
Forces which really works to
address the issues concerning
our military families,
our veterans, our active duty
reserve, our military families.
And in particular not just
the service member themselves,
but also their spouse
and their children.
And this is something the First
Lady you know really learned
about on the campaign trail in
talking to many of these
spouses and realizing the
tremendous challenges that
these families have.
They have you know after
ten years of war with an all
volunteer force, we really have
one percent of the country that
is serving to protect
the 99 percent of us.
And I count myself
in that 99 percent,
not coming from a
military family.
But I have now had
the privilege of meeting
these incredible families.
These are folks
whose kids, you know,
probably went to ten schools
before they graduated high
school, because
their parent is deployed and
moved so many times.
They are families who have
endured having their military
family members sometimes it is
actually both parents, you know,
serve multiple deployments.
You know, not just you once.
Usually two, three,
four, five, six times deployed
into a war zone.
And these are kids who are
incredibly resilient and like
their families are pretty
stoic and incredibly patriotic.
But kids who really
deserve our help.
And you know, I know, you know
mentoring and providing you know
that kind of guidance that you
all do so well for our military
kids, would be, you
know, a terrific service.
And it is not just the kids who
are near a military base because
in many ways those communities
are pretty visible and
have stepped up.
Our reserves in
Illinois, you know,
we really have Illinois guard
units that have deployed.
And then those, those, those
folks are spread out to our
communities.
They are not near a base.
So you may have a kid you know
who is the only kid in their
school who is going
through a deployment.
And finding those kids and
finding ways to connect and
support those kids
is something that we,
is I think a really
important service.
And something that you all
can uniquely provide to them.
Okay.
One more.
No.
No more.
I think we answered it all.
Well, thank you again for
all of the work that you do.
Oh, wait one more.
Speaker:
Can you comment on how
you think Big Brothers,
Big Sisters could be relevant
in helping the Council
On Women And Girls?
Tina Tchen:
Well, absolutely.
You know, we would, you know,
again I think that what you do,
you know mentorship and
providing role models for young
girls is, is very important.
And one area that we have been
able to spend a lot of time on
here, at the White House and
through the council has been in
the area of STEM education.
In fact, I just came from a,
from a bilateral session this
morning with a delegation from
India where we were trying to
find ways to support women
and girls in the science,
technology, engineering,
and math fields.
But we have tried to do
that across the board.
We know that we lose
starting after the 4th grade,
girls where they are, girls and
boys interest are about the same
in math and science, that
it starts to fall off pretty
precipitously, you
know, past that point.
And these are the
jobs of the future.
Even though women are
half of the work force,
they are only 25 percent of
the careers in the STEM fields.
And we are not only losing our
girls and our girls are losing
the ability to
access those careers,
which are both where the jobs
are going to be and the economy
of the future and where
the higher paying jobs
are going to be.
We as a country are
losing out on that talent.
And so getting, you know, doing,
providing mentorship at a young
age for these young girls
is going to be pretty key.
So recruiting, we have tried to
actually tap into our federal
scientists in our work force
to provide that mentorship
opportunity.
I think Big Brothers and Big
Sisters could do that as well.
But that is not just
in the STEM area.
We have the next area we
would like to do more in,
I will you know, be quite candid
to say we haven't spend enough
time on but would like to do
some more on is the more general
area of girl's self esteem.
I mean I think building the self
esteem of our young girls and
women and I say this as the
mom of a 15 year old daughter,
is so important with all
of the other counter messaging
that they are exposed to
that is out there.
Again, I think mentors
provide that sounding board,
an alternative role model, an
alternative ear and support to
these young girls who are
fighting against a lot of
cultural messaging
that is different.
And in many cases, you
know, even worse kinds of
vulnerabilities and dangers,
whether it is dangers at home,
and vulnerabilities at
home, or externally.
And I think making sure
that we are connected to
those young girls.
And we would welcome you
know greater partnership.
We have a Deputy Director Avra
Siegel who works with me and
Haley Schneier (phonetic)
who is one of Kareem's
colleagues in the Office of
Public Engagement who is devoted
to women and girls outreach.
And again Kareem can get you
in touch you know with a more
specifically if there is
specific things that you want
to connect with the Council
on Women and Girls on.
We would again
welcome that as well.
So again, thank you.
We hope you enjoyed your day at
the White House and we thank you
again for all of the work
that you do everyday.
(applause)
Kareem Dale:
All right.
Thank you very much, Tina.
It is always, you
know, there is,
there is a few of us around
here that have been around
here since day one.
And go back to the transition.
Tina is one of those, one of my
colleagues here who we came in
on day one, when it was
a little -- you know,
we didn't quite know where all
of the bathrooms were and where
everything was going on.
So we spent a long time here
and it has been a great journey.
So while we wait
for Joshua, a couple of
other things I want to do.
The first thing is when we, you
know, we talk about, you hear,
you have heard Tina and you
heard Mike say it, if you,
questions you have about
participating in events or
getting in contact with Tina or
the Council for Women and Girls,
we actually, we are
very serious about that.
So if you do want to
make those connections,
I am happy to help
make those connections.
Particularly
because it won't go,
it won't be me having
to do the work.
I will be able to put
it off on my colleagues.
I am always happy to give
my colleagues more work.
And so but if you, if
you make that contact,
Kelly your government relations
person has my email address
and contact information.
Kelly, you are free to give it
to any of these folks and
we will make those
connections with you.
And that reminds me, I want to
thank Kelly for all of her work
in getting this done.
She did a phenomenal job, and --
(applause)
-- believe you me, doing
something here at the White
House like this, we put a lot of
demands on her to get us all of
the information, get it right,
get it by a specific time,
and this, that, and the other.
So she did a great job.
So we appreciate all of her
efforts in making the
event easy for us.
Is Joshua here?
He usually just like yells
out at me or something crazy.
So, so just if you have, if
you really do want to connect,
you know, I will second what
Tina said about the young man
who asked about the events, I
mean the schedule is incredibly
tight for the President
and the First Lady.
So it is very difficult.
And a lot of times it is maybe
we get an opportunity for some
sort of off the record
thing at the last minute.
But it is incredibly difficult
to get things on the schedule.
So just bear with us
and keep that in mind.
But the First Lady's office is
really great about connecting
particularly about
her core initiatives,
whether it be Joining Forces, or
Childhood Obesity, Let's Move,
those are her two
core initiatives.
The Council on Women and Girls
would go through the two young
ladies that Tina mentioned.
So I am happy to make those
connections and our team is
always looking for really
great opportunities.
So I have more to say to you.
But I don't want
Joshua yelling at me.
So without further adieu, let me
introduce you to the head of our
faith based office and another
one of my colleagues that has
been here since day one.
And is a long time friend and
worked for the President's
Senate office as well.
Joshua DuBois.
(applause)
Joshua DuBois:
Thank you.
I appreciate it.
Good afternoon everyone.
Audience:
Good afternoon.
Joshua DuBois:
It is such a pleasure to
be here and to bring
you greetings on behalf
the President and the
entire White House.
And also on behalf of a
fellow Big Brother myself.
(applause)
This is my crowd here.
I, I was, when I was walking
over here and I was recalling
the first moment that I met my
little, I was at the top floor.
Anybody been to Big Brothers
of Mass Bay by any chance?
There we go.
Hi, guys.
So any way, and it is
in a high-rise building.
At least it was at the time.
We were in this conference
room on the top floor.
And the dread and fear that
filled my soul when I thought
about the, this responsibility
that I was entering into.
And then I saw this little kid
with these huge eyes looking up
at me, and I had no idea
what I was going to do.
But I knew it was going
to be a good thing.
And that was, gosh,
13 or 14 years ago.
We have been hanging
out ever since.
(applause)
Thank you.
I, I knew it was much more
than you know just kind of a
programmatic connection when he
went on his Facebook page and,
you know, you add your
siblings on there.
And he added me as a brother
onto his, to his Facebook page.
And I almost got emotional
when I saw that, that happen.
So Adid, he is now, he
was a wonderful kid then,
facing a number of
challenges in his life.
His father was incarcerated.
But I am happy to say he just
find up his freshman year
at Morehouse College.
And so we are delighted
by his progress.
(applause)
And it's just a wonderful
example of what you all do
every single day.
And it's the small
things that matter.
It's the Match Support folks
reaching out to us and making
sure things are on track,
even when we ignore them,
and I'm sorry, guys.
(laughter)
I was quite delinquent.
But I was still, Adid and
I were still connecting.
But it took me a couple
weeks to return phone calls.
But -- or, you know, the
opportunities that we went to
baseball games at Fenway and ice
skating and all sorts of things.
You know, years later these
stick with us and they matter.
And, you know,
Adid, I'm positive,
is going to be a future
leader in this country.
He is going to finish up at
Morehouse and maybe run for
office or impact
kids in other ways.
And I was excited to talk to him
a couple weeks ago and he said
he's going to reach out to
his own local Big Brothers,
and when the time is right
become a Big Brother himself.
And so you know that
your work matters,
but on behalf of the President
I want to affirm that it matters
so much for so many young
men and women all around,
all across our country.
So I lead the Office of
Faith-Based and Neighborhood
Partnerships, and my job is to
work through our offices at 13
federal agencies to connect
the Administration to local
nonprofits, both
faith-based and secular.
For example, we have an office
at the Department of Labor that
works with local congregations
and nonprofits on job training
programs, getting them
set up and running.
We have an office at the
Department of Agriculture that
works on food and nutrition
issues with local congregations
and nonprofits at the Department
of Justice and Education,
and on, and on.
We've managed the government's
relationship with local groups
around the country.
And we're also one of several
advocates for mentoring
in the Administration.
I have been particularly pleased
to work with my colleagues at
the Department of Justice on
making sure that the funding
for mentoring programs like
Big Brothers continues and
strengthens in some ways.
I was very delighted last
year we were able to support,
in somewhat of a new way,
mentoring of juvenile offenders
to the tune of about $13
million in an impactful way.
Thank you.
(applause)
And what we're trying to do is
kind of weave mentoring into
federal programs that may
be distinct from mentoring.
For example, workforce
development, you know, well,
if you're thinking
about, you know,
how to make sure that young
people are connected to jobs,
well, one thing they need is a
good mentor in their life that
reminds them about, you know,
the importance of going to
work and finding employment.
If you're looking at ex-offender
reentry, which we talked about,
or substance abuse, well, one
thing that would be great for
folks who are receiving
counseling and support for
substance problems is to have a
mentor that comes alongside them
and supports them as well.
So we're trying to
cross-pollinate mentoring
across other federal programs
and federal agencies,
and our office does a lot
of that work advocating for
mentoring across
the Administration.
We are open to new ideas.
For example, we've been
participating in some
conversations recently about
how in light of the cuts to
the Mentoring Children
of Prisoners program,
how potentially the Department
of Justice can partner with
HHS to support some
of that good work.
If there are other ideas, in
fact I was talking with one of
our other mentoring leads
at DOJ on the way over here,
we want to hear from you.
We don't want this to be
a one-way conversation.
There's a lot going on
at any given moment.
I have 13 agency
offices I'm running,
and other folks are
doing a lot of work,
and so don't assume that we have
all the ideas and info we need
to support mentoring.
We don't, we need your feedback.
We need to be in conversation
and dialogue with you.
I'll give everyone my e-mail
address so we can keep the
conversation going from here.
For any tweeters in the room,
any folks on Twitter in here?
I'm also @JoshuaDuBois as well.
And I respond to
those frequently.
My e-mail address is JDuBois,
J-D-U-B-O-I-S @WHO.EOP.gov.
I'll give that again.
J DuBois, JDUBOIS at WHO,
as in White House Office,
EOP, Executive Office
of the President, .gov.
And I'd love to continue the
conversation with you all.
But, you know, most
importantly, thank you for
all the good work you do.
I am just one of thousands of
Big Brothers and Big Sisters
who's deeply appreciative of
this wonderful organization.
You're changing lives
every single day.
People say that a
lot, but, you know,
I've seen it in my own life
and in Adid's life as well,
and on behalf of the
President I want to appreciate
your good work.
Thank you all so much.
(applause)
Thank you.
Kareem Dale:
All right.
Thank you very much to Joshua.
So our next speaker, as
you see from your agenda,
is from Department of Health and
Human Services Administration on
Children and Families.
Please give a warm
welcome to George Sheldon.
(applause)
George Sheldon:
Thank you.
Welcome.
Do we have any Floridians here?
(cheering)
All right.
I just want to make sure.
I've only been with the
federal government for
the last 12 months.
I had this nice, quiet job in
Florida running the Florida
Department of
Children and Families,
and so they decided to open me
up to the federal government,
and I'm really trying to
learn how this process works.
My Deputy in Florida when
I came here said that
Washington is 76 square
miles surrounded by reality.
(laughter)
But I -- and I think that Joshua
made this point -- is that all
knowledge doesn't reside
here, it really is out in the
communities, and I've
learned that so much.
I would also say that there
have been better times to be the
Assistant Secretary
of the Administration for
Children and Families.
I would love to have been
Assistant Secretary in the '90s,
when the federal government was
flush with dollars and we were
expanding, but these
are different times.
I mean, you know that.
You've seen the recent poverty
numbers among children,
one in every five children in
this country live in poverty.
It's even worse for African
Americans, about 38 percent,
35 percent for Hispanics.
It's upwards to almost 50
percent with children
who are growing up in
single-parent families.
And that's four times the
rate of poverty among kids in
two-parent families.
And so children are
much more at risk today than
probably ever before.
And a lot of things add to that.
I was in San Diego just
this last Thursday,
and met with the Federal Task
Force on Human Trafficking at
the high school, Glenmont
Unified School District,
and came, you know, stark in
the face of active recruiting in
that high school and other
high schools for children
to be trafficked.
It is a whole new phenomenon,
and these are children who are
disaffected, who may not have
the best of all home life.
And that's, and that combined
with everything is a real,
is the reason the partnerships
with entities like Big Brothers
and Big Sisters is so important.
And I'm not saying
that, that's a reality.
When I first got to the
Department in Florida,
I sat down with about 15 young
kids who aged out of foster
care, and these were kids in
their, you know, 20, 21, 25.
And, you know, it was one of
those kind of things you do when
you just become an agency
head and you think, well,
I've got to go by this, so
I'll spend about 20 minutes,
make a few comments.
Well, two and a
half hours later,
I think I learned more from
those 15 kids about foster care
than I ever learned from
all the professionals.
And I'm not taking anything
away from professionals.
But we designed really a whole
child welfare system in this
country, and we never
talked to the kids.
(applause)
And I think that's, I mean,
I think that's so -- what I
learned from those kids was
almost to a child they said I
would have rather stayed at
home and dealt with some of the
issues out of my home than to
go in to a child welfare system
where I was passed from home
to home, school to school.
And I don't care if you're
in ten good foster homes,
that if you're in
that many homes,
you begin to believe as a child
you don't belong anywhere.
And that is so important, that
is the reason that mentors are
so important.
Whether a brother figure or
sister figure or father figure
or mother figure is so
important to these kids,
whether it's children in
the child welfare system,
those children who are
susceptible to human trafficking
in Glenmont High School, it
is so important to
have that connection.
The other thing I learned from
those kids was how important one
human being was in their life.
It may have been
another foster child,
it may have been
a foster parent,
their caseworker,
but in many cases
it was a mentor.
Somebody who took the time to
do something with them that they
looked for every week.
The third thing I really learned
is how important being normal is
to them and doing normal things.
And if you look at
child welfare systems,
they're really designed
to be risk adverse.
You know, let's not allow
something to happen because
we're going to be sued
as a result of it.
So we, you know, when I was --
I was speaking to a group of
foster parents in
Clearwater, actually,
and afterwards some of these
foster parents came over to me
and said that we had a dangerous
activity czar in the department.
I said no, we don't.
(laughter)
She said, yes, you do.
Well, we did.
We had the this woman who
approved what foster
children could do.
Well, you can be
part of Boy Scouts,
but you can't
participate in archery.
I mean, I'm serious about this.
And so I basically
said, you know,
you can do something
else in the department,
and we created what we call --
(laughter)
We created what I
called a normalcy czar.
Because that's what
kids want to be.
They want to go, they don't want
the latest Wii game or iPad,
most of them want to go
to the prom or they want
to learn how to drive.
Ninety percent of the kids in
the foster care system age out
without a driver's license.
My god daughter, when she was
old enough to get her learner's
permit, she had
dad up at 7:00 a.m.
You know what I'm talking about.
We also use all these nonnormal
words at child welfare.
You know, foster kids are
in multiple placements.
Regular kids grow up in
several different homes.
You know, foster parents
need respite care.
Regular parents need a vacation.
(laughter)
I mean, it's, and I think it's
a mindset we really kind of have
to get out to.
The -- but I do think that I've
been mentoring a young man
for several years, and I
just got an opportunity,
he was in foster
care for 11 years,
and I just had an opportunity
to robe him at his
graduation from law school.
(applause)
Which is -- and, because a
lot of these kids who have,
who are disaffected, who have,
whether it's foster care or
whether it's poverty or
whether -- these are good kids.
And generally pretty bright if
they're given that opportunity
to dream and to think
beyond themselves.
And I think that's the reason
the partnerships -- I will tell
you that having been now at
state government now in the
federal government,
government cannot do it all.
We can provide some resources,
and that's becoming
more and more limited.
We can provide some
overall direction,
but in reality communities have
to take it upon themselves.
And that's the reason that I
think Big brothers Big Sisters
are so important.
I'm also a strong
proponent of Best Buddies,
because I think they've had this
issue working with kids with
disabilities.
So the extent to which
we can work with you,
I know that these are
particularly tough times to get
in the door of a state agency,
with the limited budgets that
they are constricting,
but we have sent out,
with my counterpart at
the Department of Labor,
a letter to commissioners around
the country pointing out the use
of TANF funds and that TANF in
use for summer jobs for young
kids is an allowable expense
to count against their
maintenance of effort.
And that they really ought to
be thinking in those terms.
I think when you're trying to
access those kind of supports
from government, it is
important to be a little
innovative in doing that.
So I just wanted to take
a few minutes and come by.
I don't want to take up
too much of your time,
but I appreciate what you do.
I'm coming back to Florida
for a day this week, actually.
I miss Florida, but I like the
rest of the 49 states as well.
(laughter)
This is a big country.
I'd be happy to take a
question or two if I have the
authorization to do that.
Yes, ma'am.
Audience member:
Most TANF funds
are directed to states.
How can you help us or help
the states understand that TANF
funds can be used quite
appropriately by an organization
such as Big Brothers
Big Sisters?
They really do fit the category
of many of the children --
George Sheldon:
They do.
And some that -- are there other
Big Brothers Big Sisters around
the country who have
access to TANF funds?
It really, to what
states are you from?
Audience member:
I'm from Pennsylvania.
Mississippi.
Audience member:
I'm from Minnesota.
Texas.
George Sheldon:
Has Minnesota accessed --
Audience member:
We just accessed
TANF funds this year.
George Sheldon:
The letter that we
sent out -- and I'll
take another look at it in terms
of guidance to state agencies --
with Labor, was really
focused on summer jobs,
but it was also articulating
using local community
agencies to do that.
But let me do that, we've had
the same issue with states with
Boys Clubs Girls Clubs, who have
also attempted to access TANF.
I would also point out that TANF
used to be almost two-thirds
direct cash assistance,
and it's now reversed.
And I believe in
flexibility for the states.
I mean, coming from the
State, I believe in that.
But the extent to which we
can give greater guidance,
I clearly am willing to do that.
I think they've got to
be innovative with it.
I also think you all have to be
aggressive, because, you know,
because they get a lot of asks.
Yes, sir.
Audience member:
Thank you for pointing
out the poverty
statistics, that 50 percent
of children with single-parent
families are living in poverty.
Over 80 percent
of the over 200,000
children in Big Brothers Big
Sisters are from single-parent
families.
So we are in that sweet spot.
In terms of working together,
Big Brothers Big Sisters
relative to many other mentoring
organizations and youth serving
organizations has a
tremendous capacity.
It's been doing research
on youth outcomes,
continuous research for quality
improvement on match strength
and match length, and we'd like
to continue to share that with
the Department of Health
and Human Services.
It may help you all
as you're informed,
and inform you as you're
designing and
developing programs.
George Sheldon:
I would be very
interested in that because,
you know, this Administration
has put a heavy emphasis on
evidence-based research, and
a lot of what we're doing,
particularly in the
child welfare area,
is now real
evidence-based practices.
We've made a major commitment
to trying to deal with trauma
as an underlying element
in child welfare,
and I think that same thing is
true with a lot of the kids
who grew up in poverty,
is the, you know,
there are some who
call it toxic stress,
and that toxic stress has
a long-term impact on the
development of that child.
So any research you
can share with us,
I would be very interested in.
And any of our programs that you
feel like you might be able to
have some additional insights
in, be aggressive in doing that.
I learned a new motto in
Texas, I think, which was,
"In God we trust.
All others must bring data."
(laughter)
And I think we've got
to recognize that.
The one thing I do, as, the one
thing that I really do -- and I
am very committed to using
data and analyzing it in an
evidence-based research fashion,
but I also think it is very
important to not lose
sight that there are real
faces behind that data.
And these kids are as diverse
as they are individuals.
And I think that's the real
value of this one-on-one
mentoring program that
you all are talking about,
is there's a real
recognition of that.
Yes, ma'am.
Audience member:
I think you will
be proud to know our
Big Brother of the Year and our
Big Sister of the Year and their
Littles, and there's something
special you want to know about
our Big Brother of the Year and
his Little Brother -- why don't
you guy stand up --
our Bigs of the Year,
and tell them where you're from.
George Sheldon:
Which one's the big one
and which one's the little one?
(laughter)
Audience member:
I'm older, and we
live in Tallahassee.
George Sheldon:
Oh, welcome.
(applause)
Audience member:
Born and raised in Tallahassee.
Lived there all our lives,
so we're Floridians
through and through.
It's quite an honor to be here.
George Sheldon:
Well, thank you.
I did stay up last night and
watched Florida State
beat Stanford --
(laughter)
-- 18 to 7.
It was close.
(laughter)
Audience member:
Thank you very much.
Audience member -- (inaudible)
a year behind --
George Sheldon:
Stand up.
(applause)
Yes, ma'am.
Audience member:
Thank you very much
for pointing out the
importance of listening to
the children, and the voices,
and the impact of
their statements.
Many of our agencies have
waiting lists where children,
the parents themselves
have called in.
They're almost equal the number
of children that we're serving.
So talk about a groundswell of
support and yearning for the
kinds of services that we offer.
How can DHHS either through
policy or resources help us
address this groundswell, this
massive need that is out there
for children who
need our service?
George Sheldon:
Well, and I'll
be honest with you,
I don't have all the
answers to that question,
because you've been
reading the newspaper,
we're dealing with
constricting budgets,
and that constricting budget
at the federal level is
impacting state and local's
disproportionately, even,
if you look at it.
So I think we've got to be a
little more innovative and a
little more -- we've got to
do a lot more to integrate our
programs together, and recognize
that we can no longer afford the
inefficiency of various
streams of funding.
And that means, the extent
to which we can -- and we're
desperately trying to
break the silos down.
The extent to which we can
integrate what's happening to
child support around a child,
and that those child support
dollars are really focused
on going to the child,
and we've got some policies
forthcoming to do that.
And the extent to which we
can also leverage
TANF in that family.
So I think part of
that is how we do it.
I think that I would be all ears
for any suggestions that you
might have as to how efforts
that we have at the federal
government can greater impact
the ability to do that
at the local level.
States are very important
to this process.
And so I think it is important
to work with your local
commissioners, in the
children and families area.
I think TANF is one of the most
flexible that -- I think you do
need to keep reminding
state agencies, as we will,
about the flexible use of TANF.
Yes, sir.
And then I'll come --
Audience member:
(inaudible)
-- receive TANF dollars, would
you be interested or willing
before you send a letter out to
your states to learn what the 20
or so Big Brother Big Sister
agencies are doing with creative
programs and maybe --
George Sheldon:
You're here in D.C., right?
Audience member:
Yes.
George Sheldon:
Yeah, I'd be happy,
I'd be happy to sit down with
some folks and explore what kind
of guidance would be helpful,
recognizing the constraints on
our budget, but I would
be very open to that,
because I -- as I indicated,
all the knowledge
doesn't reside here.
Definitely here.
But here in D.C.
Audience member:
Because I'm sure a
lot of other agencies
across the country are using
TANF dollars, creatively.
George Sheldon:
Yeah, I think states can
learn from each other.
And I think one thing
is to get the APHSA,
the American Public Human
Service Association.
And I don't mind
engaging with them.
We also just hired someone away
from the National Governors'
Association who probably knows
TANF as well as anybody in the
country, so maybe I
can sit down with her.
And I promised one and I know
I'm violating a rule --
Audience member:
(inaudible)
I think one of the things that
we've been looking at is how we
can collaborate better
with different agencies,
and the more that I think the
government and you all who are
providing us resources can
encourage that collaboration and
incent those agencies that work
together and get rid of the
redundancies would
be useful as well.
George Sheldon:
I appreciate that, and we will.
Let's get together.
One thing that we are doing
under the Affordable Care Act,
the Affordable Care Act,
among other things, you know,
you can say whatever
you want about it,
there are a lot of
amazing things about it.
But what it basically did is it
gave 100 percent federal money
to develop the information
system for the insurance
exchanges, 90 percent,
90-10 for Medicaid.
OMB about six, eight months ago
gave us a waiver so that states
can now plan that large
technology system and bring
Human Services in to it, and
Human Services doesn't have to
share in the cost of
development of the big system.
So information
sharing is important.
And I think, frankly,
and a lot of states,
in their advance
planning documents,
have really indicated a
willingness to go after those
dollars and bring
Human Services in.
I think that is a major step in
breaking down some of the silos.
In Florida, for instance, I had
real difficulties, for instance,
getting my agency to talk
to the Medicaid agency.
And yet Medicaid funded a lot of
services to the people that we
served.
And breaking down, and -- I
think this technology
thing can do that.
Thank you very much and
come back to Washington.
(applause)
Kareem Dale:
All right, thank
you very much to George for
that valuable information.
So, as we prepare
to wrap up here,
our final speaker for today is
a man who needs no introduction,
a man who actually in my role as
disability policy leader for the
Administration, is -- the
Department of Justice has done
an unbelievable job on civil
rights for all Americans,
including Americans
with disabilities,
and also whose man is a very
staunch advocate for mentoring
and the benefits of that.
I think you're going to hear
a little bit of that
from him today.
So without further ado, let
me introduce to you the
Attorney General of the United
States, Eric H. Holder.
(applause)
Attorney General Eric Holder:
Good afternoon.
Audience members:
Attorney General Eric Holder:
So I'm the last speaker, huh?
Audience members:
Yes.
Attorney General Eric Holder:
I'm all that separates you from
whatever you're
going to do next.
Did someone say cocktails?
Ooh, ooh, ooh, we've
got a live crew here.
I was told as I
walked in, though,
this is being live streamed,
which means like, you know,
my fun quotient went
way down, folks.
(laughter)
If it was just
going to be us here,
we could have some good times,
some jokes, talk about Congress,
but, you know, I
can't do that now. So.
(laughter)
I promise, I promise, I promise.
I want to thank Kareem
for those kind words,
and for all that he and his
colleagues at the White House
Office of Public Engagement
have done to bring us all
together here today.
This is something that
for me is a real treat.
I started out this morning
talking to the League of women
voters about a whole variety of
things that have been kind of in
the news lately, and, you know,
voting rights and things like
that, and this is I think a
good way to bookend what
otherwise has been a not
really enjoyable day.
But so I'm glad to
end it with you all.
(laughter)
It is really a pleasure
for me to be here with you,
and a privilege to join
so many advocates, allies,
and partners in calling
attention to this critical and
really growing need for
mentors in neighborhoods
across this country.
Now for more than a century
Big Brothers and Big Sisters of
America has led the way in
encouraging community leaders to
give of their time and talents
to support America's young
people, especially those
who are at risk and those
who are in need.
Last year alone, these
are really pretty amazing
statistics, more than 350
local Big Brothers Big Sisters
agencies served over
200,000 children nationwide.
That is very significant.
Their ongoing efforts have
raised awareness about the
importance of positive role
models and demonstrated the
enduring impact that
each mentor can have.
So this afternoon I'm
proud to stand with so many
administration leaders, many
of whom have come by here,
and understand that at least
some of you had a chance to meet
the big guy today,
is that right?
Who got to see the President?
Don't hate him, don't hate him.
(laughter)
All right.
How was that selection
determination made?
Audience member:
Big Brother of the year,
2011 and 2012 --
(inaudible)
Attorney General Eric Holder: Okay.
And how was it decided
who would meet with me?
(laughter)
Everybody, right?
Audience member:
Everybody --
(inaudible)
Attorney General Eric Holder:
That's all right, no, no,
don't try to clean it up, don't
try to clean it up, that's okay.
All right.
But I am really proud to stand
with so many people from the
Administration in celebrating
this organization's
accomplishments, and commending
you on yet really another
extraordinary year.
But I also recognize that this
leadership summit is much more
than an occasion for reflecting
on the record of success that
you have helped to establish.
It also presents an opportunity
to recommit ourselves to
building on this progress and to
continuing the unfinished work
that still stands before us.
Today, again some other
startling statistics: More than
a million students drop out
of high school every year,
and many of those kids
start down the wrong path,
turning to violence, criminal
behavior, substance abuse,
and just over 2 million
kids per year are arrested.
A third of all children
and half of all low-income
youth fail to graduate
from high school on time.
Nearly a third of those between
the ages of 12 and 17 have
recently reported using
alcohol or marijuana,
and today one in four violent
crime victims known to law
enforcement -- children, think
about that -- one in four
violent crime victims known to
law enforcement are children.
Now you've heard, you know,
these alarming statistics.
You're familiar with the
heartbreaking stories and
probably have seen some of
this harsh reality firsthand.
You also understand that we have
a responsibility to confront
this problem, and you've led
the way in responding to this
crisis, not with despair,
but with resolve.
By serving as the role models
that so many children lack,
you've shown how mentors can
teach really invaluable lessons,
help young people develop the
skills they need for future
success, and instill a sense
of self worth and self respect.
You have proven that
mentors can fill a void,
helping to guide and encourage
children as they set and achieve
goals and develop the
confidence necessary to
fulfill their potential.
Now, studies have really
consistently shown that through
stable and consistent,
consistent personal engagement,
mentored children are more
likely to grow and mature
into confident and
responsible young adults.
Now one report found that
children matched with a Big
Brother or a Big Sister were
nearly 50 percent less likely to
begin using illegal drugs and
more than 50 percent less
likely to skip school.
Great statistics.
Over the years we've also seen
that investing in mentoring
programs makes basic
economic sense.
This is a time of, you know,
great economic problems we've
had in terms of budgets and
things like that nature.
In fact if we were to increase
the high school graduation rate
among male students
by just 5 percent,
estimates suggest that our
country would save close to $8
billion in criminal
justice spending.
So there's a direct correlation
between those things.
But as I'm sure we can all
say from personal experience,
one of the greatest joys of
mentoring is that the benefits
really run both ways.
It doesn't just go to the kids.
During my time as United States
Attorney for the District of
Columbia during the
Clinton Administration,
my staff and I adopted
an elementary school in a
low-income, predominantly
African-American part of
Washington, D.C.
I was really thrilled to have a
chance to work with these kids
on a regular basis,
getting to know them,
becoming invested
in their futures,
and finding a remarkable and
rewarding sense of purpose in
the relationships that we
developed in my office and
with that school.
As a result, I'm really proud
to say that I know well and have
seen firsthand that
mentoring changes lives,
and not just for the students.
The prosecutors in my office,
hard-boiled, you know,
long-time prosecutors, were
changed as a result of their
interaction with these kids
at Amidon Elementary School.
And that's one of the many
reasons why I've been honored
to join the President,
the First Lady,
and others throughout the
Administration in supporting
mentoring programs.
We've made great strides
in bringing stakeholders,
including federal officials,
state and local partners,
community organizations, and
leaders like yourselves together
to discuss how mentors can
improve educational outcomes and
to reduce juvenile delinquency.
And I believe that there's good
reason to be optimistic about
the continued progress
that we'll achieve through
initiatives like the First
Lady's Corporate Mentoring
Challenge, as additional
partners rally to this effort,
and in the robust, ongoing work
of today's Justice Department.
Over the last three years my
colleagues and I have made a
strong and in some cases really
unprecedented commitment to
expanding federal assistance
for mentoring initiatives and
exploring evidence-based
strategies for reducing
children's exposure to violence.
Since 1994, the Department's
Office of Juvenile Justice and
Delinquency Prevention has
awarded more than $480 million
to support mentoring programs.
(applause)
And there was a direct
connection between great
mentoring and good
anti-crime efforts.
People sometimes don't
see that connection,
but we certainly realize
that that exists in this
Justice Department.
This past March we announced a
$20 million grant solicitation
for research proposals that can
give us a better sense of
which of these programs
are most effective.
Now, these investments will
help to strengthen the progress
that's been made through the
Department's Defending Childhood
Initiative, which was launched
in 2010 as part of an effort to
help us better understand
and more effectively
combat youth violence.
And it will build upon a
critical work that's under way
in ten cities nationwide
as part of the National Forum on
Youth Violence Prevention.
Now as a result of these really
broad-based collaborative
efforts, I think that we're
making meaningful, measurable,
measurable progress in
assisting the young people who
need our help the most.
But as you all know, this
work is far from over.
Countless at-risk
youth, foster kids,
young people in tribal lands
and juvenile offenders rejoining
their communities are really
still in desperate need of our
help, and every last one of
them must continue to be the top
priority for each
and every one of us.
Now it's no exaggeration to say
that our nation's future will be
defined and its progress
determined by the support that
we offer and the doors that
we open for our young people.
But as I look out
over this crowd today,
I cannot help but feel confident
in our ability to rise to this
challenge and to bring
about the change that our
young people deserve.
Never forget that they
are depending on us.
These kids are depending on us.
And know that
President Obama and I,
along with so many others
in this Administration,
are counting on each of you to
keep up your outstanding work
and to continue driving
these efforts forward.
I look forward to working with
you all in the coming months
and years to make
America what it should be for
all of our children.
Thank you so much.
(applause)
Kareem Dale:
All right.
Well, I guess that brings
us to the conclusion of
our event today.
A few things that I
want to touch on before we
let you all depart.
One encouragement or two
encouragements, maybe,
and then one announcement
of something you all
can take with you.
The two encouragements
are, number one,
we need you all to get involved.
And we need you all to get
involved for yourselves,
for your communities, but
for your young people,
and not just only on mentoring.
You've heard a lot today about
mentoring and the things that
are great about Big
Brothers Big Sisters,
but there's a lot that this
President is fighting for that
benefits you all, but that even
more importantly benefits
the future of our country.
And that's the young
people that you all mentor.
So we need you all
to get involved.
We believe that the President,
the Attorney General,
and so many others in our
Administration are fighting for
Americans, fighting for
Americans to be able to achieve.
And so we need you all
involved in that effort.
The second encouragement really
relates to getting involved.
And I'll give you an
example of, you know,
things that you can
do to get involved.
We need you to be aware of
what we're doing and the fights
that are going on in our
country right now.
One that I think should be near
and dear to your heart is the
fight that's going on right
now regarding student loans.
And I don't know if all of
you all have heard about that,
but the rates for
college students,
some of whom are here today,
just some college students,
the rates on college student
loans are going to double if
Congress doesn't pass
action to stop those rates
from doubling by July.
And so the President has been
vocal in his support for not
doubling student loan rates and
for making sure that students
don't have that happen to them.
They are the future
of our country,
and the President has been
pushing for that effort.
We need you all to get involved
and support that effort for the
student loans, the student
loan rates not to double.
There are all types
of Twitter, hashtags,
if you will -- they've told
me that's what it's called,
I'm not a Twitter guy myself.
But there are hashtags involved,
I'm sure there's stuff on
Facebook, I'm sure the
students have heard about it,
I'm sure that many of you all in
this room have heard about it,
but this is impacting the
students that you are mentoring
now, for those who are in
college or who are maybe getting
ready to graduate from college,
and those who are coming up in
the future who are
preparing to go to college.
And this is an important
fight, and so we need you
all's voices to be heard.
And for you all to get engaged
and know what's going on in your
community and support
the effort for student loan
rates to not double.
That's just one example of the
many things that are going on
in this country and that are
going to be going on over the
next five or six months.
So I strongly encourage you all
to pay attention to what's going
on, get involved on behalf
of yourselves, your families,
and the students who represent
the future of this country.
So thank you all very, very
much for joining us today.
We're delighted to have you all.
Please stay in touch, please
check out our White House
website, as I talked
about, and stay involved.
And then as you depart here
to my left and your right,
we do have copies of President
Obama's proclamation from
last year on mentoring.
I forgot the month that it was
--it's national mentoring month
Audience members:
January.
Kareem Dale:
Yeah. So everybody knows that.
(laughter)
So we have signed official
copies of his proclamation for
each one of you all to take --
one, so your colleagues get one,
too -- take one with
you as a memento.
So thank you very much.
(applause)