MALE SPEAKER: Whoa.
SEAN MALTO: The first time I
ever heard of Eric Koston?
You know what?
It was probably "Yeah Right."
Like, that was
way later, I know.
Like, there's so much of Eric
before that I never really
realize, but like, "Yeah Right"
and that whole video
coming out was probably
the first time I'd
ever heard of him.
And I saw the trailer, and it
was him yelling at some kid.
And I knew he was the best, you
know, Eric Koston having
last par, and just being that
dude at the time was crazy.
He did an ollie backside
noseblunt at Arco.
I learned an ollie backside
noseblunt like two weeks ago.
And for him to do it at
Arco, like, 2003.
That is crazy.
ATIBA JEFFERSON: It's always fun
to watch Eric get a video
deadline, because that's when he
starts like, fuck this, I'm
doing this, we're
getting tricks.
You know, tray flip noseblunt
slide in "Yeah Right."
It's an hour and a half away,
Santa Barbara, and we just
drove up right to
get that trick.
And that's what he did.
Drove up there at night, lit it
up, got it, and came home.
And to me that, that's like
a Michael Jordan moment.
Like, he literally took over
the game and won it.
TY EVANS: He was just
killing stuff.
I remember going to like that
big hub ledge in Philly, and
he just destroyed that thing.
180 nose grind, black
lip, like did all
that stuff over then.
And then, like when he went out
to Japan and skated that
white hub, and just murdered
that thing, and did a ton of
shit on that.
ATIBA JEFFERSON: He did so many
tricks on this hub in
that one night.
And this whole trip, it was
him, McCrank, and Rodrigo.
And Rodrigo got sick, and
literally him and McCrank were
like, just two fucking
wild dogs doing
demos and skating street.
They were very tight
at that point.
GUY MARIANO: Eric and
Rick McCrank.
That was a good combo.
Because Rick is like,
just like Eric.
He's super good.
Tranny, rail, gap, whatever.
And I think McCrank, being like
a bigger rail skater at
that time, he really pushed
Eric to start doing some
bigger rails and bigger gaps.
And like, in that "Yeah Right"
thing, you see them feeding
off each other.
I like the Rick McCrank and Eric
Koston better than the
Guy Mariano Eric Koston.
My opinion.
MALE SPEAKER: You were
dragging him down.
GUY MARIANO: I was dragging
Eric down, and
Rick brought him up.
MALE SPEAKER: You were like,
let's [INAUDIBLE].
GUY MARIANO: I'm trying to get
Eric to bum walls, McCrank's
getting him to the
double kinks.
TY EVANS: The early, early
2000 era of Eric, he was
unstoppable.
Dudes are in their prime in
their certain time where all
that stuff works, and like, that
was like his chunk right
there where he was
just killing it.
Back then, all that stuff came,
like, so quick that like
now, it's like, forget it.
Guys are like, checking
the wind.
Fucking, every distraction in
the world's like, crazy now.
ERIC KOSTON: 2001 Reader's
Choice Award.
Best all around skater.
You know, now it's pretty high
pressure, where when we
started, it was pretty fun.
Now it's like a virus,
or some antibiotic.
You know?
It only works for so long, and
then the virus gets stronger.
That's how I look at it.
Like guys, OK, that
trick was gnarly.
Now it's not gnarly.
Now it's just like, another
trick in the bag.
MIKE CARROLL: That's one thing
I've felt sorry for him about,
is just like, seeing how much
pressure I would assume he
puts on himself.
ERIC KOSTON: Aw, you
son of a bitch.
MIKE CARROLL: And he feels that
everyone's expecting,
like, I wouldn't even
want to have that.
MALE SPEAKER: For filming "Fully
Flared," did he have a
lot of the pressure that
some of the other
dudes talk about, or?
KELLY BIRD: Yeah.
I feel like he did, because he
was the guy that like, came in
and really was like, the final
piece of the puzzle.
Where everybody was
like, oh my God.
Look, OK.
This is going to
be ridiculous.
Like, the guy thing was
already in motion.
Everything else had been going
for so long, and then it's
like, oh, here comes this dude
to like ice the whole thing.
So I'm sure he felt the pressure
to be like, well,
everybody's going to expect me
to have like the last part,
caliber part.
And then having a year and a
half, maybe fucking a little
bit longer than that
at best to do it.
I'm sure it wasn't the most
pleasurable thing for him.
MALE SPEAKER: A lot of people
thought that you kind of came
in just to film the part,
and that the plan
was to leave anyway.
That's what I heard.
ERIC KOSTON: That pretty absurd
to think that I would
come in just to film a
part and then leave.
Timewise, you just don't have
that kind of luxury in life to
be just bouncing around.
The thing is, when Lakai
started, I'd been a long time
at S. My contract was up, and I
wanted to feel like, sort of
secure at where I was going to
end up at that point on.
I wanted to have, like, some
sort of stake in a company.
At a brand that I, you know,
back and believe in.
And that's what I thought.
And we had come out with like,
a pretty fucking insane video
with "Fully Flared." Probably
one of the best marketing
tools a brand could
come up with.
You know what I mean?
I guess it didn't translate.
KELLY BIRD: His business manager
unearthed some stuff
that was going on, that I
think people either just
didn't take the time to realize,
or were just too busy
that they didn't, you
know what I mean?
They didn't have the time to
deal with it previous to that.
But that really was a point
where everybody was like OK,
some shit's going on here that's
probably not that great
for the brand.
TIM GAVIN: That sucked.
He just came on at
a shitty time.
And he quit.
It really affected me and
him in our relationship.
And you always hear business
and friends, and it sucked.
MALE SPEAKER: Yeah.
TIM GAVIN: You know, if I were
to do it all over again, man,
I would never, I would've
fucking never have done it.
You know, Rick and the Girl
guys, those guys, like, were
so close, and they're family.
I mean, literally, like
were just so close.
So I always wanted to do
something with them.
And for it to not work out is
really hard to deal with.
ERIC KOSTON: I didn't know
what else to do.
I'd sort of had to take just the
choice of making kind of a
life decision.
Of like, having to--
I've got to go and do
what's best for me.
MALE SPEAKER: Did you know you
were going to go to Nike?
ERIC KOSTON: No, when
I left Lakai, no.
I left knowing I'm just
going to go out and
like, free agent style.
I mean, if you asked me five
years earlier, I'd have been
like, fuck no.
Fuck those dudes.
Fuck that place.
Fuck that.
No, I don't fucking
trust them.
You remember the fucking
first run they did?
It sucked.
But after time, seeing like, how
they run things and what
they do, and how they get
behind their team.
It's crazy how far it's come
along in skateboarding.
It's like, skateboarding's this
huge responsibility to
Nike, you know what I mean?
That we all have.
Now, looking back at
all my shoes that I
designed I copied Nikes.
it's all these Jordans
and Nikes.
MALE SPEAKER: And now you can
make a shoe that, like,
someone else is going to copy.
ERIC KOSTON: Hopefully,
that's like--
MALE SPEAKER: You're like,
the starting point.
ERIC KOSTON: Yeah.
It's a great spot.
SEAN MALTO: When he does
something, he kind of gets
involved in it to the fullest.
Like, Four Star, Girl, Nike,
whatever sponsors he has, he
kind of like, fully
gets into it.
You know, now that he's like,
doing Oakley stuff, has a lot
of responsibilities.
But he's handling it well, and
he's had like, a great career.
And if I've ever learned
anything from
him, it's like, yeah.
You know what I mean?
You gotta work for it.
This shit doesn't just
like, come to you.
You've got to like, work hard
towards something, and just
try to do it right.
And I think that's
what he's done.
He's done a great job at it.
GUY MARIANO: There's a lot of
people that think that he was
just a great skateboarder,
and everything just
fell into his lap.
But that's not true.
Like, Eric worked really hard.
He battled for his stuff,
you know what I mean?
Like, he put together like,
over 15 video parts like
"Bangers," you know
what I mean?
Like, I don't need another
Koston "Banger" video part to
know that he's amazing.
You know what I mean?
I have tons of that.
It makes me happy to see him
with his family, like, doing
good, and being almost
like the Michael
Jordan of our industry.
And I can say that, and a lot
of people will back that.
ERIC KOSTON: This is Finn.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Finny.
ERIC KOSTON: Yeah?
You want me to help you
on your skateboard?
FEMALE SPEAKER: Yeah.
ERIC KOSTON: OK.
I have to like, tighter
her wheels up.
I tighten the wheels up, too.
But still, it's like, I've gotta
crank them even more.
MALE SPEAKER: You know, us at
Girl, and just skateboarding
in general, we've always looked
to Eric to show us the
way, and that's why
he is Eric Koston.
ERIC KOSTON: Take your paci
out when you skate.
It's safer.
FEMALE SPEAKER: It goes
back and forth.
ERIC KOSTON: It does.
It goes back and forth.
MALE SPEAKER: Have you ever
seen your dad skate?
ERIC KOSTON: She saw
me at a contest.
I think it was like a Maloof,
or something.
But she was there.
And she was following me the
whole way, I guess, and like,
laughing and like,
tripping out.
I don't think she could
even talk then.
That's so sick.
Sketchy.
Stay on your knees.
Whoa.
Stay on your knees, June.