when the baseball had
parent crying
part about how
his daughter
lit up the room
uh... i have a hard time cuban at the
end
but what's interesting is that
when i a drone strikes
kids that are not american
and gets almost no coverage
and people are not broken about about it
then the president who was teary eyed
about
new town which is exactly what he should
have been when you you've got a control
on that
uh... is not teary-eyed about
civilian casualties
throughout strikes
the reason we have all machala out they
risk is is a town in southern yemen
and uh...
we actually the tomahawk missile strikes
there
and there is also cluster bombs as well
and we killed fourteen women and twenty
one children
twenty one children
now newtown there was twenty kids killed
twenty eight overall
now of course the u_s_ says that's all
incredibly different because we're
trying to target militants
in which are in any milton cements right
well it's unclear when there is
reporting
bhaiyya many journalists
and prepare that said and that showed
the bombs were from the u_s_
and they show the civilian deaths
so what happened the journalists to show
the civilian deaths
he was put in prison by the government
yemen
uh... they will let him out
cub leaders later
there were a pardon soleil who's no
longer president him it was going to do
it
this is a journalist than it was obvious
and the people yemen were upset
but he was put in jail uh... for
covering the civilian deaths
present nobama called
and said no
the u_s_ government still calls at your
list of terrorist
do not give mum pardoned put him back in
jail and they did
and he still in jail today
vice-president while made that call
why 'cause we don't want the world
to see the kids
that died because of or box
now i know a lot of people think there's
justified in collateral damage
but at least see the kids first
as we didn't in the newtown massacre
before you make that decision
now brave new foundation went
talk to people on the ground where the
straw strikes happen
lot of these victims are from
pakistan
yemen somalia it's ever been not or from
all majali in fact all machala
as i told you was a tomahawk cruise
missile strike
but look at
the different rose strikes
killed those kids throughout the world
myself am
three-years-old
solace listed his fans
generates pancake carries
two thousand seven
no-risk cited in years old
selfless there's time
february fourteen to four months for
cited references that we have to last
ten years old not take their standard
counter-terrorism efforts has been
exceptionally circle an exceptionally
target areas because he has been very
precise
precision strikes against off at that
time
no it was a response
u_s_ officials to thrones are highly
actors want to start seven-year zones
have not caused a huge number of
civilian casualties sha three years old
you're able to target and smuts more
precision dot times all the actions that
we take his fully consistent with
international loans from the past here
that has invented a single collateral
death orphans of his money managers to
make a lot but life is really war really
have a very colorful about
from boarding civilian casualty
so when we say that
the kids were not killed in the news
no civilian tags please we are
indisputably line
based on
reporting
based on international groups that have
gone on the ground and seen
the dead kids the you just saw
if that doesn't
also cause you
to think hate me he would do something
long there as well
act you got a question yourself on that
now the thing is
as you dipping will be doing this
are also have concerts 'cause they've
seen it
one particular guy is brenda brian
hughes a u_s_ strong pilot
and equip because uh... he was
racked with guilt over killing civilians
now the u_s_ media of course has not
cover that story almost at all
there should be going for many did you
talk to
and here's how he explains one
particular instance they say bryan in
his co-workers sat in for a fourteen
computer monitors and four keyboards
when brian press the button in new
mexico someone died on the other side of
the world
he remembers one incident very clearly
when a predator john was circling a
figure a pattern in the sky above
afghanistan
the article explains it was a countdown
and neice heat
bryant's job was to focuses the laser on
where the drone was going to go
and a guy sitting next to him
pushes the but
but he can move the laser and if he does
the bond those elsewhere
and is a countdown happening in ec he's
seen go to seventeen seconds in the
bench leaves you about the sea
seven seconds
any sinking down i don't know who's in
there i hope they got the right
information
and the their spiegel picks it up from
there
was seven seconds left the dell
there was no one to be seen on the
ground brian could still have diverted
the missile at that point that it was
down to three seconds by felt as if he
had to count each individual pixel on
the monitor
suddenly the child walk around the
corner recess
the story then continues
second zero was the moment in which
bryant's digital world collided with the
real one
in a village between bob louden
and mosser he sure re
bryant saw flash on the screen
the explosion
parts of the building collapsed
the child had disappeared
brian sick feeling in his stomach
burma this is one of our drome parts
and he says
did we just kill a kid
he asked the man sitting next to him
and the man who pushed the button says
yeah
i guess that was a kid the pilot replied
so they asked was that a kidney road in
the chat window on the monitor
their shingle continues this someone
they didn't know answer
someone sitting in the military command
center somewhere in the world could
observe their attack
no so that was a dog a personal
they went back
ang be reviewed the scene on the video
and dog
on two legs
so when they tell you we don't kill
civilians
and you know they're lying because
recently they reclassified every
military age now
and by the way there now including
children in that two we did that story
as well
as young as eight years old
is saying
by definition
there now
all considered militants
if we killed them
you have to prove
that they were innocent
otherwise
we assume they were militants
that they did that to our kids what
would we think
look at what happened in newtown and how
devastated we work
and ever seen anything practice areas
had devastating the figure minutes
and all these places were were due intro
strike every pros right
and then
adding insult to injury we call the kids
dogs
because we couldn't possibly make a
mistake
glenn greenwald made a good point about
this is part of the dehumanizing amo of
muslims across the world
this is hard to kill kids
it's hard to live with that is bryan
found that he couldn't live with it
and so he moved on any quit that job
so what do we do now and i know
they're not kids they're militants
and if it looks on
camel like their kid
we're going to calm a dog
if those kids don't also affect you
i think you got a question yourself man
i'm ripped apart by what happened
newtown
masa ripped apart by what happened on
in almond jhala
and so many different
cities across pakistan yemen
and other countries that we do draw
strict