ROBERT TAGLIAPIETRA: Hi, I'm
Robert Tagliapietra.
JEFFREY COSTELLO: And I'm
Jeffrey Costello.
ROBERT TAGLIAPIETRA: And we're
Costello Tagliapietra, and
you're watching Vice.
It's funny when we met.
We actually met at a nightclub,
and the joke was
sort of, like, both of our
friends said we both looked
alike, even back then.
We were both dressed alike
at the same time.
Also, we had the luck of
sharing a closet, too.
So I think it's a lot of
things mixed together.
JEFFREY COSTELLO: What you see
is what it always was.
ROBERT TAGLIAPIETRA: It was on
our 17th-year anniversary that
we got married.
JEFFREY COSTELLO:
It was simple.
Basically, I had made some
cardigan jackets, and it was
such a quiet affair.
It's like we just had Rob's
mother and sisters come.
I don't know, we just wore
khakis and sweaters.
ROBERT TAGLIAPIETRA: There was
just something nice about
actually having that--
JEFFREY COSTELLO: Almost
validation.
ROBERT TAGLIAPIETRA:
--that wedding ring
and having that day.
JEFFREY COSTELLO: I grew up
in suburban Pennsylvania.
My parents are in the grocery
store/roadside stand, so I
guess I was a little intrigued
by the farmers
we had to deal with.
To me that was so otherworldly,
to see real men
working farms, dressing.
I don't know, it just always
looked so cool,
the cool work clothes.
ROBERT TAGLIAPIETRA: When I
was in high school, I was
obsessive over collecting The
Smiths' singles, so I have all
the 12 inches.
We love the soundtrack quality
of certain music to help
define the collection.
About four years ago, Jeffrey
and my mother were talking,
and just through some casual
conversation, they found out
that both of our grandmothers
had worked for Norman Norell.
MALE VOICE (OFFSCREEN):
Quick, please, a gown.
FEMALE VOICE (OFFSCREEN): Oh,
I'll be the talk of the town.
ROBERT TAGLIAPIETRA:
Norman being a huge
influence on us as well.
But we both grew up in
households that sewed, so I
think the craft of fashion,
it was embedded in
us at an early age.
I think that's why throughout
the building of our career,
we've had such a concentration
on the craft, and it's been so
important to our brand
in general.
When we start designing it,
it's really about process.
The way we approach a dress
is it starts almost
mathematically.
The way we build collections
out, the way we create any
kind of garment, it's just as
based on the process as it is
everything else.
I guess we approach fashion in
the way you would almost
approach painting.
For us, it kind of starts at
the pattern-making table.
We love playing with patterns
and ideas that way, and then I
think it slowly develops
that way.
And then on the other side,
you have color.
And I think for us, it could be
just a painting or a movie
that inspires a color story.
So you kind of work out your
color story, and then through
that, through all those
processes, you start seeing a
story develop.
I like it when it's
not so clear.
I love that dreamy quality that
can happen with stuff,
with things you create.
And for us, it's about that.
We like to create something
that's otherworldly, that's
not clearly definable
by trend or era.
I feel like with a dress,
it's an object that's so
modern, in a way.
It's like this one-piece
dressing.
It's almost like how we imagine
the future to be, just
sort of one-piece dressing.
But it's also this blank canvas
that you can create
these beautiful things on.
We're big boys, so I know the
difficulties of finding
clothes sometimes.
And I think not every dress is
meant for every type, but to
have a selection of dresses that
have the ability to work
on different body types is
really important, I think.
You have to address those
issues sometimes.
You realize who the customer
really is.
It's not this 17-year-old
model that we
shove down the runway.
It's not what I think a lot of
designers think their ideal
customer is.
For us, it's like our job is to
make something that looks
beautiful on the female form.
And for us, it's got to
be effortless, too.
I like that aspect to it.
JEFFREY COSTELLO: And at the end
of the day, doesn't every
woman really want to feel
beautiful, and not necessarily
feminine, but at least beautiful
and put together?
ROBERT TAGLIAPIETRA: Yeah, we
used to be big flea market
people, and then we realized
that our apartment was
becoming like a hoarder's
nest.
I think that show Hoarders
was what really was
eye-opening for us.
We're like, OK, it's looking
a little similar.
I think we like a level
of hoarder.
It's kind of like an urban
grandmother's lumberjack lodge.