Soo Woo, soo woo.
[LAUGHS].
[THEME SONG PLAYING]
EDDIE HUANG: Yo what up?
It's your boy Eddie Huang.
We're in San Francisco's
Mission District today.
We're going to go visit the
Rice Paper Scissors crew.
These girls do a lot of
guerrilla cooking, so we're
going to pop up curbside, grill
some octopus, eat some
rice paper, see what's
really good.
This is "Fresh Off the Boat."
EDDIE HUANG: Hi, I'm Eddie.
VALERIE LUU: Hey, I'm Valerie.
EDDIE HUANG: Valerie, hi.
KATIE KWAN: And I'm Katie.
EDDIE HUANG: Katie, great.
So you all are Rice
Paper Scissor.
VALERIE LUU: Yeah
KATIE KWAN: Rice.
EDDIE HUANG: Rice paper--
I got it.
That's what's up.
So what do you guys want
to make today?
KATIE KWAN: We basically
are going to grill.
So we just want to find
stuff to grill.
EDDIE HUANG: Check for
the smell, y'all.
No smell.
All right, we're about to
try and make some Asian
parents proud now.
Order in all Vietnamese.
VALERIE LUU: All right
[SPEAKING VIETNAMESE].
-[SPEAKING VIETNAMESE]
VALERIE LUU: Some, octopus.
EDDIE HUANG: I think he just
fucked you up because you had
to use some English.
KATIE KWAN: No!
[SPEAKING VIETNAMESE]
EDDIE HUANG:
-[SPEAKING VIETNAMESE]
EDDIE HUANG: The little cooking
lesson for y'all that
he's giving us is, he's saying,
if you're going to
grill oysters, get the bigger,
fattier one because it'll
stand up to being cooked.
If it's smaller, it's not
enough, it's too delicate--
you just want to eat it raw.
VALERIE LUU: Big and fat.
Big and fat.
EDDIE HUANG: Big and fat.
EDDIE HUANG: I do.
I think the think that bothers
people in the Chinese
community or Asian community
is, we don't have a food
critic or a food writer who grew
up in a Chinese home or a
Vietnamese home.
So don't come tell me what's the
best until you've really
tried to immerse yourself
and give credit to
where it comes from.
EDDIE HUANG: When it's not a
food that I really grew up
eating and really feel like I
understand, I let people tell
me about it.
And then I go to explore.
You have to eat your way
through a cuisine and a
culture before you can say
something about it.
That's how I feel.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
VALERIE LUU: Welcome
to San Francisco.
EDDIE HUANG: I like this town.
I fucks with this town.
VALERIE LUU: So we're going to
Duc Loi supermarket, which is
our go-to spot.
It's like a Vietnamese haven in
the heart of the Mission.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
EDDIE HUANG: This is a
nice grocery room.
Very multicultural, serving
the neighborhood.
Got some galanga for the Thai
people, epazote, Mexican, baby
dill for the WPs.
KATIE KWAN: I think
we're going to
grill some rice paper.
EDDIE HUANG: That's
your shit, right?
Grilled rice paper.
VALERIE LUU: Three Ladies?
KATIE KWAN: Three Ladies.
I love the Three Ladies.
EDDIE HUANG: Three Ladies
go great with sausage.
Usually bagels, hard
outside, right?
Watch what happens
to these bagels?
Doof.
Do you see that?
This is not a bagel.
It's like a hamburger bun with
the middle taken out.
If the bagels were good,
burritos would not be this
popular in San Francisco.
VALERIE LUU: Who's got
the cash money?
KATIE KWAN: Eddie.
EDDIE HUANG: That's my-- oh.
I got money.
Yo, David, where that
"Vice" money at?
Pop-ups are everywhere, man.
Like, I think pop-ups are
actually played out.
But what these girls are doing
transcends the moniker of
"pop-up." They're culturally
relevant beyond the box that
people want to put them in.
This is a funny situation.
Like, pop-up or not,
man, like, what the
fuck is this, man?
VALERIE LUU: So the Vietnamese
way to get all your friends
and family to work for
you-- this is what's
happening right here.
Food is a lot about stories.
It's about where it came from,
and who is eating it,
and how it's made.
And to get people together.
And so that's what we do at
our pop-ups, to get people
together on the street, and
look at each other, and
rubbing elbows and kneecaps.
[MEOWING]
EDDIE HUANG: Oh, we got cats?
That's the authentic
Vietnamese food.
[LAUGHS].
KATIE KWAN: So I'm American.
I was born and raised
in Sunnyvale.
Vietnamese food was my way
to get into my culture.
After college, I didn't really
want a real job.
I wanted to do my own thing.
And again, that's that
Vietnamese blood.
You want to hustle and
be your own boss.
And then food was just
a way to do that.
EDDIE HUANG: Food is a
great gateway drug
into any foreign culture.
Because you can consume it, and
it's like the base level
that you share with people.
That is just perfect.
KATIE KWAN: And it was a great
way to hang out with grandma.
Like grandma--
I grew up eating Red Baron
frozen pizzas because mom was
a single mother, and that's
all we had time for.
And also grandma's cooking
when she took care of us.
As I got older, I got
more into that.
And so it's my way of getting
to my culture.
Because my parents won't
understand the tech stuff I
would have done in
another life.
Social media stuff.
But we could all understand
food, and geek out about it,
and connect around it.
EDDIE HUANG: This
one looks good.
-Ooh, limes.
-Octopus.
Put it in your mouth.
-Excuse me.
-Put it inside your body.
-Ooh.
Ai-yah.
I saw that.
EDDIE HUANG: This is
fucking delicious.
-[INAUDIBLE] soba?
VALERIE LUU: Soba?
EDDIE HUANG: Yo, y'all
can actually cook.
VALERIE LUU: Aww, yeah.
-Are you surprised?
EDDIE HUANG: Mm-hmm.
Food, to me, can get boring when
all you're talking about
is the things that are on the
plate, within the dimensions.
But they're really embracing
the culture of dining, the
lifestyle of being a cook.
It's just great to see, man.
I eat at a lot of places.
I tell a lot of horrible
stories, but
this is a good one.
KATIE KWAN: OK, I think it's
time for some rice wine.
EDDIE HUANG: Rice wine.
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
[CHEERING]
EDDIE HUANG: Oh please, please,
more doo-doo water.
This is some horrible,
horrible shit.
ALL TOGETHER:
[SPEAKING VIETNAMESE].
-There's like floating
shit in there.
EDDIE HUANG: I love counting
in poor Asian languages.
Next up on "Fresh
Off the Boat--"
burritos, burritos, burritos.
Then I'm off to Little Manila
to hang with the Pinoys.
Get a fresh cut, and get your
lotus flower game up.
-We fuck with lotus flowers.
No, that's pussy, right?
[MUSIC PLAYING]