Like Dyrdek, Mikey Taylor,
Barra, is so upriver.
INTERVIEWER: What
does that mean?
JASON DILL: They're upriver.
They're where--
you know, where TVs exist, the
internet, fishing's better.
BILL STROBECK: I could see where
it seemed like if Kalis
felt that way, which I feel like
he did, that he felt like
he didn't fit in.
JOSH KALIS: First of all,
I can't be mad at
anything Fat Bill says.
Because Fat Bill is my homey.
And he can fucking call me a
piece of shit jerk-off, and
I'm not going to give a shit
because he's Fat Bill.
He's my favorite filmer
to film with.
I fucking love Bill.
Dill, on the other hand--
it really bummed me out.
It was like a lack of respect.
It was like, who the fuck are
you to talk about me, in one,
Dylan's thing.
You know?
And two, call me upriver.
I mean, my thinking
is like, hey, man.
I'm about as street
as you get.
You know what I'm saying?
PATRICK O'DELL: Welcome back
to Epicly Later'd.
This episode's about
Josh Kalis.
This episode kind of came
to be because of the
Dylan Rieder episode.
Dill said some stuff and
Kalis didn't like it.
He called me and was bummed and
kind of wanted to set the
record straight.
He's like, I got stories.
I was in an insane asylum.
I did this.
I did that.
I was like, all right.
This is gonna be awesome.
So I first started hearing
of him in Timecode.
I really remember him
doing kickflip
backside noseblunt slides.
And I think I shot a photo
of him doing one.
I just think of backside
tricks, like backside
noseblunt slides and backside
tail slides.
And crooked hat, like
all the way crooked.
And like earrings, and
like, dirt 'stache.
So I met up with Kalis and
talked about skating.
We talked about Lennie Kirk,
Dyrdek, Stevie, Philly,
Chicago, Texas, all
this stuff.
So it's cool to interview
someone that's
such a skate rat.
Like he's like die-hard
skater.
And just go through
skate history.
I don't know.
I'm really excited about
this episode.
So here it is--
Josh Kalis episode.
Where do you think'd
be the best zone?
JOSH KALIS: This is
good right here.
PATRICK O'DELL: These big-ass
SoCal houses don't even have
lights in the ceiling
anywhere.
JOSH KALIS: Actually, before I
skated, my biggest thing was
rollerskating.
I was like this big speedskater
kid, you know?
Well, what killed my roller
skating was that I
had lied to the cops.
Well, I used to go roller
skating every weekend, but
then I lied to the cops about
getting kidnapped.
Or not getting kidnapped, but
I told them that this
kidnapper was out, like,
trying to get me.
It was like the big thing at
school, was this kidnapper.
So I lied and said that
I met the dude.
And they broke me down
in the cop shop.
I mean, they broke me down.
I was tearing.
I told them I was
full of shit.
So my dad grounded me from
my roller skates
for like six months.
And it was like, that was it.
I didn't even give a shit
about it anymore.
Going way back to my first days
of skating, it was the
Bones Brigade.
Steve Caballero was probably
like my favorite dude out of
all of them.
I don't remember what Powell
video it was, but it was
Caballero and Tommy Guerrero
and all those dudes were
skating outside.
Like there was a neighborhood.
And that's what I
kept watching.
The vert stuff and none of
that, I didn't even pay
attention to it.
I just would rewind
and fast forward.
And I think that's what
got me, right there.
Gonna do some tricks, man.
MIKE BLABAC: I first
met Josh--
I lived in Lansing, Michigan.
We just kind of knew one another
through skating.
He knew that I shot photos.
So he'd come down to
Grand Rapids and
shoot photos with me.
It's funny.
He got grounded.
His dad-- like, he stole a bunch
of baseball cards and
shit of his dad's, and he got
grounded for hella long.
I don't even know how long.
But he lied and he told his
dad that I worked for
TransWorld.
So his dad would let him go out
and shoot photos with me.
He thought that I was like some
magazine photographer.
And I barely knew how
to use a camera.
But I was just kind
of learning how.
And it's sort of ironic that
he's one of the dudes that I
learned how to shoot
skate photos of.
That's what he looked like.
It's hella funny.
PATRICK O'DELL: That's Josh?
MIKE BLABAC: Yeah.
That's Josh in 1989.
So that was 21 years ago.
It makes me feel hella old,
thinking about how long ago
that was, but yeah.
That was the skate-rat Josh.
And then I met the Josh with his
earrings and fucking pot
leaf and like the thugged-out
Josh in SF,
about four years later.
PATRICK O'DELL: And you saw
Sheffey then, too, right?
MIKE BLABAC: Back when I lived
in Michigan, yeah.
He was the Sheffey with the
big hair, you know?
Sheffey from the videos
and stuff.
It was sick.
I remember he was just hauling
ass, going as fast as you
possibly could.
Yeah, it was insane.
Like crazy--
like how much power he had
and how fast he went.
That was the raddest thing
about watching
him skate in person.
You know what I mean?
Yeah, he was a pretty
main dude.
It just so happened that he
lived in Grand Rapids.
JON LEE: I'll show you the three
raddest skateboarders
that I know.
The vegetarian powers.
Sean Sheffey, by far the
raddest, craziest, gnarliest
skateboarder.
JOSH KALIS: It was like this
myth, urban legend.
And it wasn't until
like a year after
that that I was downtown.
We were maybe 50-50-ing
granite curbs,
trying to do that shit.
And this dude with this big-ass
'fro just comes
through and back lips one of
the full-sized benches.
Our jaws hit the ground.
We were like, Sean Sheffey.
Holy shit, man.
PATRICK O'DELL: It's definitely
like seeing a legend.
JOSH KALIS: Well, one of the
cool things about skating with
him back then was like, you
didn't want to sit down.
Like he gave you that vibe and
that energy, where like, if he
was skating five stairs, he
wanted you to skate with him.
I swear to god I learned more
tricks that day, just skating
with that dude, than I ever
have, even still to this day.
And he would just--
bounce to the next spot, and
everybody's trying to
keep up with him.
You know what I mean?
It was sick, dude.
SEAN SHEFFEY: What's up?
PATRICK O'DELL: What up?
JOSH KALIS: Ever since I met him
that day, that was like my
drive to want to skate
and always skate.
And like, just Sheffey, dude.
The illest dude, ever.
Ever.
PATRICK O'DELL: Does he you
remember you from then?
JOSH KALIS: You'll
have to ask him.
I've never asked him.
I always played it cool.
Like, that's Sean, you
know what I mean?
I ain't fucking with
that dude.
PATRICK O'DELL: There's a lot
of skate history in here.
SEAN SHEFFEY: I would like
to say what's up
to the Wu Tang Clan.
I was 17.
I remember I was going
by your house once--
JOSH KALIS: Oh my god,
that's the story.
SEAN SHEFFEY: And this
elementary school where they
used to skate, with
the yellow curbs.
Remember that?
JOSH KALIS: Yeah.
Oh, I can't believe this
dude remembers me, man.
SEAN SHEFFEY: Yeah.
JOSH KALIS: Yeah,
I was grounded.
I was grounded in my room.
And it must have been
for like, I think,
three or four weeks.
I can't believe this
story, man.
My dad comes in my room,
knocking on the door.
And he's like, hey, there's some
guys out in the driveway.
And I was like, what?
So I went out there and I
looked, and it was Ted Lee--
SEAN SHEFFEY: Yeah.
JOSH KALIS: And Sheffey.
SEAN SHEFFEY: And myself.
JOSH KALIS: Tooling around in my
driveway, trying to see if
I could skate.
Ted Lee.
And I was like, oh my god.
'Cause this was after I had
started seeing them downtown.
And my dad let me off grounding
to go skate with
these dudes for a while.
He let me off.
I couldn't believe it, man.
That was like the best day
in my entire life.
SEAN SHEFFEY: Oh, wow.
He let you out?
Yeah, that's intense.
Cool.
JOSH KALIS: Yeah, that was
pretty insane, man.
Damn, you remember that shit.
MALE SPEAKER: Film Jack.
MALE SPEAKER: Less
work for you.
Go ahead.
JOSH KALIS: You gonna
follow me?
PATRICK O'DELL: Dude, what do
you remember about Josh?
SEAN SHEFFEY: Very already
mature skater and sharp when
we first met him.
He was already known around his
city and state as being a
sharp and clean skater.
So I was pretty impressed
when I first met him.
JOSH KALIS: Aw, shit.
That's only because I was
out with the big dogs.
And I was trying my hardest,
dude, to do my thing.
I didn't want to look like
no punk out there.
Yeah.
[CAR HORN HONKING]
JOSH KALIS: Huh.
SEAN SHEFFEY: Great experience
to see how far he's came with
his skateboarding and
progressed, and the
technicality of it.
I'm very proud to have
been a part of that.
JOSH KALIS: I've always loved
Matt Hensley's skating.
He was like a huge one for me.
But I think my early days of
learning how to kickflip and
how I want to skate is directly
related to Sean's
skating and that influence
he gave me, like live.
The downtown-- our little
city wasn't that big.
But it was like, we didn't want
to skate anything else
besides downtown after we seen
Sean down there, you know?
SEAN SHEFFEY: And what
is your sign?
JOSH KALIS: Taurus.
SEAN SHEFFEY: Taurus.
Well, bullheaded and strong like
one, you are, Mr. Kalis.
Nothing wrong with that.
Pretty cool, yeah.
Pretty cool.
Strong sign.