The morning of the 15th started
off with relatively
passive demonstrations in
the center of Ramallah.
And then at about 1:30 PM,
some of those people and
others who weren't there
headed to the
Israeli prison Ofer.
[PEOPLE CHANTING IN PROTEST]
Once the crowds reached Ofer--
[SIRENS]
--they were cut off by an
Israeli, I suppose, blockade
or checkpoint.
And there was border guards,
heavily armed with M16s that
shot volleys of steel bullets
coated with rubber, and a
"skunk" truck, which is kind of
a-- it looks like a water
cannon truck, but actually it
shoots out this kind of acrid,
horrendous-smelling
unknown liquid.
[SMALL EXPLOSIONS, CHEERS]
The Palestinians threw rocks
continuously for maybe four or
five hours.
[SHOUTS AND GUNFIRE]
The Israeli defense forces are
fairly predictable in terms of
their action towards these
kind of demonstrations.
There were volleys of tear
gas roughly every
15 minutes or so.
[TEAR GAS EXPLOSIONS]
Once the volley hits the ground
in and around the
Palestinian protesters, the
teenagers go over and pick up
these canisters, put them into
these rock slings that they
have, and swing them back
at the Israelis.
[MAN CHANTING]
It's a lot of rubber bullets
flying around, pinging off the
metal around us.
[MUFFLED VOICE OVER
LOUDSPEAKER]
[SUDDEN SHOUTS]
[GUNSHOT]
[VOICES CRYING IN UNISON,
CLAPPING]
[SECOND GUNSHOT]
A guy just to my right was hit
in the head with a rubber
bullet, and it was not
a pretty sight.
There was a huge gash
in his forehead.
[SIRENS AND SHOUTING]
The medics, I don't know
how they do it.
They swoop in a matter of
seconds, pick these people up,
and get them out of there.
[INTERPOSING TALKING
AND YELLING]
[COUGHING]