Da-ee da-ee indo.
[INAUDIBLE]
Oh, my god.
Let me tell you, she's
got a great tuckus.
I love this shit.
Oh, look at the two guys
with the camera.
What a bunch of shmucks.
[SINGING]
Hava unda nav a dah.
Mm.
NOAH BERNAMOFF: My name is
Noah Bernamoff, and the
restaurant's name is Mile
End Delicatessen.
Mile End is called Mile End
because of my love for that
neighborhood of Montreal, and
the very, very personal
history of my family in
that neighborhood.
I was a second year
law student.
I just really hated my life.
I started making smoked meat
at home, as a hobby.
That led to me actually thinking
through the idea of a
Jewish deli in any
serious way.
New York's like the most Jewish
place in the world.
Even more Jewish, in many
ways, than even Israel.
And it always struck me that
all these well represented
cultures in this city have
more restaurants
than you can count.
Except Jews.
We just have like three, or
something, like, stupid.
And I just thought to myself,
we should have our own
restaurants.
We should have our
own cuisine.
And the cuisine that everyone
knows is sort of like this
deli thing.
But then we do more than
that at night.
They're not dishes that you
would find in old time
cookbooks from Europe, or
Yiddish cookbooks from the
early period of Jews
in America.
The cooking actually
is innovative.
I mean, it's not really
something that
Jews do, you know?
Jews own businesses, we're
professionals.
We don't actually cook in
this sort of context.
The kasha dinner is really,
really popular, because it's
kind of it's like this
healthiness of the grain, has
the noodles, has some
meat in it.
It's kind of rich, but it's kind
of light at the same time
and somewhat healthful.
Kasha is generally a
pretty gross thing.
Like--
SAM FILLORAMO: That's
what everyone says.
NOAH BERNAMOFF: Most people
make it and it sucks.
Like my mom's.
No offense to my mom.
My wife, Rae, she handles a lot
of our customer service
side of the business.
She does all the catering,
off-site events.
We've been very picky with who
we've hired as our staff.
And partly because we
care so much about
the camaraderie aspect.
All right.
Very classic.
SAM FILLORAMO: Cheers.
RAE COHEN: L'chaim.
NOAH BERNAMOFF: Cheers.
A lot of gravy [INAUDIBLE]
in this.
We all headed to Russ &
Daughters, a appetizing shop
in lower East Side.
SAM FILLORAMO: I bought a Russ
& Daughters t-shirt couple
months ago from them.
And she was like, now you pay
me to advertise the store.
All right, I will.
That's fine.
NOAH BERNAMOFF: Love that.
Such a Jewish thing to say.
Russ & Daughters, it's
an amazing place.
I mean, you walk in there and
it's just like, whoa, this
place has not changed in as many
years as it's been open.
I think it's been open
85 years now.
And what's so cool is when you
look up and you see the photos
of the original owners, or like,
even the second or third
generation owners.
And you look at where they're
standing in the store, and
then you look at that spot in
the store, they're actually--
you know, it's the same products
sitting in the same
case, in front of them.
When I see that, it's
just unbelievable.
The history in there is
profound, that's for sure.
Our friend, Josh Tupper, who is
a fourth generation owner
of Russ & Daughters.
JOSH TUPPER: Let's
go make eggs.
So this is one of my favorite
little treats, caviar in a
soft scramble.
NOAH BERNAMOFF: We soft
scrambled some eggs, and threw
some caviar into it.
And ate that on a sliced
challah rolls.
JOSH TUPPER: Mm.
NOAH BERNAMOFF: That's it?
That's where it's at?
JOSH TUPPER: Uh, huh.
I'd make you guys one but
I'm too busy eating.
NOAH BERNAMOFF: Seriously,
you should sell this.
JOSH TUPPER: This is
an expensive--
RAE COHEN: How much
would it cost.
JOSH TUPPER: $50.
SAM FILLORAMO: And you have
to cook it yourself.
NOAH BERNAMOFF: Seriously,
Josh, this is heaven.
SAM FILLORAMO: All right, we
should have some shots.
NOAH BERNAMOFF: Yeah.
You're going to need
to do a shot.
Cheers.
SAM FILLORAMO: Thanks
again for having us.
NOAH BERNAMOFF: To our
gracious hosts.
JOSH TUPPER: Wonderful.
Beautiful.
NOAH BERNAMOFF: You
already drank it?
Fuck.
JOSH TUPPER: We might
have an issue.
This is cold.
It's called Devil's Springs,
but it's 160 proof.
NOAH BERNAMOFF: Dude.
SAM FILLORAMO: 160 proof
bottle from New Jersey.
JOSH TUPPER: It's Brucha.
NOAH BERNAMOFF: Hold on, Devil
Springs is in New Jersey?
Where else?
Vodka is the typical pairing
for a lot of the
foods that they have.
They have the smoked fish.
In fact, a lot of fish is cured
in a vodka solution.
We did a little taste
test of herrings.
We did a shmaltz herring,
pickled herring,
and a Holland herring.
Life is very good, right now.
We're in the middle of Russ &
Daughters, the greatest Jewish
institution.
All right.
Cheers.
Thank you.
So after Russ & Daughters we
headed over to Sammy's
Roumanian Steakhouse.
It's a really wacky place.
The keyboard player, the
whole shtick there.
The dancing, the block of
vodka on the table.
It's just by pure
Jewish kitch.
Russ & Daughters remain
in the family.
And it's gone, over
the years, it's
become fancier and fancier.
Where at Sammy's it seems like
it's just sort of devolved
over the years into being
kitchier, kitchier.
And like, just kind of held
up with its kitch.
We ate chopped liver, which was
mixed at the table, which
was excellent.
We had the karnatzlack, which is
like a rolled sausagey sort
of thing with a ton of garlic.
Look at this sandwich.
A chopped liver karnatzlack
pickled green tomato sandwich.
SAM FILLORAMO: Mom
would be proud.
NOAH BERNAMOFF: This
is phenomenal.
There was a lot of vodka
shots there.
We consumed another whole
bottle of vodka.
We had what Sammy's calls
their tenderloin steak.
And we really loved it.
There's only one Jewish
variation on the steakhouse in
New York City, and
that's Sammy's.
DAVID ZIMMERMAN:
How's it going?
NOAH BERNAMOFF: Awesome.
DAVID ZIMMERMAN: Realy.
I'm David.
NOAH BERNAMOFF: Noah.
DAVID ZIMMERMAN: I'm
the son of Sammy.
NOAH BERNAMOFF: Son of Sam--
Thanks for having us.
DAVID ZIMMERMAN: Ah,
you're welcome.
The restaurants been here
for about 80 years.
My father won the restaurant
in a poker game in 1975,
against Sammy.
So there is no Sammy here.
SAM FILLORAMO: It's
the Jewish--
NOAH BERNAMOFF: Is it always
a Bar Mitzvah every night?
SAM FILLORAMO: We try.
DANI LUV: I want to see the
boys just come alive.
Hey boys, you came late,
you have to do it.
Leave your--
leave your vodka, that's
right, that's a Jew.
That's a Jew-bird, come on.
He's walking towards the circle,
he's still eating--
I want to see at least
20, 30 people.
My name is Dani Luv,
you're beautiful.
Come on.
Everybody in the shitzas
too, come on.
[ROUMANIAN SINGING]
NOAH BERNAMOFF: Well
there is definitely
some dancing involved.
[ROUMANIAN SINGING]
DANI LUV: Come on,
girls, come on.
[ROUMANIAN SINGING]
DANI LUV: Yeah.
This is Jewish rock and roll.
NOAH BERNAMOFF: Woo,
to Dani Luv.
Woo.
Shalom.
TAXI DRIVER: Where you going?
NOAH BERNAMOFF: We're
going to Brooklyn.
TAXI DRIVER: OK.
NOAH BERNAMOFF: OK?
No, you're supposed to say,
ah, you fucking assholes.
Gracias.
Sammy's is so insane.
Woo.
Dani Luv for life.
We started doing the hora.
JOHN: He really was like,
singing there, huh?
NOAH BERNAMOFF: Yeah.
Playing the piano and singing.
And he was chirping us.
He was like, look at you fucking
Jews dancing around in
the middle of the room.
It was awesome.
We're going to make poutine.
And then we're going to
throw the steak from
Sammy's on top it.
Poutine actually literally
translates as hot mess.
But what it actually
is is French fries,
cheddar curd, and gravy.
It always surprises me when
people come in and they want
poutine for a brunch
or something.
I'm like, this is
not when you're
supposed to eat this thing.
This is total drunk
person food.
All right, now we're going
to sauce this bitch up.
It's like the most
gut busting dish.
And just for the hell of it, I'm
kind of thinking we should
pour more gravy over it.
This is as gross as it gets.
And this is like a Guinness
World Record's poutine.
This is Sammy's Roumanian
Mile End poutine.
Why the fuck not?
John, your poutine.
JOHN: Thank you,
so much, Noah.
NOAH BERNAMOFF: So poutine
is the go-to
drunk food of Montreal.
It's also like truck driver
food, but, because it's such a
unique thing that you can't
really get anywhere in New
York-- or very few places
in New York--
people tend to consume it
at all times of the day.
So it's interesting
for me to watch.
Shall we say l'chaim to Russ &
Daughters and Sammy's Roumanian?
SAM FILLORAMO: Yes.
NOAH BERNAMOFF: And uh,
and to Dani Luv.
Dani fucking Luv.
Check that punim out.
Look at that punim.
Oh.
too much wadkie.
Back to the water.
Back to water.
[MUSIC PLAYING]