Bryan May: For the
New Madrid earthquake.
Wilma Bryant: For a
series of F5 tornadoes.
Narrator: And
protect themselves.
Man: Watch it, man.
Push him away,
push him away.
[screaming].
Blevins: Stop
right there!
Narrator: From what they
perceive as the fast
approaching end of the
world as we know it.
Daughter: Dad!
Braxton: Leave
her alone!
Narrator: Next, we
go inside the lives
of three committed
preppers.
Josh Wander: There's
gonna be a lot of
people dying
very quickly.
Narrator: Who have
devised extensive plans.
Croft: More arms works
better than less arms.
Narrator: Gone
to great lengths.
Josh Wander: Go on
treat the wounded.
Come on,
quickly, quickly!
Narrator: And made
huge personal sacrifices
to ensure their
very survival.
Jade Kay: Half a million
dollars for a helicopter?
Narrator: The experts
will assess their preps,
to see if they
have what it takes.
Ryan Croft:
You've got chaos.
That's where the
prepper steps in.
Narrator:
To survive.
Alexis Kay: It's not as easy
as it looks in videogames.
Narrator: This is
doomsday preppers.
Bob Kay is the
wealthy creator of a
hugely successful
vitamin supplement.
Living in Temecula,
California, Bob,
his wife and two
young daughters have
almost everything
they could ask for.
Bob Kay: I live on
two and a half acres.
The views are
spectacular.
I can see mountains
in the distance.
I can see
the wineries.
It's just an
absolutely wonderful
area to live in.
Narrator: But Bob fears
that the cost of owning
this high-priced
real estate could
one day be the lives
of his family because
they're sitting on a
ticking time bomb.
Bob Kay: I'm preparing
for a massive earthquake
that will change
society as we know it.
I know something is
going to go wrong.
I think the people
that say nothing will
go wrong and everything
will go right,
I think they're obsessive
in the wrong direction.
We live on graham
cracker crust here.
In this part of
Southern California we
don't have one fault,
we have approximately
five or six
major faults.
Narrator: Although most
are too small to feel,
roughly 10,000
earthquakes strike
Southern California
every year.
Bob believes it's
just a matter of time
before one of them is
powerful enough to
destroy his community and
throw society into chaos.
Bob Kay: We have major
earthquake faults
running directly under
the major freeways here.
It wouldn't take much for
a major earthquake to
pretty much sever those
arteries so that folks
can't get materials in
and they can't get out.
Narrator: If a magnitude
7.8 quake or stronger
hits California, it could
topple 1,500 buildings,
kill 2,000 people
and damage and
disrupt the
infrastructure survivors
would depend on for
getting food and water.
So Bob's plan is to
turn his two and a
half acre estate into a
self-sustaining oasis
where his family
can safely wait out
the chaos following
a killer quake.
And he's not afraid to
spend money to do it.
Bob Kay: I don't
do anything small.
Over the course of the
last twelve months
I've spent approximately
$150,000 on my preps.
I've been extremely
successful at what I do.
And that has allowed me
to have the financial
resources and the time to
be able to invest part of
my life to making sure my
family is taken care of.
Narrator: Many preppers
dream about the elaborate
things they would buy, if
money were not an object.
For Bob, having
multiple back-up
bug-out vehicles
is worth any cost.
Bob Kay: My preferred
bug out vehicle?
Motorcycle, nothing
impedes the motorcycle.
You can get pretty
much anywhere on it.
And I don't have
just one, I have six.
Narrator: The motorcycles
cost Bob another $110,000.
He spent $35,000 more
landscaping his estate and
every tree and shrub
serves a prepper purpose.
Bob Kay: I have well
over 300 different types
of plants that can be
used for food either by
their fruiting or
the plant directly.
Narrator: Bob dropped
another $100,000
on a pool in order
to have 35,000
gallons in his
backyard that he can
filter into potable
drinking water.
Bob Kay: Once we
distill it and then
just run it through
a carbon filter,
it's fine.
You're taking the water,
turning it into a gas,
and then converting
it back right
into a liquid again.
Cheers.
What do you think?
Alexis Kay: Tastes just
like normal water.
Narrator: No matter
how hot it gets,
Bob's forbidden his
kids from swimming
during the day.
He doesn't want
their sunscreen
to contaminate
the water.
But his daughter, Alexis,
still fully supports
her father's extravagant
prepping habit.
Alexis Kay: I like
prepping with my dad,
I think it's
pretty fun.
I'm pretty much the one
that comes up with the
ideas and then my
dad buys the preps.
Narrator: Today, Bob
and Alexis are looking
for a freeze-dried
food source
they can
stock up on,
in case earthquakes
one day destroy
California's
supply lines.
Chris: One of my favorites
is freeze-dried chicken.
Bob Kay: I love this.
I mean, his is, this
is the ultimate
high-tech
prepper food.
Chris: You'll
notice it actually
kinda re-hydrates
in your mouth.
Bob: You know what?
That's really good.
Alexis Kay:
Just like chicken.
There's nothing
fake in it,
it's just chicken.
Bob Kay: Can you put
together like two
or three palettes
of stuff?
What do you think
it would cost,
per year,
per person?
Chris: Somewhere between
$12,000 and $16,000 a year.
Bob Kay: I do spend
towards the upper end.
I make sure that I get a
good value on what I'm
purchasing and I want
to make it so it lasts.
Narrator: The average
American household
spends roughly $3,700
on groceries each year.
Bob just spent
more than 10 times
that in a
single day.
Now he has to
tell his wife,
Jade and she doesn't
always find her
husband's spendthrift
ways amusing.
Jade Kay: I'm
not a prepper.
I think it's kind
of, uh, weird.
It's weird;
it's a little
bit crazy.
I don't think,
you know,
that something
will happen.
How much did
this food cost?
Bob Kay: Uh, it's
very reasonable.
It's um.
Jade Kay:
Reasonable means what?
Bob Kay: Uh,
about $40,000.
Jade Kay: What?
Bob Kay: Yeah.
Jade Kay:
$40,000 for food!
What if nothing
happens?
What are you going
to do with the food?
Bob Kay: That, that's
a very good question.
In terms of how I prep,
I always think of the
greatest value, because
if my life's on the line
or my family's welfare
is on the line,
I don't want to have
to be second guessing
what I've done.
Narrator: Bob and
Alexis spend much of
their quality time
together prepping.
But they worry that their
home full of expensive
preps would be an
irresistible target
for desperate, violent
looters in the chaos
following catastrophic
earthquakes.
So recently, they've been
focusing on security
and defensive preps.
Bob Kay: If the house were
to become compromised
or I am not able
to get home,
Alexis is fully capable
of defending herself.
Narrator: Like
many children,
Alexis is drawn
to martial arts.
She received her second
degree black belt
in tae-kwon-do
when she was ten.
Bob Kay: Ow.
Narrator: But Alexis
wants to be able to
defend herself before a
violent confrontation
comes down to
hand-to-hand combat.
She recently told her
father she wanted
to learn how to
throw knives.
So Bob custom built a
target range on his
property and
bought her $1,000
worth of top of
the line knives.
Bob Kay: These knives are
incredibly high quality.
The larger ones we
use are actually
competition
quality knives.
It's a very effective,
concealable type
of weapon for
self defense.
Very convenient.
You have to have a lot
of respect for a knife
or a bladed
weapon and
she's learning
the respect.
Alexis Kay: I was
more influenced by
videogames than
anything else,
because any
videogame character,
you tell it to throw a
knife and it looks easy,
it looks effortless.
So I thought,
why not?
Why not try
throwing knives?
But when you actually
try to throw a knife,
it's a lot more of
a challenge than
it actually looks.
Bob Kay: Perfect.
Pretty good.
Narrator: Throwing
knives would help Alexis
in a short-range fight,
but she also wants an
option to protect
herself from attackers
at even greater
distances.
So Bob's hired her
a personal firearm
instructor, spent $4,000
on a high-end rifle,
built a private shooting
range on his own property
and added $300 of zombie
targets that bleed
or explode to get her
accustomed to aiming
at a human figure.
Nate: You're too
close to the scope.
Lean forward.
Can you see
your target?
Alexis Kay: Yeah.
Nate: Okay,
ready to fire?
Fire!
Good job!
Bob: First shot, that
gun I can't do that.
One shot, right through
the top of the chest.
Joel: It's
where you want it.
Bob: That was incredible.
Nate: That's a combat
accurate hit right there.
You can't ask any more
than that from this far.
Bob Kay: You guys did a
great job, thank you.
Alexis Kay: Definitely
not as easy as it
looks in video games.
Narrator: Including
Alexis' defensive
training, Bob's
already spent $150,000
on prepping in
the past year.
But now he wants to ensure
his family has a clear
path to safety, if
California is ever
leveled by a
massive earthquake.
So he's about to
spend almost half a
million dollars on
one final prep.
Bob Kay: A year
ago I'm watching
Doomsday Preppers
and I come to the
realization:
I'm a prepper.
Narrator: In Bob Kay's
first year as a prepper,
he spent $150,000
preparing his southern
California estate for a
catastrophic earthquake.
He just spent
another $40,000
on freeze-dried food.
Alexis Kay: It's
like freeze-dried
life insurance.
Narrator: And the
constant spending is
threatening to
divide the family.
Jade Kay: It's
so much money.
I think prepping is
a little bit crazy.
Um, I still
think it's kind
of wasting,
wasting money.
Narrator: Bob lives only
an hour away from a
nuclear plant he fears
wouldn't withstand
a quake greater than 7.0.
For most, quickly
escaping nuclear fallout
would be an
insurmountable obstacle,
but Bob can afford to
spend his way to safety.
Bob Kay: If things
go really badly,
nobody's going to
be getting out of
this area by a truck
or bus or a car.
The way to go, gotta
take it to a new level.
Narrator: Today, Bob
and his daughter,
Alexis, are meeting
pilot Johan Nurmi.
Bob Kay: Let's do it.
Want to talk to you
about some helicopters,
need your services.
Johan Nurmi: Yes sir.
I recommend this one.
It's a four seater.
She can carry 800
pounds inside and
we can still
have fuel.
Bob Kay: Okay,
and range?
Johan Nurmi: We
can fly for about two
and a half hours.
In California you
have an airport every
30 miles approximately.
Bob Kay: Ahhhh!
Johan Nurmi: So you
have no problem get fuel.
Something happens; I'll
be there in five minutes.
I'll rescue you.
Land outside your
driveway and off we go.
Bob Kay: This looks
like the way to go.
Looks like it has plenty
of room, so how much?
Jade Kay: You
actually purchased
a helicopter, or?
Okay, how much, how much
does the helicopter cost?
Bob Kay: About half
a million dollars.
Jade Kay: What?
Half a million dollars
for helicopter?
Bob Kay: Well, you
gotta let me tell
you the rest
of it though.
We're going to
do a test run.
We're gonna have a
helicopter come here.
We can land it out
here, right out here.
We should give
it a try.
Keeping in mind that
there are about a quarter
of a million people
living in this area and
bugging out isn't
necessarily the
easiest thing to do.
One highway in,
one highway out.
The advantages of
using some type of
air transport, helicopter,
allows one to take off
and land in a
very small area.
It's a tremendous
advantage.
A little bit
pricey way to go,
but it does deliver
on the solution.
My wife does view many
of the activities
that I engage in for
prepping with amusement.
The truth of the matter
is she does understand
the type of environment
we live in.
We've experienced
several earthquakes.
So she does
appreciate truly that
being prepared
is important.
To me, major earthquake,
if it was a matter of
money to save my
family's lives and
take care of
their well being,
show me where I
stick the debit card.
Narrator: Bob,
the experts,
Practical Preppers, have
assessed your preps.
Your gardens, orchard,
and stored food will
be a great asset if it
comes to feeding your
family over an extended
period of time.
However, currently you
lack sources of protein.
The experts recommend
you start raising
chickens and rabbits.
Bob Kay: I think we need
to find an alternative
and I think the stores
that we can purchase
that are freeze
dried would be an
excellent alternative.
Narrator: Your
35, 000-gallon pool
is a good start
for water supply,
but relying on the pool
alone will leave you
without any potable
water at all should
your desalination
equipment ever fail.
Bob Kay: We had thought
about drilling a well.
We tried to
get permits;
not allowed because
the water rights
are not ours.
Narrator: To determine how
long you could initially
survive a catastrophe,
Practical Preppers has
scored your preps in
five categories of
20 points each, for
a total possible
score of 100.
Food: 11 out of
20 points.
Water: 17 out
of 20 points.
Shelter: 9 out
Security: 13 out
of 20 points.
Your knowledge of
vitamins and nutrition
gives you 11
x-factor points.
Overall your score
is 61 out of 100.
You have nine months
initial survival time.
Bob Kay: I agree with
most of it except its
left out a
critical factor:
our ability to have
business activities
and barter and
increase our ability
to live a longer
period of time.
Narrator: Experts rate
the likelihood of a
magnitude 6.7 earthquake
or stronger striking on
the fault under
Temecula, California
within the next
30 years at 11%.
Josh Wander is a
deeply religious
prepper living
in Pittsburgh.
He fears the
end is coming,
but can he prep to
keep his family
alive without disobeying
his God's commands?
Narrator: Josh Wander
is a husband and father
of six who moved from
Jerusalem, Israel,
to Pittsburgh,
Pennsylvania,
about 10 years ago.
Josh Wander: You
all buckled up?
You ready?
Here we go.
Narrator: He's devoted to
his orthodox Jewish faith,
his family and
community politics.
Josh Wander: A
normal day in my life
starts off around
6:30 in the morning
where I go to
pray in synagogue.
After that, I start
my campaigning.
Thanks,
thank you.
Narrator: Each day, Josh
works on his campaign
for city council,
cares for his children
and fulfills his
prayer obligations.
But every moment
not devoted to God,
his kids, and politics,
he spends prepping.
Josh Wander: I'm
preparing for a
series of catastrophic
terrorist attacks,
which will
fundamentally change
our lives as
we know it.
Terrorist attacks are
just a way of life
and something that's
necessary to prepare for.
It wouldn't be difficult
for terrorists to blow
themselves up in suicide
bombs in major cities,
buses, in malls throughout
the United States.
There would be
continuous attacks on
these locations over
and over again.
Police, firemen, and
the paramedics would
come to respond.
There would be additional
attacks as soon as the
first responders
would come that would
kill and maim
those people.
This is something
that was perfected in
the Middle East.
People would be afraid to
use mass transportation;
afraid to go to stores
for fear that there
would be
continuous attacks.
People would be stuck
in their homes in fear
without the ability to
bring in new resources.
Once that happened
there's going to be
a lot of people
dying very quickly.
Narrator: Josh is
running for a seat
on Pittsburgh's
city council.
But, unlike his
opponent, the focus of
his platform is
not improving the
city's infrastructure.
Josh believes
terrorist attacks
could happen at
any moment,
so he wants the entire
city of Pittsburgh
to begin prepping.
Josh Wander: As
a politician,
I'm looking at the
welfare of the
greater community.
I educate
people on the
importance of
preparedness.
What's motivating me
to run for Pittsburgh
city council is that
fact that there is
no preparedness
at all.
People are not
listening.
What we need is somebody
who's going to stand up
and legislate and
explain that there has
to be required
education.
David Raphael: You
see these people now
worried about you know,
building bunkers.
Everyone's building
bunkers now.
And that's cool and
if I had the money,
I'd build
a bunker.
Like that,
that's great.
I think it would be
nice to have someone
involved in government
that wants to be prepared.
I would vote for Josh
Wander unconditionally.
Narrator: Josh
believes politicians
like himself will
be targeted when
terrorists attack and
he fears one of his
own political rallies
could soon be the scene of
a massacre aimed
at silencing him.
In the last year, the
number of government
officials killed in
terrorist attacks
worldwide increased
more than 13 percent.
So today, he's putting
his staff through
their first mass
casualty drill.
Josh Wander: Let's
get bloodied up.
It's a misnomer
that people
panic during
attacks.
Instead you find
that people just
shut down and
they don't move.
Narrator: In a
life-threatening
situation, instead
of fight or flight,
the human body will
sometimes freeze,
or play possum, to avoid
becoming a target.
To help his team fight
that urge in a real
catastrophe, Josh is
trying to get them used
to acting in a crisis
by making this scene
of carnage as
realistic as possible.
Josh Wander: Doing
something repetitively
ingrains it into you,
so that when something
actually happens you
won't break down.
Narrator: Josh was trained
as an EMS responder
in Jerusalem and
witnessed the impact
of suicide bombings
first hand.
Terrorist attacks
sometimes happen in
quick succession,
with secondary bombs
exploding once emergency
responders arrive,
to prevent people
from receiving care.
So Josh is training
his team to secure
the perimeter before
attending to any victims.
Josh Wander: I want
all three of you to
make a perimeter,
then we're gonna go and
treat the wounded.
Come on,
quickly, quickly!
EMS: Clear
over here.
Josh Wander: Okay,
it seems safe.
Now let's start
treating them.
Joe: He's breathing,
pulse is rapid.
All right, let's
red tag him.
Narrator: Each victim
is assessed and
assigned a color
coded tag based on
the severity of
his injuries.
Green for minor
injuries that can wait,
yellow for urgent
but stable,
red for critical.
Joe: Do we
have a pulse?
Student: No pulse.
Narrator: And black.
Joe: No pulse,
no breathing.
He's a black
tag, he's gone.
Let's get help to
the other people.
Josh Wander: We
put an enormous
amount of
sanctity on life.
We need to just save as
many lives as possible.
This is exactly
why I'm a prepper.
Because I think
that the survival
of my family,
friends, supporters,
is, is my ultimate
responsibility.
Narrator: Josh's
orthodox faith impacts
every aspect of
his prepping.
But can he prepare his
family for the life of
terrorist attacks
he fears without
having to
disobey God?
Narrator: Josh Wander is
a Pittsburgh politician
who fears a series of
terrorist attacks will
soon tear across
the United States.
He believes the
unpredictability and
frequency of the attacks
will force people to
remain in their homes
and survive off only
what they
have on hand.
So Josh is
preparing to bug in
for at least
three months.
Josh Wander: Urban
centers would be targeted
in any terrorist
attack.
It would make most
sense to basically
stay put for a
period of time.
Narrator: Josh has
been trying to build up a
stockpile of provisions
for when doomsday comes.
But as an orthodox Jew,
he faces a complication
that most preppers don't
have to worry about.
Josh Wander: We
have to keep kosher.
So our food
preparations have to
be all certified kosher.
Narrator: Because of
the trouble he's had
finding kosher
food designed
for long shelf life,
it's taken Josh three
years to accumulate
just a three month
supply of kosher
preps that
won't spoil.
Josh Wander:
Matzah, I believe,
is actually the
ultimate prepper food.
Narrator: Unleavened
bread made only from
flour and water,
Matzah is a source of
protein and
carbohydrates and has
a two and half
year shelf life.
Josh Wander: I've seen
these boxes be opened
years after its expiration
and it's still fresh.
Narrator: Josh also has
a dozen cases of kosher
MRE's, enough for 144
1,200-calorie meals,
which have been
cooked and
packaged under
rabbinical supervision,
and can last up
to five years.
Josh Wander: Kosher
MRE's are specifically
made for Orthodox Jews
who are in the military.
They are U.S.
military rations,
and they are
completely kosher.
Narrator: Having served in
the Israeli defense forces,
Josh has experience
surviving off MRE's.
But his
children don't.
So today, he's giving
them a taste of what
they'll be in for, if
multiple terrorist
attacks confine
them to their home.
Josh Wander: You're gonna
pour in just a drop, okay?
Narrator: The heater
pouch is filled with
iron and
magnesium dust.
When they come in
contact with water they
begin to rust, and
the rapid oxidation
generates heat.
Josh Wander:
Feel it, Sara?
That's how the
chemicals work.
Feel how
hot it is?
Josh Wander:
Baruch atah adonai,
elohenu melech ha'olam,
borei mi nay mazanos.
Tamara: Ewww, it
looks like barf.
Sara: It looks like barf.
Josh Wander:
Not bad.
Make a mazanos close
your eyes and eat it,
come on.
Tamara: No.
Josh Wander:
Come on.
Tamara: No!
Josh Wander: Corn
and, and carrots.
No?
That's just 'cause your
sister told you not to,
right?
Cause you were
about to do it.
Narrator: Josh's
current store of kosher
supplies should
last 90 days.
But he fears wave after
wave of terrorist
attacks could keep
Pittsburgh under siege
longer than
three months.
Josh Wander: Whoever has a
bite of this can have a treat.
Who's gonna have it?
Narrator: If that
were to happen,
Josh believes he'd
eventually be forced to
choose between
keeping kosher and
staying alive.
Josh Wander: There
are 613 commandments
in the Torah.
We are instructed to
break any of those
rules in order
to save life.
If necessary we
could eat pork,
we could eat
shellfish or
any other non-kosher
species for
the preservation
of life.
Under normal
circumstances is
a rabbit kosher?
Daughter: No.
Josh Wander: Right?
Rabbits are
not kosher.
In fact, it says
in the bible,
it mentions rabbits as
one of the species
which is not kosher.
Narrator: Because
these rabbits are
raised to be dinner,
Josh won't allow his
children to give them names.
Josh Wander:
They're not pets.
We do play with them,
but they understand
that they're eventually
going to be used for food.
Tamara: I think
it's disgusting.
Josh Wander:
It's disgusting?
But it's better
than dying right?
Tamara: No.
Josh Wander: I don't
feel conflicted at all
once we've finished all
of our kosher options
it smoothly transitions to
whatever's out there and,
that's necessary
to preserve life.
Narrator: Keeping kosher
isn't the only Jewish
tradition Josh may
have to break with in
order to keep his
family alive.
If terrorism comes
to Pittsburgh,
Josh and his children
are willing to do
whatever it takes to
protect themselves.
Josh Wander: Jewish law
is clear that we are
obligated to defend
ourselves to the
point of using
lethal force in order
to preserve our lives.
Narrator: Today, Josh
is taking Hannah and
Etan to their local
shooting range.
As a certified
NRA instructor,
Josh makes sure they
practice once a week,
so that their shooting
skills are honed
in case of an onslaught
of terrorist attacks.
Josh Wander: Now look
between these two
and this and
see the read.
Okay, whenever
you're ready put the
finger in and
slowly pull once.
[gunshot].
Slowly, slowly, that
was way too fast.
Continue to
look through it.
Relax, relax.
[gunshot].
Good, perfect.
Deep breath, relax, lean
forward a little bit.
[gunshot].
Most children out there
know to pick up a phone
and dial 911,
unfortunately very few
know what to do when they
pick up the phone and
there's no dial tone
on the other end.
Narrator: As much as
Josh loves Pittsburgh,
he believes it's
possible that,
in the wake of
terrorist attacks and
subsequent looting,
their home could
no longer be
a safe haven.
So if the terrorists
gain the upper hand,
Josh has a plan.
Josh Wander: We
would have to get
out from this
urban death trap.
We would definitely
be bugging out
to a remote location.
If they're woken up in
the middle of the night,
they know to bug out.
It's something that we
constantly work on.
We're bugging out!
Narrator: Josh's
15-passenger van
is large enough to
fit his family
of eight and
some supplies.
His plan is to camp
in a wooded area,
where he hopes he can
remain camouflaged
until he can determine
his family's safest
route out of the city.
Josh Wander: We're
headed into the forest
in order to reassess
the situation.
The relationship
between Judaism and
prepping is
very strong.
Jewish communities
throughout the millennia
have been required
to bug out.
The Exodus was a
form of a bug out.
They were forced to very
quickly pick up their
things and marched out of
Egypt to the Holy Land.
Moses did what was
necessary for himself
and his nation in
order to survive.
Just like any other time
in world history the ones
that are gonna survive are
those that are prepared.
The ultimate
prepper food.
Narrator: Josh,
the experts,
Practical Preppers have
reviewed your preps.
Your rainwater catchment
barrels are a good idea;
however, you
should consider
storing more water.
250 gallons is not enough
for a family of eight.
Josh Wander: 250
gallons is just the
beginning of our preps.
I think we have plenty
of water to go around.
Narrator: We suggest
that you include
others in your plans.
In an urban
environment,
you will find your greatest
strength in numbers.
Josh Wander: There's a
lot that we've learned
through our military
experience.
One of the things
that we've learned is
the fact that in
order to improve you
have to hear the
negative as well.
Narrator: To determine how
long you could initially
survive a catastrophe,
Practical Preppers has
scored your preps in
five categories of
20 points each, for a total
possible score of 100.
You need a more
complete food plan:
11 out of
20 points.
Water: 14 out
of 20 points.
Shelter: 12 out
Security: forming a
prepping group would give
you a more complete
skill base:
17 out of 20 points.
For attempting to inform
your community about
prepping through your
political campaign,
you receive 16
x-factor points.
Overall, your score
is 70 out of 100.
You have 12 months
initial survival time.
Josh Wander: Well, a 70 is
generally a passing grade,
but I'm not
satisfied with it.
I would say that it's
necessary to do better
and we're always
looking at ways that
we can better
ourselves.
Since National
Geographic was here,
things have been getting a
lot worse in this country.
We've decided
that if necessary,
myself and my family are
going to move back to
Israel, where Jews are
protected and safe.
Narrator: Despite
more than 10,000
terrorist attacks and
12,000 deaths in 2011,
more than 3/4 of those
attacks occurred
in the near east
and south Asia.
Overall, the total number
of terrorist attacks
worldwide dropped almost
12% to a five-year low.
Ryan Croft is willing
to eat anything,
if it means keeping
his family alive.
Ryan Croft: And
he's dinner.
All right, guys.
Narrator: But when it
comes to their safety,
only the best will do.
So he's attempting
to build the
perfect prepper
weapon system with
his own two hands.
Ryan Croft: Frontal!
Narrator: Ryan Croft is
a former airman in the
US Air Force who now works
as a weapons manufacturer
in Asheville,
North Carolina.
With five teenage
boys at home,
keeping enough food
in the house is a
constant battle for Ryan
and his wife, Rebecca.
But it's even harder when
they're also trying to
stockpile provisions for
the end of the world.
Ryan Croft: We're
preparing to stand our
ground during a worldwide
financial collapse.
Frontal!
Alex: Covering!
Ryan Croft: Our
country's not okay,
our world is not okay
and it's not getting better.
There aren't
enough resources.
Can FEMA arrive?
Uh-huh.
Can FEMA arrive in a
thousand cities at once?
Nuh-uh.
So who are they
going to show up for?
You, me?
That's where the
prepper steps in.
I'm not gonna sit and
wait for someone else
to come up with
solutions when so often
I've been involved
with government.
Their solutions suck.
Narrator: Ryan fears
the economy will
soon collapse, and
that when it does,
it'll take society
along with it.
Ryan Croft: The
value of your dollar
is completely
artificial.
Our financial collapse
has already started.
We're just in the
gentle glide of
the collapse
right now.
How close are we?
The only reason why it
keeps going forward
is because of
consumer confidence.
You knock consumer
confidence out of the way;
you've got chaos
in different and
varying degrees
around the world.
Narrator: Experts
recommend preppers in
heavily populated areas
have bug-out locations
at least two hours
outside of city centers,
to which they can
escape in a crisis.
But if the economy
does collapse,
as Ryan fears,
he has no plans
to cut and run.
Ryan Croft: We
love our community.
We are heavily
invested.
As preppers, we are
not going anywhere.
This is our town.
This is where we live and
we love these people.
Whatever they're
missing,
if I can fill in
the pieces, I will.
Narrator: Currently only
1% of the food consumed
in western North Carolina
is grown locally.
But Ryan's not
stockpiling canned or
dried food for
his community.
Instead, he's planning
on growing an algae
that's one of the simplest
life forms on earth.
Ryan Croft: I'm
very excited
about culturing
Spirulina.
Spirulina alone promises
to take starvation
out of any crisis
in the world.
Narrator: Spirulina
is an algae so rich
in vitamins, protein,
and other nutrients
that it's been said a
person could survive
on it and
water alone.
Spirulina's even
been included in
planned diets for NASA
missions to mars.
Israel: What exactly
does blowing air
into this tank
do anyway?
Ryan Croft: Agitation
is really good
for the solution
but also you are
introducing carbon
dioxide and oxygen.
It loves carbon
dioxide.
The best way to
harvest Spirulina is
to just put
a tube in.
Almost like
siphoning gasoline.
I mean, you can eat
it right off the
filter cloth if
you wanted to.
It's like a
buttery,
almost tasteless
substance.
You need about five to
10 grams of it daily
to get a good nutritive
supplemental supply.
If you want to
live on it alone,
probably 20
grams a day.
Narrator: Ryan thinks
his ten gallon aquarium
can produce up to five grams
of Spirulina each day.
That means by his
estimates he'd
need more than 30
Spirulina aquariums
just to feed his
family of seven.
In order to make it
a resource for his
whole community, he's
recruited friends and
neighbors to help him
establish Spirulina
farms throughout town.
Ryan Croft: Your
number one resource
should be people.
And that is not on most
people's preppers list.
They think that means
I've got a doctor.
I've got a tactician,
I've got an engineer;
that's not people,
those are jobs.
We'd like to select
maybe a half a dozen
people that we can
actually spread this
Spirulina tech to right
away so that we have
got 100 to 150
gallons on hand fully
mature and available.
You only need about 15
milliliters to go in,
start a new colony.
So we'd have the
resources to set up about
1,000 little
microfarms.
I believe that the
people with the greatest
chance of survival
are those that can
genuinely stick
together.
I'm talkin' about
regionally stick together,
I don't mean your
little 20-person group.
That's not enough.
You need as many
people as you can to
have the same
objective.
And that is to stay alive
with one condition:
Everyone lives,
no one dies.
Narrator: If America's
food supply lines break
down following an
economic collapse,
Ryan understands
not everyone in his
community will
want to eat algae.
So he's cultivating
another abundant
source of protein:
earthworms.
Ryan Croft: Six little
worms will provide
you with an entire
day's worth of
high quality protein.
You'll have a thousand
or 2 or 3,000 of
them in the average
American yard.
Once you hit
about 3,000 worms,
you're always going
to have worms.
So guys this is our
next little piece of
survival tech for
prepping our city.
Tom: The big
question is,
which one of
you guys,
is gonna have
the worm?
The first worm.
Israel: I think
that will be you.
Tom: No, I'm talking
about you young kids.
Kid: I don't
like worms.
Ryan Croft: Oh
they're tasty;
wait till
you try one.
My gosh, they
are flavorful.
Kid: No thank you.
Ryan Croft: It's
important to teach my
kids because morale
and mindset is
a huge component
to survival.
So long as you don't
think it's a worm,
it's a lot
easier on the mind.
Narrator: Earthworms
provide a comparable
amount of protein you
can get eating eggs or
cow's milk, and are
consumed regularly in
almost 90 countries.
Ryan prefers his
with hot sauce.
Ryan Croft: Hot sauce
goes a long way with
helping you eat things
you normally wouldn't eat.
Alex: Corbin!
I'll pick one out
for you, a good one.
We'll give you
this little guy.
Hold him,
clean him off.
Corbin: This
is so crazy.
Alex: No sauce.
He's straight
up, he's a man.
Tom: Oh, you're
the man.
Ryan Croft: Tastes
like dirt, huh?
Corbin: Yeah.
Tom: Wow, nice.
Good man!
You did well, I'm
proud of you boy.
Corbin: I would have
to be pretty hungry
to eat one of those
but I would do it.
Ryan Croft: You have
the capability of
taking care of
yourself with only
that which nature
provides in abundance.
Adaptability, flexibility
is the number one
skill that you should
cultivate in yourself.
Narrator: Apart from
algae and worms,
Ryan doesn't put
too much emphasis
on stockpiling
additional food.
Ryan Croft: We have
about 1,200 pounds
of food storage.
On a normal 2,200
calorie per day diet.
I've only got about
3 to 4 months.
But you really don't have
to stock a lot of things.
Especially if you
have got some
experience with primitive
survival techniques.
Narrator: Ryan spent four
years in the Air Force
and learned how to
survive off the land
with limited
resources.
Ryan Croft: I
lived primitively
for years,
intentionally.
No power, no
running water and
I lived for
a long time.
We're going to
scavenge from our
local environment,
to supplement our
food storage.
Narrator: Tonight,
he's taking his boys
out into the local
woods to show them what
else he expects them to
do should doomsday come.
Ryan Croft: One of
the lesser and least
appreciated foods
around America
is the common
field mouse;
full of nutrition.
If you eat the
whole thing,
the whole
little mouse,
you're gonna have
a complete diet.
Narrator: Field
mice are a
constantly
renewable resource.
Each female can give
birth to 83 mice
in the course
of one year.
But at roughly
70 calories each,
in order to meet
minimum recommend
calorie requirements on
a 100% mouse diet,
he'd have to consume
17 mice each day.
So for Ryan it's
extremely important that
his boys become
skilled mouse hunters.
Ryan Croft: We're going to
demonstrate a Paiute trap.
You put a little
twig in here.
See my side, where
my fingers are?
That's where you need
to apply the pressure.
Narrator: Ryan is building
a simple deadfall trap
out of notched sticks
and a heavy rock.
By tying the bait to the
end of the trigger stick,
if it's disturbed
it will cause the
delicately balanced
sticks to collapse,
and the deadweight
will fall.
Ryan Croft: All he has
to do is sniff on that
peanut butter a
little bit.
It does not take
very much pressure.
A fraction of an ounce
touches that stick
and we want that little
tiny bit of weight
to trip this off.
This is a very dense
habitat for mice.
So hook 'em up with the
convenience store right here.
They can check in,
but not check out.
Alright, well
there you go.
Common field mouse
and he's dinner.
All right, guys
I brought dinner.
Corbin: What
are we havin'?
Ryan Croft: Little mouse,
little field mouse.
He didn't
feel a thing.
There's no good way
to skin a mouse.
You pretty much just
destroy them if you do.
We're gonna
hammer him out.
Break his little
bones up.
Front to back, from
the head down and
then we just drop him
right into the coals.
You roll him around
a little bit.
Let him get crispy.
Ben: So what's the
best part to eat?
Ryan Croft:
His head.
So boys, who's gonna
try some mouse?
Corbin: Not me, I had
the worm last time.
Ryan Croft: Gordy?
Gordy: I don't
think so.
Ryan Croft: You
don't think so.
You might be
hungry someday,
you might really.
Gordy: Yeah, I'll do it
when I'm really hungry.
Ryan Croft:
All right.
Ben: I'll try it.
Ryan Croft:
All right.
Ben: Mmmm.
Ryan Croft:
Charcoal-y, huh?
Count of three.
Gordy: One
two three.
Alex: Go.
You got it,
you got it.
Go 'head,
crunch it up.
It's gone, it's
gone, it's gone.
There you go,
there you go.
Ryan Croft:
It's delicious.
Gordy: Ugh!
Ryan Croft: A few good
tools, plus know-how,
you can find
mice anywhere.
You'll never
go hungry.
Narrator: Scavenging
enough food to
survive on in an
apocalypse is one thing;
keeping it safe from
those who would take
it from you
is another.
So Ryan has taken
extreme measures to prepare
his community to
defend themselves
to the death,
if necessary.
Narrator: Ryan Croft and
his fellow preppers in
Asheville, North Carolina,
are preparing for the
looming economic collapse
that Ryan feels
is inevitable.
Ryan Croft: We're not
prepping for ourselves.
We're going the
step beyond;
we're prepping
for our city.
Narrator: Ryan fears
his determination to
stay in the city and
help his neighbors will
put him in the path
of violent looters.
So Ryan wants every
prepper in his group to
be sufficiently armed.
Ryan Croft: I think we
should all be armed.
If you're armed,
it changes the
game completely.
More arms works better
than less arms.
Narrator: But Ryan's not
content with what's on the
market, so he's looking
to create a custom weapon
specifically to suit
a prepper's needs.
Ryan Croft: I took
the best of the AK-47
and combined it with
the logistical system
of the AR-15.
Narrator: The AK-47 is
generally considered
durable, cheap,
and easy to use,
but an inferior
weapon to the AR-15,
which is generally
more expensive.
Ryan thought if he could
combine the best aspects
of each gun, he'd have the
perfect prepper weapon.
Ryan Croft: This
is Joshua Mark One.
I named it after
a general Joshua,
my favorite
biblical character.
Ah, the general pretty
much that secured the
Promised Land for
the Israelites.
This is my very first
gun that I built.
It's sort of the
closest thing a man
can get to having
a child, I think.
Cause it's just a
little bunch of parts
and you bring
it together.
You breathe
life into it
and it's magical,
you know?
This weapon is
perfect for, ah,
I would say for
American prepper,
but really just
for America.
Period.
Alex: Covering!
Ryan Croft: We're
prepared to do
everything that's
necessary to survive.
We choose to try and save
as many lives as we can.
Frontal!
Number one advice
I have for America?
Be flexible.
Widen your mind,
broaden your
capabilities adapt
and overcome.
Narrator: Ryan,
the experts at
Practical Preppers
commend you for
your community
action plan.
By rallying your
friends and neighbors
you will establish
a system that
mutually benefits
everyone.
Ryan Croft:
Thank you.
Narrator: Your varied
and non-conventional
food sources are
clever and efficient.
However you may
have trouble
feeding your
family of seven.
We recommend you look
into expanding your
stockpile of traditional
foods with long shelf life.
Ryan Croft: Understood,
I don't disagree.
However, if we
fully develop our
Spirulina tech, I think
we'll be just fine.
Narrator: To determine
how long you could
initially survive
a catastrophe,
Practical Preppers has
scored your preps in
five categories of
20 points each.
Food: 14 out
of 20 points.
Needing to walk half
a mile to collect
water is impractical
and could be dangerous:
9 out of 20 points.
Shelter: 13 out
of 20 points.
Security: 15 out
Your community approach
to helping neighbors
and sharing your
Spirulina gives you
12 x-factor points.
Overall, you get
a 63 out of 100.
You have ten months
initial survival time.
Ryan Croft: Well my
family have deeply
appreciated the
assessment.
You check us out.
If the world will
give us another year
I think we'll be doubly,
triply impressive.
We've made a lot of
really good progress.
Not in every way
that we want to,
but in very
significant ways.
Our Spirulina is
doing quite well.
It's very thick, it's
ready for harvesting.
And we've posted a lot
of videos on YouTube
showing what we've done
and how we've done it,
so that we can help
more people that
are also trying
to prepare.
Narrator: In spite of
the recent recession and
European debt crisis,
most economists believe
a near-term depression
is unlikely,
and the odds of a global
collapse that would result
in a severe breakdown
of society are remote.