Nature kills 10,000 animals
for each one it produces.
I better do that with a worm.
If you could spread this
idea into all areas:
Worms are born...
This is a drawing of a worm.
A worm has light cells
all over its body.
They're very weak, their eyes,
but the early stages of the eye.
When this worm sticks its
front end out of the ground
and a bird sees it,
it picks it off.
If it's born with more light
cells up here, just a few more
then if the bird's shadow comes, it retracts.
- Gotcha.
Then eventually all the worms that
survive have light cells over here.
The eye is an organization
of light cells.
It starts out with light cells all
over, but the worms that survive
are the worms with the light
cells at the leading edge.
If they're at the trailing
edge, it doesn't survive.
When a bird lands with a worm, and
the other birds open their mouths
(I did this years ago)
the bird that moves the most with
its mouth open gets all the worms.
- Gotcha. - It doesn't feed all the birds.
- It feeds the most active.
- I made a plastic bird
with its mouth wide open
on a spring that moved more, and the
bird put all the worms in there.
That's when I
became a mechanist.
I believe that human beings
cannot think or reason
they're mechanisms that
respond to the environment
because they have a wide
range of responding sensors.
I looked at robots the same
way, but we're organic.
We get hungry, so we hunt.
Robots don't.
Robots don't say "I
need lubrication
so I'm going to behave
a certain way."
They don't care whether you
lubricate them or not.
They don't evolve.
No man has been able to make a
robot that says "Just a minute.
I feel good doing that.
" Robots don't feel good or bad.
I don't know if you've noticed this:
when a wolf has incisors (larger)
he could tear off
bigger pieces of meat.
If he swallows it faster, he
could survive starvation.
Animals do not chew their food.
They rip off the meat and swallow it
whole, just as it is.
I don't know if you've noticed that.
That animal will
survive in scarcity.
The animal that tears the meat off and
chews on it won't have enough food.
The animals tear it apart, fast
and they don't outgrow that.
The animals born with
larger fangs survive
those with shorter fangs don't
get a bigger piece of the meat.
Animal life has no purpose
is what I'm trying to say.
There's no purpose to eyes,
ears, teeth or anything.
If you're born with things that work
under those conditions, you survive.
If you're born with a
more rational mind
and you're rational about
everything, you can't live.
You might leave a little
food for your young.
If a bird doesn't feed its young
(let's say it just eats the
food) that species is gone:
a bird that doesn't
take care of its young.
Birds are not born to
take care of their young.
They say "They instinctively
take care of their young."
The birds that don't feed their
young are dead. They're gone.
If you start looking
for purpose in life
everything seems
to have a purpose.
Questioner: So you're looking at the
successful birds that still exist.
- Under those conditions.
- Yes, under those conditions
that feed their young.
That's why they're there...
(Jacque)
- Yes, same with humans.
You feed their young because
they're not helpless.
Chinese used to drown
babies that were female.
Did you know that?
Because they can't feed them.
An Eskimo would put his
grandma out on the ice
when there is a
shortage of seals.
She never wanted to
be put out on the ice
so she'd always
behave very well.
It took an Eskimo who had
a wonderful grandmother
a little longer to put
her out on the ice.
That's very hard to accept
that humans are machines.
They're responding organisms.
Very difficult.
People that used to attend
my seminars for years
would write songs about
'I'm a responding organism
a bundle of tropisms.'
You know, and they couldn't
get along with normal people.
You must understand that.
A guy said "I've been attending your sessions.
I'm losing my friends!"
I said "You're not
losing your friends
you're losing people that
are hardheaded, hardwired."
You'll have to change people
to get along with them.
I call it poisoning the well.
I'm saying that all things are shoved
by something else. There's nothing...
Although we can't see the wire
up our ass connected to the sun
we depend on the sun, the
radiant energy of the sun.
You may not see the
forces that move you:
nutrition, different food combinations
strengthen your fingernails
lack of it makes them
soft and they crack.
You don't know how your body
operates, but if you study nutrition
and physical degeneration, you
know more about the body.
You never know everything.
The word 'everything' is a stupid word.
It implies that there is
such a thing as everything.
When you get into the mechanistic point
of view, all that the mechanist says
is that all things are
shoved by other things.
There is no prime source
of that movement.
In other words, if this begins to roll,
it means the table is not level.
Nothing moves of itself.
Plants do not grow.
They depend on sunlight, water,
moisture, soil, temperature
many different things.
There's no prime mover.
They say "How did the
universe begin?"
That's a stupid question.
It assumes a beginning.
A seed they say is the
beginning of a plant.
How do you know it's
not the end product?
Why do you call
it the beginning?
Do you understand what I am saying?
Man projects like hell
including scientists.
There's no good, no bad, no
smart people, no dumb people.
There are people that have
less tools than you do.
You might have better tools.
If a girl falls in love
with a taller guy than you
because she likes tall people,
and you get mad at her
you don't understand the
effects of environment.
When you understand you'll never
dislike anybody or hate them.
You'll understand where
they're coming from
and that will stop a lot
of crime and a lot of...
That's what I mean by
we're not educated.
I hope you know what I mean
now, we're not given a...
"Well I've never heard of
Fresco, he has no Ph.D.
He never graduated junior grade school.
Therefore, fuck Fresco.
You're a follower of
some fraudulent guy."
That's what they'll tell you
if you talk to normal people
but if you understand
what I'm saying
you'll only understand those
things that have parallel
that you have experience with.
I can't talk to anybody.
They would hate me.
If I talk to
scientists, they'd say
"Well where the hell do
you get your ideas from?
You know I got mine
by hard work."
So did I.
To get it, I worked very hard
questioning everything,
trying to.
I still have a few carry-overs
which I'm okay with.
- Primordial slime.  - What?
- Primordial slime.
- Yes, primordial slime, exactly.
That goes for all of us.
We could never be objective.
Do you know why?
We can never be open-minded, because
all of us have some of the slime.
There are some of us that can
accept a wider range of behavior
due to background.
If you don't have this background
if you've never been here, you'll
retain what you've been given
but from now on, you're poisoned.
You can't go back
to the old way of thinking.
You'll never be able to go back.
There are no roads to yesterday.
Do you know what I mean by that?
We can't go backwards and say "Well
I've become an atheist.
Now I'm going to become a Catholic again"
unless you see
things differently.
Believe in miracles, and you believe
in people with power of telekinesis.
If you don't know how they do that,
you might go back to church.
Questioner: Were you
once Christian?
Jacque: Yes, I was once a believer in God.
Let's say that.
I believed that somebody made the world
because that's what they told me.
Questioner: What made
you change your mind?
Jacque: A motion picture
called 'The Ten Commandments.'
Ever hear of it? Cecil B. Demille.
- Yeah, I saw that.
Jacque: The old one,
the original.
I came home and said to my older brother
"I don't understand the Egyptians.
Didn't they believe in the
same God we believe in?"
He said "No, maybe
they were atheists."
My brother was a little older,
and I asked "What's an atheist?"
"Well atheists believe
that animals evolved.
The giraffes, they ate things,
and made a longer neck
and animals went
through evolution."
He knew a little bit
about evolution
and from my background at that
time, that made more sense.
If I had another background, I'd have
said "Gee, maybe there isn't a God."
I began to talk to people.
They said "You're nuts!
There's got to be a God."
Then I read books on
atheism, a little bit
and it made more sense than God
making a man and a woman out of clay
earth, and he turned them
loose in the Garden of Eden.
That sounded more
like a fairy tale.
I had enough of a
background to make it.
If I didn't, I would
have rejected it.
When the minister said "It
rains to make the plants grow"
I said "Why does
it rain at sea?"
I really wanted to know.
I was not an atheist.
He said hold out your
hands and he beat me
and I began to doubt the
wisdom of that guy.
Then he said "God works
in strange ways.
After we die, we'll know
why certain things happen.
Today, you won't understand it.
" So I bought the package
and then I said "Why does
a flood drown children.
They've had no experience."
He said "Because the Lord
works in strange ways.
We may not know that, but there
is a reason for everything."
Then he gave me some
reasons, he did.
He said a man he met went
blind due to cataracts.
The blind man said
"Since I was blind
I realized a lot of things that I
didn't appreciate in the past."
He said "The purpose of
that guy going blind
was to give him the realization of
how wonderful it is to have sight
and then how wonderful
it is to have senses.
There's a reason
for everything."
That stalled my ability
to think things out.
It was a good example,
and then going on
I didn't find blind men particularly
smarter than anyone else.
This particular blind man
that he quoted, yes it did
but there are many people that
have a negative experience
and it makes them more negative.
Do you understand what
I'm talking about?
It's very hard to be objective
and I found conflict in the early
stages of beginning to question things.
I found "Well, it's better if
you go to church once a month"
you know, not give
it up entirely
so I said "God would
know I was false then."
Then I didn't have
to go once a month
because I said "I can't
put it over on God."
Then I learned more
about evolution
and learned more about
God sacrificing His son
and if He knows everything He would
know that His son would be crucified.
Then it didn't make sense.
I began to question that whole pattern.
It went in circles, you know what I mean?
Then I pulled out
but if I didn't question the patterns.
I don't think I could make it.
If I wasn't shoved
further enough along
I wouldn't have
questioned anything.
Here you're being shoved
and from now on you'll
question more things.