Okay, go ahead, Troy,
and make a muscle.
All right,
check out these guns.
Those aren't muscles.
These are muscles.
Kevin.
Time for breakfast.
Hey, dad.
What are you doing, boy?
I'm showing Troy
my muscles.
Those aren't muscles.
These are muscles.
Wow.
My whole screen went black.
It's like a bicep eclipse.
Kevin's got to go
eat breakfast.
He'll see you later, Troy.
Bye, Mr. Kingston-Persons.
Catch you later.
Kevin.
Kevin, do you have my lotion
in here again?
I can't believe
it's so round.
It's, like, out there.
I mean, it's gross.
Look.
Boy, you're supposed to use it
to make your skin soft.
♪ I like big butts
and I cannot lie ♪
♪ you other brothers
can't deny ♪
♪ that when I girl walks in
with a itty-bitty waist ♪
♪ and a round thing in your face
you get sprung ♪
♪ want to pull up tough ♪
♪ 'cause you noticed that butt
was stuffed ♪
♪ deep in the jeans
she's wearing ♪
♪ I'm hooked
and I can't stop staring ♪
♪ oh, baby,
I want to get with ya ♪
♪ and take your picture ♪
♪ my homeboys
tried to warn me ♪
♪ but that butt you got makes ♪
♪ me so horny ♪
♪ ooh, rump of smooth skin ♪
♪ you say you want to get
in my benz ♪
♪ well, use me, use me ♪
♪ 'cause you ain't
that average groupie ♪
♪ I seen her dancing ♪
♪ to hell with romancing ♪
♪ she's sweat, wet, got it going
like a turbo vette ♪
♪ L.A. face
with a Oakland Booty ♪
♪ ♪
♪ baby got back ♪
♪ are we there yet? ♪
The Viral Video
S01x07 Original Air Date on June 23, 2010
♪ tell me, tell me, tell me ♪
♪ tell me,
are we there yet? ♪
-- sync, corrected by elderman --
-- for www.addic7ed.Com --
Dinner's almost ready.
What you making?
Mom's teaching me
how to make peppered salmon.
Awesome.
Peppered salmon
is awesome?
No, I just pulled up
this viral video.
It's an old lady dancing
to Baby Got Back.
I love dancing
to that song,
but who would record it
and put it on the Internet?
Look at this fool.
She is a mess.
Got not makeup on,
looking like a ghetto Lady Gaga.
Hey, that looks like
your room.
Baby, those look like
your pajamas.
What?
Mom, that looks like...
Oh, my God.
Oh, my God!
♪ Shake that healthy butt ♪
Thud!
♪ ♪
♪ baby got back ♪
This is horrible.
I think it's hilarious.
Turn it off.
I didn't know you could dance
like that, mom.
Well, you weren't supposed
to find out on the Internet.
It's no big deal.
Cats are put online
all the time.
Doesn't seem to bother them,
because they just keep doing
stuff that's hilarious.
You ever see surprised Kitty?
Pop!
I am not a cat.
I'm a wife and a working woman
and a mother,
and I'm not hilarious.
How did this video
even get on there?
Did you record your mother
without her knowing it?
Ew, no.
Did you leave your webcam
running?
I don't know.
Maybe.
Probably.
I guess, yeah.
Man, I told you, you got
to be careful about that.
You leave your webcam running,
people can capture video on
what they see from your computer
whether you're there or not.
I can't believe
this happened.
I'm on the Internet
in my drawers
doing the big butt dance.
Could be worse.
How?
Could have been dancing to...
♪ ice, ice, baby ♪
Dad.
♪ Ice, ice, baby ♪
pop!
Pop!
Nick!
Baby.
What's she so upset about?
I mean, it's not like
it's a sex tape.
What is wrong
with you, man?
So explain to me again
why I'm here.
We're having a little
family emergency.
Ooh, do I smell a divorce?
No, ma.
I need you to help Lindsey
finish making dinner
while I deal with Suzanne.
I thought you invited me over
here to eat dinner, not make it.
If I'd have told you Suzanne
and I were having a problem,
would you have come?
No.
All right, then.
So what's wrong with her?
I mean,
other than the obvious.
It's a long story.
Well, it better be over
by 10:30.
Mama got a hot date.
Hot!
Hot, honey, I tell you.
Hot.
Ma.
What?
How do you think
you got here?
I just feel so violated.
You know, it's like I was
spied on in my own house.
What else can record me
without my knowing it?
Well, technically, anything
that can receive a signal
can transmit a signal.
So the tv, telephone,
radio, headphones.
Ugh, you're not helping.
I'm just trying
to answer your question.
Okay, Nick,
you're an I.T. guy.
This is your world.
Isn't there some way to get
the video off the Internet?
Well, unfortunately,
once something's up on the Web,
it's there for good.
But don't worry about it.
This will go away.
You're not Kim Kardashian.
This week, it's you.
Next week, it'll be
a cat in a fishbowl.
What is up
with you and cats?
Cats are funny.
Look, you can't even tell
it's you.
Really?
Really.
Why do you think I hate it
when you come to bed
looking like that?
Pop!
No, you don't understand.
I didn't put it
on the Internet.
Hello?
Who's that?
I just had
another client cancel
because they saw the video.
Mom, what are you doing
with my computer?
It's my computer
until you learn
what that thing
is capable of.
I know
what it's capable of.
That's why I don't want you
to take it.
How am I supposed to communicate
with my friends?
Talk to them.
How?
Face-to-face.
Like an old person?
You know, Suzanne,
I don't think the video's
that big a deal.
I mean, it's not like
it's a sex tape.
Though it'd be better for you
if it were,
because I guarantee nobody
would want to see that.
Aren't you supposed
to be eating?
I would if I had
some real food.
You don't like
peppered salmon?
It's mom's specialty.
Specialty, huh?
Lindsey, you need to learn
how to cook some real food,
because you are not gonna
get a man cooking like this.
I got a man
cooking like this.
Baby, believe me,
it was not your cooking.
Maybe it was your dancing.
I want a man to like me
for my mind and my personality,
not how I look
or how I cook.
I had one of those once.
It gets old fast, trust me.
Maybe that's not
what got old.
You guys gonna eat
or you gonna fight?
All I'm saying is,
I need to teach Lindsey
how to cook
some real soul food.
What's soul food?
The number two cause of death
in black men over 40.
What's the number one cause?
Stress.
Now, eat, please.
Butter, butter,
lard,
chicken.
What is wrong with this thing?
It looks disgusting.
What the heck is all this stuff
wrapped around it?
That's called the skin.
Ew!
No, you mean, "mmm."
You see, the skin is what gives
the chicken the flavor.
Is this an organic
free-range chicken?
No, it's a flavorful
hard-knock-life chicken.
If that chicken was a rapper,
it'd be Tupac.
Ooh.
What do we need vodka for?
I'll give you a hint:
It's not for the chicken.
Mom!
Kevin.
Why do you have your computer
when I took it away from you?
I thought my punishment
was over.
Nuh-uh.
I was just gonna watch
a video.
Were you gonna watch
the video,
or was the video
going to watch you?
Go put that computer
up in my bedroom,
and I don't want to see it
back in your hands
until I put it there.
Yes, ma'am.
Hi, Mrs. Kingston-Persons.
Hi, Troy.
Hi, Jackie.
Come on in.
Suzanne, can I talk to you
for a moment?
Sure.
Suzanne, you need to be more
responsible with your child.
What are you talking about?
Well, Troy was recording
his Web chat
with Kevin the other day,
and the next thing he knows,
you're in the room
dancing around
like Tila Tequila.
I was shocked.
Wait a minute.
Troy did this?
And you're upset with me
because he recorded me
in the privacy
of my own home?
He wouldn't have had
anything to record
if you were
a little more responsible.
I used to think
the Internet was safe,
but now...
If you're so responsible,
Jackie,
than why is your son
posting videos of people
all over the Internet?
For your information,
he's not posting videos
of people.
He posted a video of you
because the rest of the people
weren't dancing around
in their underwear.
I feel like my innocence
has been taken from me.
Are you at least going
to make him say he's sorry?
Do you have any idea
how many people might see this?
1/2 million,
but that was just yesterday.
By tomorrow, you'll probably
pass printer cat.
What is so funny?
I was just thinking
about printer cat.
Fump! Fump!
Fump!
Okay, if it makes you feel
any better,
Troy, just say you're sorry.
Sorry, Mrs. Kingston-Persons.
I hope you're satisfied.
You need to be more responsible
with your child.
Ooh, if that lady pointed her
finger at me one more time...
Goodness gracious.
I'm telling you, man,
Suzanne's video is huge.
She's, like,
the featured video of the day
on 15 different websites.
You're wife might be
the next Star Wars Kid.
My wife is not gonna be
Turn it off.
Turn what off?
Nothing.
Just some stupid cat videos.
Oh, well, you guys must be
the only ones watching that,
because everyone else
seems to be watching me.
Did you know that video of me
has over 1/2 million hits?
That was yesterday.
Today it's more like
3 1/2 million.
What?
Oh, yeah.
You better hope that none of
those kids watching this video
is good with Photoshop.
Ow.
Nick, you're my man,
and you said
that this was gonna go away.
So I don't know
how you're gonna do it,
but you have got to get
that video off the Web.
What am I supposed to do?
I can't just shut down
the Internet.
Have you tried?
Listen, man,
you do what you need to do,
but if you shut down
the Internet,
you and me
are gonna have a problem.
Ah!
Suzanne,
why aren't you dressed?
We got to get going.
I can't think of work
at a time like this.
Because it's time
to go to work.
Well, I'm not going to work.
I'm too embarrassed.
Oh, gosh.
Are you still worried
about the stupid video?
Gigi, that stupid video
has over 5 million hits,
and obviously somebody at work
recognized me,
because my inbox
is filled of videos
of me dancing
to Baby Got Back.
I even got an email
from Sir Mix-a-Lot.
Well, it could be worse.
How?
You could be dancing
to Everybody Dance Now,
and lord knows you don't want
an email from Freedom Williams.
Why do I keep falling
for that?
Well, you know what?
You don't have anything
to be embarrassed about.
Look at all these cool comments.
People think it's great,
think it's fun.
Ha!
You're making 'em laugh.
Gigi, it's not funny.
How would you feel
if this were a video of you?
If this were a video of me,
I wouldn't be dancing,
and there would be a whole
different set of comments.
Okay.
I have Suzanne's video up.
Okay, click play
and tell me what happens.
Oh, wait a second.
I got, like,
a billion pop-ups here.
Well, as a matter of fact,
I would like to meet singles
in my area.
Thank you for asking.
Okay, now the screen
just froze.
Good.
It works.
You wanted this to happen?
I can't shut down
the Internet,
but I can shut down
the people.
If they try
to watch this video,
it'll be the last thing
they watch.
So you're willing to crash
20 million computers
to save one marriage?
Yes.
Yes, I am.
Okay, now put
a little salt in it.
Okay.
Oh, baby, they haven't
taught you anything, have they?
Excuse me.
This is how you put
a little salt in it.
Stir it up.
Okay.
Mmm, that smells good.
What are we having?
Well, Lindsey is making
southern fried chicken,
macaroni and cheese,
and collard greens.
And Marilyn's teaching me
how to make pot liquor.
Pot liquor.
I hope she's also teaching you
how to make a cure
for type 2 diabetes.
Ha!
Type 2 diabetes.
I worry about that kid.
For your information,
I also taught Lindsey
how to make
my sweet potato pound cake.
Of course,
you won't want any,
because you're afraid
you might get type 2 diabetes.
Pfft!
Type 2.
You're funny.
Don't look at me.
I don't know
what's wrong with him.
You made
sweet potato pound cake?
Yup,
with buttercream frosting.
Oh, my goodness.
See?
I told you men can't resist
soul food.
You were right.
This pound cake gonna make
my blood pressure go up.
Well, have one of these.
It'll send it
right back down.
Ha!
Blood pressure!
Great.
Now my computer is frozen.
Well, try hitting
the escape button.
I tried that.
It didn't work.
It's still frozen.
Why do they even have
an escape button
if it doesn't
help you escape?
It feels more like a trap.
Well, press the command key
and start hitting
all the other keys.
What does that do?
I don't know,
but we're about to find out.
Suzanne.
I've solved your problem.
Thank you, honey,
but now I have
a new problem.
I clicked on my video,
and my computer is frozen.
That's not the problem.
That's the solution.
Just restart your computer,
and everything will be fine.
I don't understand.
I'm your man.
You're responsible
for this.
Yes, I am.
I figured I couldn't stop
the video from circulating,
so I attached a virus
to the keywords
associated to the video.
Now people will stay away
from your video like the plague.
I have my own virus.
Yes, you do.
Oh, my God.
That is so romantic.
I want a virus.
Give it time.
Nick.
Come on.
She'll get one.
Dad gave you a virus.
That's awesome.
Yes, it is awesome,
but what wasn't awesome was you
leaving your webcam running
so Troy could record me.
I know.
I'm sorry.
It's okay.
Apology accepted.
Here's your computer back.
Thanks.
Mm-hmm.
Mom, have you seen
the lotion?
Produce some ashy elbows,
and then maybe you can have
the lotion back.
Sweetheart,
this is delicious.
You did a fantastic job.
Thank you.
I'm gonna have use
my bullworker for five hours
to burn off
all these calories.
Pass the gravy.
I love gravy.
I love gravy too.
Gravy goes with everything:
Chicken, biscuits,
mashed potatoes.
Gravy even tastes good
with gravy.
This gravy's so good,
you don't need the food.
I gained three pounds
just smelling it.
I'm gonna have to dance
like you in that video
to burn it off.
You know,
now that I think about it,
the video was kind of funny.
Plus, it all worked out
in my favor.
It was so popular, I actually
gained clients from it.
Wow.
See, that's great.
Everything worked out
for the best.
Ooh, I haven't ate like this
in years.
You used to eat like this?
Sure, every day
when I played football.
You didn't get to be
300 pounds
by eating flavorless, skinless,
stress-free chicken.
You know, as much as I hate
to admit it,
this is just like
a Sunday dinner.
Mmm. Mmm.
Wow.
That's really good.
Mm-hmm.
Oh, my goodness.
♪ Shake it, shake it,
shake it, shake it ♪
♪ shake that healthy butt ♪
♪ baby got back ♪
♪ L.A. face
with a Oakland Booty ♪
♪ ♪
♪ baby got back ♪
and in technology news,
reports are spreading
of a crippling new computer bug
experts have dubbed
"the dancing housewife virus."
Apparently, when you click
on this viral video
of a woman dancing
to Sir Mix-a-Lot's hit
Baby Got Back,
it freezes your computer,
sends you
countless pop-up ads,
and, in some extreme cases,
wipes out
your entire hard drive.
Ew.
What time is it?
It's Thursday.
Oh, I forgot to warn
you guys.
It's one of the side effects
of eating soul food.
It's been known
to put you to sleep.
For a day and a half?
Ooh, my ears keep ringing.
That's not your ears.
That's the doorbell.
Oh.
Coming.
Ooh.
Ow, my leg.
Hi, Mrs. Kingston-Persons.
Hi, Mr. Kingston-Persons.
Hi, Troy.
You guys have cake?
In the kitchen.
What can we do for you,
Jackie?
The dancing housewife virus
crashed my computer.
I need you to fix it.
What does that have to do
with me?
Well, if your wife hadn't been
prancing around on the Internet,
none of this
would have happened.
If you knew
there was a virus, Jackie,
why would you click
on the video?
I was trying to figure out
how you did it.
Is she still doing it, Nick?
Yeah.
Mm-hmm.
Maybe you could show me.
Want some cake?
We got some, uh,
sweet potato pound cake.
Let me fix it.
-- sync, corrected by elderman --
-- for www.addic7ed.Com --