I'll try anything once, me,
except bestiality.
And maybe Morris dancing.
Yeah, I'll try
and give them aswerve.
Now round here where I live,
everyone's heard of Jason Locke.
He'd just done a five stretch for armed
robbery. Been outless than 24 hours.
Mr. D. had asked me
to drive him about for a few days,
so I said, "Yeah, sure."
We pick up this van, and Jason says...
he wants to look up an old friend
who he knew from before.
You squealin' git!
You fucker!
You want some, huh?
Yeah, you cunt!
Please, no more!
Fucking grass!
Come here!
Leave him alone!
You fucking grass!
This is what you get.
Fuckin' grass!
Get in there!
Oh, my face!
Shit.
My face is burning up!
Come on.
Let's go home.
And that was that.Job done.
Jason needed a new shirt.
The geezer needed a new face.
Next, I take him to his mate's place,
which he's been hearing
things about.
Fucking bastards.
Lisa?
I've seen his house.
He's taking the piss.
Nice, isn't it?
Oh, yeah. How'd he get
that sort of dough?
How'd he stay
out of prison?
- You want egg with this?
- No. Yeah, go on.
- Would you like anything?
- No, I'm all right. Ta.
He had a Porsche
and a Bentley, the bastard.
What, a Porsche now?
That must be new.
- What about Wayne?
- Oh, he's got a five-series BMW...
and a nice little three-bedroom house
in Billericay.
It was a fucking mansion...
great big drive, electric gates,
fucking statues of lions
on the gate posts.
- You could have told me.
- What, spoil the surprise?
Anyway, so look, I'm thinking,
"It's been a really interesting morning.
Thanks very much.
If it's all the same to you..."
- And then he says,
- Gonna need you some more, Billy.
- All right? Later on.
- And I say...
- Yeah, sure.
- And that's it. I've got the job.
Your girlfriend won't mind,
will she, Billy?
You have got a girlfriend,
haven'tyou?
Yeah, I got a girlfriend.
She won't mind.
Liar.
One-nine. Yes, that's right.
Mrs. Knight for Brentwood.
Yeah, one-nine. Yeah, on my way.
- The geezer grassed him up.
What else could he do?
- Oh, yeah?
I ain't sayin' he should have gone
that far, but you know how it is.
Oh, he just sounds
like an animal to me.
They should put him back inside,
do us all a favor.
He's just done a five-year stretch
'cause of this mug.
- I'd have done exactly the same thing.
- That's you, is it, Billy?
You could do that
to someone?
In principle.
Billy, don't get involved
with this bloke.
See him, Peter, oh, he's the top boy.
He runs the show.
Him, Wayne, does whatever
Peter tells him.
And Jason... Well, every firm needs
a mad acidbath murderer, don't they?
What do you think
of my hair, Billy?
- You look like a fuckin' poof.
- Fuck off!
What?
Fuck of, will ya?
It's all right, isn't it?
It looks really,
really fucking stupid.
Can't you go any faster, Billy?
I'm racing in the back here.
I thought you were supposed
to be Billy fuckin' Whizz.
It's all come from the doors.
You run the doors, and you
control what get inside.
Clubs don't give a shit.
Just don't want any aggro.
Most weeks now, we're...
turning over 20 grand.
- Yeah?
- Mm.
Fucking hell.
We, uh, do a bit of weed
in the week maybe,
but pills is where
the money's really at.
I keep away from them
when they're on them.
Fucking eyes all go wonky, don't they?
He's done 'em, soppy nuts.
I won't touch 'em meself.
They're not for you, Jase.
They make you wanna love everyone.
I love you!
Pull in here, Billy Whizz.
What's happened to the Honeycomb?
Half a million on a refit,
and it's now called Blondz.
- Packed every night of the week.
- Is it still ours?
No. They gave it
to that prick, Perry Elley.
Perry fucking Elley?
Yeah. It's him and us now, Jase.
That fucking wanker.
He was knocking out
dodgy Sierras.
Yeah, well, he's moved in
on the doors now, like us,
'cause that's
where the money is.
Every door he gets is one
we could be making money from.
You know what I'm saying, Jase?
Billy.
I want you to pull up outside
in exactly five minutes, yeah?
- Sure.
- Don't fuck about.
You make sure
you're right outside.
You all right, Nic?
All right, listen, darling,
I don't think I'm gonna be
back till about midnight.
Yeah. No, it's nothing
like that.
No, I'm just waiting
for 'em outside Blondz in Southend.
You know, the one
with the glass.
Nic, I gotta go.
Bloody hell, they've
thrown him from the bloody window.
Leave him!
Fuckin' leave him!
Go forward!
Go forward and run the bastard over!
We ain't got time to fuck up about.
Careful, Billy Whizz.
Fucking amateur!
Shit!
Oh, God!
Get down.
You are fucking Billy Whizz.
Yeah. Let's move.
Well done, Billy Whizz.
You did all right.
Yeah, nice one, Billy.
What do you think
of the barnet, Billy?
- It's all right, isn't it?
- Yeah, it looks all right.
See, I told you.
And this boy knows
what he's talking about.
Mm, pair of fucking poofs.
Nicole. Nicole.
Oi, look. Ta-da.
Ta-da!
You said you was going to be back
at 12:00, Billy.
I know. I'm sorry.
I've had a right result, though.
Look at that, 500 quid.
That's for one night's work.
- Where are you going?
- I needa wee.
So, what happened?
Well, it just seemed to go on,
and I couldn't get away.
If I'd known you was going
to be out all night, I wouldn't
have bothered coming around.
- I'm sorry.
- I've got to pick up Candice
in a couple of hours.
Yeah, but that's 500 quid.
It's not bad, is it?
That's just for driving them
about. And I tell you what,
they're well pleased with me.
All of a sudden,
I have just become Billy Whizz.
It's like Billy Whizz this
and Billy Whizz that.
- Better than cabbing, isn't it?
- o you mind?
Sorry.
They'll want me again tomorrow.
Thank you very much.
Come on, get into bed.
Warm me up.
Make yourself useful.
The following night, I'm out with them again.
Pete Chaseruns the security
at Dantes,
which means I don't have to queue up
with all the other mugs,
which is nice.
Billy Whizz, come on, son.
You're with the A-team now.
Who's he, Billy?
Oh, my God, that's Jason Locke,
isn't it?
He's just come out.
did she?
It's a simple question,
and I want an answer.
Why'd you have to ask me?
It's insulting.
No is the answer.
Absolutely not. No.
did you see her
spending time with anyone?
Come on, Jase.
I just told you.
That I know of,
she didn't mess around.
What do you mean,
"that you know of"?
Hey, Billy Whizz,
come over here.
Stay there.
How you doing, Billy?
- Not too bad, Mr. Chase.
- Call me, Peter.
- All right?
- Are you Jason?
Yeah.
What you gonna do when you've finished
with Jason, go back to cabbing?
Er, yeah. I mean, I thought
I might do the knowledge.
- You know what I mean, do it properly.
- That's a hard game, that.
All them fuckin' tests. Sloggin'
about onmopeds. Goodluck to you, boy.
Well, you've gotta
do something, ain't ya?
I don't like to see anybody
work when they don't have to.
And you're
a bright bloke, Billy.
We've been very impressed
with you. Very impressed.
We'd like to make you
an offer.
How about when you finish driving Jason
around, you don't go back to cabbing?
How about you stay
driving for us?
- What, you mean...
- I mean, you work full-time for us.
What's the matter, Billy?
You saw a few things last night,
Billy, but, er, well...
in my book...
makes you one of the boys.
Yeah, but you know I'd never
say nothing about last night, don't ya?
Oh, yeah. I know that, Billy.
I know I can trust you.
It was either that, Billy,
or we stick a knife in ya.
Bing.
did you speak to Peter
about the business?
Pete's me mate.
Yeah.
You tell him you want to
be his partner, not his mate.
He'll sort me out,
all right.
Look. I know how they work.
I've been watching them.
There's too many people
in the chain.
What fucking chain?
What are you on about?
Jason!
Anyway...
he's given me
some spending money.
It's in me pocket.
It's five grand.
A thousand a year...
that's all you're worth to him.
That's just for starters.
Anyway, what was I supposed to do,
grass them up like Chippy?
Oh, no, he knewy ou wouldn't
do that. You were a sure thing.
Yeah?And what about you?
You're asure thing.
Yeah, I'm a sure thing.
Yeah? Well, you waited
for me, did ya?
All that time for five years,
did ya?
didn't let anyone inside your knickers
while I was away?
What's brought this on?
Wh-Why didn't you
just say no?
Why did you have to fuck about
being clever?
Why didn't you just say no?
Because I was at it
all the time.
I had so much cock I started
a cock factory... big, fat, small, short.
- Anyone bought me a drink,
I fucked them in our bed.
- Shut up!
- Just for the price ofa drink!
Shut up! Shut your fucking mouth!
Shut up!
Fucking shut up!
Why do you have to ask me?
Because I'm a jealous fucking bastard,
and I don't trust you.
I'm sorry.
If I was gonna mess about,
I'd have done it a long time ago.
Yeah, I know.
Jason.
I waited for you
because I believe in you.
I don't ever want handouts
from them again. We can't
go back to how it was before.
You get in that bedroom.
I get a call from Mr. D.
I mean, strictly speaking,
I'm still working for him.
He's asked me to pick up Henry
and drive him to this place.
I've never been there before,
some farm.
I just thought probably not a good idea
to tell Jason and the others...
about where I was going
that night.
Old Henry Hobbs never said much.
And when he did, hes till never said much.
Switch.
The pilotis Mr. D.
Wow.
Dropped it down sweet as you like,
just like he said he could.
This is fucking fantastic.
- Can touch down and be in the air
again in less than 30 seconds.
- Right.
The other chap is Peter Chase's
big rival on the club scene,
the infamous Perry Elley.
You just keep yourself wrapped in cotton
wool for awhile and we're home and dry.
Mr. D. and Perry had been hatching
this one for months.
This was the final
dress rehearsal.
Boys, this is gonna work.
So, John Dyke... Mr. D...
he was the one
who got me into this.
I was doing me cabbing,
and I picked him up one day.
We had a little chat and got talking,
and he asked for me again.
I used to deliver things for him,
packages, and drive a few people about.
But I didn't ask any questions.
I think he liked that.
What do you make of Jason?
I wouldn't like to get on the wrong
side of him. He's an 18-carat nutter.
- He's kept you busy.
- Yeah.
Actually, um, him and his pals
have asked me to do a bit
of driving about for 'em.
Well, full-time.
How do you feel about that?
I don't know.
Thought, "Why not?"
I mean, they're all right.
They look after me.
I wouldn't mind seeing
where it'd take me.
I can still do a bit of driving for you.
That's no ta problem, is it?
Well, good luck to you, Billy.
do you think
it's a bad idea?
It's not for me to say.
Now it's starting to get complicated.
Straightaway, Peter Chase asked me
to do a little job for him.
I drive 'em to this burger bar,
and they tell me to wait.
Police, stop!
Armed police!
Sit.
I just lost
200 fucking grand.
How'd it go?
A total disaster.
Couriers got arrested.
We lost thegear.
Pete lost his money.
Couldn't have gone
much better really, could it?
- Oh! Oh, God!
- Eh?
- Are you gonna see him then, babe?
- Yeah.
Oh!
Now he owes you, you know that.
Now's the time to call in the debt.
Yeah, I know.
What was her name again,
that blond one at the club?
- Suzy.
- Yeah.
She had a beautiful
little arse.
You get her number
for me, yeah?
Either her arse or your arse,
Billy Whizz.
Welcome back, Jason.
You didn't tell me
you were rich, John.
I'm not rich.
Everybody's suddenly rich
while I'm inside.
It's a nice place, John.
Could easily get a swimming pool
in this garden. Yeah.
Nice pool with a cover on it.
Gym upstairs.
I could handle that.
I leave the garden to Henry.
That's his domain.
- Cheers.
- Cheers, John.
I'm very grateful for what
you did for me inside, Jason.
That's all right.
I was wondering whether
I could repay the favor.
Is there anything
I can do for you?
Well, if you're asking,
John, maybe there is.
I've got some friends who need
some gear brought into the country.
- Gear?
- Naughty gear, John.
All right, Henry?
How's it going?
Been having a lot of trouble
with drainage.
Clay soil round here.
Water lies on the surface.
Heavy rain drowns
everything off.
Yeah. Gutting when
that happens, isn't it?
All right, come on.
Come on.
The truth is I work just for
one person now, then only occasionally.
Working outside that arrangement
would be too dangerous.
And, you see, I...
I simply cannot
go to prison again... ever.
Well, you think
about it, John.
See if you can't
get your head around it.
See, the way I see it,
people with special
relationships, like us;
people who've got secrets,
like us...
Yeah? Well,
we should stick together.
Oh, yes, yes,
I agree with you, Jason.
That's why I-I'd be, uh, I'd be happy
to help you out fi nancially,
- until you get on your feet.
- Mm. No, no.
I don't want your money.
I'm looking to the future
now, John.
I wanna go into
business with you.
Welcome home, Jason.
Thanks for keeping
your mouth shut.
One or two of the boys have overdone
the sunbed tonight, but we're all here.
And we're wondering
what's next.
Come on.
Look at this!
Look, look at this!
Hello, leader.
How are you doing?
Oi! Billy Whizz, drinks.
Tell Tommy to get the scotch.
The good stuff,
the malt, all right?
Oi, you little sods. Hey, come on,
this is not a toy. Off you get!
Hey, Beverley. Beverley, would you
come and look after these sods?
Jason Locke!
Out from under lock and key at last.
Here he is! Yea!
That's the color of the moon
Secretin the rainbow
Him, with Jason...
that's his old mate,
Kiri Christos, the banker.
Well, geezers couldn't very well
go to the NatWest, could they?
So, they went to him.
You are looking
just as beautiful as ever.
- Oh!
- Beautiful!
Oh, and fiery!
Oh, yes, it's that
Peter Chase spouting off.
Oh, my God, Kiri!
Can you believe it? We're in
our thirties. I feel so ancient.
If I looked as good as you,
it wouldn't bother me much.
o you know how upsetting it is to have
hair coming out your nose and ears?
That's what they should have told us
in biology, not how to cut up...
What were they, locusts?
You always did make me laugh.
Jason says he wants to
go into business.
Yeah, well,
isn't it about time he did?
- Haven't they made enough money
off his back?
- So, he needs a banker.
- But he's got a problem.
- What's that?
- He's got no security.
- Okay. How's he get that?
Well, he needs to put up
something against the loan.
Something valuable.
Something I want.
I didn't know Jason had
anything you wanted.
Well, you haven't been paying much
attention all these years, have you?
Kiri, um,
would you just excuse me
a minute?
It was just getting interesting.
- All right?
- Who's that?
don't know. I just said
hello to her tonight.
- Are you enjoying yourself?
- I said, "Who is she?"
don't know.Just some little bird
Billy's knocking off.
Anyway, it went well
with Kiri.
don't shame me, Jason.
- Beverley, all right?
- Mm.
- So, what you been up to then, Lisa?
- Oh, you know,
getting beasted by Jason.
When they've been inside for so long,
they want to do it up the arse.
If that's what your mate's been
doing to you for five years,
it's bound to have an efect.
- Anyway, what about you girls?
- Oh, yeah.
I didn't tell you what Pete bought me
for Christmas, did I?
A horse.
I've called him Toby.
- Oh, he's mad, isn't he?
- Put him down then.
And the horse.
I'm trying to be nice to you, Lisa.
Oh, you've got a short memory, babe.
Bit too quick to forget who's been
helping you while Jason's been inside?
Two hundred and fifty quid a week?
Helping us out? do me a favor.
Well, I didn't expect for one minute
that you'd be grateful.
Okay, Beverley. I'm so fucking grateful.
Will that do?
Oo-er. You just make sure you enjoy
this party tonight, darling,
'cause it's the last thing
you're gonna get from us.
Make sure you keep your legs
pressed tight together when you
ride Toby, make you all tingly.
You do remember that feeling,
don't you?
- Who's a naughty boy then?
- What?
That little blond bit. That's why
you didn't bring your girlfriend.
Who, her? No, she's not
with me. She's just...
Well, she's with anyone,
if you know what I mean.
Where is she?
Groaning Continues]
Oh, shit.
You bastard.
You do this here
in front of everyone.
You bastard! Bastard!
- Fucking bastard!
- Shut up!
- You bastard! Get off me!
- Shut your fucking mouth!
Just fucking cool off!
Go on, fucking cool off!
You think you own me?
"do this, Jason. do that, Jason."
Well, fuck you!
I waited for you for five years!
Yeah, you waited for me, did you?
You think I'm fucking stupid?
- I didn't do anything!
- I don't believe you.
I didn't do anything!
Fuck off! You're like
a fucking leech!
What the fuck
do I need you for, eh?
I mean, why do you think
I go with other women, eh?
Because you're
a fucking nuisance!
You're not even a good fuck!
I don't even fancy you anymore.
That's a lie!
Get her out of here.
You all right?
That bastard's done this
to me before.
He got the last one pregnant.
Another little blond bit.
He had a little boy with her.
You see...
I can't have kids, Billy.
That was a fucking laugh,
weren't it, for everyone else?
Everyone looking at me, knowing.
The joke is...
I actually waited for him.
I used to sit
behind him in class.
did you know that?
I thought he was God's gift.
All the girls fancied him.
But I got him.
I thought I was
such a lucky girl.
Mm.
Lisa. Lisa!
Wait, hold on. I don't think
we should, all right.
It's not that
I don't want to.
Thanks, Billy.
Thanks for not taking advantage of me
when I'm like this.
Most of the other guys
would have jumped on me.
You're different.
Thanks.
Um, it's just, um, you know...
Billy. Billy, I'm taking
the piss out of you.
Look at you.
You're no good to me.
You're just a fucking pussy
like all the rest of them.
Bring my bag.
Tell Billy the groceries
are ready.
I want this over
as quickly as possible.
- All right? It's all in there.
- Yeah.
You fucking beauty.
There you go.
Thanks.
See you later.
Have fun.
Spotty dogs.
Seen them, Billy?
No.
Here you are.
Try one.
Cheers, Wayne.
Now, Jason is very anti-drugs.
Thatis anti anyone else's drugs.
It's an odanda wink and in goes
his man with a bag of Spotty Dogs.
Thank you very much.
See you later.
- Oi!
- All right?
- How's it going?
- Sweet.
This is a piece of piss.
What are we looking at
when we knock this lot out?
I don't know,
200, maybe 250 profit.
Quarter of a million?
Fuckin' hell!
You've done well, Jase. You've come
through for us, just when we needed it.
You know what this is?
It's a contract...
to provide security for
Blondz nightclub in Southend.
Sorted it out with the owners.
Got fed up with the other lot.
Too much aggravation.
People flying through windows.
Perry Elley's out, we're in.
Partners?
Partners.
I fuckin' love it here.
don'tyou?
I tell you, I'm never going back
inside again, I tell you that.
Where do you live, Billy?
I'm in Canvey Island.
Yeah?
There she is!Hey!
Bring the motor. Hey!
Hey.
Jason, I didn't mean to cause
any trouble the other night.
- I'm really sorry.
- That's all right.
Get in the motor.
Let's have a laugh.
- I didn't know you were married.
- I'm divorced.
do you wanna marry me?
do you wanna get married?
Billy. Billy,
you can be the witness.
- I don't wanna cause any trouble.
- Well, I do. Come on.
drive, Billy Whizz.
Give me a couple of them Spotty dogs,
will you, Billy?
Okay. Let's see
what this shit's like.
No, Jason, please.
Please, will you just take me home?
No chance.
That's it.
You and me, Billy Whizz.
We'll run
that fuckin' gaff, eh?
Nice one.
You got some booze,
Billy Whizz?
There's loads up there, Jase.
Which way's the bedroom?
This one?
Jason, can't we just
have a drink first?
- Come on.
- Ow!
Bring some in later.
Billy! Billy!
Get him off me!
don't be silly.
Jason, please, why don't
we go out another night?
Why don't we go out tomorrow?
don't play hard-to-get, babe.
don't like that game.
But I don't want to.
I just wanna go home.
Billy! Billy, help me!
Help me!
Jason, stop!
Get off me!
Get off me! Billy!
Please, Billy!
Get off me!
I don't want to!
No!
Get of me!
You're hurting...
No!
Why didn't you
just say no, eh?
Why'd you have to fuck
about being clever?
Why didn't you just say no?
Fucking about being clever.
Suzy, wake up.
Suzy, wake up, babe.
Fuck.
Come on, open up. We're freezing.
Just wait a sec!
It's cold, isn't it?
Hiya. What's happened?
Look at the state of ya.
- You can't come in. I'm sorry.
- Why not?
You just can't.
Why not, Billy?
-You got some one in there, haven'tyou?
-No.
Yes, you have.
Who is it?
Come on, Candy.
- Sorry, Candy.
- Don't talk toher!
Just go back inside
and leave us alone, all right?
This is a fucking nightmare.
Twenty kids in hospital,
throwing up, hallucinating.
I've never seen Spotty dogs before.
Must have been a bad batch.
Bad? It's disastrous!
-It makes us look like fuckin' amateurs.
-What about her?
I don't know.
Think of something.
You're the fucking driver.
Fucking drive her!
Somewhere! Anywhere!
I don't care!
Just get rid of it!
I don't wanna hear about it again!
Hurry up, Billy.
It'll be light soon.
It's moments like this
that either make you...
or break you.
Come on.
Either you learn
to live with it...
or you crack up.
Now which one
is it going to be?
Henry!
Henry.
All right, John?
do you think
I'd try and stiff you?
Do you think I'm mad?
It was a bad batch.
There was nothing I could do.
You know,
when I was inside,
I heard this screaming one day.
So I went to have a look,
and I found yke here...
bent over the table with his trousers
round his ankles,
four big, hairy paddies holding
him down, about to bugger him.
Old Henry, he's off playing bingo.
Ain't that right, Henry?
Please. Please, Jason,
don't do...
don't do anything stupid.
That was the first time
I met you, wasn't it?
Well, in a little while,
you're gonna be wishing I'd walk
straight past you that day...
- and just let 'em get on with it.
- I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, Jason.
I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
You've got 48 hours
to get me my money back...
and the profit we lost.
You fucking worm!
What you gonna do about Lisa?
Fuck all!
- Hey, Billy Whizz, have you seen her?
- No.
Where'd you take her then?
You drove her away.
I brought her back here
and I went home.
Leave her. She'll come back
with her tail between her legs,
-likes he always does.
- What about that other business?
- You sort that out as well?
- Yeah.
- Where did you dump it?
- I sorted it out.
That's all you need to know.
- You ought to watch your fucking mouth.
- Leave him.
- No! Fucking kid!
- Leave him, leave him. Come on.
Billy, which one
do you want, eh?
Huh? You can have
first choice,
as long as it's not
the blond one.
Um, I'll pass, thanks.
Is it all right
if I see you lot later?
Which one, Billy?
Where you going?
I'm going home. I'm tired.
- You're not leaving.
- Look, I've had enough. I want out.
You don't want out on me,
you skinny, little prick!
Now I said,
which one do you want, eh?
This one? Eh?
do you want this one,
or do you want this one, eh?
No? Well, why not
do 'em both, eh?
Now get in there and don't fucking
come out till you've done 'em!
You know, I went to that place...
what's it called?
Lakeside last week.
I spent the whole afternoon
in a tea shop just watching.
Something about the women
in that part of the world that
I find absolutely irresistible.
Thought you were only
interested in Henry.
No, they're fiercely pretty,
yet hard as nails,
and it's a perfect combination.
What I wouldn't give to have
my youth again in Essex.
All I remember of my youth is getting
freezing cold under Southend Pier...
with me knickers around me ankles.
Well, I'll take you
under that pier again.
You can haveyour knickers
around your ankles again.
You know, I'm gonna
have to go back to him,
don'tyou?
You know, I'm just about
to do something... really big.
After that, I'll be able
to pay them of,
and I'll still be
a very rich man.
We could go somewhere
where he'd never find us.
It's just a little investment. Spreading
out the old tentacles, youknow.
Had bit of spare cash
laying about,
and I fucking hate
waiting for cabs, so why not?
- Perry.
- Oh, thanks, darling.
-did you, uh, watch 'em make it?
- Yeah. Smoked salmon?
Yeah, great.
You know they gob in these things
in those places.
So, what happened
to your face?
Oh, I, I, uh...
I had some, um...
- I had some problems the other night.
- Uh-huh.
- So speak to me.
- Well, I just wanted
to talk about the drop,
make sure everything's
going to plan.
Oh, yeah. Everything's
still going to plan, John,
except for one small detail.
You're no longer
part of that plan.
What's the matter?
You think I don't know about things?
Perry, I need this job.
We've been friends for a long time.
Are you taking me
for a cunt, John?
Perry, that was a one-off.
John, are you
taking me for a cunt?
- It's a very simple little question.
- No. No, of course not.
Well, listen. Take my advice
and fuck off right now...
before I lose my temper,
all right?
Perry, you...
you can't just cut me out.
Can't? Can't?
You just watch me.
The minute that you do business
with those fuckers, you become dirty.
I can no longer trust you.
So now... you're gone.
Fuck off.
Nothing personal, John.
I haven't got your money.
But I've got something better,
a new proposition.
Something that will be
worth much more.
-It'll make you a million each. Minimum.
-Come on, Jason.
Let's listen to what he's gotta say.
Perry Elley is flying in
a consignment of coke.
- A big one.
- Mm-hmm.
I know when and where
the drop is going to be made.
I can put you in the right place
at the right time to hit the courier.
We divide the consignment
into four,
and that's a million a piece.
And we get to whack
Perry Elley.
It's perfect.
There are two stipulations.
Stipulations?
Like what?
First, this wipes the slate clean.
And?
And we never cross
each other's paths again.
Why not? Who wants
to see you again anyway?
So, now they're all in it together.
A nice little
jolly boys outing.
Well, we're gonna need
a four-wheel drive, ain't we?
The plane will come in
over the top of those trees,
and the pilot will probably set it down
in that stretch of field over there.
They have runway lights
that flick on at the last moment.
Oh, yeah? Well, what if it's
raining then, like tonight?
Shouldn't make any difference.
Well, we can hole up over there
for a couple of hours
before they make the drop.
Yeah. Get here nice and early.
And then boom, boom,
fucking boom.
Take out
the reception committee...
and the courier.
We'll need automatic weapons
and night sights.
Yeah, we can do this.
- When then?
- Oh.
Soon.
Look, I've, uh... I got the keys
to the, uh, to the gate here.
You won't want me around,
will you?
It's not my scene, really.
What's the matter,
ykey? Squeamish?
This is a field.
This is where worms belong.
I wouldn't let you miss this,
not for the world.
That goes for you too,
Billy Whizz.
Who wants to be a millionaire
We do
There's no way we're gonna chuck
it all away, not what we've got.
- Good.
- Yeah. I mean, we're really great together.
Get us another bottle, will you, babe?
Come here.
You know, we've
discovered the secret...
to a happy relationship,
haven't we, Lisa?
I do what I want,
and she does what I tell her.
That's what works for us.
And a back hander every now and then.
Only it's important to have a secret
when they get to this age, you know.
Once they get past 30,
they start getting saggy, you know?
imples in their arses,
eh, Lisa?
And their tits
start to hang down.
And they still wear frilly underwear,
but it don'tlook very nice, no.
But I tell you, they're still handy
for carrying and fetching.
Now go on, get some glasses.
Billy Whizz, give her a hand.
He's a fucking arsehole.
Forget it.
I can handle him.
When this all comes off, perhaps
you should bury the hatchet with yke.
- He could be useful.
- Oh, I'll bury it in his fucking head.
Look, I've made up me mind.
We hit yke
and have his share between us.
About the other night,
I'm really sorry for what I said.
I was hurt, and when
I'm hurt, I lash out.
You just happened
to be in the way.
- Are we still friends?
- Yeah, no problem.
What about Billy Whizz?
Can we trust him?
No. Better do him and all.
Evening, Billy.
How many of them
will there be?
About three or four,
I should think.
They'll all have to
be taken out.
Fucking hell.
Wish me luck.
All right, Billy Whizz!
You wanker!
Heckler & Koch MP5.
Fires a standard
9mm Parabellum round.
Thirty rounds a magazine, eight hundred
rounds a minute on full auto.
Fucking quality.
We couldn't get
the night sights,
so we're just gonna have
to get in close, eh?
Shall we go?
What's up, Mr. Worm?
Who wants to be a millionaire
We do, we do
- Who do?
- We do!
Yeah!
I'll get the gate, shall I?
Boom.
Hello.
Where are you?
You sound funny.
Yeah? Yeah,
get a couple of bottles.
Shut up, Billy!
There's no need
for this, John.
You can keep it all.
Oh, Jason,
you foolish, greedy boy.
There are no drugs.
There is noplane.
You want to mess with me?
You're not in the same league.
I thought we were mates.
I looked after you in prison.
I'm a man of honor, Jason.
I always pay my debts.
Please.
This is silly.
Billy, you said you wanted to know
how far this was going to take you.
- No! don't!
- Hold it, John.
- Leave him, Henry.
- He's a witness.
I'm not having this little bastard
hanging over me.
No, no, no.
Leave him alone, Henry.
That's enough for tonight.
Who wants to be a millionaire
They don't
Hello, Billy.
Yeah, come in.
You can listen to this.
Obviously,
if you don't mind, Lisa.
I had no idea where
Jason was going that night.
Yeah, but... That's weird though, isn't
it? It's not very romantic, is it?
He'd been out of prison for,
what, two weeks?
I mean, he's hanging out with
all sorts of strange people,
leaving you here home alone.
Don't know who he's with,
where he is.
My husband fucked around.
Is that what you want to hear?
- You ever heard of Suzy Welch?
- Who?
Suzy Welch. Young girl.
Very pretty.
on't know whether your husband
associated with her in the last
couple of weeks, do you?
It's possible.
If she had a cute arse,
it's certainly possible.
Hmm. She disappeared.
And you think Jason's death
may have something to do with it?
Some one killed him
because of her?
Thanks. Makes me feel really great.
Oh. I've upset you now, ain't I?
I didn't mean to do that.
All right.
I'll leavey ou here.
Leave you two in your grief.
Billy.
Used to drive for Jason,
didn't you?
Yeah, now and again,
but not that night, obviously.
Obviously.
I'll be in touch.
You didn't think I'd go through
with it, did you? Admit it.
No.
I did it for you.
Where have you been?
I've been waiting for two hours.
I've had the police around.
- I'm sorry.
- It worries me how much they know.
Oh, what can they know?
They know nothing.
The only people who can
tell them anything... can't speak.
Billy can. They know
he drove for Jason.
No. Billy's all right.
on't worry about Billy.
You sure you can trust him?
No. He's too scared
to say anything.
So, how are you?
Is the burden of knowledge
weighing you down?
No. I'm fine.
It's like I told you, Billy.
It's moments like this
that will make you...
or break you.
Have the police been to see you?
Yeah. There was a smart arse
Old Bill around Lisa's.
- What did he ask you?
- Nothing.
- He just give me his card
and said he'd get in touch.
- Good.
We must expect this, Billy.
It's perfectly normal.
They'll be questioning
all his associates.
I'm sure they'll be
talking to me at some point.
The situation
is very simple, Billy.
The only people who
know what happened...
are you, me and Henry.
The other people who knew...
are, of course, dead.
Mr... you know, I...
I, like...
I wouldn't say a word
about this to anyone.
Look. All this work
for a drainage trench.
Can you believe how obsessed
Henry gets about this garden?
I'm bringing a shipment in
this week.
I wanted to make sure
I could rely on you.
Y-Yeah, ofcourse.
Nothing's changed.
Now tell me, how's Lisa?
I haven't seen her for awhile.
Uh, she's a bit upset.
I want you to, uh,
look after her a bit.
drive her around, make sure
she doesn't come to any harm.
I'm worried about her.
I'm taking over
the business, Beverley.
- I want the books.
- Go fuck yourself.
Lend me one of your vibrators,
and I will.
Which one's been your favorite
since Peter got splattered?
You bitch!
Fucking try that again,
I'll fucking do you!
What gives you the right to think you
can just come in here and take over?
'Cause who's gonna stop me?
You, Beverley?
don't make me laugh.
Look at you.
This place. This stuff.
You got your drinks trolley,
chandelier, piano.
Can you even play
the piano, Beverley?
And how'd you get all of this, eh?
Of of Jason's back.
- That's how.
- You're the one's who's
got everything on your back.
don't annoy me, Beverley. The terms
are getting worse all the time.
Now, you can keep
this house and the cars.
I'm taking over the doors.
If you have a problem with that,
you can have a chat with Kiri Christos
about the money you owe him.
What am I supposed to live on?
Yeah.
I've been thinking about that.
250 quid a week.
Remember? That's what Peter
was paying me when Jason was inside.
That's when he wasn't trying
to get inside my knickers.
Fair's fair, eh, Beverley?
Where now?
I keep turning it
over and over in my mind.
I must have been speaking to him
just before he died.
Yeah?
- Where were you, Billy?
- Me? I was at home watching the telly.
Well, I knew they were
planning something.
Why didn't they
want you to drive 'em?
don't know. They were all
very secretive about it.
- You wouldn't lie to me,
would you, Billy?
- I weren't there.
So, who do you think done it?
don't know. Perry Elley?
What about John yke? do you think he
could have had anything to do with it?
No. Mr...? No.
Why, do you?
I don't know.
There's just something about him
that's not quite right.
Lisa, there's...
- there's something I gotta tell ya.
- What?
It's been playing on my mind.
What has?
It's about Jason.
And just, like...
The way he died.
How did he die, Billy?
I just...
I just keep thinking it... it's
gonna happen to you and me.
- Hello?
- Billy, the groceries are ready.
Oh, right, yeah.
Um, I'll be there as soon as I can.
- Where are you?
- I'm at home. I'm on me way.
Where's Lisa?
I, uh, I... I... She went shopping.
I dropped her off.
Okay. Be as quick as you can.
Yeah, you fuck.
Fuck.
I had high hopes of you, Billy.
Thought you had brains.
Not like those other animals.
I was prepared to help you.
I knew you'd make mistakes.
Then you went too far.
She belongs to me, Billy.
I don't want you to touch her!
You wanted to know
where this would take you.
Billy, it ends here!
You fucker!
Lisa, it's me. They just fucking
shot me. I can't believe this shit.
- Are you okay?
- No, I fuckin' ain't okay!
They just tried to kill me! Why didn't
you tell me about you and yke?
- What the fuck's going on?
- Listen, it's a little difficult.
Little difficult?
Well, I'll tell you something, Lisa.
They fucking killed Jason.
Okay. Can you drive?
did you hear what I just said?
They killed Jason, Lisa.
- I fucking saw them.
- I can't talk right now.
- Can you drive?
- Yeah, I can drive.
- Okay. I'll meet you at number six.
- Number six? The motel?
- Yeah, that's right.
- You will be there?
Yeah, I'll be there.
don't fuck me up, Lisa.
I need you.
I'm really sorry, Perry.
Something's come up.
It's girl stuff.
Can we continue this later?
Oh, that's a shame. do you know
they make these with fresh fruit?
Tell you what.
You can have my cherry.
We can't stay here 'cause
he'll come here. He'll find us.
It's all right, it's all right.
We're safe for the time being.
- Let's get you out of this.
- It fucking hurts.
It's okay. We've gotta get you
cleaned up, get you in the bath.
Why didn't you tell me
about you and him?
There's nothing to tell.
He's got some sort of
obsession with me, that's all.
Just got out of hand.
Well, he's just tried to fucking
kill me. He nearly did and all.
- He'll kill you too.
- Let's deal with
one problem at a time, eh?
What have you done here?
Well, we got them "E's" next door.
We can sell them two bags of pills
and just get out of here.
What do you think?
I'm gonna need some antiseptic,
some tweezers and a dressing.
What's the time?
Look, I'm gonna find
a late night chemist.
I'll take your clothes
to the laundry too.
We can't have you checking out
covered in mud.
Come on, drink up.
What do you think?
I think it's a really good idea, Billy.
Just you and me together.
Well, don't be too long.
I won't.
Where are you?
don't know.
You sound funny.
Good-bye, Jason.
- Hello.
- Good-bye, Billy.
John, you don't
have to do this!
I didn't know nothing
about you and her!
I swear to God!
I wouldn't have happened if I had.
John, John, here's the gear.
Look!
I'm not gonna keep it.
You have it.
I'll go away, John,
and I'll never come back!
You'll never see me again!
John, I won't say a fucking word!
I'll disappear!
We are the police! We are armed!
Come out of the cabin
with your arms up in the air!
Come out of the cabin.
Walk forward.
Walk forward!
Get down on your knees.
Face down. Face down!
Now spread your legs.
It was... very funny.
It was hilarious.
I mean, Mr. D. 's gonna kill Lisa,
and I've become a liability.
And now she's rubbing noses
with Perry Elley.
- She needs both of us out ofher life.
- Hello, Billy Whizz.
So, the Old Bill
gets ananonymous tip,
and they catch this fella
red-handed...
in a Southend motel room
with 50 grand's worth of pills.
This fella's looking at
ten years inside, easy,
unless he can make a trade.
Turns outhe's only the witness
to a shocking triple murder.
Essex boys?
She done the lot of us.