Hey, this is Christina
Milian and this is
my crazy party story.
So me and my girls decided
we're going to
take a trip to Vegas.
All of us girls had red lipstick
on and high heels.
We started drinking
in the plane.
I was drinking Bloody Marys.
By the time we got to the hotel,
they sent us to this
VIP room where they had
champagne and we made mimosas.
We were just ready to party.
So we went out to eat some
sushi, and after that
[INAUDIBLE] took us to club.
We were all being sexy,
touchy-feelie, having fun with
each other, dancing.
We started pounding tequilas
and shots.
We had some guys that were
sitting next to us, and
they're like, Ey, what's up?
You guys want to
party with us?
And we're like, yeah!
Totally!
Let's go!
And they were like,
we're leaving!
We're going to go to
the strip club!
You guys wanna come with us?
And we're like, Yeah!
Let's go!
We hop in their car with them
and somehow we end up at this
VIP room with a bunch of Barbie
dolls with giant boobs.
The next thing you know, the
guys break out these wads of
$100 bills, and these
girls ran to
us like hungry piranhas.
So one thing led to another, of
course, more drinks, more,
more, and more drinks.
The same rules don't go for
girls that go for guys.
And the strippers had these
giant balloon boobs, like
motorboating them and-- you'd
stick your head in-between and
you go [MOTOR NOISE]
We all had a stripper on us.
We all had to go to
the bathroom,
really, really buzzed.
And I think one of us
hurled a little bit.
One of the guys is knocking
on the door.
And he's like, what are you
guys doing in there?
I was like, she's not
feeling good!
And he's trying to push
the door open.
My other girl's holding her
hair up for her and
everything.
Can't get hurl in your hair.
And I'm like, oh my gosh,
I feel like I'm sick.
I feel like I'm going
to be sick.
A friend of mine happened
to be in town.
I texted him, I'm like, dude!
I need you to come save us!
I think somebody spiked
our drinks.
We made our great escape
out of the bathroom.
We were like, we gotta go!
We have to leave!
That boy was downstairs
waiting for us
with two silver Ferraris.
And we hopped into the cars,
and we were like whoa!
You saved the day!
And that was my craziest
party story.