These are the hallmarks of a hurricane,
Also called cyclons or typhoons,
hurricanes are giant storms
prowling the world's tropical seas.
An average hurricane releases
as much energy in a day
as the explosion of half a million
small atomic bombs.
Hurricanes form in the summer and fall,
when the sun heats vast stretches
of tropical ocean to over 82 degrees.
Warm moist air rises over these
hot spots, creating thunderstorms.
Upper level winds and surface winds
then come together,
forming a circular pattern of clouds,
known as a tropical depression.
When the winds exceed thirty-nine miles
per hour, a tropical storm is developed.
When the winds reach 74 miles per hour,
a hurricane is officially born.
Inside the storm bands of rain
up to three hundred miles long
meet in the eye wall,
the most violent section.
Here winds of up to two hundred
miles per hour spiral upward.
Within the centre of the hurricane,
down droughts of dry air
create a strangely calm area
called 'the eye'.
Fully formed, a hurricane may stretch
over five hundred miles in diameter
(that's a storm nearly the size of Texas)
and reach a height of nine miles,
Most of these storms being
out over the open sea,
but in an average year, two or three
will strike the mainland of North America.
And when they do the damage
can be catastrophic.
Most dangerous is the storm surge,
a wall of water that
sweeps across the coastline
where the hurricane makes landfall.
About forty-five thousand people were
killed by hurricanes in the 20th century,
including some fifteen thousand
in the U.S.
Hurricanes are also costly in dollars.
1992's hurricane Andrew was the most
expensive natural disaster in U.S. history,
causing more than twenty-five billion
dollars worth of damage.
Scientists are searching for better ways
to predict the path of a hurricane.
Special planes called hurricane hunters
fly directly into these monster storms
and drop sensors to measure
wind speed, temperature and air pressure,
providing vital clues to the
hurricane's direction.
New 3D models are also helping
scientists understand
this awesome force of Nature
and provide quicker and
more accurate warnings
to anyone unlucky enough
to be caught in its path.