he apparently war uh... gloves at all
times to school
for terry stuffed animals with them
and today you are at a different
buildings stabbing people and that's
what c_n_n_ center
now you see that
does not kill people people kill people
that night is the old kilby paul
period
knives don't kill people
all them survive
now every guy was carrying on an assault
weapon
number of those
people students wounded on that campus
would be dead
and he would have had a lot more people
god knows how many people a curriculum
so yes sometimes guns do kill people
it's only hope you to kill more and more
people so as people
the gun rights out of this this is
c_n_n_ again that's that
the reality is that matt seven as tragic
as it is
it for less than rich
than any gun would have done
now we move to the damage the guns do do
fun times are in new jersey and
four-year-old of
was biosensor although we don't know if
they got into an argument or not
we do know
but their kids one of you know
but there was an argument
who knows maybe the other one was good
job you're just playing the stratus kids
do
well well before your old one into his
house
grab a twenty two caliber rifle
shot the six year old man having killed
i don't guns don't kill people
four-year-olds to it
so to speak in which turns out
uh... there is a
transcendent tennessee he's uh...
name is ed indiana frank in the heat
show is go so frightened of aren't you
and he's laid out as guns in their
pallet load four your old is that the
walks in
pics of the gun
troops a winnings
and jokes
does the panic
at the age of forty
that bit of four-year-olds and either
case in tennessee or new jersey mean it
i would be shocked if they meant it when
they know
you don't kids play play those games all
the time
leslie don't have loaded guns there that
and everybody thinks
they're not going to make a mistake
you know that all they're not gonna have
a loaded gun around the kid
their kids live in the allure of the
twenty two caliber rifle
accept these mistakes happen
every single day
guns don't kill people
they make it a lot of these
snot than a four year olds are malicious
i want to tell these people
i'm sure they are upset about it they're
destroyed about it
pose those killed those people
any lower weapon
as we saw on the mast adding
one of the other
usually on average
but guns do do it
buns to kill people