COMMUNITY REACTS TO THE LATEST INFORMATION
ON THE BOSTON BOMBING SUSPECT, AND WE'VE GOT
DETAILS ON HOW ONE SAN DIEGO STATE PROFESSOR
AND HIS GRAD STUDENTS HELP INVESTIGATORS ZERO
IN ON THE BOMBING SUSPECTS.
I'M PEGGY PICO, KPBS EVENING EDITION STARTS
NOW.
CAPTIONS PROVIDED BY ECAPTIONS.
>> >>DWANE: HELLO, GOOD EVENING ARAPIDLY CHANGEING
SITUATION IN BOSTON RIGHT NOW.
JUST A SHORT TIME AGO, GUN FIRE ERUPTED IN
THE SUBURB OF WATER TOWN, IT'S JUST A FEW
MILES AGO FROM THE SCENE OF MONDAY'S BOMBING,
AND WHERE POLICE SAY THEY SHOT AND KILLED
ONE OF THE BOMBING SUSPECTS.
THEY'VE BEEN SEARCHING FOR THE OTHER.
THIS IS THE MAN POLICE HAVE BEEN SEARCHING
FOR ALL DAY.
THE MAN THE FBI HAD CALLED SUSPECT NUMBER
TWO.
AGENTS SAY HIS OLDER BROTHER WAS SUSPECT NUMBER
1.
HE IS DEAD KILLED IN A SHOOT OUT EARLIER TODAY
BY POLICE.
ACTIVITY CAME AFTER A STAY IN PLACE ORDER
FOR BOSTON.
THEY'VE BEEN DOING A DOOR TO DOOR SEARCH.
OFFICERS ENTERED HOMES ON 20 STREETS LOOKING
FOR ANY SIGN.
EARLIER IN THE DAY HIS URNGAL SPOKE TO THE
MEDIA AND CALLD FOR HIS NEPHEW TO SURRENDER.
>> >>: I SAY IF YOU ARE ALIVE, TURN YOURSELF
IN. AND ASK FOR FORGIVENESS FROM THE VICTIMS
FROM THE INJRED.
>> >>DWANE: THE SEARCH INTENSIFIED LAST NIGHT
HOURS AFTER FBI RELEASED PHOTOS OF THE SUSPECTS
AN MIT CAMPUS POLICE OFFICERS WAS FOUND SHOT.
THEN A CAR JACKING IN AND
A VIOLENT CAR CHASE ENSUED WITH GUN DPIER
CHANGE.
ONE OF THE SUSPECTS WAS KILLED IN THE
FIRE FIGHT.
HERE IS SOME OF
WHAT WE KNOW ABOUT THE SUSPECTS RIGHT NOW,
AS WE SAID BEFORE THEY ARE BROTHERS, THEY
ARE ETHNIC CHECHENS, FAMILY MEMBERS SAY THEY'VE
BEEN IN THE U.S. FOR CLOSE TO 10 YEARS. THE
YOUNGER BROTHER IS REPORTEDLY A MEDICAL STUDENT.
THE UNCLE SAYS THE YOUNGER BROTHER CALLED
LAST NIGHT TO APOLOGIZE FOR A RIFT IN THE
FAMILY.
ANOTHER SAYS THE BROTHERS BROUGHT SHAME TO
THE FAMILY AND CHECHENS.
>> >>: BEING LOSERS, HATRED TO THOSE WHO WERE
ABLE TO SETTLE THEMSELVES THESE ARE THE ONLY
REASONS I CAN IMAGINE.
ANYTHING ELSE, ANYTHING ELSE WITH RELIGION,
WITH IZ LM, IT'S A FRAUD, IT'S A FAKE.
>> >>DWANE: PEAK PEGGY PICO BRINGS US SOME
LOCAL REACTION TO THIS STORY.
>> >>PEGGY: LIKE MOST COMMUNITIES AROUND THE
COUNTRY, SAN DIEGO HAS KEPT CLOSE TABS ON
UNFOLDING EVENTS IN BOSTON TODAY.
JOINING ME WITH SOME LOCAL REACTION IS KPBS
INVESTIGATIVE REPORTER AMITA SHARMA.
AMITA, YOU WERE OUT AND ABOUT.
>> >>AMITA: WE ENGAGED IN A LITTLE BIT OF
SOUL SEARCHING HOW TO LOCALIZE THIS STORY
TO SAN DIEGO.
THERE AREN'T A LOT OF CHECHEN PEOPLE WHO LIVE
HERE.
I MEAN, THERE'S SOME CHECHEN CAB DRIVERS,
BUT NO ORGANIZED CHECHEN COMMUNITY WHO CARED
TO SPEAK ABOUT THIS.
THEN NEWS STARTED TRICKLING OUT ABOUT THE
STATE OF THESE TWO SUSPECTS, THE TWO BROTHERS.
IT IS ISLAM.
ONE OF THE BROTHERS, THE YOUNGER BROTHER I
BELIEVE HAD WRITTEN ON FACEBOOK THAT HIS WORLD
VIEW IS ISLAM.
THE OLDER BROTHER CONSIDERS HIMSELF AT LEAST
ON FACEBOOK @ AS A DEVOUT MUSLIM.
SO WE WENT TO GO TALK TO THE CLAIREMONT MOSQUE.
HE IS SOMEBODY WHO HAS MET WITH COMMUNITY
GROUPS OVER THE YEARS QUITE FREQUENTLY TO
TALK ABOUT THE PUBLIC PERCEPTION OF THESE
TERRORIST ACTS WHEN THEY ARE COMMITTED BY
ISLAMIC RADICALS SOAVMENT, YOU SO, YOU KNOW,
WE WANTED TO TALK TO HIM ABOUT HIS RKS TO
THE EVENTS THIS WEEK AS THEY UNFOAD LD.
HE SAID BASICALLY HE HAD REACTED TO THE BOMBINGS
IN BOSTON ON MONDAY AS ANY PERSON WOULD.
HERE'S WHAT HE HAD TO SAY.
>> >>: WE HAVE BEEN FOLLOWING THE NEWS CLOSELY.
AND WE ARE VERY CONCERNED ABOUT THE SAFETY
OF PEOPLE AND PROPERTIES IN THE BOSTON AREA.
AND AS ANY FAITH BASED COMMUNITY AND ETHNIC
GROUP, WE FELT VERY SORRY FOR WHAT HAPPENED
TO THE INNOCENT PEOPLE.
WE BELIEVE THAT THIS IS A CRIME.
AND REGARDLESS WHO IS BEHIND IT.
>> >>PEGGY: THAT WAS SORT OF GENERAL TAKE
ON IT.
WHEN YOU TOLD HIMﾊ WHEN HE LEARNED THE TWO
SUSPECTS IN THE BOMBING WERE CHECH EXPN MUSLIM,
WHAT WAS HIS REACTION TO THAT?
>> >>AMITA: HE SAID THE IRONY WAS HIS REACTION
DIDN'T CHANGE.
HE'S WELL AWARE THAT THE PUBLIC'S REACTION
MOA MORE THAN LIKELY HAS CHANGED.
IN OTHER WORDS RS ONCE THE PUBLIC LEARNED
THAT THESE TWO SUSPECTS WERE CHECHEN, THAT
THEY WERE MUSLIM, THEIR ETHNICITY, THEIR FAITH,
HE'Sﾊ HE BELIEVES THAT A LOT OF PEOPLE WILL
USE THIS JUST TO REINFORCE THE BELIEF THAT
ISLAM SOME HOW MOTIVATES TERRORISM.
>> >>PEGGY: A FALSE BELIEF, NECESSARILY.
>> >>AMITA: THAT'S A DEBATE FOR ANOTHER TIME,
ANOTHER SHOW.
I ASKED HIM IF HE WAS TIRED OF BEING APPROACHED
BY JOURNALISTS TO TALK ABOUT TERRORISM WHENEVER
THERE IS AN ACT COMMITTED BY AN ISLAMIC FUNDAMENTALIST
ANYWHERE IN THE WORLD, AND HIS RESPONSE WAS
MIXED.
>> >>: YES, AND NO.
YES, BECAUSE YOU KNOW I EXPECTED THIS AND
NO BECAUSE I BELIEVE THAT MY JOB AS AN IMAM
OF THIS COMMUNITY IS TO NULLIFY THESE KINDS
OF CONCEPTIONS.
THIS IS A GREAT OPPORTUNITY FOR ME TO TELL
EVERYONE THAT ISLAM HAS NOTHING TO GOO WITH
SUCH CRIMES.
THOSE PEOPLE WHO HAVE PRESENTED THEMSELVES
THEY SHOULD BE DEALT WITH AS CRIMINALLED.
>> >>PEGGY: SAN DIEGO HAS NOTORIOUS LINKS
TO HIGH PROFILE HAIR RS ACTS AND CRIMINALS
OVER THE DECADE.
>> >>AMITA: THAT'S RIGHT, PEGGY.
ACTUALLY TWO OF THE IS SEPTEMBERﾊ11 HIGH
JACKERS LIVED HERE, STUDIED HERE, WORSHIPED
HERE BEFORE THEY FLEW A PLANE INTO THE PENTAGON
ON SEPTEMBERﾊ11.
THEY ALSO MET PLIEIVE PRIVATELY QUITE FREQUENTLY
WITH AN IMAM AT A MOSQUE IN LA MESA.
THIS IMAM IS NONE OTHER THAN WHO WAS CONSIDERED
A LEADER OF AL QAEDA ON THE ARAB PENINSULA.
HE WAS FASCINATED BY THE U.S. GOVERNMENT IN
SEPTEMBERﾊ2011.
THERE IS ALSO ANOTHER TERRORIST GROUP BY THE
NAME OF ALSHABOB IN SMALL YOU.
ONE OF THE TOP COMMANDERS IN THAT GROUP IS
A LOCAL SAN DIEGAN.
HE STUDIED HERE, WENT THERE I BELIEVE IN 2005,
THAT'S WHAT FEDERAL OFFICIALS BELIEVE.
AND THEN JUST AS RECENTLY AS FEBRUARY OF THIS
YEAR, A JURY IN SAN DIEGO CONVICTED FOUR MEN
INCLUDING AN IMAM AT A LOCAL P MOSQUE IN CITY
HEIGHTS OF SENDING MONEY, CONSPIRING TO SEND
MONEY AND PROVIDE OTHER MATERIAL SUPPORT TO
AL SHABOB IN SO SOMALIA.
>> >>PEGGY: THANK YOU SE MUCH.
>> >>DWANE: NOW THE BOSTON MARATHON BOMBINGS
CAST A SHADOW ON THE START OF DEBATE ON A
SWEEPING NEW IMMIGRATION BILL TODAY.
A NUMBER OF REPUBLICANS USED THE EVENTS IN
BOSTON TO RAISE QUESTIONS ABOUT THE EXISTING
IMMIGRATION SYSTEM AND THE CHANGES PROPOSED
IN THE NEW BILL.
THE ATTACKS WERE ALLEGEDLY CARRIED OUT BY
TWO BROTHERS OF A RUSSIAN REGION OF CHEF NU
CHECHNYA.
WHEN THOUSANDS OF POLICE CONVERSED ON BOSTON
TODAY T CAUSED THE CITY TO COME TO A COMPLETE
HALT.
ON L PLAIJER BUS LINES WERE SUSPENDED ALONG
WITH AMTRAK SERVICE BETWEEN BAWS EXPN NEW
YORK.
ONLY AIR TRAVEL FUNCTIONED NORMALLY.
MOST HIGHWAYS REMAINED OPEN, WITH THE EXCEPTION
OF WATER TOWN WHERE THE MASSIVE SEARCH HAS
BEEN CONDUCTED. THE BOSTON RED SOX AND BREW
NS GAMES WERE CANCELED.
A MORE DETAILED PHOTO OF ONE OF THE SUSPECTS
IN THE BOSTON MARATHON SURFACED TODAY.
HE'S THE ONE THEY'RE SEARCHING FOR NOW.
HIS PHOTO APPEARS TO CAPTURE ONE OF THE SUSPECTS
ACTUALLY FLEEING WITH OTHER PEOPLE RIGHT AFTER
THE EXPLOSIONS.
HE'S SEEN IN THE WHITE BASEBALL CAP AMAN WHO
TOOK THE PHOTO WAS LEAVING THE STORE WHEN
THE BOMBS EXPLODED.
HOO GOT A QUICK PHOTO WITH THE IPHONE BUT
DIDN'T NOTICE WHO IT WAS UNTIL YESER DAW.
SOCIAL MEDIA PROVED TO BE A POWERFUL TOOL
FOR INVESTIGATORS HUNTING THE BOSTON BAWM
NING SUSPECTS.
PEGGY PICO HAS MORE ON SAN DIEGO'S CONNECTION
TO THE HIGH TECH INVESTIGATION.
>> >>PEGGY: HUNDREDS OF THOUSANDS OF PHOTOS
AND TWEETS FROM MARATHON SPECTATORS HELP UNDER
VEST GATERS ZERO IN ON THE SUSPECT SAID.
KPBS REPORTER SUSAN MURPHY JOINS ME WITH HOW
SAN DIEGO STATE'S VIZ CENTER AND HOMELAND
SECURITY SPHOONTS GOT INVOLVED.
YOU'VE TALKED EXTENSIVELY THIS WEEK WITH ERIC
FROST AT THE VIZ CENTER.
>> >>SUSAN: ERIC FROST IS CODIRECTOR OF SAN
DIEGO STATE UNIVERSITY'S HOMELAND SECURITY
PROGRAM, AND DIRECTOR O F THE VIZ CENTER.
HE GATHER MASSIVE AMOUNTS OF DATA FROM PHOTOS
AND TWITTER, AND CREATES THESE VISUALIZATIONS,
IT'S TIEBL CAPTURE A SCENE SECOND BY SECOND,
AND HE SAYS PEOPLE AT MONDAY'S MARATHON, THEY
ANALYZED THIS DATA AT LIGHTNING SPEED.
HERE'S WHAT HE HAS TO SAY ABOUT IT.
>> >>: THERE WAS AN ENORMOUS EFFORT QUIETLY
IN THE BACK END TO IDENTIFY PEOPLE AND TAKE
THEM OFF THE SUSPECT LIST.
SO THAT WHEN THEY ACTUALLY HAD A PRESS CONFERENCE
OR WHEN THE FBI RELEASED THEM, IT WASN'T WE
THINK THESE ARE, IT WAS LIKE THESE ARE THE
GUYS IT.
AND IT WAS BECAUSE OF A MASSIVE AMOUNT OF
WORK IN THE BACKGROUND.
>> >>PEGGY: NOW, HE WAS TALKING ABOUT GETTING
ALL OF THIS AND GETTING THIS INFORMATION,
IS THAT WHAT WE REFER TO AS CROWD SOURCING?
>> >>SUSAN: CROWD SOURCING USED TO BE TIP
LINES, THESE TELEVISION SHOWS THAT ASKED THE
PUBLIC TO SOLVE INVESTIGATIONS.
SOCIAL MEDIA TAKES IT TO A NEW LEVEL.
ERIC FROST EXPLAINS.
>> >>: HERE'S THIS MASS AMOUNT OF DATA COMES
IN, IT'S IN AN ORGANIZED WAY, AND IT'S ORGANIZED
AND YOU CAN DO SOMETHING WITH IT.
AND SO A COMMON THOUGHT PATTERN IS IF YOU'RE
CROWD SOURCING, SO LIKE IN A DISASTER, HAVE
OTHER PEOPLE TELL YOU WHAT'SER GOING O, YOU
THEN KNOW WHAT'SER GOING ON, AND WHAT USUALLY
WORKS THE BEST IS SAY TO THE CROWD GIVING
SOMETHING BACK THAT'S CALLED CROWD FEEDING.
>> >>PEGGY: HE'S TALKING ABOUT THIS CROWD
FEEDING, THIS CROWD SOURCING, THIS BACK AND
FORTH CONVERSATION THAT'S NOT JUST SENDING
IN A PICTURE.
BUT THERE'S SOME DRAW BACKS TO THAT SORT OF
TWO WAY CONVERSATION.
>> >>SUSAN: YEAH, RUMORS CAN START.
THERE WERE ABOUT EIGHT TO TEN PEOPLE WHO WERE
WRONGLY LABELED AS SUSPICIOUS.
RUMORS CAN FLY RAPIDLY ON TWITTER.
WELL, MOST OF THEM WERE PHOTOS OF MEN WITH
BACKPACKS OF COURSE, ANDﾊ
>> >>PEGGY: THEY WERE ACTUALLY THESE MEN WERE
ACTUALLY PEOPLE WERE SENDING IN SAYING THESE
MIGHT TBHEE GUY, RIGHT?
>> >>SUSAN: RIGHT SOME OF THEM WERE POSTED
ON MEDIA OUTLETS.
THE POSITIVE THING IS THAT MOST OF THESE PEOPLE
WERE ABLE TO COME FORWARD AND CLEAR THEMSELVES
WITH POLICE.
IT ALSO HELP UNDER VEST GATERS TO NARROW DOWN
THE SUSPECT LIST.
>> >>PEGGY: ABSOLUTELY.
SO IT CAN WORK BOTH WAYS.
IT CAN BE HARMFUL IF YOU'RE ONE OF THE RUMOR
GUYS.
NOW THE BOSTON MARATHON, LIKE THE SAN DIEGO
MARATHON OR ANY REALLY PUBLIC SPORTING EVENT
HAS BEEN KNOWN FOR QUITE AWHILE HAS AS A SOFT
TARGET.
WHEN YOU WERE TALKING TO FROST, HE WAS ESPECIALLY
CONCERNED ABOUT THIS, HOW COME?
>> >>SUSAN: HE FEARS THAT WE'VE ENTER UNDER
TO A NEW ERA OF TERRORISM.
>> >>: PEOPLE GETTING IN OVER AND OVER.
PEOPLE SEE THAT WORKED REALLY WELL, IT WAS
ON CAMERA, ALL THESE PEOPLE WERE LOOKING AT
IT AND THIS HAD THE RIGHT EFFECT, SO I'M GOING
TO DO THE SAME THING.
IT'S LIKE WHEN THE FIRST PEOPLE HIGH JACKED
AN AIRPLANE, OUR WORLD CHANGED AND FOR SPORTS
EVENTS ABSOLUTELY SPORTS EVENTS ARE AN EXTRAORDINARY
TARGET.
THE TEAMS ARE A TARGET BECAUSE THAT'S THE
MAJOR ASSET THAT THE TEAM HAS, AND HOW YOU
PROTECT THOSE PEOPLE.
>> >>PEGGY: THESE SOFT TARGETS HE'S TALKING
ABOUT HAVE BEEN KNOWN FOR SOME TIME, AND THERE
WERE GRAD STUDENTS YOU TALKED WITH AT THE
VIZ CENTERS THAT ARE STUDYING SPORTS SECURITY
SPECIFICALLY.
WHAT DID THEY HAVE TO SAY ABOUT WHAT THEY'VE
LEARNED FROM THIS BOSTON MARATHON SITUATION?
>> >>SUSAN: THEY'VE LEARN AD LOT.
THEY'RE GOING TO BE GOING BACK AND DISUDYING,
THEY'RE CONTINUING THE INVESTIGATION, COMPILING
EVIDENCE THROUGH SOCIAL MEDIA, AND PHOTOS.
THEY SAY THAT SOCIAL MEDIA IS THE BEST KIND
OF FORENSIC EVIDENCE BECAUSE EVERY PHOTO AND
SOCIAL MEDIA ENTRY HAS A TIME STAMP AND A
LOCATE LOCATION AND THAT DATA IS INVALUABLE.
>> >>PEGGY: YOU CAN SEE SUSAN MURPHY'S COMPLETE
REPORT ON OUR WEBSITE KPBS.ORG.
SUSAN MURPHY, THANK YOU SE MUCH FOR TALKING
WITH US.
>> >>DWANE: THE IRS IS WARNING OF POTENTIAL
SCAMS POPPING UP CONNECTED TO THE BOSTON BOMBINGS.
AGENTS SAY IT OFTEN HAPPENS AFTER TRAGEDIES
AND WEBSITES, PEOPLE ASKING FOR INFORMATION
BY PHONE.
THE IRS SUGGESTS DONATING TO CUAL FILE CHARITIES.
STAY WITH US FOR CONTINUING COVERAGE OF THIS
STORY ON THE RADIO AT KPBS AND ONLINE AT KPBS.ORG,
YOU CAN ALSO GET THE LATEST ON PBS NEWS HOUR
BEGINNING AT 7:00ﾊP.M.
CAPTIONS PROVIDED BY ECAPTIONS.
>> >>DWANE: IN OTHER NEWS THIS EVENING. A
BRUSH FIRE SPARKED BY TRAINING IN CAMP PENDLETON.
THE HOT SPOTS OF TWO BRUSH FIRES, BURNED ABOUT
TWO BUILDINGS.
FOURTEEN BODIES HAVE BEEN RECOVERED NOW FROM
A MASSIVE EXPLOSION AT A FERTILIZER PLANT
IN TEXAS.
SEARCH AND RESCUE TEAMS HAVE BEEN SIFTING
THROUGH THE RUBBLE FOR POSSIBLE SURVIVORS,
DOZENS OF HOMES AND APARTMENT COMPLEX, A SCHOOL
AND A NURSING HOME WERE DESTROYED.
200 PEOPLE WERE INJURED.
AUTHORITIES DESCRIBE IT AS AN INDUSTRIAL ACCIDENT
SPARKED BY A FIRE.
CONGRESSIONAL OFFICES WILL BE RECEIVING MAIL
AGAIN ON MONDAY AFTER A MS.ﾊSIPE MAN MS.ﾊSPY
MAN WAS CHARGEDﾊ HE
WAS CHAINED TO A CHAIR AND INTERROGATED FOR
SEVERAL HOURS.
ASSUMING IT COULD BE RESTARTED SAFELY WOULD
THE SAN ONOFRE NUCLEAR PLANT STILL BE COST
EFFECTIVE WAY TO GENERATE ELECTRICITY? KPBS
NORTH COUNTY BUREAU CHIEF ALISON ST. JOHN
SAYS QUESTIONS ABOUT THE PLANT'S FUTURE ARE
MORE COMPLEX.
>> >>ALISON: BILL HENMAN IS A NUCLEAR ENGINEER
AND CONSULTANT.
HE'S ASSESSED RISK AT NUCLEAR POWER PLANTS
AROUND THE COUNTRY.
I ASKED HIM IF IT WOULD BE COST EFFECTIVE
TO BRING SAN ONOFRE BACK ONLINE.
>> >>: I THINK THE ANSWER IS YES.
IF YOU LOOK AT THE HISTORY, THE PLANT HAS
DONE VERY WELL RK IT'S OPERATED ESSENTIALLY
30 YEARS WITH NO REAL PROBLEMS LIKE THE BUN
THAT WE HAVE NOW.
AND IT'S BEEN A REAL FRIEND TO PEOPLE IN SOUTHERN
CALIFORNIA BECAUSE IT'S KEPT OUR RATES LOW,
BELIEVE IT OR NOT.
>> >>ALISON: HE SAYS IT WOULD BE WORTH SPENDING
MONEY TO BRING IT BACK ONLINE BECAUSE MOST
OF THE CAPITAL EQUIPMENT COSTS ARE PAID OFF.
>> >>: THE ADDITION OF NEW STEAM GENERATORS,
EVEN IF WE HAVE OO REPLACE THE ONES IN UNIT
THREE WOULDN'T BEﾊ I DON'T THINK IS THAT
BAD BECAUSE THERE ARE ONLY 700ﾊMILLION,
LET'S SAY.
WHEN YOU HAVE A MILLION OR MORE CUSTOMERS
THAT ARE PAYING IN THAT AMOUNT CAN GET PAID
OFF RATHER QUICKLY.
WE WILL BE ABLE TO GENERATE IT POWER TO COVER
THOSE COSTS.
>> >>ALISON: WE'VE BEEN SO FOCUSED ON THE
FAILED STEAM GENERATORS AT SAN ONOFRE, BUT
THERE ARE OTHER PROBLEMS THAT WILL COST MONEY,
PERHAPS A LOT OF MONEY, TO ADDRESS IN THE
NOT SO DISTANT FUTURE.
>> >>: DO WE WANT TO GIVE THEM ANOTHER BILLION
DOLLARS AND ANOTHER FIVE YEARS TO MAYBE OPERATE
FOR ANOTHER SEVEN YEARS WHEN OTHER COSTS ARE
ON THE HORIZON.
>> >>ALISON: SHE SAYS CALIFORNIA RATE PAYERS
NEED TO KNOW WHAT OTHER COSTS ARE AHEAD LIKE
COSTS TRIGGERED BY WHAT HAPPENED.
>> >>: IF YOU DRIVE INTO THIS LOVELY CAMP
GROUND, YOU NOTICE A SIGN THAT SAYS TSUNAMI
ZONE, THERE ARE SIRENS FOR EMERGENCY PLANNING,
THE TRANSMISSION LINES AND ARE THEY SAFE DURING
A SEISMIC EVENT.
>> >>ALISON: STUDIES OF EARTHQUAKE FAULT LINES
ON THE COAST COULD REVEAL MAJOR RETRO FITS
ARE NEEDED AT SAN ONOFRE.
BECKER SAYS ANOTHER COST IS WHERE TO STORE
NUCLEAR WASTE.
>> >>: THOUSANDS OF TONS OF RADIOACTIVE WASTE
SIT BEHIND ME ON OUR COAST.
THE NRC HAS NO PLANS TO GELT IT OFF OUR COAST,
AND WE'VE BEEN PROMISED SINCE 1982 THAT IT
WOULD BE REMOVED TO SOMEWHERE ELSE, SOME DAY.
>> >>ALISON: A THIRD UNRESOLVED ISSUE IS WHAT
IT WILL COST TO REDESIGN THE PLANT'S COOLING
SYSTEM, PERHAPS WITH COOLING TOWERS TO MEET
NEW CALIFORNIA REGULATIONS TO PROTECT MARINE
LIFE.
>> >>: A MILLION GALLONS A MINUTE GOES THROUGH
THIS PLANT, SUCKING IN SEA LIFE, LARVAE, TAKING
OUT WARMER WATER.
THE ALTERNATIVES ARE REALLY VERY EXPENSE F,
TECHNICALLY VERY CHALLENGING, AND COULD RESHAPE
THIS COAST LINE AGAIN.
THEY'RE GOING TO ASK RATE PAYERS TO PAY, I
WANT TO KNOW WHAT IT'S GOING TO COST BEFORE
THEY ASK ME TO PAY.
THIS PLANT BEHIND ME WAS DESIGNED IN 1967.
MAYBE POURING A LOT OF MONEY INTO A NEW PLANT
WOULD HAVE MADE SENSE, NEW EMERGENCY PLANNING,
NEW STEAM GENERATORS, NEW SEISMIC STUDIES,
BUT DOING THAT FOR A PLANT THAT WAS DESIGNED
IN THE 1960S HOW MANY OF US ARE GOING TO DRIVE
A CAR, FIX EVERYTHING UP, AND SAY WE'RE GOING
TO DRIVE IT ANOTHER 20 YEARS.
>> >>ALISON: BILL DOESN'T BUY THE OLD CAR
ANALOGY.
>> >>: I DON'T SEE THAT AS A REAL DRAW BACK.
I THINK I'VE SEEN SOME CLASSIC CARS THAT ARE
JUST BEAUTIFULLY RESTORED AND THEY'RE REALLY
GREAT TO SEE ON THE ROAD.
>> >>ALISON: AND HE ISN'T WORRIED ABOUT AN
ACCIDENT IN THE FUTURE.
>> >>: I THIK WE'RE AT THE EDGE OF THE 50
MILE RADIUS RIGHT HERE.
WE'RE SITTING IN THE RANGE OF SOMETHING FROM
THE PLANT RIGHT NOW.
I'M TOTALLY COMFORTABLE.
FOR ME, THE TRADE OFF IN HAVING A SOLID, GOOD
ELECTRICAL SYSTEM IS FAR BETTER THAN, YOU
KNOW, WORRYING ABOUT A SMALL RISK THAT WE
HAVEN'T EVER ENCOUNTERED BEFORE.
>> >>ALISON: BECKER SAYS BEEFED UP EVACUATION
PLANNING MAY JEK GENERATE MORE COSTS, SHE
BELIEVES TAX PAYERS LIABILITY IS UNDER ESTIMATED.
>> >>: THE FEDERAL LIABILITY LIMIT IS $12.6ﾊBILLIONS.
WHEN YOU LOOK AT WHAT HAPPENED TO FUKOSHIMA,
THE DAMAGES PAYING OUT ARE OVER A HUNDRED
50ﾊBILLION DOLLARS.
THAT WAS A SMALL FISHING VILLAGE IN JAPAN,
THIS IS THE COAST OF CALIFORNIA.
>> >>ALISON: BECKER SAYS THE UTILITIES ARE
NOT IGNORING ALL THESE ISSUES, BUT THE RATE
PAYER NEEDS TO KNOW HOW THESE PROBLEMS WILL
BE RESOLVED AND WHAT THAT WILL COST.
>> >>: WE NEED TO CONSIDER THE ARGUMENTS AGAINST
NUCLEAR POWER, THE ARGUMENTS FOR NUCLEAR POWER.
THESE ARE A SIDE ISSUE.
WHAT WE REALLY WANT TO KNOW IS WHAT IS NUCLEAR
POWER GOING TO COST THE STATE OF CALIFORNIA,
COST THE RATE PAYERS OF CALIFORNIA, IF OUR
LIVES AND OUR LIVELIHOODS ARE AT STAKE, AND
WE NEED THE ANSWERS.
>> >>ALISON: SAN ONOFRE'S BEEN A SOURCE OF
SAFE, RELIABLE ELECTRICITY FOR DECADES. THE
QUESTION OF WHETHER IT WOULD BE SAFE AND COST
EFFECTIVE IN THE FUTURE IS MORE COMPLEX.
ALISON ST. JOHN KPBS NEWS.
CAPTIONS PROVIDED BY ECAPTIONS.
>> >>DWANE: EDISON IS CURRENTLY APPLYING FOR
A TEMPORARY LICENSE AMENDMENT TO RESTART ONE
REACTOR AT 70% POWER FOR TWO YEARS.
NEW STATE LEGISLATION WOULD REQUIRE APPROVAL.
>> >>: ON THE NEXT NEWS HOUR, SHIELDS AND
BROOKS ANALYZE THE WEEK'S NEWS THAT'S FRIDAY
ON THE PBS NEWS HOUR.
>> >>DWANE: STUDENTS AT SAN DIEGO STATE COLLEGE
OF BUSINESS WERE CHALLENGED TO INVEST IN THEIR
NATURAL ABILITIES AND BUILD ON THEIR OWN IDENTITY.
MANY MAY KNOW TODAY'S SPEAKER BETTER AS OPRAH'S
BOYFRIEND.
RN STEDMAN DOESN'T NEED MUCH OF AN INTRODUCTION.
HE TOLD ANXIOUS BUSINESS STUDENTS AT SAN DIEGO
STATE INSTANT GRATIFICATION MUST BE HANDLED
ONE BITE AT A TIME.
>> >>: YOU CAN'T HAND TL UNTIL YOU HANDLE
SMALL.
>> >>: LIKE IF THEY'RE TRYING TO PROJECT THAT
THEY HAVE THIS SKILL OR SOMETHING LIKE THAT,
WHEN REALLY THEY DON'T.
>> >>: WASTING YOUR TIME, WHEN YOU'RE NOT
PRACTICING ALL YOUR NATURAL ABILITIES.
THE BIGGEST CHALLENGE TODAY IN THE 21EST CENTURY
IS PEOPLE DO NOT T H I N K.
>> >>DWANE: GRAM HAS BEEN THINKING, SPEAKING
AND WRITING ABOUT THIS FOR 10 YEARS, FROM
PASSPORT TO FREEDOM, IDENTITY LEADERSHIP.
HE SAYS IT'S ABOUT KNOWING WHO YOU ARE, WHERE
YOU'RE GOING AND TRANSFORMING YOUR MIND FROM
I CAN'T, TO I CAN.
>> >>: ONCE YOU DO THAT, THEN YOU'RE OPEN
TO ALL THE OPPORTUNITIES WE HAVE IN THIS GREAT
COUNTRY, AND THIS GREAT WORLD.
>> >>: I ALSO FEEL LIKE THINGS LIKE THIS,
TARGETING SOPHOMORES AND FRESHMEN, UNDER GRAD
IS VERY IMPORT TONIGHT GET TO KNOW YOURSELF
AT A YOUNG AGE IN ORDER TO GO INTO THAT JOB
WORLD TO KNOW YOUR SKILLS AND KNOW YOURSELF.
FROM THE FIRST GENERATION COLLEGE STUDENT
IN MY FAMILY, I'M DEFINITELY BLAZING A TRAIL
FOR MY LITTLE BROTHER Y.HAVE NO CHOICE BUT
TO BE A LEADER.
>> >>DWANE: GRAHAM SAYS HIS ASSOCIATION WITH
OPRAH SAID HIS EYES TO TAKING CHARGE WITH
HIS OWN DEVELOPMENT.
>> >>: IT'S ABOUT DEVELOPING YOURSELF, AND
TAKING THAT INFORMATION AND MAKING IT RELEVANT
TO YOUR SKILL SETS TO YOUR TALENT SO YOU CAN
PRACTICE THAT AND BECOME GOOD AT WHAT YOU
DO, REGARDLESS OF WHO YOU ARE.
>> >>DWANE: TURNING TO SAN DIEGO WEATHER,
PLENTY OF SUN SHINE ALONG THE COAST, TOMORROW
WILL BE A MIX OF SUN AND CLOUDS A LITTLE COOLER
THAN TODAY.
AS FOR THE INLAND VALLEYS IT WILL BE THE WARMEST
DAY OF THE WEEK.
MOUNTAIN AREAS OF, PLENTY OF SUN SHINE, AND
IT WILL REALLY HEAT UP IN THE DESERT, TALKING
MID 90S.
RECAPPING TONIGHT'S TOP STORIES, POLICE SAY
THEY'VE CORNERED THE SURVIVING SUSPECT
IN THE BOSTON MARATHON BOMBING NEAR A PORT
JUST A SHORT TIME AGO.
THERE WAS GUN FIRE IN THE SUBURB OF WATER
TOWN, JUST A FEW MILES FROM THE SCENE OF MONDAY'S
BOMBINGS AT THE BOSTON MARATHON.
IT'S WHERE POLICE SAY THEY SHOT AND KILLED
ONE OF THE SUSPECTS, 26 YEAR OLD.
THEY'VE BEEN SEARCHING THE CITY FOR HIS BROTHER.
HIS UNCLE CALLED ON HIM TO SURRENDER EARLIER
TODAY.
>> >>: I SAY IF YOU ARE ALIVE, TURN YOURSELF
IN AND ASK FOR FORGIVENESS FROM THE VICTIMS,
FROM THE INJURED, AND FROM THOSE WHO LEFT
ASK FOR FORGIVENESS FROM THESE PEOPLE.
>> >>DWANE: ALL THE LATEST WE'LL OF COURSE
KEEP YOU UPDATED ON ALL OF THE LATEST ACTIVITY
REGARDING THIS STORY.
WE'LL ALSO BRING YOU UPDATES ON THE BOMBING
SUSPECT STAND OFF AT 6:30ﾊP.M. TONIGHT ON
THE KPBS EVENING EDITION, FOLLOWED BY THE
PBS NEWS HOUR AT 7:00ﾊP.M.
YOU CAN FIND TONIGHT'S STORIES, AND DOWNLOAD
THE KPBS APP ON OUR WEBSITE KPBS.ORG/EVENINGEDITION.
THANKS FOR JOINING US HAVE A GOOD NIGHT.
CAPTIONS PROVIDED BY ECAPTIONS.