right here and how does it
relate to this ice water?
I have no idea.
But I have about 30 seconds
to figure it out
while you watch this.
I'm Steve Spangler, and I'm all
about making science fun.
For the last 20 years, I've
been teaching ways to turn
ordinary science experiments
into unforgettable
experiences.
I have an amazing team who will
do whatever it takes to
affect the way people
think about science.
And to do that, I live
in one motto--
make it big, do it right,
give it class.
So here's the challenge
I have for you.
Get a bucket, get some water,
get some ice-- not any kind of
ice, glacial ice.
It's straight from Alaska,
costs $50,000.
If you want extreme cold,
pour some salt in there.
It'll drop the temperature to
about 17 degrees Fahrenheit.
Then plunge your hand into the
water like this and see how
long you can keep it there.
You don't want to stick
your hand in?
Get a friend like
Higginsworth.
See?
Higginsworth, put
your hand in.
Now leave it there
for a long time.
See, this got me to thinking--
how is it that whales can stay
in this incredibly cold
temperatures?
Well, the answer is all the
blubber that's around them.
So we're going to create
ourselves a little blubber bag
that will allow you to
be able to stay in
the water for hours.
So how you doing now,
Higginsworth?
See, kids?
He tapped out.
You'll always do better
than Higginsworth.
See, I'm not the only one
thinking about whales.
A hundred science enthusiasts
joined us for an experience
called Science at Sea.
It was a cruise to Alaska with
Holland America, where we got
to see whales breaching and ice
calving and some of the
most amazing things in Alaska.
The naturalists are the ones
that pointed out this quick
little demonstration that you
can do with vegetable
shortening, a Ziploc bag, and
some duct tape to understand
how whales withstand these
incredible temperatures.
Step one, find yourself that
vegetable shortening and put
it inside of a Ziploc bag.
So you're going to try to get
it down inside this little
Ziploc bag.
You've just got to try to keep
it away from the little top
here so that it doesn't get
real greasy at the top.
You're going to want to put
three or four really good
scoops in the Ziploc bag.
See, all this vegetable
shortening is going to
simulate the blubber.
Right.
Now you take the second bag.
This is the bag that your hand
will go in and stay clean.
And this now goes into the first
bag with all of that
vegetable shortening.
Flatten it out.
Push it down.
And now you have the start
of a blubber bag.
Once you have all of that
shortening spread out, then
you're going to want to take the
top bag here and actually
fold it inside out, trapping all
of the shortening inside.
And now, to make sure that
nothing comes out you take
some duct tape and
you seal it up.
Perfect.
You got a blubber bag.
Take a look at this.
You see, all of the shortening
is trapped between the two
layers here of plastic bag,
allowing you to put your hand
inside and feel it, yet
it doesn't get dirty.
Remember the challenge at the
very beginning-- how long can
you keep your hand in?
Well, just stick your hand in
the blubber glove and now
plunge it down inside, you
can stay there forever.
It really is very, very
warm down inside.
See, that the layer of fat
really is a great insulator,
keeping the heat in
and the cold out.
You can stay here for
the longest time.
If you've ever heard the term
"barrel of oil," it actually
came from the whaling
industry.
See, whaling was huge and whale
oil was a big deal.
In the early 1800s, they were a
little concerned about what
would happen because the supply
of whales kept on
diminishing until about 1865.
Whales were nearly extinct and
we had to move to petroleum.
Now that you know how these
creatures can withstand these
incredible temperatures, just
imagine seeing them up close.
Well, that's what happened
with a hundred science
enthusiasts as they joined
us for Science at Sea.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
See, using a blubber glove, I
could have my hand in this
water forever.