sending prices sky-high, literally,
literally taking the grass
from its own roots!
Now you've got your ConDemNation ...
Liberals noshing Tories
like altar boys picking dimps up!
Have we had a national fucking
stroke, or what?
Is revolution a word,
or was it never?
Anybody watching needs to know,
we cope better than average
with irony in Chatsworth.
Well, for fuck's sake,
we live in Manchester,
and they charge us for water!
I wandered lonely as a clown,
necking mushrooms rarely found.
This green and pleasant
land in ancient times...
yak, yak, yak, yak, yak, yak, yak,
yak, yak!
It's not theirs any more.
This is our England now.
Paaaarty!
Sync and corrected by APOLLO
www.addic7ed.com
Clearer with number one...
or number two?
'Society is dead.
'It was all a big fucking lie
anyway, so save your tears.
'Don't mourn.
'Schools, hospitals, pensions,
care for the wrinklies,
'all that "cradle to the grave"
shite was just an expensive luxury.
'What were we thinking?
'We are animals.
It is survival of the fittest.
'To paraphrase the one good Scouser,
'I don't believe in government.
I don't believe in society.
'I just believe in me.'
Straight ahead.
Noble profession, optician.
Helping the blind to see,
windows to the soul.
There's more money in dentistry,
but I didn't get the grades,
so here I am,
living the dream.
One of the girls will help you pick
some frames
from our own-brand range.
Beg pardon?
Your prescription.
Oh, no, you don't understand,
doctor.
The dole sent me down here.
You have to go through the motions,
or they dock your benefit.
I'm not a doctor,
and you need glasses.
That's... not... possible.
It's fact.
I'm not of the four-eyed persuasion.
I'm strong. Me against...
I've got the constitution of an ox.
An ox that needs glasses.
There's fuck-all wrong with my eyes,
so get serious.
Put your breasts away and look again
with your little torch,
and see if we can't get it
right this time.
(CLEARS THROAT)
LAUGHTER
Ha, ha, ha.
Very fucking funny.
How can a piss-stained tramp like
you be too vain to wear glasses?
It's not vanity.
Yeah, and a wash wouldn't go amiss!
Fuck off, you chimp!
All right, knock it on the head.
Come on, we're only having a joke.
Fuck off!
Ooh, have we hurt your feelings?
How was the graduation?
Brilliant ceremony.
All dresses and gowns
and hats like the Royal Wedding,
but without the inbreeding.
Magical, pregnancy. It's brilliant.
Oh, it's a hoot.
Do you mind if I have a little rub?
Fire in, everyone else does.
Good to have a graduate in the family.
White collar worker, respectable.
Is that what it's about,
respectability?
You're asking the wrong person.
You dirty bastard!
I hope he appreciates
all this effort.
Buzzin'. Best day of my life.
Got to go.
Come on, stay for another drink.
Yeah, don't go!
His mates are throwing a party
for him.
Yeah, my mates.
♪ THEME FROM 2001: A SPACE ODYSSEY
I graduated.
I'm a qualified teacher.
Mammoth.
Mates? Fuck it,
they can wait an hour.
CHEERING
Cheers, everyone!
Here's to the class of 2012.
You all right, love?
Yeah. Must have got caught up
with his classmates.
Did you tell him
you were planning a do?
Thought he'd pick up on my hints.
Clearly not.
His phone goes straight
to voicemail.
Poor cow's in denial.
What of?
That her man's an arsehole.
Thank fuck we're normal, son, eh?
For fuck's sake,
look in the mirror before you
come out the toilet, will you?
Sorry.
How about some porky pig?
Oh, vanity, thy name is salmonella.
Jesus Christ! What the fuck,
Nosferatu?
If you're trawling the night
for the blood of virgins,
you'll have a long wait round here.
I have the sweats, and you're lucky
I do. If you could read,
you'd see that meat's not
fit for human consumption.
I was saving it for theducks.
Ducks can't eat bacon.
Tell me something I don't know.
And aren't you a bit
past your own sell-by
to be self-conscious
about wearing glasses?
I am not self-conscious.
Bollocks. You're like a teenager
who's been told not to pop his zits.
We do have mirrors.
I am aware that energy expended on
vanity's largely wasted on my part,
kind though it is of you
to point it out.
So, what?
I cannot be weak.
I know what they think round here.
You've seen how they treat me.
Laugh, point, kick, rob.
Not many tears shed when
I fell in the Jockey, was there?
Sticks and stones.
It's only because I have this, yeah?
This.
Faculties. Senses, head, body.
If I'm strong,
they can do whatever they like,
but they cannot penetrate.
I am immune.
And wearing glasses
fractures your superhero defences?
Spectacles, hearing aids, walking
sticks, prosthetic limbs. These...
these...
place me on a very slippery slope.
If I am weak...
I will not survive.
Yeah, we open at seven. Doesn't mean
I want to be out of my pit at seven.
What time do you have, Feeney?
Just gone half past the hour, Miss.
Begin.
Right, lads, not much time. You know
the drill. You, number 10. You, 11.
Remember, be firm.
Get straight to the point.
Leave them in no doubt.
They'll be glad of it.
God in heaven, you'll have
the thing off its hinges!
Don't open the door at this time
of the morning, it can only be...
Operation New Start.
DSS Gestapo.
These are court-signed documents
ordering you
to vacate these premises
with immediate effect.
You're being evicted.
All right, all right!
Keep your hair on...
so I can scalp you
when I open the fucking door.
Can we come in?
No. It's not even nine yet.
What's going on?
We've been evicted.
Who has?
All of us.
Now, they can't search the house.
We've still got
some human rights left
in this fucking dictatorship
of the moderate.
So we don't need to
flush the drugs, then?
No, we're safe... what drugs?
You stupid...
If the place wasn't swarming with
suits, I'd strip-search you,
you little bastard.
What are you doing?
Make noise, move about.
Be several children.
Keep the noise down, will you?
We've got guests. Bloody 'ell, kids.
Mayhem up there.
Oh, hello.
He still doesn't get it, Miss.
Stop calling me "Miss".
It's creepy, like I invented you
in a fucking lab.
Sorry, Mi...
So... Aidan Croker,
14, should be upstairs.
And this little angel
should be Stella.
Are you enjoying your...
your breakfast?
Prawn Cocktail. Loves her seafood,
so she does.
Right, so no other children,
is that correct?
Or are you suggesting
there are some more up there?
THUDDING UPSTAIRS
Yeah, just the one.
But he puts himself about a bit.
This is a multi-agency operation,
Mr Gallagher.
Department of Work and Pensions,
local council,
HMRC, environmental health,
the police.
That's not fair!
In the past, people have relied
on the left hand not knowing
what the right hand is doing.
Not any more.
You can't put people out
on the street. A child, a cripple.
A geriatric fucking cripple.
No, it's a broad remit.
Premises inspection,
checking that claimants are getting
all they're entitled to...
Or not.
And in some very extreme cases,
I am sorry to say,
the serving of eviction papers
to those individuals who have
repeatedly ignored
the wishes of the court.
What court?
"Gallagher, Vernon Francis,
"has failed to answer
a variety of charges
"relating to benefit and council tax
fraud, amongst other things."
Well, nobody told me.
We have to look at this
as an opportunity.
It frees you from that cycle
of debt and dependency,
free to pursue a new start.
Temporary accommodation for you and
the boy. Make sure and call ahead.
St Helens?!
Do you get that sense of freedom...
being evicted so you can go forth
and fulfil your potential?
See it as an opportunity to give up
the fags for good. Change your life!
Fuck off, you bastard.
Look what you've done to me
I'll never fit any of my clothes
again.
In the delivery room, I want you
there,
with an extra-strength filter tipped
and a Zippo, ready to go.
I don't care whether they've
snipped the umbilical or not!
Grub up.
All nice and healthy for the baby.
Cosy!
How's the flat hunt going, Micky?
Oh, I've not started yet, y'know,
been a bit busy.
Life just takes over, doesn't?
You know what they say,
two's company.
Four's a party.
I can't believe I'm going to be
called "Uncle Micky" again.
Not... by blood.
No, but we're roomies, so she can
call me that if she wants.
I just called her "She"!
Just gonna have a dump,
kick me
mates out the spare room.
We have got to get him
out of this fucking house.
He won't take the hint.
Maybe we could move.
I better get going.
What you flogging today?
DVDs, bit of weed, fags,
homebrew, viagra, toastie makers...
they can't get
enough of the fucking toastie makers.
OMG, come and have a look at
this Kel it's absolutely enormous!
What time is it?
Something's up,
people running about all
over the place.
When did I get in?
About four.
I got caught up, I'm sorry.
Tomorrow's chip paper.
I'm off, you better think about how
you're going to make this up to me.
You're totally up shit creek.
Enough!
You're like a herd
of geese, squawk, squawk, squawk!
Gaggle.
What?
S'not a "herd of geese",
it's a "gaggle of geese".
You wouldn't say "a flock of dogs",
would you?
Half six this morning
bailiffs turned up.
DWP, who's that,
what's it stand for?
LOUD CHATTING
Any idea what they're going
on about?
Don't know, don't care.
Can't hang around here,
tell you that for no charge.
Where else are they supposed to go?
Fine, I'll go
and see what's going on.
I presume there's a story here.
Good night, was it?
Yeah.
Your missus put on a decent spread,
it's a pity you missed it.
She's a good woman, don't fuck it
up, I speak from experience.
I'll make it up to her.
What's going on?
Uh, arresting folk for false
claims.
Half the estate'll be in jail.
I think that's the plan.
Well, you know,
if you can't do the time, eh?
POLICE SIRENS
Dick.
What's the story, Ches?
Don't know, stormtroopers,
occupied territory.
Step back, please.
I'm a local business owner...
got a couple of questions.
Let her through.
Can I ask what's going on?
You are...?
Karen Maguire I run a pub
just up the road.
You are?
Oh, I'm so sorry, Carmen Kenaway,
Care Kenaway Solutions.
I'm on secondment with
Operation New Start.
You're evicting people?
We provide support to those
who most need it.
So... you're not evicting people?
Those defrauding government agencies
have all assistance suspended.
Including housing?
Karen leave it.
What?
We've got licenses to protect.
Don't open the door, Benny.
Don't open the door!
If you don't let them in,
they can't force entry...
Two streets so far, seven families.
It's got fuck all to do with us,
the last thing
we need is to draw attention.
They can't just evict people.
Pint, please.
Splitting families up, temporary
accommodation,
hostels, shelters all over the North
West.
Wigan, St. Helens, Liverpool...
That's worse than being homeless.
Any chance of some fucking service,
down here?
These families are in proper
trouble.
Everybody's got a sob story,
so forgive me if I can't get worked
up about it.
I've got problems of my own,
like where I'm going to house my
dependents.
Don't be stupid, we've put
Patty in our spare room.
I've got Aidan at ours.
And we've got Stella.
Well, don't all rush at once.
Maybe if you weren't such a...
I scrub up!
A cunt, I think
she was going to say.
You can't wash that off.
Well, fuck the lot of you.
Hello, officer.
I heard you were coming back.
Well, good luck.
They're not gonna make it easy.
So, what's happened?
No one told you?
You've been evicted Carl.
Patty's bunking at ours,
Aidan and Stella are staying
at the Maguire's, so everyone's safe.
And dad?
I'm sure we can make space for you.
I'm OK, thanks.
I'll sort something.
We'll have few drinks later,
celebrate you being back?
Oh, the prodigal Pig returns.
You let us get evicted?
Move along you're not fit company.
Oh, so, this is the plan?
Live rough,
sup the breakfast of champions?
How could you do this to me?
To you?!
Yes, to me, remember,
the one who brought you up.
Fucking shame of it what have
I done to deserve this?
It's a good job.
You're a police officer.
Fucking hell!
Yeah, fucking hell, yeah!
One of them.
Yeah, I am.
Job, pension, purpose.
You're no son of mine.
Oh, I'm devastated.
Has he joined the coppers?
Ah, I don't know.
Hello, hello, hello.
Y'all right?
Thought I might get a bite to eat.
Where've you been haven't
seen you in ages?
Doing my training.
You know that I've joined the...?
You bastard.
Welcome back, mate.
Besides not like they brainwashed
you is it?
You're still one of us.
Yeah, course.
Look at you, all grown up!
Where's the handcuffs
and the truncheon?
Don't graduate till next week,
get all the gear then.
I'm hoping
they'll let me bring a taser home.
Where are you crashing?
Don't know yet... just saw my Dad...
Stay with us
the more the merrier at the minute.
You sure?
Yeah, course.
C'mon, grab a box while you're at it.
Don't worry about that, mate,
on you go.
Jesus Christ!
How long FERRET have you been
stood there for?
Long enough to know you're
a fucking weirdo.
Pot, kettle CUNT black.
I don't like you being here
you should go.
I've got a message.
Like Jesus?
What?
Derren Brown? Magdalene?
No, fuckwit, for you.
And my ex.
Should I write it down?
You've got a babby coming,
and I know how much she wants that.
And, it's not the babby's fault
she's the spawn of a mental midget.
You said 'she'.
Yes I did, didn't I?
For what it's worth,
I don't wish you harm.
There'll be no trouble from me.
You're losing the circulation
to your hand.
Thank you. JAFFA!
Choccy's too big!
You might have to open the door.
Can you do that?
Oh! Wait a minute
I might have found another one.
There's more than one way to skin a
cat, Feeney,
little bit of initiative.
Hey, you're doing a good job.
Time someone took this
place to task.
And, er, what's your name?
Jackson Powell.
Jackson Powell...
What is it, Miss, what is it?
Oh, you dirty bastard!
Get up, get up!
Isn't that the person
we saw this morning?
I think it is, Miss, yes. Get Up!
Feeney, Feeney, wait.
This is an opportunity.
I mean, look at 'im.
How long's old Malky lived 'ere?
Don't remember a time when he didn't.
And have you ever seen him
put his hand in his pocket?
Not once, the tight-fisted fucker!
He's been nursing that
for four hours. RIGHT!
Time to get a shift on! Hooverville
won't build itself, y'know?
What you doing?
They're getting a bit cosy.
I told them they could crash 'ere!
Well, that can't be legal.
So un-tell them.
Tweet me, and complain.
Like me Uncle Terry, that.
This one time, he beat the
living shit out of my Aunty Sheila.
Did she deserve it?
What?
Did she deserve the beating?
I don't know, I was only little.
Anyway that's not the story... Argh!
She didn't deserve it,
because hitting a woman
isneveracceptable, understand?
This is an important lesson for you,
since you've married our Mam.
I understand! I do!
Give it a proper wash!
Hey!
Got a few kegs I need to shift
up from the cellar.
Give us a hand?
Earn your keep while you're 'ere.
Yeah, no probs.
What was that for?
You've made summat of yourself.
And you don't let anybody
fuck it up for you.
So...
How are we gonna make
this work, then?
How d'you mean?
Monthly retainer.
Little bit extra if we need
something more specific.
Fuck off! I'm a probationer
for two years!
I'll be mainly making cuppas and
having the piss taken out of me.
Yeah, well, call it a long-term
investment, then.
You'll be able to buy yourself
a nice little runaround before long.
Look, I'll never land you in it, J.
You know that.
But I'll always be me own man.
We can't talk about this again.
Besides, half of these are
doubled-up, you tight bastard!
Yeah, couldn't get to the
fucking bank before it shut,
could I?
So what we shifting?
These big bastards over 'ere.
Hey, they don't skimp on expenses
for the corporate raiders, d'they?
I won't lie to you.
So you feeling better?
What? I regard you bringing me
here as a hostile action.
You were destitute!
You ungrateful pig.
Temporarily, I think you'll find!
Daniella! Please excuse Mrs Feeney.
We're a very close team,
and she's naturally protective.
"Mrs?" Really?
Somebody need a passport?
Er, would you leave us, please?
So, Frank, I am curious.
Were there no family that
could take you in? No friends?
Social evolution in practice.
What?
I wear glasses.
Right?
These. Slippery slope.
Galapagos Islands round our way.
If you're weak, you'll be savaged.
If I am fucking, this, man!
Cunts in this place will eat me
alive, without a second thought.
Thanks to you lot!
My lot?
Oh, come on, don't pretend
you're "Of the people."
Your fucking shoes alone would buy
a three-bed semi in my street(!)
Come on! People are, y'know,
they're tired of this "them and us"
mentality, aren't they?
Always seems to be the Old Etonians
telling the rest we live
in a classless society
as they pass laws to deregulate
around their investments.
The old divides don't apply.
It's about survival, nowadays.
Hey, your neighbours weren't slow
to cast you out, hmm?
D'you think they're worried about
what's become of you now?
I suspect not.
We want the same thing.
You scratch my back...
Oh, God!
Well, I wondered when
this was coming up.
OK.
No more free lunches, eh?
Oh! I was thinking more...
information, and less...
penis.
Derek Molinari.
What a fucking chancer!
Punches in for his shift
at Meinhoffer's.
Ching!
And then heads out to the bookies
all day,
only stepping out to sign-on
every Thursday.
Bet he's not the worst!
Oh, not by a long shot!
I tell you who's a lying twat!
He never shares his smokes.
Biscuit-arse Pettigrew.
Ronnie, to his mother.
Apart from 'aving BO that could
fell a fucking buffalo at 20 paces,
he's claiming on four
different addresses.
And does he share
the goodies around?
Did Jesus have a rubber cross?
Thought I was going to
run out of tape.
Would you like me to have
your room cleared?
That's not my room!
Ooh, I wouldn't let that stench
anywhere near the place
where I lay my head.
No, I'm over here.
OK, would you like a wake-up call,
Miss? I could bring you a coffee?
(If you were mine,
(I'd have a cast made
of your magnificent breasts,
(and this tongue would probe
(and plunge deep... )
Front-bottom, not back...
Did you say something?
No, Miss, I was just
thinking, erm...
Night, Feeney.
Good night, Miss.
DOG BARKING
What the fuck?
Argh, I don't carry cash!
Me arse isn't clean!
(MICKY LAUGHS LOUDLY)
Go on!
TELEVISION BLARES
Yes, Kelly?
(VOICE ON TELEVISION) All you're
planning to do is sit back
and carry on selling 100 quid's
worth of weed a week!
Micky, d'you mind? Can't be
doing with telly first thing.
Oh, it's brilliant, this one!
They get the DNA and they find out...
There's no fucking milk!
Marty's got something to ask you.
Well, see, I...
You need to move out.
What?
We're nesting.
We need room for the baby, mate.
But I was gonna help you, you know.
Like the Three Musketeers.
No, we're like the two musketeers,
and you're like a bloke
who insists on crashing with us,
and won't take a fucking hint!
You've been hinting?
In neon, with megaphones! Had a
biplane fly past the other day,
trailing a banner. "Micky,
have the sense you were born with
"and get the fuck out."
You're a brilliant flatmate...
No, you're right.
Your needs are greater.
Don't be like that!
I'll be gone in an hour.
Think you were direct enough?
Why can't you crash
in the dormobile?
Oh, I don't get the keys for that!
They know I'd sell the rust bucket!
Don't wash your gonads in the sink!
Other people have to brush
their teeth there!
Where you gonna kip tonight?
Wherever I lay my hat, son.
I was born under a wandering star.
I need no man. I am a rock.
A rock? Frank, you're washing
yourself in me brother's gaffe,
and rolling on deodorant
supplied by the bollock-washer!
Trust me, it's every man
for himself.
Only the strongest will survive.
Don't... Don't do that.
CHATTERING
Keep your strength!
All for one, one for all.
You don't fool me
for a fucking minute!
All right, Shane,
what's the abuse today?
Go on! Do your worst, I'm a big boy.
You all right?
I got you something.
What am I looking at?
All of 'em! Any one you like.
Might as well aim high.
Time to move on.
Finally!
What if I don't want to?
I like it here.
It's what we always said we'd do,
when I graduated.
I think we were wrong to want that.
I think we're right.
Mate, you need to make
the most of it while you can.
Random drugs tests and all that.
Fuck off!
Besides, I don't think I
can go through with it.
What?
Passing out ceremony.
So you did all the training,
but you're not gonna graduate?
What's the point in that?
I can't, not...
Not without me Dad's blessing.
Fuck your Dad!
If I go, who's gonna look after 'im?
Look, he's a survivor.
If there's no-one there to
protect him from himself,
he'll be dead within 18 month.
I can't do that to him.
I can't let him cut me off.
DOOR BANGS
Miss, no-one's answering their doors!
DOOR SLAMS
I haven't the patience for this.
Call a town meeting.
Put our cards on the table.
Are you sure?
What we're doing is for the good
of these people.
It's time they understood that.
That's 75% of benefit claims
in this area are fraudulent...
They're not fraudulent, they're
rejected. There's a difference.
Parliamentary procedure!
Miss Kenaway has the floor.
If you want to make an
interjection, approach the
microphone and the chair
will recognise you.
You heard me.
MURMURS OF AGREEMENT
The thing is, you have got to
pay your way and, more importantly...
Don't lose your head.
This matters to me.
Why?
Because if I fuck them,
I fuck myself.
I don't buy into all this
nobility bollocks.
Yeah, you do. You can't fool me.
I know you.
But we can't go on like this.
Less than 15% of residents pay
any council tax at all.
No wonder!
Order!
Why...
Why should anyone pay
council tax round here?
The state of the roads!
Half the streetlights haven't
worked in a year.
APPLAUSE AND MURMURS OF AGREEMENT
You're making my point for me.
The Chatsworth is a failed estate.
It might be a shithole,
but it's our shithole!
No-one wants to move here.
You can't expect the authorities
to keep on throwing
good money after bad.
Invest.
CHEERING AND APPLAUSE
Right, OK, I know for a fact
that someone in this room
works at the Meinhoff brewery,
and is claiming disability benefit.
Someone else, lives in... Anchor Way,
is claiming on
four separate addresses.
Swing a cat, and you'll hit
half a dozen. That'snotthe point.
Order!
Well, what is the point?
I'm waiting.
Stop punishing people who can't
defend themselves.
We're not punishing anyone.
Yeah, you are.
This places sticks in your craw
because we're a dent on
the balance sheet.
And the fucking balance sheet
is your god, correct?
CHEERING
This operation will continue
whether you co-operate or not.
Fine.
Bring it on.
CHEERING AND APPLAUSE
You're barred!
Why do I get the feeling I've
just been set up?
Because you have.
Told you I knew you.
You do realise we've just
declared war?
Whatare you doing?
How d'you mean?
I told you that stuff in confidence.
You're the one who doesn't
believe in society.
Doesn't mean I want to
join in the goose-stepping!
Oh, this isn't about class.
We're not the SS.
It's about people
getting away with it.
They bought shares in utilities,
and satellite dishes
when the going was good.
They?
Who arethey?
They are the people who might be
a little bit funny
if they knew that you and me
had been chatting.
Keep your ears open, Frank.
I want to know whattheyare doing.
Shit.
20 cigs. Come on.
No.
Why the fuck not?
Cos you're a tosser.
Serve him, Ches.
It's all right, forget it.
I think I've just lost me craving.
You should be proud of Carl.
Proud? Proud?! Of that traitor?
Yeah!
Not the traitor bit, though.
What is your problem?
What, the truth? Yeah.
You are not like
your brothers and sisters.
You are destined for
far lesser things.
Cheeky bastard.
You were my one great hope.
The salvation of my loins.
We fuck up.
We turn the other cheek.
We run away.
It's our DNA.
Rotten to the core.
Like father like son.
I'm nothing like you.
Ohhh!
I'm not.
What are you doing?
You're freaking me out, you tit.
This job won't last.
The real you's in there
fighting to get out.
And I am counting down the days...
Know what gets me, though?
Some fucker's grassing them up,
passing on details, and that.
It's not right.
I fucking hate grasses.
Yeah, they know how to
treat them in Iraq and Iran,
you know, in the Middle East.
Cut their heads off, man...
Wha-a-ahhh...
No messing about.
They decapitate you
for shopping someone?
Yeah! Big, curly sword. Wha-tcha!
They've got the right idea, mate.
Nah, nah, nah, nah.
The Irish,
they had the right idea.
They tarred and feathered the
informants, tied 'em to lampposts...
Come on! Please.
Could get hypothermia.
Fucking bird flu, maybe.
Fuck off!
Like turkeys at Christmas.
Morning.
Morning, sir.
CHEERING
Yeah, fuck off.
Our very own little Che Guevara!
Who's that?
- The one on the T-shirts.
- Footballer?
Yeah.
What's your fucking hair like,
today?
Where's Karen Maguire, please?
Kiss my dick.
Perhaps your mother has
better manners.
I'll tear your fucking head off
and shit in your neck.
I'm here.
Your licence to sell alcohol
on these premises has suspended
pending investigation.
Investigation of what?
Several possible contraventions
of the Licensing Act 2003,
including letting patrons
spend the night at the location.
You don't have the right
to serve these.
Oh, this is a
multi-agency operation.
It's tobacco and alcohol too.
It's across the board.
Fine! Go ahead, suspend the licence.
We'll give the drink away.
CHEERING
What?!
We'll give it away.
We can take the hit.
This place doesn't close. Ever.
You won't starve us out.
I'll have a triple voddie,
Rockefeller.
Could you help me out, please?
I've been in here since Tuesday.
Could you not put a little more
on the deposit?
For an extra 2,000
you could get this one.
It has a downstairs toilet.
Be perfect for me.
You?
You're going to have to
get used to the idea
that this could be
a permanent living arrangement.
You're welcome to stay until you
sort out alternative accommodation,
but for the first time in my life,
I could be approved for a mortgage
and it's for my family's future,
only.
We may never get our house back.
KNOCKING AT DOOR
You wouldn't cast a destitute
pensioner out onto the streets?
If I had to, yeah.
Jackson Powell?
Yeah?
We're from Operation New Start.
You claimed income support
whilst under going teacher training.
Yes, yes, but that's...
You also received a maintenance
grant to the sum of £2,906.
No, no. It's not...
You don't under...
and a teacher trainee bursary
to the sum of £6,000.
You can't expect a man
who has family to provide for
to live off that alone.
On family tax credits
over a period of four years.
You're not listening to me.
My family need it.
Every penny goes on our survival!
I'm like you.
An honest working man.
That's the last of it.
Micky...
I'm... sorry...
We owe you big time.
If circumstances were different,
we'd love you to stay...
I could babysit...
No, get the fuck out!
Get a fucking life!
Don't have to tell me twice.
Oh, you going somewhere?
I'm moving out.
You all are. Council-sponsored
court-sanctioned eviction order.
(CHUCKLES)
I'm being prosecuted.
Can you believe that?
He invited them in,
made them a cup tea,
which, by the way,
I've noticed neither has touched,
and offered a light snack
for the privilege.
They've made a mistake.
We're not dole scroungers.
There's no point.
I'm signing off, anyway.
I'm a qualified teacher now.
I've got a post at St Morrissey's...
My husband has no comment.
Both of you,
out of my fucking house now.
Not another word!
We'll be in touch.
Did you see the way
he just looked at me?
Like they would Frank Gallagher! How
fucking dare they? I'll fix this.
That's fine, then, isn't it?
Just in case, put this pot
away somewhere safe.
Cos after that lot get
through with us, at
least we'll have something
left to piss in.
Pasta do you for lunch?
Oh, I can't stand
feckin' Italian food...
Pasta would be lovely.
Four quid! Come on!
Can't sell them in the shop.
Look at 'em all. What have we done?
Come on, boys!
Get your pennies out!
CHEERING
God knows.
Pint and an orange.
Put a large voddie in it.
Bairn's got to get
used to it sometime.
Go on, what you having?
No, you're all right, thanks,
I'm fine.
SILENCE FALLS
CLANGING
For fuck's sake,
is it panto season(?)
What have you done, Frank?
Nothing. I've just... had me fill,
that's all.
Frank?
I haven't done anything!
You're refusing a free drink?
I'm not... I'm just...
He's got a guilty conscience.
About what? You threw me out.
He's lying!
Can't even look me in the eye.
(SIGHS)
Swear on the kids' lives.
I swear.
Swear on Man City.
On your mother's memory.
MURMURING
Grass!
She's got us over a barrel.
If I don't...
Fucking hell!
No, listen!
If I don't weigh her in with info,
she's going to fucking
hang me out to dry.
MURMURING
Well, come on, then!
Come on!
JEERING
Bring it on, you pack of hyenas!
Got fuck all to lose, anyway!
Come on!
I'm just a fucking punchbag,
aren't I?
One man's torture is another
man's justified measures.
I mean, I don't know if I believe
in punishment for it's own sake.
I'm more a rehabilitation
man myself.
I'd have no conscience about it.
I want to see him suffer.
Two-faced grassing bastard!
They might cut your knob off.
You can still live knobless.
Always thought it'd cause you
to bleed to death,
but apparently not.
You can't kill Frank.
It'd be like drowning a puppy.
I've drowned loads of puppies.
Trust me, it's fuck-all like this.
Still carrying a torch
for him, are we?
Yeah(!) I don't want him murdered,
so I'm carrying a torch for him.
Is that your logic?
There's loads of people
I don't want murdered,
so that must make me
a right slapper(!)
'It does turn you
into a soprano, though.'
You know, high voice and all that.
Sopranos used to be dead
valuable in history.
When I say soprano,
I do mean castrato, obviously.
MUFFLED CRIES
The Pope had a whole choir
of them in the 16th century.
MUFFLED SHOUTING
Burn me, shoot me, drown me
at sea! I don't care what you do,
but stop fucking talking!
Punishing him for its own sake makes
no sense. How does it benefit us?
It isn't supposed to benefit us.
Maybe it is.
Look, he spied for them, yeah?
Why can't he spy for us?
Find out what they're
up to, bring it here?
And maybe pass on some duff
information to them,
while he's at it?
What, Frank Gallagher ...
double agent?!
Fuck me, we must be desperate!
Look out, Mata Hari's
on the case
Oh, ha-fucking-ha(!)
I don't have to do this.
Shouldn't have blabbed your fucking
mouth off in the first place!
You owe us, all of us. Big time.
I know... that!
That's why I'm trying
to put things right, aren't I?
Finding out what they're
up to so you...
wehave got a fighting
chance of stopping them.
Good luck.
Big, big, big plans.
Hm, pray tell.
It's bribery.
Need to keep a close
eye on your team.
Someone on the inside's passing
info in exchange for readies.
Get Frank another drink, yeah?
I think it helps him to talk
more... freely.
(LAUGHS) OK.
So Frank, what sort of information
are they supplying exactly?
It's like addresses of where
you're going to swoop next.
When are you swooping?
You know, matter of interest?
Carmen! Carmen!
I couldn't find you!
I have no sympathy or time for this.
I love you!
I used to be at
your beck and call...
Oh, great(!)
Carmen may be some time.
Ah. I'm in no rush.
All right, love. Your virtue's
safe with me. I may need glasses,
but I'm not totally Stevie Wonder.
(SLURRED) Where the fuck
has Carmen got to?
We won't see her now.
This always happens
when he shows up
and she falls for it every time.
Husband. Going through a divorce.
He's a drunk, a womaniser.
He'll have had his way with her
and then run back
to the younger model.
Men are bastards!
Do you have a little lady crush?
Hm?
I, er... I touched her boob once,
while she was asleep.
The left one.
I just... brushed my palm
across her nipple.
I sleep on it now.
Hard to tell,
cos I'm so pissed, but...
I might've just come in me pants.
You're all stuffed, though.
You know that.
What?
It's political, like immigration
No government can be seen
to be supporting benefits.
The underbelly is a cancer.
Shall we have another drink?
Oh, no!
Go on! You know you want to.
Ah, go on!
Oh, all right. Then we call
it a day. I need to, er...
Leave the table here.
Where's Feeney?
GLASS CLINKING
What you doing?
I just... I...
I dropped me glasses.
You look shagged.
You going somewhere?
I don't know who you are anymore.
Oh, I'm going somewhere!
I don't want to be
like everyone else!
I want two parents.
You're so keen to move on.
I think you should.
You're not that stupid!
15 years of marriage?
15 years?
Letitia! I wouldn't want you
looking down your nose at us.
Maybe one of your better
class of mates can put you up.
In.
In!
I won't be blackmailed!
Not a fucking word!
There you go, love.
Cheers.
Oh, come on, I've earned it!
If I had my way, you'd be propping
up a bridge somewhere by now.
Oh what, you going to stuff
your gums with orange peel?
Tell me Luca Brazi
sleeps with the fishes?
You don't scare me!
We're fucked!
They're going to evict
as many as they can,
but there's no new tenants.
No-one's moving in. They're going
to keep the houses empty, permanent.
Well, that's stupid.
No, that's clever.
Left empty, the houses'll rot.
But then no-one'll
want to live here.
Exactly what they want.
They're looking to shut down
the whole estate.
No houses, no pub,
no punters, no people.
This'll be one of those places
people used to live.
Well, I for one
am lying down to no bully.
I'm with you.
We need a plan.
I wear them for reading sometimes.
I wear contacts.
I need 'em for watching telly.
I don't need glasses.
I only wear them cos fellas can't
resist the slutty secretary look.
How are we going to fight them?
They've got cops and dogs.
They've got tasers.
We need to be smart.
Guerrilla warfare.
Yeah, French resistance!
But... we're not French.
We're all in the same fucking boat.
(FRANK) 'All right, so maybe
I was a bit premature.
'These are difficult days.
'You know, post banking crisis,
'post comprehensive spending review,
'cuts, cuts and more cuts.
'And kick the living shit
out of the underbelly
'cos they're least equipped
to defend themselves.
'The more things change,
'the more they stay the same, yeah?
'Society is dead.
'Long live society.'
Thanks to you, these people
have lost their homes.
£150,000?!
That's her bonus, if she manages
to permanently board up 120 houses.
Partner couldn't make it again?
'I can't do it on my own.'
I'll mess it up!
I'll mess it up! You will if you
carry on ignoring your baby.
Upset by a couple
of evictions, are you?
Ten years from now, this
place will be wasteland!
She has destroyed people's lives.
She's caused total mayhem!
You know what hormones are like? I
really need to go and ride me boy.
Oh, baby!
Sync and corrected by APOLLO
www.addic7ed.com
MOANING
There's spunk stains on the
pillowcase and dried-on lubricant!
It's a working house.
DOOR OPENING
Have you got a little stiffie
under there for me?
No, I've really not!
You'll come round eventually!