And it's got fancy swimming
clubs and all the big mansions
going up into the hills.
But the camps are totally
exempt from that.
Ahmad was born in Lebanon.
His dad was born in Lebanon.
But they're not considered
Lebanese.
360 degrees of their life
is consumed with
living in the camps.
But because he started making
films and getting noticed for
making those films, he's been
able to get beyond the borders
of the camp.
He got invited to go up to the
mountains to a rich French
boarding school and exchange
ideas and creativity with
other young, budding
filmmakers.
It's like France up here.
It's nice.
It's like French.
So I guess this is some
sort of humanitarian
project that they give.
Palestinians can come up to the
nice French high school
and learn things.
It's nice here.
It's a lot nicer
than the camp.
And you like coming up
to the mountains?
AHMAD: Yeah.
I like this area and
I like this place.
SHANE SMITH: Yeah.
AHMAD: We cannot be late.
SHANE SMITH: OK.
AHMAD: We have to go inside.
SHANE SMITH: During the year,
this is a boarding school for
rich Lebanese families.
In the summer, there's a program
for young Palestinian
filmmakers to come up,
take a break from
the camps, and learn.
MALE SPEAKER:
[SPEAKING LEBANESE]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
SHANE SMITH: But even here,
the kids can't escape the
political situations that
exist in the camps.
This film workshop turned
into a political rally.
MALE SPEAKER:
[SPEAKING LEBANESE]
SHANE SMITH: You know, all these
kids from the camps get
a sort of pass for the summer to
come up here into the rich
neighborhood.
It's really nice, it's clean,
it's beautiful.
It reminds me of France.
And then you come in in the
morning, and they're like, OK,
welcome to the Black
Death Organization.
MALE SPEAKER:
[SPEAKING LEBANESE]
[CHANTING]
SHANE SMITH: Politics are
embedded into the Palestinian
mindset at the basic level.
You see it every day there.
And you especially see it in
modern-day Palestinian cinema.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
SHANE SMITH: What we found at
the film retreat is that even
though Palestinians are
hyper-political and they do
grow up surrounded by violence,
there is a group of
Palestinian grassroots
filmmakers that are making
really thought-provoking films
about their situation.
Can you tell us where
we are right now?
SHANE SMITH: And you're
the coordinator
for the whole event?
SHANE SMITH: Wow.
And you also make films.
HICHAM KAYED:
[SPEAKING LEBANESE]
MALE SPEAKER:
FEMALE SPEAKER:
[SPEAKING LEBANESE]
MALE SPEAKER:
SHANE SMITH: And so how did the
other Palestinians get to
Berlin that you interviewed
there?
SHANE SMITH: They
smuggle them.
HICHAM KAYED: Yeah.
Yeah.
MALE SPEAKER:
[SPEAKING LEBANESE]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
SHANE SMITH: This story is kind
of weird for us to report
on for a couple of reasons.
One, because we're so close
to it and it's kind of
personal for us.
And also because what it shows
is that film has become woven
into our culture.
And these people with the
worst conditions, with
nothing, yearn to tell their
stories by making films.
And this gives us hope that our
film and future won't be
dominated by vapid and vacant
escapist Hollywood cartoon
franchises.
And two, that maybe Palestinian
kids will see
Ahmad and his friends' example
and drop their rocks and
instead pick up cameras.
[MUSIC PLAYING]