we just kind of lived
in this weird
apartment in Pacific Beach.
Yeah, he stayed with me
for almost a year.
At least it felt like a year.
Yeah, it was a Skate house and
we lived right across the
street from the Alien
Workshop house.
That's how those relationships
started.
JOSH KALIS: Yeah, the Alien
house was right across the
street and it was right
up my alley.
I mean, it was like Clyde
Singleton, Kelly Bird, Drake
Jones, Lenny Kirk,
and Rob Dyrdek.
I mean, all those guys were
there, and it was dominoes,
dice, 40s and weed.
And that's what I liked.
So I hung out with them
all the time.
ROB DYRDEK: And we lived in the
most psycho party house
that was like--
not only was it like the whole
Alien team and [INAUDIBLE] and
Weese and just madness.
Like one of the craziest times
in my entire life, where not
only the four of us lived there,
but then we just--
it was just absolute mayhem
every single night.
Like chicks and rolling
dice every night.
It was like the most psycho
skate house of all time.
JAMIE THOMAS: No, they had the
party house and they had
chicks and stuff.
It was like, it was
obvious, you know?
I never got it.
I never really--
I thought it was cool.
We were like skate homies.
And then he would go over and
hang out at Alien house to get
into like, the party
scene and whatever.
Smoking weed or cigarettes,
whatever.
It was cool.
I'd go over there too sometimes,
and I wouldn't stay
as long as Josh.
Josh would stay every night.
Like we lived like across the
street, so he would just walk
back to my house at like
3:00 in the morning.
And then we'd go skate
the next day.
And then after we were done
skating at night, we'd get
some food together, and then
he'd go over to the Alien
house and hang out.
And I would, like,
I don't know.
I'd hang out with a girl or
watch a movie or something I
had such a mellow lifestyle.
I was like, whatever.
Two totally different worlds.
So basically he lived with me
for like six months to a year.
And we made the Heavy
Metal video.
And he was killing it in
the Heavy Metal zone.
And we were filming every day.
We were just doing random
lines in California.
And it was sick.
And we had a really good
time filming that part.
It was a lot of fun.
And he was skating so good.
He three-flipped a
trash can off the
smallest bump in the world.
Like basically, it was
like a little ripple
in the parking lot.
And he three-flipped it straight
over a trash can.
At the time, it was
like phenomenal.
Like, nobody had seen that.
I remember when that came out,
people were tripping.
Just the way he did
tricks, too.
It was so proper
and so unique.
MIKE BLABAC: A few years later I
moved to SF and he was there
with Jamie, right when
they were filming for
a Toy Machine video.
And then I watched his part
and I was tripping on how,
what an amazing skater he'd
become from that skate rat
that I was chilling with, trying
to figure out how to
shoot photos of three,
four years earlier.
PATRICK O'DELL: Is that him?
MIKE BLABAC: Yeah.
That's his switch crook.
I remember he'd just filmed that
a day or two prior in the
first Toy Machine.
JOSH KALIS: It was cool, but
Jamie, Jamie was always real
cool and real nice.
But I mean, he's a work horse
and he's got a different work
ethic than me.
I told you my work ethic is
like, I need to be enjoying
what I do and having fun.
Then I'm a work horse.
Jamie wants to make sure
he goes and gets
what he needs to get.
And I wasn't that dude.
I like to hang out and work.
And he liked to go to work.
And we just didn't
click like that.
JAMIE THOMAS: Oh my god.
MALE SPEAKER: You
all right, man?
MALE SPEAKER: You bumped
your bill?
JAMIE THOMAS: Oh my god.
ROB DYRDEK: I mean, he lived
with straight-edge, hardcore
Jamie Thomas at Jamie
Thomas's rawest.
Living in a little apartment
in PB, like grinding, like
just building what he
would later become.
And you know, as much as Jamie
had helped him and--
he just wasn't like that.
He just wasn't in that
sort of mindset.
JOSH KALIS: He played too many
practical jokes on me, you
know what mean?
Like, I was kind of a serious
dude who was just getting out
of, like, being a tough guy.
I just couldn't get
down with it.
I couldn't get down
with Ed's crazy--
I couldn't eat hamburgers in the
house, just because like
he's this crazy vegetarian and
the smell bothered him.
So I had to eat outside
all the time.
I just--
I just couldn't deal with it.
We were two completely
different people.
Basically, he smoked, and I used
to buy him food, but I
wouldn't buy him cigarettes
because I was kind of like
straight-edge dude or whatever
at that time.
And I just thought it was lame
that, like, he had these
addictions that I
had to support.
So I just refused to
buy him cigarettes.
So I swear, he basically just
would hustle me for
cigarettes.
He would like, he would ask me,
like, dude, if I do this
trick in this many tries, will
you get me a pack of
cigarettes?
[SCREAM]
So I would like bet him
cigarettes for tricks.
I remember one time he won a
carton off me and he was so,
so psyched.
I asked him to three-flip
this flat gap.
I told him I'd give him a carton
of cigarettes if he
made it next try or something.
And he made it.
It was pretty gnarly
at the time.
JOSH KALIS: What's up, fool!
Ha-ha!
I want my cigarettes, boy.
JAMIE THOMAS: [LAUGHING]
How you gonna skate that
good for cigarettes.
MALE SPEAKER: It's funny.
A lot of people would think that
you wouldn't fit in with
the, like the Toy
Machine vibe.
Like you know what I mean?
It's always almost trivia.
Like, Josh Kalis used to
be on Toy Machine.
JOSH KALIS: Shit, I didn't
fit in that.
That's why I quit, you know?
ANTHONY CLARAVALL: Even
when I met him, he
was over Toy Machine.
I remember going to his
apartment, and like, I
remember looking in his
closet one time.
We were in his room and he
looked in his closet and he
had, like, stacks of t-shirts,
stacks of Toy Machine
t-shirts, in plastic.
Like brand new.
And I mean, to me
that was a trip.
I mean, I was like, wow, man.
And he was like, yeah, man.
That's all garbage.
I ain't gonna ride
for Toy Machine.
And I was just thinking
like, damn, dude.
I kinda want a t-shirt, but I
don't want to ask for one.
JOSH KALIS: I was now into
going to San Francisco.
I stayed with Drake Jones
all the time.
And he was actually working out
a little thing for me to
get on Real.
And I was riding Real boards,
and like, I was
going to ride for Real.
100%.
JAMIE THOMAS: I kind of
saw it coming, though.
He moved to San Francisco and
kind of just got a whole new
crew and stuff.
We started talking a little
less and less.
He was still riding for Toy
Machine, but he was wearing
different shoes every
time I saw him.
He was on flow for three or four
different shoe companies.
JOSH KALIS: Yeah.
JAMIE THOMAS: I think he felt
like he fit in more at Real,
you know, I mean, like you said,
Toy Machine was Ed, who
was kind of artsy and quirky, to
himself, kind of about his
whole vegan vibe.
And I was hard-core
skate-focused.
And I don't know, man.
I can imagine why.
I see the fit-in, you know?
He felt like he fit in.
And so the trade show came up.
And Drake Jones came down and he
was like, yo, Thibault and
those guys, they're ready
to do it, right now.
And I was like, that's
what's up.
All right, I'm gonna go
quit Toy Machine.
Right now.
Right this minute.
And he was like, all right.
So I'm walking down the ASR
hallway and I make a right and
I just bump face-to-face
with Dyrdek.
And Dyrdek was like, where
you going right now?
I was like, I'm going
to quit Toy Machine.
And he was like, for who?
And I was like--
before I could even say Real,
he was like, we'll cut you a
check right now.
And I was like, oh shit.
Let's do it.
And that was it.
I went and met Chris Carter and
he wrote me a check right
there, I think it was like
$250 or some shit.
And he was like, boop.
ROB DYRDEK: It was really a
mutual, like, I would love to
ride for Alien.
You know?
It would be so sick if I
was on like Alien team.
Like you guys have
so much fun.
That'd be sick.
And we're like, dude,
you're on.
If you want to be
on, you're on.
Like no, don't say,
really though?
And we're like, yeah,
you're on.
And that's really
how it worked.
That's how he works.
He'll be like, oh, like say
something, like that's sick.
And like, yep.
You're on
JOSH KALIS: Once I figured
out that Alien was a
real option and I--
that's where I hung out
with every day.
And I had to do it.
I was like, fuck, those
are my homies.
Boom.
JAMIE THOMAS: Yeah, of course
it was a bummer, man.
I mean, I'd--
I was--
you know, like any time when you
like help somebody out and
you like help them out of
whatever situation they're in,
I kind of was like the dude he
leaned on for a long time, for
emotional and financial support,
like in every aspect.
And when you give like that, I
mean, it obviously feels good
to help somebody out.
But if they're able to just
break it off at like a
moment's notice, it feels kind
of gnarly, you know?
It's almost like you're
in like a
relationship or something.
Not to sound too sappy,
but it was pretty,
it was pretty heavy.
I remember being
pretty bummed.
Like it rocked me for like a
week or two, where I was just,
like, lump in your throat.
It sucks.
It was never really that
weird between us.
I was a little bit butt-hurt
for a while,
but I got over it.
And when I'd see him, I'd always
act like it was cool,
even if I was a little
bitter still.
It was all right, man.
I got over it.
We just moved on.
At any rate, I saw him like
five years later.
I came through Philly and
he like, sat me down.
We were away from the
crew for a minute.
And he was just like man, I just
want to tell you how much
I appreciate you helping
me out back in the day.
If it weren't for you I wouldn't
be in skating right
now, and I just kind of
want you to know that.
And I was like, cool, man.
Thanks.
JOSH KALIS: Yeah, I got to--
I got to give way more credit to
my dude Jamie Thomas, man.
Like that dude made all this
shit possible for me.
When he gave me the opportunity
to come out here,
and like paid for me for six,
eight months or whatever, just
for me to like turn around and
quit the company that I rode
for with him--
I mean, that dude pretty
much paved the
whole way for me, man.
I guess if I owe anyone in this
shit, it would be him.
You know what I mean?
He's a good dude.
PATRICK O'DELL: It would have
been funny if you were in
Welcome to Hell.
JOSH KALIS: Yeah, I think
I just missed that one.
I just missed Welcome to Hell.
You know, actually, it was
probably a good thing I missed
Welcome to Hell, because I had
already broken both ankles and
a foot by that time, and
I just couldn't be a
stair-jumper or a rail-jumper
anymore.
And I don't know what the hell
I would have done if I would
have stayed and Jamie take
me to the rail spots.
Like, oh my god.