and he explained you know his presidency
and that he was a look
at mysore estimated
interview session or confident in what
he's done
in who use
so let's get to some of those
off some quotes
uh... first
izzy happy no longer being president all
you apeksha
he says the liberation of not feeling
like i've got
to be in the limelight
uh... is great and it is in fact
liberating as he explains
that is what we've been saying about
which for a long time he loved that he
won the presidency twice kind of
neal of the glory of it when he didn't
want the job
he was exhausted from the job
that's why he broke every record there
was a number of occasions they see that
it was that all my god is love the new
president didn't
like and this is a more
so he's thrilled to be an ex-president
right now
when asking him look
don't go away you know some of these
issues that are relevant today
answers now now let me tell you the real
reason one discuss him knowing about
here cared about him in the first place
he is one of the women anyone out to his
daddy
it's not like it's clinton's backing
them up at ninety one when i was
laughing with the economy what we can do
with pakistan using it all thank god i
have been trying to figure out hurt my
head again thinking about what is your
best bet
so they ask him
hehehehe what's your field of expertise
is wet no
and express this great quote
people ask me
what economy my answers
wide-angle higheredjobs or i've i've
organised isn't delivered a big peta at
that's the guy who was president for
eight years
what do you have a kind
hyatt cast
jesus christ and i a complicated
question
and that's for macro-economic outlook
has no
you see that
hubert saturn of cold sweat when he
asked miserable growers like that
isn't on our
but again not a lot like what are the
president
unfit
hate get georgie why do you like this
quote
i could tell me what it's like
this summer's is inherent in stores and
presents
fee ends that loves beer ads for it
better comment on the air and sea level
and read a letter in the items
you know i guess that was done
knows president
so uh...
drawers
what what is your legs you know a time
by compassionate conservative center
well he's says the
proves the point quote
the best way for people understand what
i meant by compassionate conservative
is a lot of the programs we implemented
and look at the results
lou the results
iraq war over a hundred thousand sleeves
killed more than five thousand marcus
gill
about forty thousand
wounded you know when you put private
contractors and several over trillion
dollars wasalam out war
the disastrous response that working to
trina
and the list goes on and on just one of
the results
and gigantic devasena trillion dollar
deficit he left behind
when he applied all five hundred billion
dollar surplus standard room
by bill clinton just look at the results
that you get a sense
of whether this man was a compassionate
conservative
or got anything done at all and he knows
any notices an embarrassment
so ask her about his record who lent out
telling this to see says he's not
interested infant reporting or self-pity
now i guess a successful person like
bill gates we give you the answer
we sell out it is unfair pouring out on
parade and self-pity
only a person
whose loaded with self-pity
and realizes he's a false is dope or
vendors
when jack that was abenney what warren
buffett say that why would bill
they say that why would a successful
third president like bill clinton said
that
they wouldn't say that
boyce says a 'cause he's embarrassing
even to himself
but he's gonna pretend to be comfortably
many says
much of my presidency was defined by
things but you didn't know so we want to
have happened
and by the way what those things are two
of those things with you getting elected
in the first place
or being present
and what it is great excuses as always
is it's easy to forget what life was
like
when a decision was made
regarding iraq
in other words
side we made the right decision but we
were in a panic and so uh... i don't
know i i don't let racked
i don't even believe that because of the
sixties he's got
uh... but nonetheless
that he goes back to his old ways
welfare of the stranded that's when he
talked about
the characters in the place including
george w_ bush
he said what i give them is a certain on
the current confidence
and hear the question here
i'm katherine decisions were made
the right way
an alright yeah
that he doesn't want you to be in that
quote
he doesn't say was the right decision
caesar's and competent decisions
were made
the right way
excel even he knows he knows we
desperately trying to fly can say
nos five is fine double cab oligo
alitalia
on top of our live it
began if you're successful person why we
have to say uncover worldwide of course
are double what you did bill gates are
you coming only bananas and of course i
haven't several billion dollars
comparable look if it doesn't really is
a dollars comfortable
uh... and then bush inside once to drill
home
so how about yourself to quote
i thought it was black
uh... dino george right now
and let the good news is
as you see from these quotes
it's kinda roberta mop inside
so you know we saw that he'd be like a
at whatever quantas a thousand people
kill i screwed up the whole country
and by the way i haven't even talked
about how there was a giant economic
crash
and outlook and we lost eight million
jobs in a crash right before you left
but it was a disaster on top of a
disaster right
but at least
even as he's trying to deflect and in
his group the paintings of the year
he realizes what a mess he was
that water is pressing concerns today
well the dallas morning news
explains among his most pressing
concerns
was whether his hamstrings were ready
for a mountain bike
but i'd later that day
well ok accidentally said priorities
right explained that he uh... is an avid
mountain biker
he hits the trail often
he likes to play golf and attend texas
rangers games
and as of course we all know now
he's taken a painting
uh... well but when asked them uh...
paper people surprising you kicking up
such housing passed by the way
hey like this softball and
now on
you rode a bike today georgie
and you watch the baseball game why
those are challenging pass
beating people are supplied by that
and bush give the classic
bush response quote
people's rights
of course
summit was approx
i can even be
heheh
and if there's one thing that bush was
right pride about all along
it's that's
biodata
the case for mister kantor expectations
low
indeed
don't worry
for your presidential center
for your library jury retire legacy
record george w_ bush
mission accomplished
our expectations are very low