everyone of us.
BILL CLINTON: My fellow Americans, the state
of our union is the strongest it has ever
been.
GEORGE W. BUSH: And the state of our union
will remain strong.
BARACK OBAMA, PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED STATES
OF AMERICA: And the state of our union is
strong.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
CARL AZUZ, CNN ANCHOR: "He shall, from time
to time give to the Congress information on
the state of the Union". Those words from
the U.S. Constitution are the reason why President
Obama visited Capitol Hill last night. We
asked ahead of time what you wanted to hear
the president talk about in his State of the
Union speech. Several of you brought up guns.
We had some people who said they want to hear
about education issues, health care, immigration
laws and of course, the economy.
Some folks like Brian and Shira (ph) were
hoping to hear the president talk about bringing
troops home from Afghanistan. That was part
of the president`s plan. Yesterday afternoon,
CNN reported that the State of the Union would
include an announcement about 34,000 U.S.
troops coming home from Afghanistan by next
February.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: Mr. Speaker, the President
of the United States.
(APPLAUSE)
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: When a president gives the State of
the Union speech, the room is packed. Members
of the U.S. House and Senate are there, members
of the U.S. Supreme Court, the Joint Chiefs
of Staff, special guests. Here are some of
what President Obama said during his speech
last night.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
(APPLAUSE)
OBAMA: The American people don`t expect government
to solve every problem. They don`t expect
those of us in this chamber to agree on every
issue. But they do expect us to put the nation`s
interest before party.
(APPLAUSE)
They do expect us to forge reasonable compromise
where we can. For they know that America moves
forward only when we do so together. And the
responsibility of improving this union remains
the task of us all.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: We`ve got a video on our home page that
talks about some of the traditions surrounding
the State of the Union. One of them is the
response from the opposition party. Last night,
the Republican response was made by Marco
Rubio. He is U.S. Senator from Florida, and
he`s seen as a rising star in the Republican
Party. A CNN political analyst who`s also
one of Senator Rubio`s friends, said following
the State of the Union is the toughest gig
in politics. Here`s part of Senator Rubio`s
speech from last night.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
SEN. MARCO RUBIO, (R ), FLORIDA: The idea
that more taxes and more government spending
is the best way to help hardworking middle
class taxpayers? That`s an old idea that`s
failed every time it`s been tried. More government
isn`t going to help you get ahead. It`s going
to hold you back. More government isn`t going
to create more opportunities, it`s going to
limit them. And more government isn`t going
to inspire new ideas, new businesses and new
private sector jobs. It`s going to create
uncertainty.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: Today "Shoutout" goes
out to Mr. Michie`s civics class at Emerald
Coast Middle School in Santa Rosa Beach, Florida.
Which of these words relates to vibrations
in the earth? Here we go. Is it barometric,
seismic, orthopedic or antediluvian? You`ve
got three seconds, go!
A seismic event like an earthquake has to
do with earth vibrations. That`s your answer
and that`s your "Shoutout."
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: There were reports of seismic activity
in North Korea on Tuesday, but no one was
talking about an earthquake. These vibrations
were caused by an underground nuclear test,
one that sent shock waves around the world.
Leaders from all over the globe spoke out
against North Korea. Even China, North Korea`s
closest ally, said it was opposed to this
test.
The United Nations Security Council held an
emergency meeting after North Korea announced
this test. What happened yesterday, breaks
rules that the Security Council has for North
Korea`s controversial nuclear program. Last
month, the council promised to take significant
action, if there was another test. This is
North Korea`s first nuclear test since Kim-Jong
Un took over as the country`s leader. The
North Korean government said the test was
designed to "defend the country`s security
and sovereignty".
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: There is no lights, no
water, we can`t flush. Some people were able
to shower. No one was injured. Most of us
are camping out on the top deck.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: Not a dream vacation. Three days into
a four-day Caribbean cruise, there was a fire
in the engine room of the Carnival Triumph
cruise ship. That left more than 4200 passengers
and crew drifting for days in the Gulf of
Mexico. You can see some of them in this Facebook
photo. Rooms flooded, sewage leaked in some
areas. Two tug boats were needed to tow the
ship, and Carnival sent in meals from other
crews ships. The Triumph could arrive in Mobile,
Alabama today or tomorrow, passengers have
been promised a full refund, a free flight
home and credit for another cruise. So, the
day`s question on our Facebook site is, would
you take it? If you are on Facebook, you can
find us at Facebook.com/cnnstudentnews. And
tell us if you`d been in a cruise ship situation
like this, if you`d be willing to take another
one.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: Is this legit? A cancer
patient who`s in remission doesn`t show signs
of the disease. It`s true! The cancer could
come back, but complete remission means the
signs and symptoms have disappeared.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: Earlier this month, we talked about
World Cancer Day. The goal this year was to
tackle some myths, like that cancer is an
automatic death sentence. It`s not. In the
U.S. one out of every two men and one out
of every three women will be diagnosed with
some form of cancer. But finding it earlier
and better treatments may mean those cancer
patients can and will go into remission. For
some people, that`s when a whole new kind
of stress starts.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
JAMES CURRY, CNN INTERNATIONAL PRODUCER: My
name is James Curry, I`m a producer at CNN
International. I`m 27 years old. And two years
ago, I was diagnosed with non-Hodgkin`s lymphoma.
Cancer in most people`s mind is what affects
older people. When I was being treated, I`d
go to the Cancer Center, people would ask
me - oh, are you waiting with somebody or
whatever? And I`d be like no, I`m actually
getting treated for cancer.
(LAUGHTER)
CURRY: I went to the doctor for a simple sore
throat. Less than a week later, I was told
that I had cancer, and went immediately into
chemotherapy.
Chemotherapy was the worst experience of my
life. Hands down. Your worst hangover ever
times a hundred, and then drink a bottle of
bleach - I mean that`s what chemo was like
for four days. I went through chemotherapy
and then did eight weeks of radiation, and
close to my birthday I was told that OK, you`re
finally in remission. Although you`re relieved
that you`re in remission, there is that whole
anxiety that goes with it. Every doctor`s
appointment, wondering, if you`re going to
be rediagnosed with cancer.
Every month I go to the doctor. I go get blood
test, I get scans. And then I wait seven days.
And I think it`s the worst seven days of my
life every month. They take my vital signs,
and I try to act all cool, but the vital signs
always give you away.
They hand me the test results, and it`s - I
treat it like a trophy or a diploma. It`s
a kind of big deal, even though it`s really
just a crinkled piece of paper. But I save
all of them.
There`s relief, but then I go make that appointment
again, and it starts the whole process all
over again.
You definitely learn to value things more,
and I thought I learned that in the Marine
Corps. Almost was killed in Iraq, and now
I come back and there`s a possibility I can
die again from cancer.
Ten year later, 70 people -- 70 percent of
people are not alive after their remission.
You start thinking about death, you start
thinking about whether or not you want to
go through treatment again.
You have a pretty strong support system with
your friends and family, but really, I think
it`s just something each person deals with
individually. You take one day at a time and
try not to let it dominate your life. You`re
just trying to be normal.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: Fascinating story from my colleague
at CNN International. Before we go today,
we have for you a little mascot mayhem. The
Bakersfield Condors, minor league hockey team,
decided to bring out a real condor for the
national anthem recently. The bird seemed
to draw inspiration from that "Land of the
Free" line. It escaped from its handler twice.
Even though recovery didn`t go as planned
-- ouch -- remember, ice is slippery. The
bird flocked to the Condors bench and eventually
made its way out of the arena. You know how
it left? Through the condoor (ph). Sure, it`s
sort of bird brain story, but at least it
has an ice ending.