ARE GOING TO BE HELD RIGHT AFTER LECTURE ON
MONDAY, WEDNESDAY AND
FRIDAY OVER IN THE BIO 1B AREA WHERE JOHN
HUELSENBECK HELD HIS,
SO JUST OUTSIDE OF MIKE MOSER'S OFFICE, OVER
AT 263 ON THE NORTH
WING OF THE BUILDING HERE ON THIS FLOOR. IF
YOU CAN'T MAKE THOSE
OFFICE HOURS, JUST REACH ME AT THAT E-MAIL
ADDRESS,
BBALDWIN@BERKELEY.EDU AND I'LL GET BACK TO
YOU AS SOON AS I CAN.
THE WAY WE'RE GOING TO OPERATE THIS PART OF
THE SEMESTER I THINK
IS PRETTY MUCH THE WAY THAT JOHN AND ALLEN
DID WHICH IS THAT I'LL
GIVE MY LECTURES AND AFTER I'VE GIVEN THE
LECTURE, I'LL POST A
PDF ON BSPACE OF THIS, OF THE LECTURES SLIDES.
AND IF YOU GO TO
THE 1B SITE, YOU CAN FIND MY SYLLABUS ALREADY
POSTED WITH THE
READINGS THERE AND THE ROUGH TOPICS FOR THE
REST OF THE SEMESTER
INDICATED. BUT THE EXAMS' GOING TO BE ON THE
LECTURE MATERIAL.
AND, OF COURSE, THE LECTURES ARE BEING VIDEO
CAST HERE AS WELL.
BUT I REALLY HIGHLY RECOMMEND YOU TO READ
THE READINGS TO GET A
LITTLE MORE CONTEXT AND FILL IN A LOT OF,
A LOT MORE DETAIL ABOUT
THE TOPICS I'M GOING TO GO OVER BECAUSE THE
BOOK IS ACTUALLY IS
EXCELLENT. I WAS REALLY SURPRISED TO SEE HOW
GOOD IT IS FOR THE
BOTANY PART OF THE COURSE. SO I HIGHLY RECOMMEND
YOU DO READ
THOSE READINGS. THOUGH I'M JUST CURIOUS HERE,
HOW MANY OF YOU
HAVE EVERY HAD EXPOSURE TO PLANT AND FUNGAL
DIVERSITY SAY IN HIGH
SCHOOL BIOLOGY? CAN YOU RAISE YOUR HANDS IF
YOU HAVE. ACTUALLY
MORE THAN I GUESSED. THIS IS OFTEN AN OVERLOOKED
TOPIC, AND,
BUT IT'S ACTUALLY CENTRAL TO BIOLOGY, THOUGH
MANY STUDENTS FEEL
LIKE THIS IS JUST SOMETHING THEY HAVE TO GET
THROUGH. BUT, YOU
KNOW, PLANTS ARE RESPONSIBLE FOR OUR OXYGENATED
ATMOSPHERE, FOR
OUR OZONE LAYER THAT PROTECTS US FROM UV RADIATION,
FOR
ESSENTIALLY ALL OF OUR FOOD, AND ACTUALLY
THE BULK OF OUR
MEDICINES, PHARMACEUTICALS, WHICH ARE EITHER
BASED DIRECTLY ON
PLANT PRODUCTS OR BOTANICAL PRODUCTS OR IN
MANY CASES WERE
INSPIRED BY THOSE PRODUCTS. AND IF YOU'RE
INTERESTED IN
LEARNING MORE ABOUT THAT, THERE'S AN EXCELLENT
COURSE IN MEDICAL
ETHNOBOTANY, IB 117 THAT TOM CARLSON TEACHES
HERE IN FALL AND
SUMMER SESSIONS THAT HAS BEEN REALLY VALUABLE
TO A LOT OF
ASPIRING PHYSICIANS, MEDICAL TYPES. AND IT
MIGHT BE INTERESTING
TO KNOW FOR YOU THAT BACK IN THE 1700S, 1800S,
THAT ANY
SELF-RESPECTING PHYSICIAN WOULD ALSO BE AT
LEAST AT SOME LEVEL A
BOTANIST. AND THE PEOPLE THAT REALLY LEAD
TO THE CREATION OF
BOTANY AS A FIELD WERE PHYSICIANS. MDS WERE
SOME OF THE FIRST
REALLY MAJOR CONTRIBUTORS. SO THE RELEVANCE
OF THIS TO BIOLOGY
AND MEDICINE IS REALLY IMPORTANT. AND I HOPE
THAT BECOMES MORE
CLEAR AS WE GO ALONG. ARE THERE ANY QUESTIONS
ABOUT THE OVERALL
SORT OF WAY WE'RE GOING TO PROCEED HERE? YEAH?
STUDENT: [INAUDIBLE]
PROFESSOR: YEAH. THE LECTURE MATERIAL ONLY.
BUT THE READINGS
SUPPLEMENT THE LECTURE, YOU KNOW, GIVE YOU
A LITTLE MORE CONTEXT.
FILL, FLUSH IT OUT A BIT BETTER FOR YOU. SO
I HIGHLY RECOMMEND
THAT.
SO TODAY WHAT I'M GOING TO DO IS JUST BASICALLY
GIVE YOU
AN INTRODUCTION TO WHAT ARE PLANTS. THAT MY
SEEM LIKE AN
ABSOLUTELY RIDICULOUSLY SIMPLE QUESTION, BUT
IT'S NOT REALLY.
AND THEN TO, WE'RE GOING START RIGHT IN TO
LOOKING AT SOME OF THE
COOLEST OF THE BOTANICAL ORGANISMS IN THE
BROAD SENSE, THE FUNGI,
SOME OF THEIR IMPORTANT CHARACTERISTICS, AND
THE MAJOR GROUPS OF
WHICH THERE'S BEEN A LOT OF ADVANCES IN RECENT
YEARS. SO WHAT
WE CALL PLANTS AND WHAT REALLY KIND OF DICTATES
THE, THE OVERALL
SUBJECT MATTER FOR THIS PART OF THE COURSE
REALLY GOES ALL THE
BACK TO ARISTOTLE, TO THE ANCIENT GREEKS.
ARISTOTLE CONCERNED
HIMSELF WITH WHAT ANIMALS WERE, AND BASICALLY
DEFINED ANIMALS AS
GROUPS, I'M PARAPHRASING HERE, BUT MORE OR
LESS ORGANISMS WITH
SENSORY AND PERCEPTIVE CAPABILITIES THAT COULD
MOVE FREELY ABOUT,
COULD EXPERIENCE PAIN AND PLEASURE, FEAR,
COULD RESPOND QUICKLY
TO STIMULI, THAT SORT OF THING. THOSE WERE
THE ANIMALS. THE
PLANTS ARE EVERYTHING ELSE, OKAY, THE RESIDUUM.
THE THINGS THAT
ALSO SHARE WITH THE ANIMALS IS ABILITY TO
NURSE THEMSELVES, TAKE
CARE OF THEMSELVES, REPRODUCE BUT DON'T REALLY
HAVE ANYTHING
GOING ON UP HERE. YOU KNOW, THEY'RE PRETTY
MUCH DEVOID OF
SENSORY AND PERCEPTIVE CAPABILITIES. AND THIS
WAS MORE OR LESS
ENSHRINED IN THE TAXONOMY BY LINNAEUS WHO'S
BEEN CONSIDERED THE
FATHER OF TAXONOMY. HE WAS ACTUALLY A PHYSICIAN
AS I WAS JUST
MENTIONING. ALSO A BOTANIST AND A ZOOLOGIST.
AND HE CAME UP
WITH THREE MAJOR KINGDOMS OF EXISTENCE, FORMAL
TAXA. ONE OF
THEM WAS THE MINERAL KINGDOM, WHICH IS THE
NON-LIVING KINGDOM.
AND WE'LL LEAVE THAT TO THE GEOLOGISTS AND
SUCH. BUT ALSO THE
ANIMALS AND THE PLANTS. SO THAT VIEW CAME
ABOUT -- LINNAEUS
THAT'S ABOUT THE MID 1700S -- BUT WE HAVE
THIS VIEW OF ANIMALS AS
THINGS THAT CAN MOVE ABOUT, HAVE SENSORY AND
PERCEPTIVE
CAPABILITY. THE NAME ANIMAL, THE ETYMOLOGY
LITERALLY MEANS SOUL,
SO THINGS WITH A SOUL. WHEREAS PLANTS DON'T
HAVE A SOUL.
THEY'RE, ZOOLOGY IS SCIENCE FOCUSED ON ANIMALS.
PLANTS ARE
BASICALLY EVERYTHING ELSE AS I JUST MENTIONED.
AND BOTANY IS THE
SCIENCE FOCUSED ON EVERYTHING BUT ANIMALS.
SO BOTANY HAS REALLY
HAD A HUGE SCOPE OF FOCUS ORGANISMALLY THROUGHOUT
HISTORY. AND
IT WASN'T UNTIL ABOUT THE LATE 1960S, A LITTLE
OVER 40 YEARS AGO
WHEN MICROSCOPY BECAME A LOT MORE ADVANCED.
WE HAVE ELECTRON
MICROSCOPY COMING INTO THE SCENE AND PEOPLE
REALLY GET INTO THE
DETAILS OF UNICELLULAR ORGANISMS THAT THIS
FIVE KINGDOM VIEW OF
LIFE WAS PROPOSED. AND IN HERE WE HAVE AGAIN
THE PLANTS AND THE
ANIMALS. BUT PULLED OUT OF THE PLANTS ARE
NOW THE FUNGI.
THESE OTHER GROUPS THAT, THIS MAJOR GROUP
OF THINGS THAT DON'T
MOVE FREELY ABOUT THAT ARE NON-PHOTOSYNTHETIC,
THAT ARE NOT
AUTOTROPHS, THEY CAN'T PRODUCE THEIR OWN FOOD.
AND THESE ARE
THE MAIN MULTI-CELLULAR GROUPS HERE. AND THEN
AMONG THE
UNICELLULAR GROUPS THERE WERE TWO MAJOR GROUPS.
ONE, THE
PROTISTA BASICALLY WAS ALL THESE UNICELLULAR
LIFE FORMS THAT WERE
BECOMING MUCH BETTER UNDERSTOOD. THERE WERE
EUCARYOTES. AND
THEN THE MONERA BASICALLY TAKES IN ALL OF
THE PROCARYOTES WHICH
ARE UNICELLUAR ORGANISMS. WE'RE TALKING HERE
ABOUT WHAT, WHAT'S
BEEN LOOSELY CALLED BACTERIA. AND SOME PEOPLE
WOULD INCLUDE
VIRUSES THERE BUT WE CAN DEBATE ABOUT WHETHER
THOSE SHOULD REALLY
BE CONSIDERED FORMS OF LIFE. THOUGH JUST TO
MAKE SURE
EVERYBODY'S ON THE SAME PAGE HERE, THE PROCARY-,
OR THE
EUCARYOTES, THIS LITERALLY MEANS, EU MEANS
TRUE, SO THESE ARE THE
TRUE NUCLEI BEARERS. CARRION REFERS TO A KERNEL
OR THE NUCLEUS.
SO THESE ARE ORGANISMS THAT POSSESS A MEMBRANE-BOUND
NUCLEUS
WHERE THE NUCLEAR CHROMOSOMES ARE LOCATED.
AND MEMBRANE-BOUND
ORGANELLES THAT ARE IMPORTANT FOR VARIOUS
METABOLIC PROCESSES,
FOR EXAMPLE, MITOCHONDRIA ARE ORGANELLES THAT,
WHERE RESPIRATION
REACTIONS ARE LOCATED. AND THOSE ORGANISMS
THAT ARE
PHOTOSYNTHETIC AND HAVE PLASTIDS, CHLOROPLASTS,
FOR EXAMPLE,
WHERE THE REACTIONS OF PHOTOSYNTHESIS ARE
LOCALIZED, SO THOSE ARE
EUCARYOTES. AND AS I MENTIONED THEY INCLUDE
THE PROTISTS, THE
ANIMALS, PLANTS, AND THE FUNGI, FOUR OF THE
FIVE KINGDOMS. AND
THEN THE PROCARYOTES, BEFORE THE NUCLEUS LITERALLY,
THESE ARE
THINGS PRESUMABLY MORE PRIMITIVE THAT LACK
A NUCLEUS AND
MEMBRANE-BOUND ORGANELLES AND JUST THIS ONE
KINGDOM, THE MONERA.
THIS IS THE SYSTEM THAT WAS IN PLACE WHEN
I WAS A GRAD STUDENT,
WHEN I FIRST WAS INVOLVED IN TEACHING BOTANY
AS A GSI. AND THIS
WAS PRETTY MUCH HELD IN PLACE UNTIL THE 1990S.
AND WHAT HAPPENED
TO CHANGE THIS VIEW WAS THAT IN 19, LATE 1980S,
THAT KARY MULLIS
BASICALLY FIGURED OUT THE IDEA OF PCR WHILE
HE WAS TRIPPING ON
LSD. AND THAT BECAME THE METHOD BY WHICH MOLECULAR
BIOLOGY
UNDERWENT THIS HUGE REVOLUTION AND WE WERE
ABLE TO SEQUENCE THE
DNA RELATIVELY EASILY FOR A WIDE ARRAY OF
DIFFERENT ORGANISMS.
AND WE DIDN'T EVEN HAVE TO ISOLATE THOSE ORGANISMS.
YOU CAN
IMAGINE A LOT OF THESE UNICELLULAR ORGANISMS
VERY DIFFICULT TO
ACTUALLY ISOLATE. IF YOU CAN'T CULTURE THEM,
IT'S GOING TO BE
VERY DIFFICULT TO DISCOVER THEM. AND SO THERE
WAS A HUGE AMOUNT
OF UNDISCOVERED DIVERSITY AMONG THE UNICELLULAR
ORGANISMS THAT
WAS DISCOVERED BY PCR, JUST ENVIRONMENTAL
PCR WHERE WE ACTUALLY
ARE AMPLIFYING DNA OUT OF ROSS OIL SAMPLES
OR SEA WATER, AND ALL
OF A SUDDEN ALL THIS LIFE BECOME EVIDENT THAT
NOBODY HAD EVEN
SEEN YET. AND WHAT THAT REVEALED WAS THAT
THERE WAS A MAJOR
OVER SIMPLIFICATION OF THIS VIEW OF THE PROCARYOTES.
PROKARYOTES
ACTUALLY BROKE INTO TWO MAJOR DOMAINS OF LIFE,
WHAT WE COULD CALL
THE TRUE BACTERIA, HERE, AND THEN THIS OTHER
GROUP CALLED THE
ARCHAEA. THESE, AND THE NAME REFERS TO ARCHAIC.
THESE ANCIENT,
THIS PRESUMABLY ANCIENT GROUP THAT HAS REALLY
BIZARRE BIOLOGY
THAT SEEMS TO PREDATE THE OXYGENATED ATMOSPHERE
IN MANY CASES.
SO THIS, THE PHYLOGENETIC ANALYSES THEN SHOWED
THAT THE
EUCARYOTES, WHICH I'LL GET TO IN A, BACK TO
IN A MOMENT, WERE
ALSO MUCH MORE INTERESTING AND DIVERSE THAN
THOUGHT. BUT THEY
REPRESENT BASICALLY A GROUP ON PAR WITH DIVERSITY
TO THESE TWO
MAJOR GROUPS OF PROCARYOTES. SO PROCARYOTES
ARE JUST VASTLY
MORE DIVERSE THAN PEOPLE THOUGHT. THEY BROKE
INTO TWO REALLY
ANCIENT DIVERGENT GROUPS. HERE YOU CAN SEE
A ROOTED TREE OF
LIFE. AND THE ROOTING OF THE TREE OF LIFE
IS NOT A TRIVIAL
EXERCISE BECAUSE YOU DON'T HAVE AN OUTGROUP
OBVIOUSLY TO LIFE.
YOU CAN'T USE ROCKS OR, YOU KNOW, MINERALS
FOR THAT. GET INTO
HOW ONE DOES THAT, BUT IT'S NOT EASY AND VERY
CONTROVERSIAL.
BUT THE BACTERIA THEN ARE HERE. AND HERE YOU
CAN SEE THE
ARCHAEA. IN THIS ANALYSIS COMING OUT SISTERED
TO ALL THE
EUCARYOTES. THOUGH IN THIS VIEW HERE WE SEE
THAT ACTUALLY THE
ARCHAEA ARE MORE CLOSELY RELATED TO THE EUCARYOTES
THAN THEY ARE
TO THE OTHER PROCARYOTES IN THE BACTERIA.
SO THAT WAS A REALLY
SURPRISE. AND THERE'S SOME CONTROVERSY ABOUT
THIS THAT PERHAPS
THE ARCHAEA, OR THAT THERE MAY BE GENES THAT
HAVE BEEN INHERITED
BY HORIZONTAL TRANSFER FROM BOTH OF THESE
GROUPS THAT WERE
INVESTED IN THE ORIGINAL EUCARYOTES. BUT,
THE MAIN POINT HERE
IS THAT THEY'RE JUST THESE TWO MAJOR GROUPS
OF PROKARYOTES. AND
THE ARCHAEA ARE REALLY COOL BECAUSE THESE
INCLUDE THE
EXTREMOPHILES WHICH LITERALLY MEAN THE LOVERS
OF EXTREME
CONDITIONS. PHILE JUST MEANS LOVE. AND THIS
IS BASICALLY A
CATEGORY THAT INCLUDES THE MAJORITY OF THESE
ARCHAEA. AND THEY
BREAK INTO THREE MAJOR GROUPS. THE HALOPHILES
WHICH ARE LOVERS
OF SALTY CONDITIONS OR SALINE CONDITIONS.
AND IF YOU FLY OVER
THE SAN FRANCISCO BAY AND LOOK DOWN AT THE
SOUTH END ON THE EAST
SIDE, YOU'LL SEE THESE AREAS WHERE THESE SALT
FLATS WHERE SALT IS
BEING HARVESTED. AND YOU CAN SEE THE ARCHAEA
HERE IMPARTING THIS
RED COLORATION. THESE ARE ORGANISMS THAT GENERALLY
CAN'T
SURVIVE EXCEPT UNDER REALLY HIGH SALINITY
WHICH WOULD BE AT SUCH
A HIGH LEVEL THAT ANY SELF-RESPECTING EUCARYOTE
WOULD BE, HAVE
THEIR DNA AND THEIR PROTEINS DENATURED. IT
WOULD BE A TOTAL
DISASTER. IT WOULD BE FATAL. BUT THESE ORGANISMS
REALLY
REQUIRE EXTREME CONDITIONS LIKE THIS. AND
WE CAN FIND THESE
THINGS GROWING IN NATURAL ENVIRONMENTS IN,
FOR EXAMPLE, PLACES
LIKE THE GREAT SALT LAKE, VARIOUS SALT FLATS
OUT IN THE DESERT
THAT ARE OCCASIONALLY INUNDATED AFTER STORMS
AND THE LIKE. AND
THAT'S A REALLY INTERESTING GROUP. THESE ARE
MOSTLY AEROBIC
ORGANISMS THAT REQUIRE OXYGEN. THE THERMOPHILES
ARE ANOTHER
MAJOR GROUP. AND THESE ARE EVEN MORE FANTASTIC
REALLY BECAUSE
THESE REQUIRE SUCH WARM CONDITIONS THAT THEY
WOULD ESSENTIALLY,
YOU KNOW, BOIL ALIVE OR, YOU KNOW, BASICALLY
COOK ANY, ANY
EUCARYOTE. AND THESE ARE FOUND IN SUCH PLACES
AS THESE
HYDROTHERMIC VENTS DOWN IN RIFT ZONES AT THE
BOTTOM OF THE OCEAN,
THESE BLACK SMOKERS HERE WHERE IT CAN GET
UP TO 120 DEGREES
CELSIUS, WELL OVER BOILING. AND THIS IS A
SITU-, THESE ARE
BASICALLY PRIMARY PRODUCERS DOWN IN THIS INTERESTING
ECOSYSTEM AT
THE BOTTOM OF THE OCEAN WHERE WE HAVE SOME
BIZARRE EUCARYOTES AS
WELL. AND THEN WE ALSO FIND THESE THINGS AROUND
ACTUALLY
VOLCANIC VENTS AND, YOU KNOW, THESE HOT SPRINGS
SITUATIONS AND
GEYSERS LIKE IN THE YELLOWSTONE AREA, AROUND
THE OLD FAITHFUL
GEYSER BASE AND IN PLACES LIKE THAT. AND SOME
OF THESE GUYS ARE
ACTUALLY ABLE TO, THEY'RE AUTOTROPHS THAT
ARE ABLE TO PRODUCE
THEIR OWN ENERGY FROM HYDROGEN SULFIDE. SO
THEY'RE ABLE TO MAKE
USE OF CHEMICALS THAT ARE POISONOUS TO US.
SO THESE ARE, ARE
REALLY PRETTY AMAZING ORGANISMS. AND THEN
ALSO THERE'S A GROUP
CALLED METHANOGENS WHICH LIVE IN THE GUTS
OF RUMINANTS IN AN
ANAEROBIC ENVIRONMENT. OXYGEN IS DEADLY TO
THESE THINGS. AND
THEY CAN, THEY HELP CATTLE AND OTHER RUMINANTS
DIGEST CELLULOSE
AND THE LIKE, SO THEY'RE REALLY IMPORTANT
ECOLOGICALLY AND THEY
PRODUCE METHANE AS A WASTE PRODUCT. THAT'S
WHERE THE METHANE
THAT WE ASSOCIATE WITH CATTLE IS, COMES FROM
IN PART. AND AN
INTERESTING SORT OF CIRCULARITY HERE IS THAT
THESE ARCHAEA, THESE
EXTREMOPHILES ARE ACTUALLY RESPONSIBLE FOR
PCR. SO THE DNA
POLYMERASES PRODUCED BY SOME OF THESE THERMOPHILES
ARE STABLE AT
BOILING TEMPERATURES AS I MENTIONED, AND THAT
ALLOWED PCR TO
ACTUALLY BE FEASIBLE BECAUSE YOU HAVE TO DENATURE
THE DNA DURING
THESE CYCLES OF DNA DENATURATION, AND THEN
AMPLIFYING, OR
ANNEALING THE PRIMERS AND EXTENDING THE PRIMERS.
AND IT'S,
ORIGINALLY THERMO BASILIS AQUATICUS FROM YELLOWSTONE
NATIONAL
PARK THAT WAS USED TO ALLOW FOR PCR, SO THIS
ARCHAEA GROUP WAS
DISCOVERED BECAUSE OF THE ARCHAEA. AND WITHOUT
THE ARCHAEA, WE
WOULDN'T HAVE DISCOVERED THE ARCHAEA, SO IT'S
KIND OF AN
INTERESTING SITUATION THERE. NOW TAKING THE
ARCHAEA ASIDE, THE
REMAINING TRUE BACTERIA ARE NO LESS INTERESTING
IN TERMS OF THEIR
METABOLIC COMPLEXITY. IN FACT, THEY SHOW EVERY
MAJOR MODE OF
NUTRITION IN METABOLISM, EVEN MORE SO THAN
WE GET IN ARCHAEA
BECAUSE NONE OF THE ARCHAEA ARE CAPABLE OF
PHOTOSYNTHESIS. TRUE
PHOTOSYNTHESIS WHERE WE'RE TAKING THE ENERGY
FROM LIGHT AND USING
THAT TO FIX INORGANIC CARBON INTO SUGARS.
THAT'S ONLY SOMETHING
THAT THE CYANOBACTERIA, THIS GROUP HERE HAS
FIGURED OUT HOW TO DO
IN A MAJOR WAY. THERE ARE SOME OTHER, THERE
ISN'T ANOTHER MINOR
EXAMPLE, BUT THIS IS SOMETHING THAT THE CYANOBACTERIA
INNOVATED
THE CAPABILITY FOR PHOTOSYNTHETIC, PHOTOSYNTHESIS.
AND IT'S
BECAUSE OF THESE CYANOBACTERIA THAT WE HAVE
AN OXYGENATED
ATMOSPHERE WHICH AROSE ABOUT 1.8 BILLION YEARS
AGO AND ALLOWED
FOR THE EUCARYOTES TO REALLY COME INTO BEING.
AND THESE
CYANOBACTERIA ARE ALSO REALLY IMPORTANT FOR
NITROGEN FIXATION.
YOU'RE PROBABLY AWARE THAT OUR ATMOSPHERE
IS MOSTLY COMPRISED OF
NITROGEN GAS, BUT THAT NITROGEN IS UNAVAILABLE
TO ORGANISMS.
AND IT'S ONLY THROUGH THE ACTION OF NITROGEN
FIXERS LIKE THESE
CYANOBACTERIA THAT CAN, THAT WE HAVE NITROGEN
AVAILABLE WHICH IS
AN ESSENTIAL NUTRIENT FOR ORGANISMS. AND IT'S
EASILY LOST FROM
ECOSYSTEMS BY, IT'S EASILY LEACHED OUT OF
SOILS, FOR EXAMPLE, SO
IT'S REALLY CRITICAL FUNCTIONS HERE. AS WE'LL
GET TO NEXT TIME,
THE CYANOBACTERIA ARE RESPONSIBLE FOR ALL
OF OUR PHOTOSYNTHETIC
EUCARYOTES ESSENTIALLY. THAT MAY SOUND A LITTLE
STRANGE BUT
WE'LL GET TO THAT AND IN GOOD TIME HERE. OKAY,
SO I THINK THAT
OF YOU'VE BEEN ALREADY INTRODUCED TO THESE
CONCEPTS OF MAJOR
MODES OF LIVING, THE AUTOTROPHS AND THE HETEROTROPHS
IN THE
ECOLOGY PART. BUT I'LL JUST REVIEW THIS BRIEFLY.
BASICALLY
AUTOTROPHS ARE ORGANISMS THAT CAN GENERATE
THEIR OWN FOOD FROM
INORGANIC MATERIALS OR FROM NON-ORGANIC, BY,
WITHOUT THE
REQUIREMENT OF NON-ORGANIC SOURCES BASICALLY.
SO THE
PHOTOAUTOTROPHS, INCLUDING THE CYANO- OR THE,
BASICALLY THE
CYANOBACTERIA THAT WE TALKED ABOUT SO FAR,
I JUST MENTIONED THEM.
THE CHEMOAUTOTROPHS, I ALLUDED TO THOSE. THESE
ARE THINGS LIKE
SULFOLOBUS HERE, WHICH I REALIZE KIND OF LOOKS
LIKE A PEPPERONI
PIZZA HERE, BUT THAT'S ACTUALLY A CELL. THAT'S
ONE OF THESE,
THESE ARCHAEA THAT CAN BASICALLY DERIVE ENERGY
FROM HYDROGEN
SULFIDE. AND HETEROTROPHS THEN ARE BASICALLY
EVERYTHING ELSE
THAT FEED ON EITHER OTHER ORGANISMS DIRECTLY
OR ON THE PRODUCTS
OF THOSE ORGANISMS, SO ORGANIC SUBSTANCES.
AND, OF COURSE, WE
DON'T REALLY UNDERSTAND EXACTLY HOW LIFE EVOLVED,
THE ORIGINAL
ORGANISMS, BUT IT'S THOUGHT THAT THE ORIGINAL
ORGANISMS WERE
HETEROTROPHS, AND THEY WERE FEEDING ON ORGANIC
COMPOUNDS THAT
WERE PRODUCED BY NON-ORGANIC MEANS BY, BUT
NOT BY LIVING
ORGANISMS. SO IN SOME SORT OF PRIMORDIAL SOUP.
BUT SUBSEQUENT
TO THAT AFTER THE EVO-, EVOLOUTION OF AUTOTROPHS,
THE AUTOTROPHS,
WHICH ARE GOING TO BE WHAT WE'RE GOING TO
REALLY FOCUS ON IN THIS
BOTANICAL PART OF THE COURSE AFTER THE FUNGI,
THEY, THEY REALLY
KIND OF CREATED THE CONDITIONS FOR LIFE TO
EXIST HERE TO A GREAT
EXTENT. OKAY, SO THIS AGAIN IS JUST THAT FIVE
KINGDOM SYSTEM IN
THE CONTEXT OF NOW THIS THREE DOMAIN SYSTEM.
NOW A DOMAIN IS NOT
REALLY A FORMAL TAXON. IT'S AN INFORMAL GROUP,
BUT THESE ARE
GOOD GROUPS. BACTERIA, THE ARCHAEA BEING EQUIVALENT
TO THE OLD
MONERA. ALL THE OLD PROCARYOTES HERE. AND
THEN WE CONSIDER
THE, ALL THE EUCARYOTES A SINGLE DOMAIN OF
LIFE, INCLUDING THESE
OLD FOUR KINGDOMS THAT ARE NO LONGER RECOGNIZED
AS KINGDOMS PER
SAY. AND THIS KIND OF LUMPING ALL OF THESE
GROUPS INTO ONE BIG
EUCARYOTE DOESN'T MEAN THAT THOSE EUCARYOTES
ARE LESS DIVERSE
THAN WE THOUGHT BEFORE. IT'S ACTUALLY THAT
THEY'RE, THEY'RE
EVEN MORE DIVERSE AND MORE COMPLEX IN THEIR
RELATIONSHIPS AND
THAT THIS IS A VAST OVER SIMPLIFICATION HERE
OF THE RELATIONSHIPS
OF, OF EUCARYOTES. YOU JUST PUT THEM INTO
THOSE FOUR CUBBIES.
AND HERE YOU CAN SEE THE OVERALL TREE OF LIFE.
AND SORT OF,
WELL, IT'S ROOTED HERE. BUT IT'S LAID OUT
IN SORT OF AN
UNROOTED GENERAL PERSPECTIVE WITH THE ARCHAEA
HERE IN PINK.
THESE ARE THOSE EXTREMOPHILES AND RELATIVES.
THE TRUE BACTERIA,
INCLUDING THE CYANOBACTERIA THAT I MENTIONED
THAT ARE
PHOTOSYNTHETIC. AND HERE'S ALL THE EUCARYOTE
UP HERE IN GRAY.
AND HIGHLIGHTED HERE ARE THE MAJOR TERRESTRIAL
MULTICELLULAR
GROUPS THAT OCCUR ON LAND. THE FUNGI, THE
ANIMALS, AND THE LAND
PLANTS. AND YOU CAN SEE THAT THEY'RE JUST
LITTLE TWIGS IN THIS
BIG EUCARYOTIC BRANCH OF LIFE AND THAT THEY'RE
NOT VERY CLOSELY
RELATED TO ONE ANOTHER. IN FACT, BASED ON
THE RELATIONSHIPS IT
LOOKS LIKE THEY'VE EACH INDEPENDENTLY BEEN
DERIVED FROM
UNICELLULAR ORGANISMS. SO MULTICELLULARITY'S
ARISEN MULTIPLE
TIMES IN EACH OF THESE GROUPS. I MEAN, IT
HAS ARISEN
INDEPENDENTLY IN EACH OF THOSE GROUPS. THOUGH
YOU MIGHT WONDER
ABOUT VIRUSES. I MEAN THEY'RE CLEARLY CRITICALLY
IMPORTANT IN
MEDICINE I MEAN AND HUMAN HEALTH. THEY CLEARLY
EVOLVED VERY
QUICKLY. THEY HAVE NUCLEIC ACIDS. THEY HAVE
DNA OR RNA. BUT
THEY'RE INERT UNLESS THEY'RE IN THE PRESENCE
OF THE LIVING CELLS
OF ONE OF THESE GROUPS. AND UNFORTUNATELY
THEY DON'T HAVE VERY
MUCH, WELL, THEY DON'T HAVE VERY MUCH DNA
TYPICALLY. AND IT
LOOKS LIKE THEY'VE INHERITED THEIR DNA IN
MANY CASES BY
HORIZONTAL TRANSFER FROM THEIR HOSTS. AND
SO THESE ARE VERY
DIFFICULT TO, TO ACTUALLY ANALYZE IN THE CONTEXT
OF THE REST OF
THE TREE OF LIFE AND FIGURE OUT HOW THEY EVOLVED.
ONE THING WE
CAN SAY IS THAT THEY'RE MOBILE, THEY ARE MOBILE
GENETIC ELEMENTS
ESSENTIALLY, COMPARABLE IN A LOT OF RESPECTS
TO PLASMIDS THAT
LIVE INSIDE BACTERIAL CELLS OR TRANSPOSONS
THAT LIVE ACROSS
BASICALLY ALL OF LIFE. AND THEY MAY HAVE THEIR
ORIGINS FROM
SUCH THINGS AS PLASMIDS OR TRANSPOSONS, BUT
WE'RE NOT SURE. AND
THEY MAY HAVE VARIOUS DIFFERENT ORIGINS. SO
THEY'RE SORT OF LEFT
OUT OF THIS PICTURE, BUT WE'RE NOT CONSIDERING
THEM UNIMPORTANT.
THEY'RE JUST DIFFICULT TO INCLUDE.
OKAY, SO NOW I WANT TO JUST
GIVE YOU A GENERAL PERSPECTIVE ON THE ORGANISMS
WE'RE REALLY
GOING TO FOCUS ON FOR THE REST OF SEMESTER.
THOUGH FIRST OFF
WE'RE GOING TO TALK ABOUT THE FUNGI AS I MENTIONED
HERE, WHICH
USED TO BE CALLED PLANTS. NOWADAYS PEOPLE
THAT STUDY FUNGI ARE
CALLED MYCOLOGISTS RATHER THAN BOTANISTS.
MYCOLOGY. MYCOLOGY
IS THE STUDY OF FUNGI. AND SOME BOTANY DEPARTMENTS
THAT STILL
EXIST USUALLY INCLUDE MYCOLOGISTS. FOR EXAMPLE,
OUR PLANT AND
MICROBIAL BIOLOGY DEPARTMENT INCLUDES A COUPLE
OF MYCOLOGISTS
THERE. SO THIS LINNEAN OR ARISTOTLE, YOU KNOW,
HOLDOVER FROM THE
ANCIENT GREEKS INCLUDE, IS STILL SEEN IN OUR
DEPARTMENTAL
ORGANIZATIONS. AND THEN THE SO-CALLED ALGAE
WHICH ARE BASICALLY
MARINE OR AQUATIC, TYPICALLY MARINE OR AQUATIC
PHOTOSYNTHETIC
ORGANISMS. YOU CAN SEE THAT THEY FALL OUT
ALL OVER THE PLACE,
THAT THEY'RE NOT A MONOPHYLETIC GROUP OR A
CLADE, AND THAT THE
ALGAE ARE MUCH, MUCH MORE WIDELY SCATTERED
IN THE TREE OF LIFE
THAN ANYBODY GUESSED PRIOR TO THIS MOLECULAR
BIOLOGY REVOLUTION
BACK IN THE '90S. BUT AS WE'LL GET TO NEXT
TIME, THEY'RE
ACTUALLY IN SOME REGARD MORE CLOSELY RELATED
THAN THEY APPEAR
BASED ON THIS TREE. SO THAT'S WHEN WE START
TALKING ABOUT THE
ORIGIN OF PHOTOSYNTHESIS NEXT TIME. BUT JUST
KEEP THAT IN THE
BACK OF YOUR MIND. AND THEN FINALLY THE THINGS
THAT WE CAN ALL
AGREE ARE ACTUALLY PLANTS, THE LAND PLANTS,
THE TRUE GREEN
PLANTS, THESE ARE, THAT OCCUR ON TERRESTRIAL
HABITATS, THESE ARE
A NATURAL GROUP, A MONOPHYLETIC GROUP THAT
WE'LL BE TALKING ABOUT
FOR MOST OF THE SEMESTER. AND YOU CAN SEE
THAT THEY'RE CLOSELY
RELATED TO SOME BUT NOT ALL OF THE ALGAE.
OKAY, SO LET'S FOCUS
IN ON THE FUNGI NOW. THIS IS GOING TO BE THE
TOPIC FOR THE REST
OF LECTURE TODAY. AND IT WILL SPILLOVER NEXT
TIME INTO TALKING
ABOUT THEM IN TERMS OF THEIR ECOLOGICAL IMPORTANCE.
BUT YOU CAN
SEE THAT THE FUNGI ARE REALLY DISTANTLY RELATED
TO THE LAND
PLANTS, THE PLANTS IN THE STRICTEST SENSE.
AND THAT THEY'RE
ACTUALLY, I ALREADY MENTIONED THAT THEY'VE
INDEPENDENTLY EVOLVED
MULTICELLULARITY RELATIVE TO THE PLANTS AND
THE ANIMALS ACTUALLY.
BUT YOU CAN SEE THEY'RE QUITE CLOSELY RELATED
TO ANIMALS, THAT
THEY'RE ACTUALLY MUCH MORE CLOSELY RELATED
TO ANIMALS THAN THEY
ARE TO PLANTS. AND REALLY WE SHOULD BE INCLUDING
FUNGI AND
ZOOLOGY DEPARTMENTS IF SUCH DEPARTMENTS STILL
EXISTED RATHER THAN
BOTANY DEPARTMENTS. AND THAT WAS A REALLY
MAJOR SURPRISE. BUT
THERE'S SOME THINGS IN HINDSIGHT THAT MAKE
SENSE ABOUT THAT.
THOUGH, AND ACTUALLY THE FUNGI ARE MORE CLOSELY
RELATED TO
ANIMALS THAN TO ANY PHOTOSYNTHETIC ORGANISM.
AND NEITHER THE
ANIMALS NOR THE FUNGI SHOW ANY EVIDENCE OF
HAVING EVER HAD
PLASTIDS, EVER HAD ANY KIND OF PHOTOSYNTHETIC
APPARATUS THAT THEY
MAY HAVE LOST. THERE'S NO EVIDENCE THAT THAT
EVER WAS THE CASE.
AND THEY SHARE A COMMON ANCESTOR BASED ON
FOSSIL AND MOLECULAR
CONSIDERATIONS ABOUT A BILLION YEARS AGO,
WHICH SOUNDS LIKE A
LONG TIME AGO, BUT EUCARYOTES STARTED REALLY
EVOLVING ALMOST
TWICE THAT LONG AGO, I MEAN BACK ALMOST 2
BILLION YEARS AGO. SO
THAT'S NOT REALLY ALL THAT LONG AGO IN THE
OVERALL HISTORY OF THE
EUCARYOTES. AND THAT'S REFLECTED PRETTY NICELY
IN THIS TREE.
SO LET'S FOCUS NOW IN ON CHARACTERISTICS OF
THE FUNGI. THE FUNGI
HAVE SOME REALLY AMAZING FEATURES THAT MAKE
THEM ENDLESSLY
FASCINATING TO EVERYONE. FUNGI I THINK ARE
REALLY FASCINATING
TO THE LAY PUBLIC AND EVERYONE BECAUSE THEY'RE
SO DIFFERENT FROM,
FROM OTHER ORGANISMS. AND YOU CAN SEE THEY
INCLUDE A WIDE ARRAY
OF MULTICELLULAR ORGANISMS. AND THERE ALSO
ARE SOME UNICELLULAR
FUNGI AS WELL, THE YEASTS. AND THERE ARE ABOUT
A HUNDRED
THOUSAND SPECIES OF FUNGI THAT ARE RECOGNIZED
THAT HAVE ACTUALLY
BEEN DESCRIBED, BUT THERE ARE PROBABLY VASTLY
MORE FUNGI THAT
REMAIN UNDESCRIBED AND REMAIN TO BE DISCOVERED.
AND THAT'S
ESPECIALLY TRUE FOR THE YEASTS, THESE UNICELLULAR
FUNGI WHICH MAY
INCLUDE MORE THAN A HUNDRED THOUSAND TAXA.
THERE'S ONLY LIKE
1500 DESCRIBED, BUT THERE MAY BE LIKE 150,000
YEASTS THAT AWAIT
DESCRIPTION. SO THE YEAST MAY ACTUALLY OUT
NUMBER THE
MULTICELLULAR FUNGI. BUT THEY'RE JUST, THERE'S
NOT A LOT OF
MORPHOLOGY TO GO ON THERE TO DESCRIBE THEM.
OKAY, IN TERMS OF
MAJOR FUNGAL CHARACTERISTICS THEN, OF COURSE,
THEY'RE EUCARYOTES.
THEY HAVE MEMBRANE-BOUND NUCLEI AND MITOCHONDRIA,
BUT NO
PLASTIDS. THEY DON'T HAVE ANY EVIDENCE OF
HAVING EVER BEEN
PHOTOSYNTHETIC. THEIR BODIES ARE NON-MOTILE.
OF COURSE THIS
IS ONE OF THE REASON THEY WERE CONSIDERED
PLANTS BACK IN THE OLD
SENSE. I SHOULD SAY THEIR MAIN ADULT BODIES
ARE TYPICALLY
NON-MOTILE. THERE ARE SOME EXCEPTIONS. AND
THAT'S ONE OF THE
THINGS THAT I THINK YOU MAY HAVE ALREADY FOUND
OUT IF YOU TOOK 1A
AND TALKED ABOUT ANIMALS THERE. WHEN YOU START
TALKING ABOUT
THE DIVERSITY OF LIFE, THERE ARE ALWAYS EXCEPTIONS
TO THE RULES.
BUT WE'RE GOING TO FOCUS ON THE GENERAL --
YEAH?
STUDENT: [INAUDIBLE]
PROFESSOR: OH, MOTILE JUST MEANS THE ABILITY
TO MOVE. YEAH,
SORRY, BE ABLE TO MOVE AROUND FREELY. THANKS
FOR ASKING. AND
THEY HAVE A FILAMENTOUS TYPE OF BODY. AND
THAT MAY STRIKE YOU
AS WEIRD IF YOU'VE SEEN MUSHROOMS. THOSE SEEM
LIKE BIG SOLID
OBJECTS, BUT THEY'RE ACTUALLY MADE UP OF FILAMENTS,
DISCREET
FILAMENTS THAT ARE ALL INTERWOVEN, THAT ARE
WEAVED, WEAVED
TOGETHER. AND WE CALL THESE FILAMENTS HYPHAE,
OR THAT'S, THAT'S
ACTUALLY PLURAL. HYPHA WOULD BE SINGULAR.
AND THESE MAKE UP
TOGETHER WHAT'S CALLED THE BODY OF THE FUNGUS,
THE MYCELIUM.
OKAY, SO THAT'S WHAT WE CALL, THIS REFERS
TO BODY OF FUNGUS.
THAT'S WHAT IT LITERALLY MEANS. AND THESE
ARE HETEROTROPHS.
THEY NEED ORGANIC CARBON THAT'S BEEN FIXED
BY SOME OTHER
ORGANISMS. BUT THEY CAN'T ACTUALLY ENGULF
IT. THEY DON'T HAVE
A WAY TO ACTUALLY SWALLOW BIG CHUNKS OF ORGANIC
MATERIAL. THEY
AREN'T CAPABLE OF PHAGOCYTOSIS, YOU KNOW,
LIKE AN AMOEBA, TO
SURROUND SOMETHING AND DIGEST IT. THEY HAVE
TO ACTUALLY
ENZYMATICALLY DEGRADE ORGANIC MATERIAL OUTSIDE
THEIR BODIES.
THEY HAVE TO BASICALLY EXUDE ENZYMES INTO
THEIR ENVIRONMENT,
BREAK DOWN THAT MATERIAL, AND THEN ABSORB
IT THROUGH THEIR
HYPHAE. SO THEY HAVE AN ABSORPTIVE MODE OF
NUTRITION. AND
THEY ACTUALLY, THEY DO HAVE CELL WALLS. NOW
REMEMBER ANIMALS
DON'T HAVE CELL WALLS. ALL THE EUCARYOTES
HAVE CELL MEMBRANES,
BUT ONLY CERTAIN EUCARYOTES HAVE CELL WALLS
WHICH ARE OUTSIDE THE
CELL MEMBRANES. THESE IN PART SOME RIGIDITY,
RIGIDNESS TO THE,
TO THE CELLS. THIS IS ONE OF THE REASONS THAT
THEY WERE
CONSIDERED PLANTS IS THAT PLANTS ALSO HAVE
CELL WALLS UNLIKE
ANIMALS. BUT THESE CELL WALLS IN FUNGI ARE
COMPRISED MOSTLY OF
CHITIN, WHICH IS THE SUBSTANCE THAT MAKES
UP THE EXOSKELETONS OF
ARTHROPODS LIKE INSECTS AND CRUSTACEANS. SO
FUNGI ACTUALLY, AS
ONE OF THEIR MAJOR CONSTITUENTS, THEY SHARE
A LOT WITH THE
ARTHROPODS, WHICH YOU PROBABLY DIDN'T REALIZE
BUT THAT'S A
PRETTY, INTERESTING SIMILARITY THERE. UNLIKE
IN PLANTS WHERE
THE CELL WALLS ARE MADE UP OF CELLULOSE. NOW
BOTH CHITIN AND
CELLULOSE ARE COMPLEX CARBOHYDRATES, BUT THEY
HAVE VERY DIFFERENT
COMPOSITION. AND THERE'S A REALLY FUNDAMENTAL
DIFFERENCE HERE
BETWEEN PLANTS AND FUNGI. ALSO THE FUNGI STORE
THEIR CARBON AS
A COMPLEX CARBOHYDRATE LIKE PLANTS, BUT IN
PLANTS THEY STORE
THEIR, THEIR CARBOHYDRATES AS STARCH. WHEREAS
IN FUNGI THEY
STORE IT AS GLYCOGEN JUST LIKE WE DO. SO THEY
SHARE WITH
ANIMALS THIS STORAGE SUBSTANCE OF GLYCOGIN.
SO THAT'S ANOTHER
INTERESTING SIMILARITY WITH ANIMALS. WITH,
ACTUALLY WITH ALL
ANIMALS HERE AS OPPOSED TO JUST SOME HERE.
OKAY, THE LIFE CYCLE
OF FUNGI INCLUDES SPORES. AND IN THIS REGARD
THEY'RE SIMILAR TO
PLANTS. PLANTS ALSO HAVE SPORES IN THEIR LIFE
CYCLES. AND
THAT'S ONE THING THAT HAS BEEN POINTED TO
AS A BOTANICAL OR
PLANT-LIKE FEATURE EVEN THOUGH IT'S NOT DIAGNOSTIC
OF A CLOSE
RELATIONSHIP WITH PLANTS. AND I ALREADY MENTIONED
THAT THEY'RE
BOTH UNICELLULAR AND MULTICELLULAR. OKAY,
SO ANY QUESTIONS ABOUT
CHARACTERISTICS OF FUNGI? WE'RE GOING TO GET
INTO MORE OF THAT
IN A SECOND HERE. SO HERE WE SEE SOME FUNGI
HYPHAE. HERE YOU
CAN SEE AN ENLARGED PIECE OF THE MYCELIUM
WHERE YOU CAN SEE THESE
INDIVIDUAL FILAMENTS MAKING UP THESE, I MEAN
I'M SURE YOU'VE SEEN
THIS SORT OF THING ON MOLDY FOOD AND SUCH.
AND IT LOOKS PRETTY
DISGUSTING WHEN WE'RE LOOKING AT IT, YOU KNOW,
JUST WITH OUR BARE
NAKED EYES. BUT WHEN YOU GET DOWN TO THE MICROSCOPIC
LEVEL, IT'S
INCREDIBLY NEAT. AND AS I MENTIONED, THESE
HYPHAE ARE, WELL, I
DON'T THINK I MENTIONED THEY'RE TUBULAR FILAMENTS,
AND THEY GROW
FROM THEIR TIPS. THEY HAVE A REALLY HIGH SURFACE
AREA TO VOLUME
RATIO. THE IMPORTANCE OF THAT IS THEY CAN
REALLY COME INTO
CONTACT WITH THEIR ENVIRONMENT VERY EFFICIENTLY.
THERE'S A LOT
OF SURFACES IN CONTACT WITH THE ENVIRONMENT.
AND THAT'S
CRITICAL BECAUSE THEY HAVE TO DIGEST THEIR
FOOD OUTSIDE THEIR
BODY. AND SO IT'S IN PARTS SO THEY HAVE THIS
CONTACT, THEIR
SURFACE AREA TO VOLUME RATIO IS CRUCIAL. ENHANCES
THEIR
ABSORPTION. AND YOU CAN SEE THAT THE MYCELIUM
IS EXTENSIVE IN
THE CASE OF SOME OF THESE MACRO FUNGI UNDERGROUND.
WHAT WE SEE
ON THE SURFACE IS JUST THE TIP OF THE ICEBERG.
THE VAST
MAJORITY OF THE MYCELIUM IS NOT THE FRUITING
BODIES WHERE THE
SPORES, THOSE SEXUAL SPORES ARE PRODUCED.
BUT THE UNDER, USUALLY
WHAT'S IN MANY OF THESE TERRESTRIAL FUNGI,
THE SUBTERRANEAN PART
OF THE ORGANISM THAT'S IN CONTACT WITH SUBSTRATE
THAT THEY CAN
DIGEST. THEY'RE JUST GETTING THEIR FRUITING
BODIES HERE UP INTO
THE ATMOSPHERE SO THEY CAN DISPERSE THEIR
SPORES. I MEAN
TELEOLOGICALLY SPEAKING, THAT'S, THAT'S THE
END RESULT OF THAT.
OKAY. AND HERE YOU CAN SEE THE DEVELOPMENT
OF, OF THE FRUITING
BODY OF A TYPICAL MUSHROOM. AND THIS IS OBVIOUSLY
NOT AT THE
TYPICAL RATE HERE. THIS IS, THIS IS ACCELERATED
GREATLY. BUT
IT MAKES, BUT I WANT TO MAKE THE POINT THAT
THE FRUITING BODIES
OF FUNGI CAN DEVELOP INCREDIBLY FAST. SO WHEN
THEY GO TO
PRODUCE SEXUAL FRUITING BODIES LIKE THIS,
THEY REALLY INVEST A
HUGE AMOUNT OF THEIR ENERGY IN THIS. AND IT'S,
IT CAN HAPPEN IN
A MATTER OF HOURS THAT YOU CAN SEE THE EMERGENCE
OF A FRUITING
BODY. SO IT'S BASICALLY AN OVERNIGHT PHENOMENON.
AND I THINK
YOU PROBABLY MAYBE YOU'VE SEEN THAT IN YOUR
OWN EXPERIENCE, BUT
IT'S A PRETTY AMAZING CAPABILITY OF FUNGI.
AND HERE JUST WE SEE
A LITTLE BIT OF DETAIL OF THE FUNGAL HYPHAE.
AND THERE ARE A
COUPLE OF MAJOR TYPES OF HYPHAE THAT WE SEE,
AND THESE BREAK OUT
PHYLOGENETICALLY. SO THERE ARE CERTAIN MAJOR
GROUPS OF FUNGI
THAT HAVE THIS TYPE AND OTHER MAJOR GROUPS
THAT HAVE THIS TYPE.
SO THIS IS ACTUALLY HELPFUL TO UNDERSTAND,
TO UNDERSTAND
RELATIONSHIPS OF FUNGI TO ONE ANOTHER. SO
THERE'S ONE TYPE
CALLED COENOCYTIC, AND THIS IS BASICALLY WHERE
THE FILAMENT IS
COMPLETELY OPEN INSIDE. THERE ARE NO PARTITIONS,
OR SEPTAE THAT
BREAK UP THE HYPHA INTO CELL-LIKE UNITS. THOUGH
WE HAVE AN OPEN
CYTOPLASM INSIDE THE HYPHA AND WE HAVE THE
NUCLEI IN HERE, NOT
SEPARATED FROM ONE ANOTHER BY CELL MEMBRANES.
THE ALTERNATIVE
TO THAT ARE THESE SEPTATE HYPHAE WHERE YOU
CAN SEE THESE, THESE
SEPTAE THAT, THAT DO BREAK UP THE MYC-, THE
HYPHA INTO
PARTITIONS. BUT YOU, I DON'T KNOW IF YOU CAN
SEE IT FROM THE
BACK OF THE ROOM, BUT THERE'S A LITTLE HOLE
INSIDE THESE SEPTAE
IN THE CENTER OF THESE PARTITIONS THAT ALLOW
CYTOPLASM TO MOVE
FREELY THROUGH, THOUGH THEY DO HAVE SOME PARTITIONING
OF LARGER
PARTS OF THEIR CELLS LIKE THE NUCLEI HERE.
BUT THEY, CYTOPLASM
CAN MOVE FREELY THROUGH HERE. AND SO THE HYPHA
IS STILL CAPABLE
OF RAPIDLY MOBILIZING RESOURCES TO GROWING
PLACES. FOR EXAMPLE,
IF THEY'RE GOING TO PRODUCE A FRUITING BODY,
THEY CAN SHUNT
RESOURCES QUICKLY TO DIFFERENT PARTS OF THE
HYPHA.
STUDENT: DR. BALDWIN.
PROFESSOR: YEAH?
STUDENT: IS THE WHOLE [INAUDIBLE]
PROFESSOR: WELL, YEAH, WE DON'T REALLY HAVE
CELLS IN THE TYPICAL
SENSE IN FUNGI. AND IT'S, IT'S A DIFFERENT
KIND OF SITUATION
REALLY. YOU CAN THINK THOUGH OF EACH OF THESE
PARTITIONED-OFF
AREAS AS CELL LIKE. THEY ARE CELL-LIKE IN
A SENSE. AND I'LL
GET MORE TO THAT SHORTLY. SO, BUT FUNGI ARE
WEIRD. I MEAN
JUST FACE IT, THEY'RE NOT LIKE YOU AND ME.
THEY'RE VERY
DIFFERENT AND NOT LIKE PLANTS IN THIS REGARD.
THEY REALLY DO
HAVE AN UNUSUAL BIOLOGY. AND THEY'RE NOT ALL
A BUNCH OF
DECOMPOSERS LIKE YOU MIGHT HAVE HEARD IN HIGH
SCHOOL BIOLOGY. I
MEAN WE OBVIOUSLY KNOW THERE ARE SOME REALLY
HORRENDOUS PARASITES
AS WELL. THEY ARE PARASITIC ON LIVING ORGANISMS
IN PART. BUT
THERE ARE ACTUALLY EVEN SOME PREDATORY FUNGI.
IT'S PROBABLY
HARD TO REALIZE THAT A FUNGUS CAN BE A PREDATOR,
AN ACTIVE
PREDATOR, BUT THERE ARE SOME OF THESE SPECIALISTS.
AND THIS ONE
GROUP OF ASCOMYCETES -- WE'LL GET TO THAT
PART OF THE FUNGI
LATER -- IT'S THE MOST DIVERSE GROUP THAT
ACTUALLY PRODUCE THESE
HYPHAL LOOPS THAT CAN ACTUALLY ACT AS NOOSES.
AND YOU CAN SEE
HERE A HAPLESS NEMATODE IS UNFORTUNATELY GOING,
TRYING TO GET
THROUGH ONE OF THESE HOOPS AND NOW IT'S CONSTRICTED
AROUND IT AND
IT'S DIGESTED THEN BY THE FUNGUS. SO THERE
ARE SOME REALLY
BIZARRE INNOVATIONS THERE. AND THEY'RE NOT
JUST DEVIOUS, RIGHT,
THE FUNGI ARE NOT JUST DOING THINGS TO OTHER
ORGANISMS THAT ARE,
THAT ARE NEGATIVE. THEY ALSO HAVE SOME REALLY
IMPORTANT, IN
FACT ABSOLUTELY CRUCIAL POSITIVE INTERACTIONS
WITH OTHER
ORGANISMS. AND THIS IS THE ONE THAT'S REALLY
FUNDAMENTAL TO
BASICALLY OUR SURVIVAL AS WELL AS THE SURVIVAL
OF MOST PLANTS.
AND THAT'S WHAT'S CALLED THE MYCORRHIZAE.
MYCORRHIZAE LITERALLY
MEANS FUNGUS ROOT. SO IT'S AN ASSOCIATION
BETWEEN A ROOT OF A
PLANT AND FUNGUS. AND IT'S A MUTUALISM, SO
IT'S A TYPE OF
SYMBIOTIC ASSOCIATION THAT'S ACTUALLY POSITIVE
TO BOTH PARTNERS.
REMEMBER MUTUALISM IS BOTH PARTNERS BENEFIT,
NOT JUST ONE LIKE IN
A COMMENSALISM. THIS IS A MUTUALISM. AND WHAT
YOU CAN SEE
HERE IS A FUNGAL HYPHA THAT'S IN CONTACT WITH
ROOT CELLS OF A
PLANT HERE. AND WHAT THE FUNGUS GETS OUT OF
THIS ASSOCIATION
WITH THESE PLANT CELLS IS IT ACTUALLY GAINS
CARBOHYDRATES. IT'S
GETTING FOOD FROM THE PLANT. AND THAT MIGHT
SEEM LIKE A BAD
THING FOR THE PLANT, BUT THE PLANT'S GAINING
INORGANIC MINERALS
AND SOME REALLY CRUCIAL ONES LIKE NITROGEN
AND PHOSPHORUS THAT
ARE DIFFICULT, THAT COULD BE LIMITING IN THE
ENVIRONMENT. BUT
THE FUNGUS IS REALLY EFFICIENT AT ABSORBING.
AND IT CAN ALSO,
IT'S VERY EFFICIENT AT ABSORBING WATER AS
WELL, SO THE PLANT
GETS, GETS A LOT OUT OF THIS ASSOCIATION.
AND WE KNOW THAT
BECAUSE IF YOU, IF YOU PREVENT THIS ASSOCIATION
FROM FORMING IN
PLANTS, THEY DO MUCH MORE POORLY IN MOST CASES.
THERE ARE SOME
PLANTS THAT DON'T NEED THIS BUT THE VAST MAJORITY
OF PLANTS NEED
THIS KIND OF AN ASSOCIATION. AND THERE ARE
A COUPLE OF TYPES OF
THESE MYCORRHIZAE. ONE'S CALLED ECTOMYCORRHIZAL,
ECTO JUST
REFERRING TO BEING OUTSIDE THE ROOT. SO THESE
ARE FUNGI THAT
DON'T ACTUALLY PENETRATE THE INDIVIDUAL ROOT
CELLS. THEY JUST
CLOAK THE OUTSIDE OF THE ROOT. AND THEIR HYPHAE
WILL PENETRATE
BETWEEN THE CELL WALLS, BUT THEY WON'T GO
INSIDE OF A CELL WALL.
SO YOU CAN SEE HERE THE DIFFERENT CELLS OF
THE PLANT ROOT. AND
THIS IS THE HYPHA. YOU CAN SEE IT'S BEING
INTRUDED IN HERE, BUT
THEY'RE ONLY GOING IN THE INTERCELLULAR SPACES
BETWEEN THE CELLS,
AND THEY'RE NOT ACTUALLY PENETRATING THE CELL
WALLS. AND WE SEE
THESE TYPE OF FUNGI, WHICH IS A SPECIAL GROUP,
SORT OF LINEAGES,
ASSOCIATE WITH THE ROOTS OF TREES IN TEMPERATE
OR BOREAL
ENVIRONMENTS. SO NON-TROPICAL TREES, BOTH
CONIFERS, LIKE PINES
AND SPRUCES AND THINGS LIKE THAT AS WELL AS
HARDWOODS LIKE
BIRCHS, ET CETERA, OAKS, AND OTHER FLOWERING
PLANT TREES IN
TEMPERATE REGIONS. OKAY, SO THOSE ARE THE
ECTOMYCORRHIZAL
FUNGI. NOW THE VAST MAJORITY OF PLANTS HAVE
THIS TYPE OF
ASSOCIATION. SO ALL THE HERBACEOUS PLANTS,
PLANTS THAT DON'T
PRODUCE WOOD. HERBS, AND A LOT OF TROPICAL
TREES HAVE THIS TYPE
OF ASSOCIATION CALLED AN ARBUSCULAR, WELL,
IT'S AN ARBUSCULAR
MYCORRHIZAE FORMED FROM ARBUSCULAR MYCORRHIZAL
FUNGI. REMEMBER
THE ASSOCIATION BETWEEN THE PLANT AND THE
FUNGUS IS CALLED THE
MYCORRHIZAE OR MYCHORRHIZA, SINGULAR. AND
WE CALL THE FUNGI BY
THAT NAME, MYCORRHIZAL FUNGUS BECAUSE ONLY
PARTICULAR FUNGI WILL
HAVE THESE TYPES OF ASSOCIATIONS WITH PLANTS.
AND HERE YOU CAN
SEE THAT THE FUNGAL HYPHA NOT ONLY GOES IN
BETWEEN THE ROOT CELLS
OF THE PLANT BUT ALSO PENETRATES THE CELL
WALL. SO HERE YOU CAN
SEE THIS WEIRD TREE-LIKE BRANCHING PATTERN
OF THE FUNGAL HYPHA
WHERE IT'S COMING INTO CONTACT WITH THE CELL
MEMBRANE. AND YOU
CAN SEE THIS REALLY DENSE AREA HERE WHERE
THESE DENDRITIC OR
TREE-LIKE BRANCHING PATTERNS OF THE FUNGAL
HYPHA ARE IN CONTACT
WITH THE ACTUAL CELL MEMBRANE OF THE PLANT.
SO THEY PENETRATE
THE CELL WALL, AND THEN THEY'RE COVERING THE
OUTSIDE OF THE CELL
MEMBRANE. THEY'RE NOT PENETRATING THE CELL
MEMBRANE OF THE
PLANT CELL. THEY'RE NOT PUNCTURING IT. THEY'RE
JUST COVERING
IT. AND SO THEY HAVE A LOT BETTER CONTACT
AREA WITH THE PLANT.
AND THERE'S A LOT MORE SURFACING CONTACT HERE
FOR TRANSFERRING
SUBSTANCES. SO THAT'S THE MORE COMMON ASSOCIATION.
AND WE SEE
THIS IN, THIS TYPE OF ASSOCIATION IN MORE
THAN 80 PERCENT OF
PLANT FAMILIES, INCLUDING SOME OF THE EARLIEST
DIVERGING PLANT
FAMILIES. SO THESE GUYS WERE PROBABLY CRITICAL
TO THE ORIGINAL
COLONIZATION OF LAND BY PLANTS, OF TERRESTRIAL
PLANTS. AND SO
THE MYCORRHI-, THIS PARTICULAR GROUP IS ACTUALLY
JUST A FEW,
THERE'S ONLY A COUPLE HUNDRED SPECIES OF THESE
TYPES OF FUNGI
THAT WE KNOW OF TODAY, BUT THEY'RE REALLY
IMPORTANT. AND HERE
YOU CAN JUST SEE A CARTOON OF THIS TREE-LIKE
DENDRITIC PATTERN OF
THE FUNGAL HYPHA. AND IT'S SORT OF, IT HASN'T
PUNCTURED THE
CELL MEMBRANE HERE. YOU CAN SEE THE CELL MEMBRANE
OF THE PLANT
ROOT JUST RUNNING ALONG THE OUTSIDE THERE.
SO IT'S JUST SORT OF
LIKE STICKING ITS, ITS FINGERS INTO, INTO
SORT OF [INAUDIBLE]
LIKE SITUATION WHERE IT'S NOT PUNCTURING BUT
JUST GETTING IN
CONTACT. OKAY, SO A LITTLE BIT OF TIME LEFT.
I JUST WANT TO
INTRODUCE YOU TO THE FIVE MAJOR GROUPS OF
FUNGI. FOUR OF THESE
WE ACTUALLY RECOGNIZED IN THE PAST. BUT ONE
OF THESE THAT WE
DIDN'T UNTIL DNA EVIDENCE. AND YOU CAN SEE
THAT THE FUNGI FORM A
MONOPHYLETIC GROUP. SO HERE'S THE ROOT OF
THE FUNGAL TREE RIGHT
HERE. IT'S LAYING ON ITS SIDE. AND THESE ARE
THE FIVE TERMINAL
GROUPS WITH EXAMPLES OUT HERE. WE HAVE TWO
MAJOR CLADES OF BIG
MACRO FUNGI THAT PRODUCE THESE BIG FRUITING
BODIES THAT ARE
SISTER TO EACH OTHER, THE ASCOMYCOTA AND THE
BASIDIOMYCOTA, THESE
BEING THE TRUE MUSHROOMS. AND THESE BEING
THE SAC FUNGI. I'LL
SHOW YOU SOME MORE EXAMPLES IN A MINUTE. THESE
ARE THE ONES
YOU'RE PROBABLY FAMILIAR WITH. AND THEN I'LL
TALK ABOUT THESE
IN A MOMENT HERE. THIS INCLUDES MOST BUT NOT
ALL THE ORGANISMS
THAT HAVE BEEN BEEN CALLED FUNGI IN THE PAST.
AND YOU'RE GOING
TO SEE SOME THINGS IN LAB THIS COMING WEEK
THAT ARE THINGS WE
USED TO THINK WERE FUNGI BUT TURN OUT NOT
TO BE. BUT THEY HAVE
KIND OF SIMILAR LIFESTYLES. SO HERE'S THE
SISTER GROUP. A
CHYTRIDIOMYCOTA, THESE ARE ORGANISMS THAT
HAVE BEEN CALLED
CHYTRIDS. THAT'S THE SHORTHAND NAME. AND THERE
ARE ONLY ABOUT
A THOUSAND SPECIES OF THESE COMPARED TO LIKE
65,000 OF THESE AND
ABOUT 30,000 OF THESE. SO REALLY SMALL DIVERSITY.
BUT THEY'RE
VERY INTERESTING BECAUSE THEY'RE ONE OF THE
EARLY DIVERGING
LINEAGES HERE. AND IT WAS QUESTIONABLE WHETHER
THEY WERE EVEN
REALLY FUNGI IN THE PAST, BUT THE MOLECULAR
DATA REALLY NAILED
THAT DOWN. AND HERE YOU CAN SEE SOME OF THESE
CHYTRIDS.
THEY'RE REALLY INTERESTING BECAUSE THEY'RE
THE ONLY GROUP OF
FUNGI THAT HAS SPORES AND GAMETES THAT CAN
ACTUALLY MOVE AROUND
WITH FLAGELLAE THAT HAVE A SINGLE FLAGELLUM,
WHIP-LIKE FLAGELLUM.
AND IN THAT REGARD THEY'RE REALLY SIMILAR
TO SOME OF THE CLOSE
RELATIVES OF THE ANIMALS, AND UNICELLULAR
FORMS I SHOULD SAY.
THEY, THIS WHIP-LIKE FLAGELLUM IS SOMETHING
THEY SHARE WITH A
COMMON ANCESTOR WITH THE ANIMALS. SO IN THE
BROAD SENSE THIS BIG
FUNGAL ANIMAL GROUP ARE CALLED THE UNIKONTS
WHICH IS NOT A NAME
YOU HAVE TO KNOW BUT IT MEANS BASICALLY HAVING
A SINGLE WHIP-LIKE
FLAGELLUM. AND WE SEE THAT IN THESE CHYTRID
ZOOSPORES. AND
HERE YOU CAN SEE A LITTLE ANIMATION OR IT'S
NOT ANIMATION, THIS
IS ACTUALLY REAL LIFE. YOU CAN SEE ONE OF
THESE SWIMMING
ZOOSPORES. AND THEY CAN REALLY GET IT ON.
THEY CAN REALLY MOVE
FAST. YOU CAN SEE THEM MOVING. I MEAN YOU
HAVE A HARD TIME
KEEPING THEM IN THE FIELD OF VIEW UNDER A
MICROSCOPE. AND HERE
YOU CAN SEE THEY'RE BEING EXUDED OUT OF THE
TIP OF THIS
SPORANGIUM HERE. THERE'S ONE BEING EXUDED
OUT. AND AS SOON AS
THEY'RE RELEASED, THEY TAKE OFF AT TOP SPEED.
AND THEN THEY CAN
SETTLE DOWN ONTO THE ENVIRONMENT, PRODUCE
THESE HYPHAE, AND THEN
A SPORANGIUM. SO THEY CAN, SOME OF THESE HAVE
A REALLY SIMPLE
LIFE CYCLE. OTHERS PRODUCE BIG FILAMENTS.
YOU CAN SEE ONE OF
THESE HERE. THIS IS ALLOMYCES. AND THE CHYTRIDS
ARE REALLY
IMPORTANT ECOLOGICALLY FOR A NUMBER OF REASONS.
THEY'RE IN THE
SOIL. THEY'RE IMPORTANT TO DECOMPOSERS. THEY'RE
IN AQUATIC
SITUATIONS. THEY'RE IMPORTANT THERE. SOME
OF THEM ARE IMPORTANT
IN THE GUTS OF RUMINANTS, LIKE I MENTIONED
THE METHANOGEN
BACTER-, OR ARCHAEA. SOME OF THEM ARE IMPORTANT
AS DIGEST-, IN
THE DIGESTIVE TRACTS OF UNGULATES. BUT YOU
PROBABLY HAVE HEARD
ABOUT THEM IF IN ANY REGARD BECAUSE THEY'RE
ONE OF THE MAIN
FACTORS IN AMPHIBIAN DECLINE WORLDWIDE. AND
THIS WASN'T A
PHENOMENON THAT WE KNEW ABOUT UNTIL FAIRLY
RECENTLY, OVER THE
LAST 10, 20 YEARS. THIS PHENOMENON OF CHYTRIDIOMYCOSIS.
THIS
CHYTRID INFECTION OF PARTICULARLY FROGS AND
TOADS HAS LEAD TO THE
EXTINCTION AND RAPID DEMISE OF LOTS OF ANURANS
WORLDWIDE. AND
IT'S A REALLY SERIOUS DISEASE THAT'S SPREAD
INTO CALIFORNIA AND
OTHER PLACES FAMILIAR TO US. AND IT'S BEEN
A HUGE PROBLEM TO
ORGANISMS THAT ARE ALREADY HAVING PLENTY OF
TROUBLE. SO THESE
CAN BE A REALLY AGGRESSIVE PATHOGENS, PATHOGENIC
DISEASE-CAUSING
ORGANISMS. OKAY, SO WE'RE OUT OF TIME. BUT
NEXT TIME WE'LL
GET INTO THE REST OF THESE FUNGI, TALK A LITTLE
BIT ABOUT THEIR
LIFE CYCLE. SO HAPPY HALLOWEEN. SEE YOU MONDAY.
OR IN
OFFICE HOURS.