And the commander has actually
come here to tell the
international press about
their brand new toy.
So we're going to
check it out.
SIMON OSTROVSKY: This latest
war with Gaza was the first
time Iron Dome had been deployed
against an onslaught
of this kind.
Israel and the United States
decided to fund it for almost
a billion dollars each after
the 2006 conflict with
Hezbollah in Lebanon.
That war saw 4,000 similarly
crude rockets kill 44 people
in northern Israel.
With casualties low, public
pressure on Israeli
politicians to retaliate
was weak, too.
It made me wonder if targeting
Hamas was a military
necessity at all.
Do you think it's less necessary
for Israel to strike
in the Gaza Strip as it has
been, now that people here are
protected by your very
successful Iron Dome system?
-Thank you very much.
SIMON OSTROVSKY: My question
was answered by the Israeli
Air Force instead, which
launched a strike on the Gaza
media center at about the same
time our press conference was
being held, killing a top leader
in the Islamic Jihad.
So was all of this carnage
necessary?
Could it have been avoided?
I met an Israeli who thought
it could have been.
Gershon Baskin is the man who
had negotiated with Ahmed
Jabari for the release
of Gilad Shalit.
He told me that the day Jabari
was killed, he was supposed to
have given an answer about a
ceasefire proposal Baskin had
put forward.
If you're able to negotiate
with Hamas, how come this
time, negotiations weren't
able to head off this new
round of violence?
GERSHON BASKIN: The day that it
happened, Jabari had seen
the proposal for an extended
ceasefire.
It was for a three to month
trial period that involved not
only stopping fire but taking
preventive action on their
side against groups that would
try to attack Israel.
Every time over the past two
years we've gotten involved in
helping to negotiate a
ceasefire, at the end of the
day it was Jabari who went and
sent his forces out to impose
the ceasefire.
So there was more than a good
indication that he would have
supported a three to six
month trial period.
The prevailing wisdom amongst
the Israeli military and
security forces is that what
we needed to do, more than
anything else, was to
create deterrence.
Make them so scared of what
we will do that they
won't shoot at us.
The decision to take out Ahmed
Jabari was very clear.
This guy's the head
of the pyramid.
If we could get him, there's
no one who has impunity.
SIMON OSTROVSKY: Yet, you're an
Israeli who doesn't support
the fact that Ahmed Jabari
was assassinated.
GERSHON BASKIN: What I'm saying
is that you use force
as the very, very,
very last option.
You try and exhaust every
other possibility
before you use force.
And I believe that there was
at least one more option to
try before going to war.
Israeli officials knew about the
attempts of the ceasefire
that we were trying
to develop.
They were well aware, and
they didn't try it.
SIMON OSTROVSKY: We're in
Rishon Lezion, a town in
central Israel.
And this building was hit by a
rocket fired by Hamas about an
hour and a half ago.
We're almost 60 kilometers away
from the border with the
Gaza Strip.
Hamas are trying to show the
Israelis that they can hit the
country right in its center.
This part of the country hasn't
been hit for 20 years.
And this has kind of been a
wake up call for Israel.
SIMON OSTROVSKY: They destroyed
your house, your home.
SIMON OSTROVSKY: What do you
want your country to do now?
SIMON OSTROVSKY: The next day,
we heard that a bomb exploded
on a bus in Tel Aviv.
Officials didn't yet know if
Hamas had planted it, but
there were already reports
of injuries.
The conflict had entered
a new phase.
It wasn't just rockets coming
out of Gaza anymore.
There were now bombs being
placed on public
transportation.
We headed south,
back to Gaza in
anticipation of Israel's reaction.
It was the eighth day
of open hostilities.
And Israel's troops weren't
showing any sign of getting
ready to go.
[GUNSHOT]
Jesus.
Fuck.
SIMON OSTROVSKY: No filming?
OK, sorry.
SIMON OSTROVSKY: And there
seems to be some
rocket fire coming in.
Because we've heard a couple
of explosions just now.
There's a really big troop build
up just behind these
trees over here.
And we're only about a couple
of kilometers away.
So--
[GUNSHOT]
Fuck.
Jesus Christ.
Meanwhile in Egypt, mediators
had finally gotten Israel and
Hamas to agree to a ceasefire.
So it's only a couple of minutes
left until 9:00 when
the ceasefire is supposed
to come into effect.
So far, we've seen rockets
coming into Gaza, and
exploding rockets coming
out of Gaza.
When the rockets have been
coming in, these guys here
have been cheering.
They are not happy,
apparently, about the ceasefire.
Because they want to see Israel
flatten Hamas in the
Gaza Strip.
But so far, it doesn't feel like
the ceasefire is actually
coming into effect.
But we'll give it a couple
more minutes.
See what happens.
[SPEAKING HEBREW]
SIMON OSTROVSKY: And then
everything went quiet.
That is, aside from the
celebratory gunfire in the
Gaza Strip and the muezzins
calling from the mosques.
10 minutes, and you can hear
soldiers in the field between
here and Gaza cheering
about it.
Haven't heard any
rockets explode.
Haven't heard anything come
in or go out of Gaza.
So I guess this one's over.
And we'll see you in a
couple of years when
the next round happens.