Sup, sup.
It's Kreayshawn and this
is my wildest party
adventure I've ever had.
The 4th of July.
The 4th of July you kind of set
out to go get wasted with
all of your friends.
Me and all my friends
go to this party.
So it's like all the cute boys
that don't go to your school
that were too good for you.
Everyone's dressed preppy, and
we're kinda dressed hood, I
guess, like, white tees, blue
jeans, and sneakers.
My friend hands me a bottle
of whiskey and no one has
chasers, so I find a big
old water bottle.
I'm drinking this
whiskey about to
chase it with the water.
And the water ended
up being vodka.
And it was the most disgusting
thing ever.
We're just getting super
drunk and one of my
friends gets lost.
So we find her upstairs.
And she's passed out
in some room.
And in the room, there's a whole
bunch of weed cookies.
Us being us, we just start
taking all the weed cookies,
and we're just floating and
playing weird music, and just
looking at all the stars.
And you can hear fireworks.
And during all this drunken
craziness, I
pocket-dialed my mom.
My mom starts freaking
out because she
thinks I've been kidnapped.
So we go to the next party
in this pickup truck.
We heard these rumors of
there being 100 blunts.
It ends up being at
a frat house.
There's a tray with
100 blunts.
And there's literally every
type of 40 you can have.
Me and my friends instantly
start taking all these blunts
and putting them behind our
ears and in our pockets.
We're trying to take as
many blunts as we can.
My mom is going crazy, calling
me over and over again.
We all go to my friend's house,
and we passed out.
And the next morning, I wake
up super high to like 200
missed calls and texts from
my mom and my grandpa.
And they called the police
as if I was kidnapped.
So that was my craziest party.
[MUSIC PLAYING]