President Obama, members of Congress, corporate
executives, small business owners -- all of
them involved in meetings this week, they
are all talking about the same thing -- the
fiscal cliff. Yesterday, we said what could
happen if the government goes over that cliff,
so to speak, on January 1st. Taxes would go
up for all Americans, government spending
would be automatically cut for different government
services. What we didn`t mention, is that
the government set this thing up when they
couldn`t work out a deal to lower the U.S.
debt, lawmakers and the president came up
with this idea for this automatic spending
cuts. Everyone involved agrees that the debt
needs to be reduced. They don`t agree on how
to do that. So for now, the clock is ticking.
The person you`re looking at here is Maria
Santos Gorrostieta. From 2008 to 2011 she
was the mayor of a town in Mexico that was
plagued by violence from the country`s drug
war. The mayor herself was targeted by attacks
twice. She survived both times. This month,
Gorrostieta was kidnapped. Her body was found
last week. The drug war and the wave of violence
that`s part of it have dominated Mexican politics
for years. It`s something that the outgoing
president, Felipe Calderon has faced, and
it`s something that Mexico`s next president,
Enrique Pena Nieto will face as well. Brian
Todd examines their approaches.
(BEGIN VIDEOTAPE)
BRIAN TODD, CNN CORRESPONDENT: Deploying the
Mexican army and Marines as never before,
Calderon fought the cartels head on, took
out several kingpins. But during his six-year
term, the streets of Juarez, Tijuana, Sinaloa
flowed with blood. At least 50,000 Mexicans
were killed. Many of them innocent civilians.
That`s far more than the American death tolls
in Iraq and Afghanistan combined. Homicide
rates in those areas have recently plateaued.
And a Mexican official tells us, civilians
there are telling them they do feel safer
now. Tourism is bouncing back. Analysts say
President-elect Pena Nieto will continue to
confront the cartels, but in a more nuanced
way.
ERIC OLSON, WOODROW WILSON CENTER: With the
United States, he is going to ask for more
intelligence sharing from the United States.
There`s been intelligence sharing, it`s been
in a little more limited way. They would like
to see that expanded. So that Mexican authorities,
police, army, Marines have more information
and can go after the bad guys with that intelligence.
(END VIDEOTAPE)
AZUZ: Today`s first "Shoutout" goes out to
Mr. Oswald`s class at Craver Middle School
in Colorado City, Colorado.
Who was the first American to travel into
space? You know what to do. Was it Neil Armstrong,
John Glenn, Alan Shepard or Buzz Aldrin? You`ve
got three seconds, go.
On May 5, 1961, Alan Shepard entered the history
books as the first American in space. That`s
your answer and that`s your "Shoutout."
Shepard`s historic flight lasted around 15
minutes. Captain Scott Kelly is going to be
in space a little longer than that. 365 days
longer. Started in the spring of 2015, U.S.
astronaut is set to spend an entire year in
space. Kelly and a Russian cosmonaut will
be up in the international space station,
orbiting the earth, while the planet does
one full orbit around the sun. Officials at
NASA are hoping that this mission will help
them learn more about how extended time in
space effects the human body. And that might
help plan for future missions to an asteroid
or even another planet. Kelly has spent a
total of 180 days in space, but that`s been
spaced out over four previous trips. Going
for a year straight, that would set a new
U.S. record.
Scientists create new technologies and give
them artificial intelligence. The machines
take on a life of their own, rise up against
their creators and destroy the human race.
It sounds like a plot of a sci- fi movie,
and it has been. But some researchers wonder,
if it could happen in real life. Scientists
at a university in Great Britain say it`s
reasonable to predict that machines could
have independent intelligence, sometime in
the next couple hundred years. They suggest
it would be dangerous to dismiss concerns
of a potential robot uprising. So they are
going to spend time studying it. The potential
dangers from biotechnology, artificial intelligence
and nanotechnology.
It`s time for a "Shoutout" extra credit.
Shrimp, crickets and scorpions are all members
of which of these groups? Here we go: are
they all arthropods, vertebrates, cephalopods
or crustaceans. Put another three seconds
on that clock and go!
Shrimp, crickets and scorpions are all arthropods,
the largest phylum of animals. That`s your
answer and that`s your Shoutout" extra credit.
So, you might be like me and that you are
more used to seeing shrimp on a plate than
in the wild. It turns out, any of those arthropods
could be served as food, though, the idea
of crunching on a cricket or scarfing down
some scorpions might make your skin crawl.
These bugs aren`t just edible, though. Some
experts are saying they are healthy. Dr. Sanjay
Gupta dishes out the details.
(BEGIN VIDEOTAPE)
DR. SANJAY GUPTA, CNN CORRESPONDENT: Silkworm
larvae stir-fried with soy, sugar and just
a dash of white pepper.
The silkworms have -- have texture of like
popcorn, and they have a creamy center. Bon
appetite!
Typhoon restaurant in Santa Monica is one
of a handful of restaurants right here in
America that serves patrons bugs on purpose.
Chilly-pepper seasoned crickets. Even scorpions
on shrimp toast.
KEVIN OH, TYPHOON RESTAURANT: Scorpions still
have the stinger in them, but they are dried,
so the poison is neutralized.
GUPTA: Scorpions are just one of 1,700 bugs
that are safe for people to consume.
It`s still a novelty here in the States, but
insects are part of a daily diet in most of
the world. Earlier this year the United Nations
held their global conference on the benefits
of eating insects, even suggesting it might
be a good solution to world hunger.
OH: I don`t know why the United States doesn`t
eat insects, when they are actually very healthy
for you.
GUPTA: And he is right: insects are high in
protein, low in fat and cholesterol. Take
a cricket, for example. A six-ounce serving
of these crunchy bugs have 60 percent less
saturated fat as the same amount of ground
beef.
OH: And now the ants.
GUPTA: These string potatoes aren`t complete
without adding some dried ants.
OH: They taste a little sour, tangy, and they
have a hint of black pepper to them.
GUPTA: They also have 14 grams of protein
per serving. With the growing population and
rising costs of food, the rest of the world
just might be on to something.
Dr. Sanjay Gupta, CNN, Santa Monica, California.
(END VIDEOTAPE)
AZUZ: If you can stomach it, eating some bugs
might be healthy, but you know not to go dig
in around your yard for dinner. Bugs in the
wild, they could be poisonous, they could
be coated with chemicals. So you need to make
sure that you only eat bugs -- if you eat
bugs -- that come from certified sellers or
restaurants.
We didn`t expect to see people doing pushups
in here. But on the side of the road after
getting in trouble with police? That`s what
got an investigation going in Rhode Island.
Police say, a group of people between ages
15 and 18 vandalized the mailbox. And the
video is blurry, but you can barely see them
here doing pushups. That`s what officers made
them do instead of arresting them or filing
a report about the incident. But now the police
are being investigated.
(BEGIN VIDEOTAPE)
MAYOR CHARLES LOMBARDI, NORTH PROVIDENCE,
RI: We are not going to tolerate juveniles
coming into town and knocking out mailboxes.
And at the same time, we are not going to
allow our police officers to take the law
in their own hands.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: One of the accused vandal`s mother said
this: "the cop did wrong, but I`m glad he
tried to teach my son a lesson. Personally,
I don`t think he should be suspended."
Our affiliate spoke to some residents of the
area, many of whom seem to support the pushup
punishment. Do you think police went too far
or that justice was served? Talk to us on
our blog at cnnstudentnews.com, but please,
use only your first name.
And finally, a gym in Orlando, Florida specializes
in helping certain family members keep fit.
The four-legged ones. Fat cats and portly
poodles might seem cute and cuddly, but doctors
say the extra weight could be taking years
off the pets` lives. Part of the problem is
how much they eat and one solution for that:
hit the gym. This one`s got a pool, treadmills,
Pilates equipment.
This dog`s owner says he`s lost six pounds
in four months. It takes some effort to shed
those extra pounds, but if it makes your pets
healthier, it could be well worth the weight.
Yeah, just a couple of puns today. We really
had to scale it back a bit, but we know many
of you find them uplifting, so we`ll work
out some more and have them ready tomorrow
when CNN STUDENT NEWS returns.