SIMON OSTROVSKY: We'd finally
arrived at the Havat Gilad
outpost in the West Bank, which
is home to some of the
most hardcore settlers.
This was a community that was
prepared to live at the top of
a hill in the Palestinian
territories, in defiance of
both international
and Israeli law.
There to tell us about their
lives were Simcha and Yosef, a
pair of teenagers who are busy
doing what settlers in the
area did best--
building a house without
a permit.
When they hear somebody say the
West Bank, they think that
it's a war zone,
it's dangerous.
You're living right next door
to Arabic villages.
Are you fearful for your own
safety, moving out here?
There's no fence around
the settlement at all.
You're kind of exposed.
SIMCHA: I don't feel any--
like I'm afraid.
I have God here.
Yeah.
You getting used to it.
SIMON OSTROVSKY: But you can
even hear the call to prayer
going now from the nearby
Arabic town.
SIMCHA: Actually annoying.
SIMON OSTROVSKY: Simcha didn't
seem to have much sympathy for
his Palestinian neighbors
or their culture.
But then again, he was kind of
pissed because a couple of
weeks ago they'd apparently
burned down a house he'd
helped build, and
killed his dog.
SIMCHA: Came in the morning,
and they saw nobody here.
And then came two guys and
just burned the house.
So after, all of our guys, they
went to the village and
start fighting there, and
it was a big mess, yeah.
SIMCHA: From our guys?
No.
SIMCHA: I think so.
SIMCHA: Yeah, probably
they're afraid.
SIMCHA: We don't meet girls.
That's one of the problems.
SIMCHA: Lonely?
No, I never get lonely.
[HAMMERING]
[GUITAR STRUMMING]
SIMON OSTROVSKY: So you're
going to start
a settlement band?
SIMCHA: Yeah.
We're going to just make Jewish
blues, some kind of
something like that.
SIMCHA: Kind of.
SIMCHA: Ah, yeah.
SIMON OSTROVSKY: Simcha struck
me as an oddly-normal teen for
someone who is taking part
in a blatant land grab.
But the settlers don't
see it that way.
In their view, God had promised
the Jews this land.
End of story.
[SPEAKING HEBREW]
SIMON OSTROVSKY: What do you
think the Arabs want?
[SPEAKING HEBREW]
SIMON OSTROVSKY: Does it make
you angry that most of the
international community agrees
with the Palestinians in that
you shouldn't be in
the West Bank?
[SPEAKING HEBREW]
SIMON OSTROVSKY: Have you
personally had any problems
with Israeli police?
[SPEAKING HEBREW]
SIMON OSTROVSKY: Simcha and
I left Yosef to do some
construction while we took a
stroll around the settlement.
I suppose if you do like
everybody else here, you have
to start your own family soon.
SIMCHA: Yeah.
SIMON OSTROVSKY: But you also
have to go to the military, so
how do you do both?
SIMCHA: I do military
and I'm done.
SIMON OSTROVSKY: But you
want to go to the army?
SIMCHA: Yeah, I want to
go the army, yeah.
SIMON OSTROVSKY: Can you imagine
a situation where
you'd be part of a unit that
was ordered to provide
security for a demolition?
SIMCHA: Never.
No.
SIMON OSTROVSKY: What about
the demolition of a
Palestinian's house?
SIMCHA: I'll be happy
to do it.
That will be my dream.
SIMON OSTROVSKY: Simcha
introduced me to Yair, a
19-year-old who was about
to enlist in the army.
Yair's house had recently been
destroyed by the police, and
he seemed even more vocally
opinionated than both Yosef
and Simcha.
I wonder if you tried to look at
it from the perspective of
the Palestinians.
Their fathers were here, their
grandfathers were here, and
their great-great-grandfathers
were here.
They don't know any
other country.
YAIR: They do.
SIMON OSTROVSKY: They
might say, where are
we supposed to go?
YAIR: You know how many
countries have Arab
[INAUDIBLE]?
22.
We have one.
And now we have half of it.
Not even all of it.
And the little piece we
have, they want to
steal from us again.
SIMON OSTROVSKY: Would be really
stupid of me to say
that the Canaanites were
here before Israel?
Maybe their descendants
can claim to have
more rights than Jews.
YAIR: You see the
Canaanites now?
You see them anywhere?
SIMON OSTROVSKY: No, I'm just
trying to make a point that
history moves in many places,
and many different ways.
YAIR: History moves.
Again, the Jewish people didn't
move a millimeter.
SIMON OSTROVSKY: But
even Israel says
this isn't your property.
YAIR: I feel sorry for the
government that they feel that
they still, in Poland
and Germany.
And they think, oy, Obama.
Oy, we are afraid of Obama.
We are afraid of all the
rest of the world.
We are not in 1945 anymore.
That's it.
No Jew is going into the
burning places anymore.
That's it.
Finish.
Done.
SIMON OSTROVSKY: Is it true that
settlers sometimes attack
a Palestinian village as a
reprisal against the Israeli
police destroying a
settler's house?
YAIR: Uh, I heard about those
things, but as a settler, I
never did that.
I never saw that.
I have no idea what they're
speaking about.
I believe that it's a
manipulation of the media.
Every media guy has a agenda.
My father always says that the
only true thing in the
newspaper is the date.
That's it.
This is my ideology.
This is what I believe in.
I believe that the Israeli
people should
live anywhere in Israel.
SIMON OSTROVSKY: I headed back
to meet with Simcha and Yosef,
who'd taken a break from
construction, and were
ordering a pizza from a nearby
settlement called Kedumim.
The goal for Havat Gilad and
Kedumim is to eventually merge
and form a settlement block,
which would, in turn, separate
the Palestinian villages
on either side of it.
In the meantime, I headed back
to Tel Aviv across the Green
Line, and into Israel proper.
[SIREN]
SIMON OSTROVSKY: There's tons
of soldiers and police here
today because they're expecting
a confrontation with
the Palestinian demonstrators.
[SHOUTING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]