ELLIOT BAMBROUGH: We're here in
Soweto at one of the many
taxi ranks that dot
the landscape.
That's because they're the
most popular form of
transportation in the townships
because most people
don't have the money to buy
a vehicle themselves.
And it gives them accessibility
to places all
over Johannesburg.
The taxi drivers themselves have
played a key and evolving
role in shaping the music
scene here in Soweto.
But joining me for this
mission is Krishna.
Krishna is from Brooklyn.
How ya doing?
KRISHNA ANDAVOLU: Hey, doing
great, how about you?
ELLIOT BAMBROUGH: I'm doing
really well, thanks.
So we're going to go now and
find out a little bit more
about how these guys actually
fit into the music scene.
So tell me, what is Krishna?
KRISHNA ANDAVOLU: Well, I'm a
writer and an editor for an
online-only magazine that's
about death and dying.
ELLIOT BAMBROUGH: An
online magazine
about death and dying?
How big is your audience?
KRISHNA ANDAVOLU: Well, they're
all dying, so they
don't even count.
ELLIOT BAMBROUGH: [LAUGH]
KRISHNA ANDAVOLU: We
don't even know, we
can't even keep track.
So what do you know about the
music scene in Johannesburg.
ELLIOT BAMBROUGH: It was born
out of the townships and at
the end of apartheid.
So we're talking
about '93, '94.
The music that sprung up
instantaneously was called kwaito.
So to get the music to the
people, and to get these
people hearing this new kwaito
music, the artists found the
best way of doing it was
by using taxi drivers.
So the artists would give
their demos to the taxi
drivers to play in
their taxis.
And that's how these musicians
and kwaito stars broke into
the bigtime in the '90s,
was via taxi drivers.
KRISHNA ANDAVOLU:
That's amazing.
ELLIOT BAMBROUGH: So rather than
me going on and on about
my definition of kwaito,
do you actually
want to hear some?
KRISHNA ANDAVOLU: Yeah,
absolutely.
ELLIOT BAMBROUGH: OK, hang
on, let me sync up.
[MUSIC PLAYING - KWAITO]
ELLIOT BAMBROUGH: So
this is kwaito.
And this is one of the biggest
stars in kwaito.
This guy's called Brickz.
KRISHNA ANDAVOLU: Wow.
ELLIOT BAMBROUGH:
What do think?
KRISHNA ANDAVOLU: I think
it's awesome.
ELLIOT BAMBROUGH: Well, we are
actually on our way now to go
and meet Brickz.
KRISHNA ANDAVOLU: Man,
that's exciting.
ELLIOT BAMBROUGH: A
star of the music.
So we're on our way now.
[MUSIC PLAYING - KWAITO]
ELLIOT BAMBROUGH: Brickz,
first off, awesome
performance.
KRISHNA ANDAVOLU: Yeah,
that was amazing.
ELLIOT BAMBROUGH: You put a
whole lot of energy into that.
BRICKZ: Thanks guys,
thanks guys.
I try to make sure that
I bring personal
experiences in my music.
Things that I've seen.
And everything that's happens
in the streets.
It's more like hip-hop.
People who listen to kwaito,
they are mostly people who
understand ghetto life.
ELLIOT BAMBROUGH: And am I right
in thinking that taxi
drivers were the way that
everyone got their music out
to the people?
BRICKZ: Yes, because most
taxi drivers, they
come from the township.
And taxi drivers know
how to pump a song.
And each and every one who goes
in and out the taxi gets
to hear your song,
which is good.
When someone gets out of
the car, he wants to go
and buy that CD.
And that's what you want.
KRISHNA ANDAVOLU: Could you
teach us that Mandela dance
before we go?
BRICKZ: [CALLING OUT IN RHYTHM]
[LAUGHS]
You guys rock, man.
We meet at the taxi ranks.
KRISHNA ANDAVOLU: We're at
Bara taxi rank in Soweto.
It's one of the largest taxi
stands in the city.
KRISHNA ANDAVOLU: Oh, you
turn up the music at
1:00 for the kids.
ELLIOT BAMBROUGH: The
kids like it louder.
Yeah, that makes sense.
ELLIOT BAMBROUGH: Are there
drivers that people know--
I have to go in his taxi because
I know that I'll hear
a great new kwaito artist.
How do you find them?
KRISHNA ANDAVOLU: Red BK.
They can also you hear you
coming from blocks away,
probably, right?
So you probably have
a big soundsystem.
Can we go inside and
have a listen?
MANDLA: What--
ELLIOT BAMBROUGH: To
the music, yeah.
KRISHNA ANDAVOLU: Yeah,
let's do it.
ELLIOT BAMBROUGH:
Let's do this.
It's not your typical
cab ride.
OK, so four speakers
in the back here.
[MUSIC PLAYING - KWAITO]
KRISHNA ANDAVOLU: Yeah,
this is good.
ELLIOT BAMBROUGH: I think you
actually have to be in there
to really appreciate the power
of the subwoofer sitting in
the back and it reverberating
through your entire body.
KRISHNA ANDAVOLU:
It felt great.
ELLIOT BAMBROUGH: So if you're
ever in Soweto and you're
looking for a taxi--
BK Red.
A mundane thing like getting in
a cab, anywhere else in the
world, is just that.
But here, it's almost just
like you're immersed in a
cultural activity.
KRISHNA ANDAVOLU: When I was
expecting to come here, I
thought, you know, taxi stands
in New York are shit holes.
But this is like, it's kind of
nice here, and the taxis
themselves are just
immaculate.
ELLIOT BAMBROUGH: So what's
the music that you
play in your taxi?
ELLIOT BAMBROUGH: House music.
KRISHNA ANDAVOLU: So do
you think it's an
evolution of the sound?
ELLIOT BAMBROUGH: In America and
in Europe, you get into a
taxi, you don't talk
to the taxi driver.
You don't want to
hear his music.
You turn it down.
And here it's a totally
different lifestyle and
acceptance of, you get into it
because you want to have a
conversation.
You want to hear the music.
Do you feel like a music
promoter, in that respect?
ELLIOT BAMBROUGH: So we managed
to track down this DJ
called DJ Qness.
And he appears to be a bit of
an authority on house music
and also the shaping role that
the taxi drivers have played
in the house music scene
here in Johannesburg.
KRISHNA ANDAVOLU: So now, when
you hear your song coming out
of a taxi, you know that
you've made it.
It's not your way
of making it.
You know that people have
already heard your music.
KRISHNA ANDAVOLU: Tonight we're
meeting [INAUDIBLE]
at a street party of Soweto to
check out some local DJs spin
South Africa's biggest
house songs.
ELLIOT BAMBROUGH: So we finally
go to the party.
It's completely bangin inside.
We brought [INAUDIBLE] along to
check out JKN, which dude,
you're gonna absolutely
love him.
Guys, you ready?
Want to go to a party?
KRISHNA ANDAVOLU:
Yeah, let's go.
[MUSIC PLAYING - HOUSE]
ELLIOT BAMBROUGH: Krishna.
KRISHNA ANDAVOLU: Elliot.
ELLIOT BAMBROUGH:
South Africa.
KRISHNA ANDAVOLU: What
a great trip.
ELLIOT BAMBROUGH: Thanks so
much for coming along.
I've really enjoyed having
you along for the ride.
KRISHNA ANDAVOLU: Yeah, we
had such a great time.
Such great music.
ELLIOT BAMBROUGH: Well, like
talking about the music.
I mean, like, I think we can
agree that while taxi drivers
and the role they played
has changed.
They'll always be inextricably
linked with music and giving
it to the people here.
KRISHNA ANDAVOLU: Absolutely,
and they
bring people together.
The music is irrepressible,
so.
ELLIOT BAMBROUGH: To the music,
and the night's being
young, and us still being here.