American Alligators are apex predators in the Everglades.
They can grow between 10 to 12 feet in length and
they don’t have very many enemies at that size.
Especially snakes.
There is a new type of predator surfacing in the Everglades these days.
Burmese Pythons.
Alligators, especially adult alligators are certainly not used to being attacked by snakes.
In this extremely rare footage, an overly aggressive Burmese
Python actually attacks a full grown American Alligator.
A python of this size normally is no match for an adult alligator.
However, nature does take an extreme turn form time to time.
And in this instance, instead of the alligator tearing up the snake to shreds,
It’s actually intimidated by the python and retreats.