little bit to benefit those of you that
don't have a table or those of you that
aren't in it professionally who just want to do it with your
friends and family.
One of the things
that is important is that the person on
the floor is comfortable some kind of a
little padding or cushion
is nice
it's not a good idea necessarily to work
from a bed because the bed sinks
down and you don't get the nice solidness underneath. This is similar to the
table.
The other thing is I'm going to explain some
what how that mechanics need to be for
the person doing the massage because
there is
uh... it's a lot harder to work from the floor for the therapist.
So we'll start with the back
and um... basically i'm just on my knees
So you'll be able to see how the body
is going to work a little bit.
this is where it's important to have good
strength in your core if you're the one doing
the work.
Okay, just applying the oil...
Now basically I work
similar to what I would do from the
table.
So i'm gonna start up here and
begin to work. Now here because there's
no face cradle the neck is turned
so the muscles are gonna be in a little bit different position. There will be a shortening and a lengthening
but you can still basically work the same way
spreading open the trapezius into the shoulder blades
and you can glide down along side of the spine
working through.
Bringing your hands back up and spreading out and again.
This is like a...
I usually do this three times.
No reason. Just
that's what I do.
I tend to move outside. I do one closer to the spine and then more in the
middle of the muscle and then on the edge, so that's really where I get my "three" from.
The neck is very differently placed when it's turned.
So you'll be able to notice just how
different that is. You can't really work the neck
very well when it's turned.
Okay so then to go down into this
arms you have to reposition yourself by coming
over to the side
and then beginning to work
outward in this direction.
Around the shoulder blades. So all of this technique is really
the same.. similar I should say
to what you're doing.
I can already feel in my body
the strain
of the different
position that has to be done.
It's best to be on your knees, if possible high on your knees so you can
move your body around.
There's a little bit of twisting that goes on.
And then of course we can rub back upward.
And then working back down
sliding the hands
and repositioning
myself.
Now here I tend to put my leg up because then I can get
a little bit more
of a
direction on the
muscles.
It's a little bit easier to get when I'm higher
than when I'm lower down.
And working up
again.
And then
to work across, lowering myself down.
It's still staying fairly mobile.
Still staying in a way that I can
moves with the
action of the massage work.
So this is the basic
routine that i've done
many times over. I've been
doing this same basic routine for my
entire massage career. It's a good
routine because it does cover
everything. It moves from muscle to muscle very smoothly.
And it just covers it all. It doesn't
leave anything out and i do recommend
that you find some routine that you can
work because that way you get both sides of the body
equally
and if you have a routine, pretty soon that
becomes very
much
part of
what you do and you don't have to think too much so you can concentrate on
sensations that are under your hands.
That's how you begin to work and understand the body more
on an intuitive level.
So we are just working there
and back up
and down. Okay and then
let's start to the other side
same thing.
and of course this routine is
somewhat modified
not a lot but there is some
modifications happening here.
Use the upper..pushing upward on these muscles near the hip.
right along the hip edge
and then up we go. This is another "threesome" thing that I do when I go up the spine.
The spine has a little bit different movement when you're going upward or downward.
And then coming back down and then working up across by her....
across the erector spinae
and then back up. Now for the vibration along the
vertebrae...
You won't be able to start up at the base of the skull, so you'll start down here, about
C7.
And vibrate down
and then you can go back up
vibrate down, up
and again and vibrating down...
and back up. This is a little bit different than what I normally do when I'm working from a
table.
Okay and I'm gonna switch to the other side and reach up here
going between each vertebrae
Down to the sacrum, the SI joint...
And then on the floor I do the
body wrapping from both sides
just pushing down the...
downward
downward, down through the ribs
and then you can wrap back up
and up
upward
and upward...
And a nice finish by just bringing it up.
And then little brushes to sweep.
Okay so i hope that gave you some ideas
for working on the floor.