tiring over its entrance is an
engineering masterpiece the cast me
immortalized by hollywood films pictures
of mister loveless structure was built
directly into solid rock
nearly twenty centuries ago
now discoveries are nothing
the startling engineering behind the
casket
and the law states that people can built
how was this magnificent building
constructed
who could have achieved such an
incredible
and the biggest questionable
watch was before
every year in the added landscape of
jordan southern gaza over half a million
tourists trek through and out of court
over one kilometer long
penetrates deep into the pattern rocky
terrain
they are retracing the route of intrepid
swiss explorer johanna moves we could
book out
who in eighteen hundred and twelve came
here
chasing rumors of an ancient
most city
the narrow twisted fica winds its way
through high cliffs
yielding tantalizing glimpses of a
structure apartment
nothing prepares the visitor for what
lies beyond the final band
pastures most magnificent creature
aspect
this ancient building stands thirty nine
meters high
its ground column two entrances towers
over visitors who come to wonder text
delicate carvings and dramatic
sculptures
built into the red sandstone
because ms cavernous inner chambers
breach deep into the heart of the clip
it's god's the gateway into the two
thousand year old city affects
beyond the counseling
the narrow canyons opens out into a wide
basin
share of the landscape is littered with
the ruins of a lost civilization
at temple
but amphitheatre
dozens of two
only traces remain of what was once the
ancient capital cities with the old
manuscript school petra
the greek word system
the greatest surviving structure in
petra is the casting
none
off the other buildings the facades that
you haven't had time
the perfection
off the cust name
lecturing me to do etc is fascinated by
the customer
was assaulted odds
sorted through
very very well
and what they achieved that is
absolutely spectacular
the cancer is pictures finest
construction
a sophisticated piece of engineering on
a scale rivals anything in the ancient
world
for nearly two hundred years experts
have been backing to understand the
engineering genius behind its
construction
over the centuries theories have been
constantly disproved and altered
nobody knew who built the cat's name or
what it was full
the sheer logistics of building such a
monument in the bleak diamond doesn't
seemed impossible
to have any hope of finding answers
experts first have to solve even bigger
mystery
bit protest
in the nineteenth century the only clue
historians had was the name of the local
bedouin tribes catered
cosmic photo
shadows treasury
discarded arabic
president but on that circling
it certainly isn't a very up their own
jordanian occu images doctor how the
economy that is trying to unlock the
kashmiri secrets
the battery believe that the cat's name
was an ancient egyptian treasure for
but modern experts have discovered clues
that prove the ancient egyptians did not
build
they were able to identify its
distinctive architecture
and
many of the hottest it features a greek
peter's here
abruptly president at the top
at the following switches
drought-like
structure in the middle
but that the length of the pulpit and
terence
grabbing back columns infront
some of the futures reflects the late
afternoon mystics job
found throughout the roman empire in
cities like alexandria to the west of
petra
from this experts calculated at the cats
may may have been built sometime around
eighty bc
nearly a thousand years
as after the glory days of ancient egypt
the ancient egyptians did not building
sarcasm
that is another theory
clues line two thousand-year-old greco
grumman manuscript
they speak of petra
the magnificent city in the desert
and describe it as the home
thirteen
rabbit series where nomadic tax
originally camp
buried impotence of love
it became well-known for their trading
activities and their control over the
trade routes
than other g_m_
dominated the traded incidents inspires
running camel caravans across the
arabian desert
think about how bad not to five times
just must think of few hundred camels if
not thousands
behind the whole this was this capital
city that they don't
which is that right
petra was perfectly positioned at the
point where several of the ancient
worlds most important trade routes
intersected
from here than i have a chance to trade
with the romans the greeks to the west
the questions to the east
running caravans from a radio to the
mediterranean sea
betrayed made him one of three
and powerful
the reputation of the matter to insist
that they are the richest of the rich
it's megabucks it's newt gingrich
historians newton who never to be
informed by dynastic kings
and by the first century b_c_ had
settled communities in the area
but no one had suspected that levity
ends what must have been
his capable of creating a city like
petra animosities that is the casting
they disappeared effort
in serbia
four hundred since yest
little of patrick has survived for more
than researchers to investigate
however groundbreaking new work is
starting to unearth the secrets of
levity in engineering
the archaeology is producing
extraordinary results
using these results the mysteries of the
cast many can be unlocked
revealing the secret of its doc purpose
and the great american behind its
construction
the one question its own spring fest
how did the levity ins engineer to make
a structure like the castle
in the middle of the desperate
petra is one of the ancient worlds most
beautiful cities
and the charismatic is it's crowning
glory
experts now where the medicines were
behind its creation
but this discovery provokes and even
bigger ritual
how a group of nomadic traders were able
to construct such and engineering
masterpiece
did such a band appears even more
astonishing one examples of only nobody
an architectural taken into account
advocate is that what you can see here
behind that
and you can see they're pretty player
these basic caracas tumse have dominated
by a simple design called a cruise state
oaks like to staircases leading opposite
directions
sucrose set
seems to have the
all along with the most difficult type
of seventeen facades
but the charismatic
reasoned and totally differently
well than average in cities hit
is different and probably more
impressive than anywhere else
the challenge facing the buildings was
enormous
experts wanted to work out how they
could scale than you know veggie
conclude to the height of the casting
thirty-nine meters
one researcher is re-examining the
clintons
uh... school goals
uh... screw
supports heat rises
doctor shah heroin problem
a leading expert on our picture was
built
is focusing on a set of slots to the
sides of the casting
some experts believe that these slots
held scaffolding pose
but in patrons rocky wilderness trees
are in short supply
scaffolding over thirty nine meters high
it would take a foretaste form of tender
doctora baba is convinced them that the
tunes wouldn't have relied on such a
rare commodity
he investigates for that
he finds that the homes are not entirely
square
they are in fact deeper at the base than
the out of the top
circumferential this tooth costs vehicle
with the disease
so you don't think that the
where he was discourse
doctor barbara has a theory
i recently we're used to sarah's let's
close
proposed work a little bit
he believes that these fortunes were
carved long after the cans name was
constructed
perhaps during the medieval period when
the sculptures of living things with
being defensive
this may have been when vandals beheaded
in deface the figures on the cancer
whether medieval or not
dr obama believes the square slots had
nothing to do with the construction of
the cast
sonar roboblogger wants to find out how
i was the napa june's data access the
structure
he finds his own son and more tutu they
had left unfinished
we love our respond to all of
the unfinished warm
it isn't really very important to slip
through
this unfinished tomb unlocks the secrets
of the kasinga's construction
it's brings the digital's to see the
replicas students use
with the risk of food
intersted the view was much more on the
platform
the evidence reveals that the builders
carved not true platform out of the rock
they used this platform is the lead role
in which to standpoint
what's more this discovery indicates a
revolutionary approach to construction
another tns tenant building techniques
on their heads
the main difference between the three
standing buildings
and here and bureaucrats monuments is
the starting point industry standing
buildings we started from
the foundation
but the band broke up we started from
the top
the buildings not constructed in the
traditional fashion
from the ground up
it was carved out of the rock
from the top
dismantle builders had to start as a
hike to thirty nine meters
they had planned a cousin is location
carefully
natural com tools in the cliffs
formed a narrow groups to the top of
that building site
the time must have been precarious
in fact a simple solution may have used
that way
staffs cut into the rock
many of these cards staircases can still
be seen in the surrounding clues leading
up to the cast
having gained access to the construction
site the hard work begins
the entire job was completed in two
stages
first the heavy work attacking backed
the uneven surface of the cliffs
starting at the top of the casting
the napa tns told them on the walk fast
create the first working platform
from here they worked on
pointing the way the rafters
face to create a smooth
flat working centers
all over the cavs met doctor rub up on
has identified scars in the wrong
these reveal the simple hand-held to
that's required for each stage of its
construction
large couch stars indicate most of this
work was achieved using pick ax
it must have taken a month
ste florio destroyed
criminality and reach the bottom
that blank canvas was ready to pick up
the second stage beginning
the builders climbed back up to the top
'cause another election
and began to painstakingly contradictory
to fiza
every cop had to be perfect
if the builders made a mistake they
couldn't climb back to the past
gravity and stand to lose weight only
made from fruit on it
but they were skillfully used to shape
petra soft sensed it
as they work that way it's done
the builders started to revealed the
finished structure
it was like dropping like flies stone
curtain to unveil masterpiece behind
but very genuine she did not end there
the way in which these desert bill just
dealt with the huge quantities of the
greenwalds brilliantly resourceful
clues from around petra reveal the
secrets of the construction sites do you
want at this
the unwanted rock was removed and great
blocks of stone
trenches were cut into the lecture that
bridge
leaving squares of rock exposed in the
middle
these individuals squares with and leave
it in split off their rocky base
using net trove cleavage points in the
sense to them
rather than waste energy and lowering
the blocks
the mapucchi and simply push them off
the ledge
these great clumps of stonewalling all
the way to become the building blocks
for free-standing structure is nearby
because there was both a construction
site
decor
however
they stopped on construction technique
did not come without a price
there was no margin for error
with a free-standing building workers to
make sure the walls and columns are
strong enough
before adding the weight of the office
sections on top
with a top-down technique pick up the
sections a finished first
if the weight of the opposition's
becomes too heavy
the entire structure could collapse on
top of the workers below
for some to this building is so
surprising
at mccann is a civil engineer
has been examining the structural forces
within the casper
with each other thing ravages of
you realize that what they see as his is
effectively a carving into the place
this when we start talking about it as a
structure and how does it work is a
structure very very different to a
building in the in the conventional
sense
the whole of the cancer is carved from a
single piece of rock
however there is one place which could
still be at risk the portico or entrance
way
that dominates the lower section
hundreds of tons of rock is suspended
over this must entrance space
the solution is a massive stone lynching
which spans the width of the building
and pest this weight
it sits on top of six columns
but even the columns have carved out of
the cliff
while the out before i left imbedded in
the rock face the central two columns
uh... free-standing
it appears as if these two columns take
most of the weight
if this is the case
then the columns have difficulty
absolutely straight to bear the weight
of the lentil upon
big risk
but the napkins knew how to avoid
when we look at that structure which
looks like he's a little wisconsin
forcing it
i mean when you look further you realize
it lynn please still fully attached to
the christmas still politics with andes
invaded into the massive rock at the end
it's it's hard to imagine they even if
we took the central columns away let
this thing will collapse
that is compelling evidence to support
this theory
because many was heavily restored in the
nineteen sixties
before this one of the central columns
was missing
from nineteen th century paintings the
foreman column concretely bc
even without at the casimir remained
intact
the columns anot load them
berlin
in fact the entire facade is fully
supported by the great cliff in which
it's it's
these discovery show that the building
of the cat's name was no fluke
than other teams knew what they wanted
to do
how to do it
people conscious of
absolutely every elements
before they built something like that
the construction was meticulously
planned and carefully managed
refuse
there was
authority the conflicts before leaving
the scope that was reportedly squad even
both also here was the supervisor here
was an architect who designed the he
emphasized
through the architects sleight of hand
than other teams were able to create the
appearance of a massive monumental
structure
for a fraction the engineering
restaurant
few to try and build a building on this
scale and i can't stand up
it would be
proceeded to him
technology and costs and so this is a
cheap and effective
leading fantastic effect
the experts suggest at this time of the
facade spin
but their investigation still had a long
ways to go
questions remain about the interior of
the cat's name and what it was full
and the structures inhospitable location
praised problems with feeding and
watering such a large workforce
indus at temperatures of up to fifty
degrees centigrade
but first another more pressing riddle
lay before them
in spite of all their travel planning
the psych the builders of chosen for the
cast may seem to suicide
the sea
camaro crack in the cliffs opposite was
cut into the rock by thousands of years
of flood water surging along its parts
it could flood suddenly
and unpredictably
and the chasm and its builders lane
right in that spot
bitmap intends to use the site of the
cat's name
the jewel of petra from maximum impact
directly opposite to seek
the narrow twisting gorge that form the
entrance to the city
but they must have known that the sequel
dot stay dry or thier rock
rainfall is a rat chicken desert
environment
if you get a few inches so you get a few
feet an iso
it's totally unpredictable transporting
offers a hydraulic engineer
he's been studying the water management
impex was barren desert
in the wet season between november to
march
the rain is sometimes so heavy that the
hard ground cover or soak up the water
instead it triggers destructive
flash floods
his authority of the water is the debris
is carrying at that speed off the flash
floods
very destructive
the land around try is no exception
heavy rain storm
it's or on all things considered the
stage
the cps patrons narrowest in august dot
hundred meters in-depth one point
two kilometers long it was called by
centuries of flash flooding
during a heavy down
it was transformed into a raging torrent
of water
one and a half meters d
heading straight for the charismatic
endangering the delicately carved
structure
and extends
but in two thousand and two researchers
discovered a complex system of towns
into thirty meters tumble excavated
through the cliffs
another team builders had anticipated
the danger
the tunnel was parked of an elaborate
plan to deal with the sikhs destructive
hot water
but um... diverted the tolerance of
flood water through the tunnel to a
nearby court bypassing c completely
it's an extraordinary achievement for
engineers working two thousand years ago
they literally held back for a flat
but this wasn't just about protecting
the cast me
recent archaeological work has made a
dramatic breakthrough in the study of
petra
the tunnel is just one element of the
finest water management system
one of the
biggest elements
in the study also have the teens
knocking is
waterworks it's the hydraulic
engineering
it's kaelin sophistication make it one
of the greatest feats of hydraulic
engineering in the ancient world
and its efficiency was second to none
every drop is used in some way or
another so what you basically have would
be a good of continuous
awards supplying throughout the year
actually perfect
to discuss this on to another
power another tns kept their work force
applied with a reliable source of water
in the middle of the test
they understand
importance of
preserve the water
standing water
managing walter if you have not worked
in an area like contract you die
than other teens chairs pictures
location carefully to ensure they could
collect enough water for a constant
supply
actually picture sits at the bottom of
the patient
so if it gets water from warning of this
coming into the central core of the city
as well as collecting rainwater
engineers harvested supply is from
distant spring
off and i would say that uh... every
spring within a fifty-mile radius of the
quarrel picture itself has been tapped
transporting water into such huge
distances is a complex process
allman evidence had with terra cotta
pipes
short sections of pipe
could be placed into what caused cruise
they did in with more time and the joint
sealed with watertight pasta
but they're wants a problem
while more than water systems use deal
that can withstand huge internal
pressures
terra cotta is much weaker
these types of relatively fragile
and a few pressurized and bill blended
joints in pune
than other teams had to find a way to
safely get water through the pipes
their solution can be seen the high up
in the cliffs around the city
they've got to have a system
which doesn't generate significant
internal pressures and once the system
is a constant great system where the war
comes themselves from end to end for
constant gradient manages the forces
within the pipes by controlling the flow
water
if the types of food
the flow of this water exerts huge
pressure on the freemen
if there's an anika between the water
and
the pressure is dramatically reduced
this is called the open channel system
at most
efficient way to get food to the pipe
is to have the plank
to a certain height
this works best when the party's eighty
percent full
interest water pipes work perfectly
designed to achieve this flap
banality ins got the maximum amount of
water through the pacts with a minimum
amount of risk
over two thousand years ago
these ancient people was specialists in
hydraulic engineering
they have massive the hydraulic
principles of four weekend pipeline
systems
to indy career only matched ended twenty
first century
it's one thing to collect ring and
what's next
but quite another challenge to source
water during the drive-ins
the solution
underground water storage
there are two hundred systems within the
city
the engineering genius of the chemical
pipes up off the ground is matched
underground by this complex network of
systems if you look at what's retained
in the sisters you have sharp
almost supply a to sustainability
corporation
what's more the scale of the water
system suggests a city with a population
of fifty thousand people and functions
of visiting traitors
the city was like a man-made oasis in
the test
existence of god
system
everywhere you look
that is that it's beautiful to testing
down from someone else
it reflected the growing ambitions of
its people
monumental buildings were constructed in
the city center
the great templeton trying to run the
main thoroughfare
and the rock coffee otehr and
magnificent royal tombs of the street a
facades
which leads down from the city's
entrance under seek
one way of showing how important you are
on the international scene
is to create a city which eventually
everybody remembers
ivy ultimate embodiment of the netaji
and success is cast
across with it's visitors
is on the explosion and displays or
whilst uh... dipole workers
picket lines
right at the entrance to petra
it must have been put there
to overall visitors to the city
definitely it was
slowing off something
but surely the napkins didn't build this
extraordinary monument just to impress
visitors
what's what's the purpose of the cast
the cliffs of petra pitted with rock cut
structures
that function very different tomb to
temple too huh
from the impressive scale of the cat's
name
it was clearly built for great things
the question is what
the clues lying hidden in the sculpture
the grand facade is adorned with
god-like mythical figures animals and
franz and flies
that these sit in stark contrast to the
usual medicare and decoration
traditionally an aba g_m_'s use
geometric designs depicted records in
the arabian style
as rectangular blocks
because all of these
turning other teens
for centuries the scene
all blocks of snow
far from simple blocks of stone
sculptures on the facade had been
identified as carson's
great warrior women from greek legend
the trial of crisis the egyptian goddess
has been discovered in the center
what just below the head of medusa wants
to have done on visitors
the cosmic is the first as far as we
know
also great
facades which are full of images derived
from other nations
it certainly is the greatest
finality ans gained more than just
twelve from working the desert trade
groups
as they traveled across the eastern
mediterranean they gathered ideas
s artistic styles and beliefs
the gods on the map in sean's eventually
changed
they change appearance they are no
longer just blocks of stone
the local excuse
ices aphrodite to you because of all the
nations that surrounds them
and it is not just the decorations
reflects an adoption of mediterranean
styles
the home facade
mimics the architecture of the classical
world
i think that the
monument ality
and he
influence of egypt is definite that
abt that the entrance of the greek roman
world is also present in the cosmic
it's easy to imagine how the never tns
gathered these ideas spot it's less
obvious why they wanted to copy
the answer isn't relevant today as it
was two thousand years ago
i look at the close of wearing
uncovering
traditional docking in close up
because he uses such and trust
very very similar at that time period
when they can't go wrong and culture
very dominant
as the militants grueling wealth of
knowledge they adopted the fashion since
that day
no through applying this adopted
mythology
the stories hidden inside the sculpture
can be unmarked revealing vital clues
about the great buildings function
yet before he kills
without that date
assault of adds up to have an
at the sides there are six figures off
that singh as always with the double
accent is but that gotten so bad that
sounds
and the two figures at the base of the
charismatic for to be the room and twins
castro and politics
hoop guided people's souls to the
underworld
there's a very strong association was
breath-taking everything almost
everything we see here
and uh... are offer clues to the cast
making dedicated to the dead
dikkat access here
you could see this may seventh
call at the channel leading out tough at
and this would have been for offering
sacrifices so people up about liquid
kind
and see the beautiful fursat
lol cap
sacrifice which could that be
precious audience precious fairfield
inns
maybe is small
for the blood-letting here
habitat that guy that in the basin out
there
offerings and sacrifices to the dead
were an important part of the napkins
beliefs
the evidence of death and ritual
tantalizing hints of the cast makes
function but they do not repeal of the
buildings true purpose
it could still be at temple monument
bull too
perhaps the final terms would lie inside
but after the glories of the facade
interior of the cast becomes as a
surprise
new great suite of rooms or elaborate
decoration here
just a simple main chamber twelve meter
square thirty meters high
with to side rooms at the front
the task of creating them without modern
technology is almost unimaginative
the scene sign it would have been
horrendous the absolute with choking
dust
the burials origins vertical on
conditioner lol result
only small oil lamps contribute fairways
staked went into the heart of the
clinton
bedrooms for this telescope just iron
pics chisels
and that that happens
the chambers were carved using the same
top dog technique is the outside facade
when the covers reach the level below
the great clinton work started on the in
their homes
but on one was cut directly into the
truth
and was white to create the portico
behind the columns
from this further troubles will cut to
create the roofs of the changes
the only clues to discover technique to
windows above the doorways which served
as the first time entrances
then this work continues on the facade
and it's working platform dropped dot on
the plane
the floors of the chambers forward
apocalyptic on
goes on to six carl
propose four-wheel warped problems for
you because
foreign and gunshot to start doing six
thousand cubic meters of rock from the
chamber
the equivalent of two olympic swimming
pool
filled with stones
it's an incredible achievement
but hard labor was not the only secret
of their success
despite its simplicity of the chamber
required careful engineering
above it lies the crushing force of more
than a hundred and sixty meters of solid
rock
he's got a great deal of saying about
you
tens of millions of world all of which
all whiting down on top of this whole
and there loads have to be transmitted
somewhere and what happens is that the
loads will follow the stiffest
cost-effectively the loads pushing
around the side
off the kinds of most of the senate yes
the problem comes if the chamber is made
too wide
they're going to love the bars would not
be able to my kids loggia anywhere on
the side person in the middle east
breakthrough like that
than other students clearly understood
the limits of their design
they kept the interior chambers small
enough to prevent a catastrophic ruth
but the simplicity of the interior space
gave archaeologists no clues to the
callousness religious function
quite a lot of speculations about uh...
what this has been
there have been was at the temple
but it does not
the correct divisions
another weather was it's just too
again
arnaz sides of mario's in there
the interior has no trace of a better no
sarcophagus
new clean where one would have stored
without any signs of a bloody it could
not be a too
perhaps the kashmir was a monument on
during the great king
presently s
such large scale it's mustn't be invoked
by somebody extremely wealthy and
powerful
must have been picking
this is another question
archaeologists were only able to take
the casting to a rough
four hundred and fifty year winter on
the birth of christ
and during this period
any of several liberty and kings
could've built the structure
with no further needs to follow it seems
like as maze true purpose would never be
discovered
but then archaeologists made a startling
breakthrough
in nineteen ninety-six they found
evidence that the ground level in front
of the casket was much lower in netaji
and time
declared one-man on a journey of
underground exploration to find what
lies beneath and to unlock the kashmiris
last secret
why the new evidence proof that hasn't
has remained a mystery for centuries
no groundbreaking new discovery his
revealed crucial clues to its true
purpose
ebbing
discoveries in excavations but nothing
quite as important is this particular
one
it's excavations act
more informations for this beautiful and
unique we'll make it happen
suman fund transfer is director of the
picture archaeological haha
fighter jet news of the paved surface of
the sikh the winding korchi leading into
petra
disappears beneath the sand three
hundred meters before it's and
he had a hug
if the pols continued its downward
trajectory
it would reach the has made well below
decks current ground level
there could be an entire hidden level of
the council is submerged beneath
centuries of sent
so in two thousand and three he started
a major excavation
but his gamble soon paid off
six meters below the surface he made a
discovery
barrier chambers
inside with the bones of eleven
individuals
close the file
to we had a strategy
there we found a very unfair
burial from and
and some
hanging the offerings light
uses
the kashmiri is more than just a moment
it is a more slowly and with the
critical needs
but who's buried
all these the skeletons of the castle is
royal builder and his family
to identify the king
fighter jet needed to take to the better
deals
gas attacks updated
pairs toward the beginning of the
crescent remarried
with the date of the first century eight
d
finally the likely identity of the
callousness king is revealed
i believe that president
lies
coburg outta during the of it s be for
courageous the fourth was perhaps texas
greatest and most successful group
as i think that uh... because it was
both biking access apart
doing course time actually liberty at
liberty instincts their height of
power fixes
over eighty percent of all nobody and
claims filed there the image of reaches
the fourth
and it appears he put the switches to
good use
experts believe he was pictures most
infamous e_s_t_ develop
he is attributed with constructing the
great temperance and city streets
knowledge seems he also built actress
most reluctant structure
as his family's more civilian
their lives optimus
bezel from
the family of five iq tests the the
farce
patted doing wonderfully square towards
though the king himself is thought to be
buried elsewhere
these underground tunes could contain
the remains of his relatives lying
beneath the cast
every chance was bestowed with the title
friend of his people
pick as they seems to have been greek
key revered
suman fighter jets excavations revealed
that it laying at the heart of a
thriving religious complex
the fact that archaeologists have found
bosley incense and guests
to the gods or suggested that this is a
place in question
the discoveries of alternatives and
ritual offerings implying that this was
a place of public celebration
pilgrimage
no all these discoveries according to
compete we think of petra and the napa
jim's place in history
the perception of the leopard skins
has changed dramatically even in the
last ten years
they will march more than desert radius
they would accomplished architects
combining inspirations from other
cultures with a an ingenious engineering
than other teams created an incredible
structure
they are an extraordinary civilization
there an extraordinary people
and the canceling
is the greatest achievement
it stands today
marking the golden age of the city come
from the desert rock by the sheer
ingenuity when entrenched people
people who have finally been restored to
their rightful place in history
thousands of visitors come tomorrow
undisputed crown jewel extra
lost city
of another two years