abused by her husband she had her nose and
ears cut off and then she was left to die
uh...
got a prosthetic nose in california
and she looks great so we have a video recorder
about it so let's go with the video and will
discuss actors
now we want to bring you up to date on the
remarkable young afghan woman you me remember
agnew show also called bb
her face was mutilated by her taliban husband
and his family
on the cover of time magazine she became an
emblem of the brutality
but somewhat both strangers brought her to
california for reconstructive surgery a long
process but we thought you'd want to see what's
already begun
that's when i first saw her she was a young
girl sitting charlene on the wall her scar
covering her face
as we talk she took down your hands
to show me back in town
she was just twelve which you've been given
to a taliban man who married her an abuser
forcing her to sleep in the stables with animals
after she tried to run away the village men
handed down her sentence
her husband cut off her nose and years
by his brother held her down
left for dead
she managed to crawl first in her ankles house
but he refused to help her
so she kept on until a relative got her to
a hospital when by strangers
the strangers
where an american military medical team who
cared for her for two-and-a-half months
and gave her something she hadn't had
communists
even taught our a little english like that
what happens
after that keep active sparkly new pair of
shoes to come to america for surgery to give
her back her face as surrounded by caring
strangers people carson
you're listening to ask and music on youtube
and different counseling
this month she was begin with a prosthetic
nose like the kind that used in the movies
for special effects
she put it on herself
with the special skin if he's in each morning
kind of
preview of what the surgery will make one
inside function from different countries
it was a benefit for the gross numbers foundation
with the surgeons operated on prayer for three
the see half of the favorite musician lunging
in at former first lady laura bush
he was on the telephone first lady in the
field
and hallelujah
head of the girl she dreams he will be
the girls with a smile
of her own
uh... though she's as beautiful as as the
the best temporary they're gonna get her out
permanent knows that i didn't understand that
part yeah i think i think they're still working
on now reconstructing her face
case of reconstructing a nose that is in a
prosthetic but that's gonna take time so for
now she's gonna have apathetic but it's good
i think it's uh... incredible and so happy
for i don't know whether i am angrier at uh...
at uh... husband who
did that you were but the brother that with
the brother brother down or her own opal who
wouldn't help for all might in that is just
such a disgusting story
com
and then let me tell you something
there's a great country
like we helped
pat you know i thought
little american friday nights he should be
lurker prior and off of that swing look we
do great things as well we get so mad at the
crappy stuff we do screws were capable of
such great right that was great now where
we have the technology to do it
that we you know we essentially move a hospital
to help
our soldiers and civilians
in afghanistan
like what and mason capability you know what
would the script that my acceptable how we
would have screwed out of the army corps of
engineers have been charged or found out i
had some problems in the world
the point is jeans
uh... they um...
now because there's no what they're doing
and and and
that that would would orals not therefore
and uh...
you know so that's remarkable and then this
sort of
you know goodness of americans which we have
uh... which is not evidence
this election cycle
worth being
overwhelmed by this
them but we had this greatness in his goodness
only takes grow and help relieve the keep
billy dale per and somebody brings are over
you know and then all these other afghans
who work the taliban
embrace her and helper so i mean they're all
these good people in the world in the movies
nut job religious fanatics