So I bet you think this is the
part of the show, where I'm
going to say, don't try these
experiments at home.
And you're right, except
there is one experiment
we want you to try.
Just look for the graphic
that's right here
that says try it.
That's your signal that
you can try that
experiment at home.
Everything else, off limits.
Look, I've already given you
homework, and the show hasn't
even started.
I'm Steve Spangler and I'm all
about making science fun.
For the last 20 years I've been
teaching ways to turn
ordinary science experiments
into unforgettable learning
experiences.
I have an amazing team, who will
do whatever it takes to
affect the way people
think about science.
And to do that, I live
by one motto--
make it big, do it right,
give it class.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Well, we're here at DIA,
we are ready to go
to the Ellen Show.
It's a quick trip to Burbank.
And now it's my job to just
practice the demos.
So I figure I'll just flip
down the tray table and
practice the demos that I'm
going to do on the show.
I actually am her bodyguard,
I'm Carly's bodyguard.
I speak into my arm.
Sector one clear, sector
one clear.
And I just make sure that
everything is fine.
I always accompany her like
this, like she is a criminal.
Usually I have to
take her hands.
The other thing is
we've learned how
to merge into traffic.
So there's a correct
way to walk and a
correct way not to walk.
You'd better turn around,
because you're
going to fall in.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
All right, we're here
at the airport.
And, I think, I've got all the
demos figured out for the
Ellen Show because of good
friend here, Lopez.
All right.
So he and I have discussed this,
and we know exactly what
we're going to do on
the Ellen Show.
Tell them what we're
going to do.
LOPEZ: Well, I'm going
to wait and everybody
else will see later.
STEVE SPANGLER: That's right,
see he's a consummate
professional, because he knows
you don't tell the
demos ahead of time.
You've got to tell
me the demo.
But when you think of
it , you tell me.
Because I've--
[MUSIC PLAYING]
So here we are in lovely
California.
And I didn't realize this, but
look at the Hollywood sign.
It is so much smaller
in person.
And it's so big on TV.
But look at those letters
right there.
And right now, I think that it
would be a good idea for me to
climb up in there and
I'm just going to--
AIRPORT PORTER: Sir, it's
time for you to go.
Please.
STEVE SPANGLER: But I just
wanted to see the sign.
AIRPORT PORTER: Well,
you see it, sir.
Time for you to go.
STEVE SPANGLER: OK, But I just
wanted to see the sign.
I just wanted--
Whenever we do the Ellen Show,
this is the time in the
morning, when we sit down
and go through notes.
So we do have notes.
So going to kind of go through
all the demos, and just make
sure that everything is
set, and so forth.
And then, I'm sitting here at
the table with Carly and Jeff,
and there's a ton of science
stuff that you can do.
Anything that you can
find around you.
So look what I've got.
A little diaper time.
If you can find yourself a
diaper, you have all the
makings of a great little
experiment.
Believe it or not, the secret
that makes these diapers super
absorbent is this polymer
that's inside.
So you are going to have to give
me a couple minutes here.
But you rip open the diaper, and
then you kind of get the
polymer out.
Ah.
See, you can start to even
see it coming out here.
Watch this.
See the powder that's
coming out?
That powder is the polymer
that is super absorbent.
OK, watch.
So this goes into a cup.
Here, we won't use all of it.
Perfect.
Watch this.
Here is this water, watch.
So here's what makes
it super absorbent.
Watch, three, two, one.
Isn't that awesome?
So this is the material that's
in the diaper that causes it
to become super absorbent.
It's a polymer that absorbs
about 500 times
its weight in water.
So you can hide this, for
example, in the bottom of one
of these cups.
OK, see these cups here?
They're perfect.
So you just put this in
the bottom of a cup.
OK.
And so here's that powder.
See, it's hiding here.
So not this one goes on top,
a this one's here.
And nobody knows it's there.
Now you just have to
find somebody to
play along with you.
Look, it's Jack.
Jack manages the club up here.
And we've made kind of a mess,
but I want to show you
something cool.
And disregard most of this.
And the fact when you
do this and you open
this up, it goes tah-dah.
Like this, see?
This is a defect
in the bottle.
There are actually holes in
the bottle like that.
And that was her idea, so
that's her problem.
But here, let me
show you this.
This is very cool.
All right, so have you ever
seen the three shell game?
JACK: Sure.
STEVE SPANGLER: You know where
you put the pea in one.
OK, so watch this.
You put the water here.
OK, now.
Here's what I'm going to do.
I'm going to move them around.
And you tell me where it is.
Oops, it's not in that one.
JACK: Yeah.
STEVE SPANGLER: OK?
All right.
So you're ready?
JACK: Aha.
STEVE SPANGLER: All
right, watch this.
It's going to be good.
OK, here we go.
OK, where is it?
In the middle one, left
one, or right?
Whoa, see you're watching
pretty closely.
OK, I'm going to give you
a hint this time, ready?
It's not in this one.
You ready?
Oh look, Elvis.
STEVE SPANGLER: All right, so
now where do you think it is?
Left, middle or right?
Ah, see you're watching very,
very, very closely.
All right, so this one here, I'm
going to give you, OK, you
know where it is.
OK, ready?
Here we go.
Right here.
See, it's not in this, so
I did that on purpose.
Ready?
I'm doing this whole switcheroo
like this.
Where do you think it is?
Nope, not in this one, but
that's a good guess.
OK, so now.
Are you ready to keep going?
Here we go.
Here and here.
Now where do you think it is?
JACK: The middle.
STEVE SPANGLER: OK,
not in the middle.
No.
OK, keep going.
Right here, and here.
Where you think it is?
JACK: The middle.
STEVE SPANGLER: OK,
that was close.
Watch this one.
See the water's gone.
It's gone.
Tah-dah.
JACK: Wow.
STEVE SPANGLER: See
is that cool?
JACK: How did--
you're not going to tell me.
But, wow, that was great.
STEVE SPANGLER: When you weren't
looking, I just went
ah, and I drank it.
It was perfect.
JACK: Get out of here.
STEVE SPANGLER: See?
That's awesome.
JACK: That was very,
very good.
Very impressive.
STEVE SPANGLER: Thanks, man.
Very cool.
There you go, now next time
you see a diaper--
see it's a science
of a diaper.
All right, cool.
And, now you know.
See how cool is this to be
able to do all of this.
We are ready to go.
We'll head to the studios here
in just a couple minutes.
And nothing that we did this
morning will be on the show.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
STEVE SPANGLER: Well, here
we are backstage
at the Ellen Show.
Not everybody gets to see this
backstage area at the show.
We are getting ready for the
big finale, so we're using
this big, huge swimming pool.
And logistically, you know,
you've got to work on things
about how things are going to
move in and out of the show.
So, these are the pros that
know how to make it work.
I just stand here and wait for
them to say go, and we'll head
into rehearsal.
So, I think we've got the
cannon pressure set.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
STEVE SPANGLER: Look at this.
This is nerd fest over here.
Do you see this?
See, she has to have a little
gun to make sure that the
temperature is OK.
It's ice water.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
STEVE SPANGLER: One of the
things I've learned from the
people here at the Ellen Show is
not to telegraph things to
the audience.
So normally, as a teacher,
I'd just have
everything sitting out there.
But what I've learned is how
important it is to keep things
as kind of a secret.
So, when it's ready and they
say go, and they open the
doors, everything kind of gets
moved into place, and the
audience gets that
real reaction.
The other thing that you have to
know is that Ellen doesn't
want to see anything that has
to happen with the science
experiments ahead of time, so
we keep things as shielded
from her as possible.
So it's completely a surprise
when she gets to see it.
So when she's seeing it for the
first time, it's just like
the audience seeing it
for the first time.
It just means we've got to
practice a lot internally,
making sure that we're OK.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
STEVE SPANGLER: All right,
it's go time.
Let's see how it goes.
Back this way.
See you.
ELLEN: I have safety glasses
ready and I have the fire
marshal standing by.
And that can only
mean one thing.
Please welcome our science
guy, Steve Spangler.
[APPLAUSE]
STEVE SPANGLER: How are you?
ELLEN: Oh I'm good.
How are you?
STEVE SPANGLER: I'm great.
ELLEN: I never like to know
what's happening.
I like to be surprised
with everybody else.
So what are we doing today?
STEVE SPANGLER: My socks
are from JC Penney's.
ELLEN: Thank you very much.
Thank you.
STEVE SPANGLER: So I'm
fascinated with pendulums.
I don't know about this,
but you probably
are too, aren't you?
ELLEN: Sure.
STEVE SPANGLER: Yeah.
So, maybe it's just the swinging
repetitive motion.
Maybe I have nothing
to do in my life.
But it's--
I like that.
And so I was thinking
why don't we do
something with a pendulum.
And so look, it's a bowling
ball attached to a
great big huge rope.
Come here, this will be fun.
If I pull it back, and add some
energy to it, like when
you're pushing a kid on the
playground, you know swinging
the kid, you can make them go
higher than how you started.
ELLEN: OK.
STEVE SPANGLER: Which
could be dangerous.
ELLEN: Yes.
STEVE SPANGLER: Right?
So that's why I have the
stand-in right over here.
This is Mellon.
ELLEN: Hi, Mellon.
STEVE SPANGLER: And,
Mellon meet Ellen.
Awkward.
ELLEN: And how do you
know it's going to
come exactly back?
STEVE SPANGLER: I don't.
I just saw this on
the Internet.
ELLEN: I see.
STEVE SPANGLER: This is what I
was thinking is I want you to
stand in the place
of Mellon, OK?
ELLEN: No.
So, it's fine.
You don't have to worry
about that at all.
ELLEN: I'm not going
to do that.
STEVE SPANGLER: But if you had
a friend who wanted to?
Lauren, come on out here.
STEVE SPANGLER: Ah, this
is so awesome.
So if you stand right here like
this, I'm going to go get
the bowling ball.
I'll be right back, OK?
All right, so now watch.
If I bring this right--
LAUREN: Oh boy.
STEVE SPANGLER: --to your
face, like this.
Let's see it to your nose.
See how it's touching
right there.
And then I let go, it should
not come back and hit you.
Now if you move, it could
be dangerous.
So that's why this wall is going
to come in behind you.
All right, so here we go.
Watch this.
Bring in the wall.
Keep coming.
LAUREN: Thank you so much.
It's been great.
Thank you for having me.
STEVE SPANGLER: Keep the-- right
there, oh it's perfect.
So now, I'm going to bring
it right to your nose,
and it'll be great.
All right.
And this is for me, just in
case, because I have more
experiments to do, all right?
Drum roll, please.
Here it goes.
Don't move.
Here it comes.
Ahh.
See, you're fine.
Everything was great.
Let's here it for Lauren.
[APPLAUSE]
STEVE SPANGLER: What I was
thinking was is there another
way to crush a can that
would be better?
And this is it, all right?
So I've taken the cans
here, these cans.
And I put a little bit of water
into each of the cans.
So I'm cooking them on our
little stove here.
If we turn it upside down into
this colder water that's here,
you're going to allow the air
pressure to crush the can.
All right, so which one do
you want Sprite or Coke?
Which one?
ELLEN: I'll take Sprite.
STEVE SPANGLER: Bingo.
All right, so now you're going
to pick up like this, hold it
like this, and turn it
upside down, and
put it into the water.
ELLEN: All right.
STEVE SPANGLER: Turn it upside
down, put it in the water.
That was a nice one.
Look at that power
that's there.
ELLEN: Wow.
That's amazing.
STEVE SPANGLER: But I was
thinking, this is your big
show, and you would never allow
just that to happen.
So when I was thinking, I
thought what if we did it with
a 55-gallon steel
drum, all right?
Because who doesn't want
to crush one those?
ELLEN: Everyone needs to.
STEVE SPANGLER: Look at
this set up here.
This is going to be
really great.
ELLEN: Ah, yep.
STEVE SPANGLER: So here's
what we have going here.
We have a 55-gallon
steel drum.
As he caps it off now, no more
air inside, just that steam.
And the molecules are going to
go from 1,700 times farther
away from each other
then close by.
And see the swimming pool?
Some cold water.
Jeff, will you pour some
water on it for me?
So now, watch this, where you
just have the air pressure
pushing on it.
And now it's condensing down,
and now-- the weird thing--
[LOUD POP]
Isn't that awesome?
Come here, it' s OK
now, it's OK.
Listen, listen, listen.
ELLEN: All right, well let's--
[CLUNKING NOISE]
STEVE SPANGLER: See
how it's working?
It's just kind of crushing.
The same kind of thing that
we're trying to do to get kids
excited, whether it's online
or on YouTube, or any other
way they we're doing it.
ELLEN: Well it's always
a lot of fun, Steve.
Go to our website to learn more
about Steve and his new
YouTube show, the
Spangler Effect.
We'll be right back.
Steve Spangler.
[APPLAUSE]
STEVE SPANGLER: It crushed.
Bam, and we got it down.
And the bowling ball didn't
smack her in the face.
I say it's good.
Well, if you enjoyed this week's
episode, go ahead and
click the Subscribe
button here.
You'll be the first to know
when a brand new episode
appears each week.
This button right here will
show you some more cool
science experiments that we
do outside of this show.
This button right here will
take you to last week's
episode, just in case
you missed it.
And if you want to see the stuff
that you shouldn't see--
that's the bloopers and the
outtakes--- well, just click
this one right over here.
If you want to hear me stop
talking, through the magic of
television, just click this
button right here.
Go ahead, click it,
and I'll stop.
[MUSIC PLAYING]