SUROOSH ALVI: All right.
This is Basim.
BASIM USMANI: This is Suroosh.
SUROOSH ALVI: This is The
Vice Guide to Karachi.
BASIM USMANI: Oh, shit.
[MUSIC PLAYING AND
YELLING IN URDU]
SUROOSH ALVI: Karachi is the
biggest and fastest growing
city in Pakistan.
And with a population of around
18 million people, it's
one of the biggest
in the world.
It is also the country's
financial capital.
And is considered the
most educated and
diverse city in Pakistan.
However, it is also
the most violent.
[MUSIC PLAYING AND
YELLING IN URDU]
SUROOSH ALVI: It's true.
We hear about violence in
Pakistan all the time.
At least when it comes to the
seemingly never ending war
against the Taliban
and al-Qaeda.
But in 2011, more than three
times as many people were
killed in Karachi than the
number of people killed in
American drone strikes
in the tribal areas.
Why does that matter?
Because Pakistan matters.
Whether you're an American
worried about the extremists,
an Indian worried about the
nukes, or an Afghan worried
about Pakistan's ambitions,
basically, Pakistan is a
powder keg.
And Karachi is the detonator
that could set it all off.
We wanted to explore the inner
workings of this ultraviolent
metropolis and meet the players
who make Karachi one
of the craziest cities
on earth.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
TARGET KILLER: [SPEAKING URDU]
UZAIR BALOCH: [SPEAKING URDU]
CHAUDRY ASLAM: [SPEAKING URDU]
SUROOSH ALVI: Will anyone
shoot at us?
TARIQ MALIK: Yeah.
SUROOSH ALVI: Will they shoot?
Yeah, everybody there.
BASIM USMANI: [SPEAKING URDU]
DRIVER: [SPEAKING URDU]
BASIM USMANI: Fuck yeah.
We've got a escort from
the fucking most
dangerous people there.
SUROOSH ALVI: Lyari is
considered a no-go area by
most people.
It's Karachi's most densely
populated slum and is
notorious for it's thriving
drug and gambling dens.
Hardly a day goes by without a
headline detailing some kind
of horrific violence that
occurred there the day before.
And every so often, like the
night we chose to visit, the
police decide to conduct an
operation against it's most
famous residents, the
Baloch brothers.
Zafar Baloch and his brother,
Uzair, are the dons of Lyari.
And they're credited with
providing basic social
services to the residents
that the city
itself doesn't provide.
So even though they're accused
of operating a mafia based on
drugs, kidnapping, extortion,
and murder, they are the
patron saints of Lyari.
BASIM USMANI: The people over
there are not going to fuck
with us if we're talking
to Zafar.
SUROOSH ALVI: If anything, we
got to worry about the cops.
Because they're not going to
want it to get on film that
they're killing the locals.
BASIM USMANI: That they
probably don't want.
SUROOSH ALVI: Yeah.
Let's avoid the cops and just
hang out with the oppressed.
BASIM USMANI: Yeah.
Fuck the cops.
We already know that.
Fuck the police.
SUROOSH ALVI: We rolled up to
the edge of Lyari and saw a
slew of cops and local news
outlets standing on the
outside looking in.
MALE SPEAKER: [SPEAKING URDU]
SUROOSH ALVI: We met up
with Zafar's boys and
followed them in.
There's a huge police
operation trying
to arrest this guy.
And look at him.
He's just standing there.
BASIM USMANI: Meet the
man behind the plan.
[SPEAKING URDU]
SUROOSH ALVI: Very
nice to meet you.
BASIM USMANI: [SPEAKING URDU]
ZAFAR BALOCH: [SPEAKING URDU]
We made it.
What'd you think of him?
SUROOSH ALVI: I like him.
He's nice.
It seemed, like, I felt
safe around him.
BASIM USMANI: Yeah.
SUROOSH ALVI: You know,
like, uncle.
Classic mafia, right.
The guy who's in parliament,
he doesn't do anything.
And this guy does everything.
Sounds like he should
be in office.
BASIM USMANI: Too bad they're
trying to arrest him.
SUROOSH ALVI: But it doesn't
feel like anything's going on.
What is the operation, though?
What are they trying
to achieve?
SUROOSH ALVI: And you're
protecting him?
[MUSIC PLAYING AND
YELLING IN URDU]
MALE SPEAKER: [SPEAKING URDU]
[MUSIC PLAYING AND
YELLING IN URDU]
SUROOSH ALVI: I think the cops
are around the corner.
They said the cops were too
afraid to come any closer.
[MUSIC PLAYING AND
YELLING IN URDU]
SUROOSH ALVI: We're basically
hanging out with a bunch of
young punks in the ghetto
at 4:00 in the morning.
Though there were signs of
serious fighting earlier in
the day, while we were there
the police fired a single
canister of tear gas.
And our escort was running
around suggesting slogans for
everyone to yell into
our camera.
SUROOSH ALVI: This is kind of
not what I was expecting.
BASIM USMANI: No.
It wasn't what I was
expecting, too.
When they said that there was a
protest with 10 people dead,
I didn't expect 15-year-old hood
rats just going around
tearing shit up.
SUROOSH ALVI: And no people
dead thanks to the
misinformation in
this country.
This is the tear gas that
the cops shot today.
Welcome to Karachi.
[MUSIC PLAYING AND
YELLING IN URDU]
MALE SPEAKER: [SPEAKING URDU]
[MUSIC PLAYING]