[MUSIC PLAYING]
EDDY MORETTI: It's the first day
of shooting on the first
film of the Grolsch Film Works
and Vice Films collaboration.
We're in Nashville
in a roller rink.
The first film is called "The
Filmic Fourth Dimension," and
it's being shot by Harmony
Korine, who is over there.
And the star of this chapter
is Val Kilmer, completely
amazingly dressed
as Val Kilmer.
And this is going to
be really good.
VAL KILMER: I'm going to
bleed for this film.
HARMONY KORINE: I had always
wanted to write a film that
was almost like a stage play.
But it was presented in the form
of a motivational speech.
And with this idea that the
person only would give the
most paranoid advice, or the
most tangential advice, or the
most random.
And it's really based on this
one central monologue.
[LAUGHTER]
VAL KILMER: Can you see it?
It's like an alien ship.
Can you see it?
FEMALE SPEAKER: I see it!
VAL KILMER: Look up!
Look up!
MALE SPEAKER: Sit down!
Sit down!
HARMONY KORINE: I thought if I
could have anyone to do it,
who would it be?
And I kept thinking about Val
Kilmer with like a Bluetooth
microphone on stage, and a pony
tail, and a beret, and,
just giving amazing
advice to people.
VAL KILMER: It's cool that
I'm here for you.
FEMALE SPEAKER: I'm so happy
that you're here for me.
I want you so bad.
I want you.
VAL KILMER: Sexy.
[CHEERING]
VAL KILMER: He liked some
of my improv ideas.
Some things sort of come
out like a chant.
ALL: Awesome secret,
awesome secret.
VAL KILMER: Awesome secrets!
Awesome secrets!
Awesome secrets, they
now come true!
There were some very natural
catch phrases almost.
So I started thinking about that
as an idea of actually
thinking about catch phrases.
You know what my catch
phase for today is?
EDDY MORETTI: No.
VAL KILMER: Catch phrase.
EDDY MORETTI: That's a
good catch phrase.
I like it.
VAL KILMER: Yeah.
It's a catch phrase,
is catch phrase.
Catch phrase.
HARMONY KORINE: I kind of wrote
it thinking about him.
It's not really a character
as much as it's the way I
reimagined Val Kilmer.
If I could have Val be
anything, that's
what he would be.
VAL KILMER: It's a motivational
speaker, but it's
me, but not really me.
And I just loved it.
So it's really been fun kind
of creating this outrageous
character together.
Hold it in!
Hold it in until we begin!
You don't want to give
it all away.
Look at me.
Focus.
I've got to focus now like a
Ninja, like a white Ninja.
Do you feel it?
FEMALE SPEAKER: Uh-huh.
VAL KILMER: I'm going to take
vibe jack right now.
[LAUGHTER]
HARMONY KORINE: I didn't know
what to expect, or what his
process was, or how he
wanted to do it.
But I can't tell the difference
when I talk to him.
I don't know if he's,
like, motivational
speaker, or if it's Val.
VAL KILMER: Harmony!
HARMONY KORINE: Yeah.
VAL KILMER: I don't know about
you, but I'm already filming.
HARMONY KORINE: Like, I can't
tell, like, where Val ends and
this guy begins.
VAL KILMER: Come in.
We take a vibe jack.
Then you do an insert.
I turn away.
And I return.
EDDY MORETTI: You've uplifted
her for sure.
FEMALE SPEAKER: This is the
best thing that's ever
happened to me.
VAL KILMER: That's correct.
[LAUGHTER]
HARMONY KORINE: It's crazy.
Because it feels like
I'm dreaming.
Like, when I see Val riding
a BMX bike with
what, like, MAG wheels?
EDDY MORETTI: Yeah.
HARMONY KORINE: And
like a fanny pack.
It's so great.
It's so trippy.
I would like to think
that that's what
Val Kilmer does now.
In my mind, I'd like to imagine
that's, like, what
he's doing.
VAL KILMER: He's so enthusiastic
in general.
He's so refreshing because he's
excited about everything
and doesn't have any creative
blocks at all.
He reminds me a lot of my little
brother, who is very,
very free as an artist.
HARMONY KORINE: If you were
like this now, like if you
hold it by the scruff of it's
neck and be like [SCREAMING]
come on, Val!
I'm waiting for you!
Like that, all right?
I don't know what it is, it's
like a performance, or a
prank, or a film, or a play.
I've never made something that
was like this before.
Also that was like a
live audience that
was reacting to something.
So what's going to happen is
he's going to give this
performance.
And he's going to be free.
And he's going to
be all around.
He's going to react.
And I want you guys to react
to what he does.
I'm not going to tell
you too much.
I want you to do what
you're going to do.
VAL KILMER: Combining theater
experience with a movie and
film it so that there's
two products.
There's the real theater
that you're generating
and then the film.
MALE SPEAKER: You know the
character in "Tropic Thunder"
that arranges all the explosions
for the film
production?
Well, he--
Chris does that with
disco and lights.
HARMONY KORINE: What I want
you to do is I want you to
become an active participant
in the performance.
MALE SPEAKER: That's great.
HARMONY KORINE: Just
change it.
Never let anything get
too comfortable.
If anything feels like
it's getting too
comfortable, switch up.
MALE SPEAKER: All right.
HARMONY KORINE: All right.
MALE SPEAKER: Sounds good.
EDDY MORETTI: Here's your
moment to shine, man.
[GROUP CHATTER]
EDDY MORETTI: So Val said that
he didn't pick this place.
This place picked him.
And I kind of agree.
The weird thing is that I'm
dressed exactly like him.
VAL KILMER: Wait a minute.
EDDY MORETTI: Yeah.
Yeah, I know.
Yeah.
VAL KILMER: Hang on a second.
EDDY MORETTI: Yeah.
I was vibe jacking you
telepathically.
But this is how I dress
every day, so.
VAL KILMER: Me, too.
EDDY MORETTI: Yeah.
Oh, good.
VAL KILMER: No, I got a little
dressed up because I'm giving
a talk today.
[CHEERING AND APPLAUSE]
VAL KILMER: What up!
We love you!
[CHEERING AND APPLAUSE]
EDDY MORETTI: So this is where
the extras check in.
There's about 150 extras.
They're coming here
to be inspired and
motivated by the outcome.
Lots of people want to be extras
in the film because
there's so many unemployed
people in Nashville, you know,
that everyone's, like,
hell, yeah.
I want to be an extra for $50
a day or whatever it is.
But they don't really have any
ideas on how Val is going to
really uplift them.
HARMONY KORINE: I mean, we're
filming in a roller skating
rink with a lot of people that
are down on their luck, a lot
of unemployed people, thinking
that they're going to hear one
of the great motivational
speakers.
A lot of them need like
financial advice and da, da,
da, da, da.
But what's going to happen is
Val's going to come out and
speak mostly in pure paranoia.
EDDY MORETTI: But I think
there are also like real
moments of kind of poetry.
HARMONY KORINE: Yeah.
EDDY MORETTI: And they're,
like, images.
HARMONY KORINE: And they
go by very quick.
They change.
They go from being really stupid
to really profound.
VAL KILMER: It very hard to
compare this to anything,
particularly some of the
prankish elements in it where
you wonder if it's
really me or not.
I think that's what Harmony
was intending
that's really veiled.
But there's some serious
elements in my character
really, very sincere about
wanting to help people.
HARMONY KORINE: So we shot a
scene of Val and Rachel just
riding bikes.
And there was this van that was
parked in the back of the
parking lot under a light.
And then these two
guys came out.
And Val start talking to
them, and we made a
little scene happen.
But it turns out that they
both are homeless.
VAL KILMER: You're so
happy you're insane.
Have you ever been so happy
you're just almost insane?
Just--
MALE SPEAKER: No.
VAL KILMER: Well, that's why
the Lotus Community Center
might be for you.
It just makes you so happy that
you're almost insane.
It's like a happy campaign.
HARMONY KORINE: It was a pretty
cool scene where Val
used some of his illogical
wisdom and tried to help them.
I don't know if it succeeded,
but it seemed like they were
pretty excited.
VAL KILMER: A lot of times the
biggest things in life are
unexpected, right?
They just seem to be random.
And just like talking to you
two tonight, we had that
experience.
It's just like nothing
else in the world.
It's like the most important
things right now.
Thanks, man.
It's part of Harmony's world
where he doesn't judge.
He kind of loves all life, and
particularly the back alleys
where people have
been discarded.
HARMONY KORINE: So
it was awesome.
It was something really
beautiful just now.
I'm just excited just
to see what happens.
EDDY MORETTI: Yeah.
HARMONY KORINE: I mean,
I think I have like
a pretty good idea.
But it'll be good.
This guy is too genius.
And a hero to the working man.
He's one of the best.
He's an icon.
It's also just very good to see
him actually, like, doing
you know, good stuff.
Like, you know what I mean?
[LAUGHTER]
[MUSIC PLAYING]