[PAKISTANI MUSIC]
BASIM USMANI: While we were
filming in Karachi, our shoot
took one dark turn
after another.
Things just got heavier
and heavier.
But we met one person in the
midst of all this chaos that
gave us hope.
His name is Abdul Sattar Edhi.
And he is to Karachi what Mother
Teresa was to the poor
of Calcutta.
As the founder of the Edhi
Foundation, the largest
welfare organization in
Pakistan, he's opened over 300
centers across the country,
run by more than 3,500
workers, plus thousands of
volunteers, providing medical
aid, family planning, and
emergency assistance.
The Edhi Foundation has also
made donations towards
disaster relief around the
world, including to victims of
Hurricane Katrina in the US.
They rely entirely on donations,
and avoid political
or religious affiliation.
We got a chance to meet with
this living legend in Karachi.
Edhi is one of the
most important
public figures in Pakistan.
But recently there were reports
that he was being
targeted by the Taliban.
So now, against his own wishes,
he has round the clock
police security.
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
ABDUL SATTAR EDHI:
BASIM USMANI:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
ABDUL SATTAR EDHI:
BASIM USMANI:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
ABDUL SATTAR EDHI:
BASIM USMANI:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
ABDUL SATTAR EDHI:
BASIM USMANI: We all piled into
an Edhi ambulance and
headed to Lyari.
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
ABDUL SATTAR EDHI:
BASIM USMANI: Once word got out
that Edhi had arrived in
Lyari for a visit, hundreds
of locals came out
to pay their respects.
And it's no wonder.
Edhi's like a superhero,
and he's incorruptible.
While we were in Karachi, he was
the only person who gave
us hope for this city.
ABDUL SATTAR EDHI:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
[PAKISTANI MUSIC]