In
the
last lecture we had looked at some of the
issues in the location of facilities and we
had got a broad overview of the problem of
location of different types of facilities.
In this particular lecture we are going to
be talking about some mathematical models
for facility location. In fact before we take
up any mathematical models we initiate the
discussion.
I will discuss the case study. This case study
is actually based on paper that Prof. Prem
Vrat and I wrote and this is the reference.
It is called a decision model for a multi
objective plant location problem and the basic
intention in this particular case study is
to look at various factors which are relevant
for the plant location problem and try to
then determine after conducting a feasibility
study as to what should be the best location
for the manufacturing plant. So this would
be the kind of study that any new entrepreneur
or any new company contemplating a new location
for a manufacturing plant would go through.
In this particular case study the objective
of the location was actually to setup a straw
board plant. Straw board as you know is a
packaging material which is made from industrial
waste and basically the idea was that this
would be setup in an industrial setting so
that there would be availability of industrial
waste automatically and that particular industrial
waste would serve as the input for the plant
and this would then be processed to supply
various industries needing packaging material
in the form of cottons and so on and various
things. This was the basic idea behind the
location of this particular plant. Now what
was actually done was that in order to conduct
this study systematically, interviews were
carried out with the plant managers and various
other people in the organization to identify
what were the various factors that they consider
important for this particular decision.
After series of discussion with the management
it was found that the factors that needed
to be considered are A nearness to raw material
source. Obviously the nearer you are to the
raw material source, it would cut down the
cost of transportation and it is also easy
to get your raw materials. Second factor that
was considered important was the availability
and dependability of power. Then the manager
identifies transport facility as an important
factor. Labor supply was another important
factor, employee facilities, the kinds of
facility that employees will have in terms
of shopping recreation schools etc. This was
considered to be a factor in the beginning.
Competition for the market was considered
to be another major factor because if they
were already a large number of manufactures
of straw board in that particular area it
would be difficult to sell your product. So
the lesser the competition for the market,
the better it was. Proximity to market was
considered another important factor. Government
incentives, as we know, typically the government
might want to give certain kinds of incentives
for certain locations may be to encourage
development of certain backward areas. These
are the kinds of incentives that are available
and then finally the cost of land in that
particular site which we are considering.
In fact you see these factors are almost generic
in any plant location problem. You would have
to consider various factors. The only thing
that would happen is the relative importance
you might give in these factors. They could
vary depending up on the nature of the plant.
Our approach in the problem is essentially
something very simple and it is summarized
in the form of this table.
What you would like to do is we have identified
the objectives that we have. You would like
to prioritize these objectives and give certain
weights and then we identify alternative locations
A1, A2 and up to Am and each alternative location
is evaluated on the corresponding objective.
For instance P11 is the score given to the
first alternative on the objective, P12 is
the score given to the first alternative on
the second objective and so on. So if we can
then get these scores, somehow then what we
simply have to do is we can calculate the
effectiveness of alternative A1, alternative
A2, alternative Em if there are m alternatives
we and get a kind of a score. This is very
similar to the manner in which we evaluate
students in a class. These are the candidate
location of the candidates (Refer Slide Time:
07:19), and these are the performances in
various subjects as you go through. Each subject
has different weightage or different number
of credits and what we assign basically to
you is some kind of marks based on some scheme
and ultimately you calculate a CGPA or a grade
point average. So what we are trying to say
here is that, we use this kind of a scheme
to evaluate different alternative locations.
Now let us see how it can be done.
Earlier however we do what would be necessary
are the various objectives that we have, the
objective that we just listed out nearest
to the raw material source availability and
dependability of powers and so on. You have
to score these objectives to determine the
weights, so what is actually being suggested
here is that if you construct a triangular
matrix, the purpose of triangular matrix is
because there are n objectives. There will
be nC2 possible comparisons or pair wise comparisons.
All pair wise comparisons. So we look for
pair wise comparisons, for instance in comparing
objective 1 with objective 3. You might want
to give o1, two marks whatever the interpretation
is; to these marks. Then ultimately you can
determine the scores by counting the number
of scores or votes polled by different objectives.
So you will able to get scores. The basic
advantage of scheme like this is when you
have a large number of objectives; it is very
difficult to give weights to the individual
objectives. But if you are comparing only
2 at a time, it is much easy for a person
or a manager to say between o1 and o3; I can
compare and say o1 is more important. The
difference is medium. So it is much easier
to adopt a pair wise comparison approach and
evolve a set of scores.
For instance for this particular problem what
was done was this triangular matrix was constructed
and these were the objectives A, B, C, D,
E, F, G, H, I. The management was asked to
compare between A and B and the management
felt that A was more important and the difference
was medium. So you wrote A2 here. Similarly
in comparing for instance C and G, the management
felt that G was more important, but the difference
was minor. So you put minor. This is because
you are basically distinguishing between (Refer
Slide Time: 10:17) and then you say how much
better, so this is a simple way of doing it.
So having got this information we can simply
compute, for instance total A, you can count
the rows in this particular row. For B it
can be in this column and this row for C,
you can count the votes here and so on. So
you would know exactly what is the score or
the weightage for each of these various objectives.
So in this particular example we have these
objectives A B C D E F G H I which were nearness
to raw materials source availability and dependability
of power, transport, facilities etc and the
total weightage given to these particular
factors came out from their as 16, 4, 6, 3,
0, 14, 8, 12, 8, 7, and this was what was
basically involved here and the weightage
for all these the percentage weightage you
sum it up this seems to be an error here sum
it up and then divide this by the total you
get 23.0 percent weightage given to this particular
factor here and so on similarly so hundred
percent weightage this is how it is finally
distributed to these individual objectives.
So this was the rational way of arriving at
these weightages, basically using pair wise
comparisons. There are a number of techniques
available these days which you can employ
if you so desire. AHP is one example. Analytic
hierarchy process is also pair wise comparison
technique which essentially gives you these
weights and so on. But you have to go through
a similar kind of an exercise.
So ultimately the results for this problem
could be classified as the above. A survey
was conducted as to where the location should
be. Now the management in this case was interested
that the location of the plant should be anywhere
in north India. We did not want to go to South
or West so the major industrial districts
in the north were considered and these districts
Panipat, Sonepat, Rohtak, Meerut, Faridabad,
Gurgaon, and Ghaziabad. These were the tentative
locations that were possible for setting up
the plant and now we have these objectives
and these are the weightages that we have
discovered and just determined from the pair
wise comparisons. Finally what we are required
to do is to evaluate each of these locations
on these individual factors. If you recall
the analogy this is not very difficult, it
is like saying if this subject is Physics
I have to give quizzes in Physics to determine
the marks. I have to determine this factor
which I will find out and so on. What we are
trying to say is that the first factor which
was essentially near to raw materials sources
was found in this particular classification,
nearness to raw material source, Rohtak was
the best.
Hence, Rohtak got 100 points. The scheme was
the worst location which will be given 50
points and the best location will be given
100 points. It is very much like trying to
say that we normally do not fail candidates
in the IIT and therefore the worst fellow
will get 50 marks. The best fellow will get
100 marks in the particular. So in comparing
these, in terms of distance in the raw material
source, Rohtak was relatively raw at that
time and plenty of raw materials were available
there and so on, so it was 100 which were
the worst. Faridabad, Gurgaon and Ghaziabad
were all low in the hierarchy and Faridabad
was the worst. Faridabad was the worst although
it is an industrial town. Whatever, there
were already large number of industrial units
set up for the availability of raw materials.
It was difficult, more difficult as compared
to other factors. So this was the scheme,
this was on a normalized scale of 50 to 100.
Similarly all these evaluations were done
on a normalized scale from 50 to 100. For
instance in the second objective it was felt
that Sonepat was the best and Meerut and Gahziabad
were the worst. For instance the third factor
was transport facilities. As far as transport
facilities were concerned, it was Panipat
that was the best out of these options. It
got 100 points, Rohtak was petty good, Faridabad
was petty good Gurgaon was bad and Ghaziabad
was okay. So this was basically an evaluation
of these locations on all the factors.
Once all these scores are available what we
can do is 90 into 0.23, 80 into 0.057 so on.
The final points that you get here are 86.1
and similarly 85.98, 91.16, 75, 61, 71, 64
etc. So from this analysis it emerged that
Rohtak was the best option out of these. Now
however you find that this was a very good
option, no doubt but the second best option
was petty close. This is 91 marks, this is
86 marks. So it is like trying to say that
a company comes to recruit, you need not only
recruit the best candidate, but the second
best, and the third best will also get jobs.
So in the same sense you find that here 91
and then 86 will be petty close and then 85,
0.8 which is almost 86, so these are petty
close. So you could do a more detailed comparison
between the first three. What this means is
that Rohtak was best on one, two, three and
four. Out of these various objectives, Panipet
was the best one on only two of these objectives.
Let us see where Rohtak was worst. It was
worst on this particular factor i.e., 60 marks.
But it was even worst on this factor and this
was likely to be better but then it was best.
So on the whole it seems that Rohtak would
be the optimal location. So the optimal location
was in fact suggested as Rohtak and the company
adopted this. After many years the feed back
received from the company is that they are
very happy in Rohtak which means the decision
that was taken more than 15 years ago was
probably the right decision for them in terms
of whatever we did. Now having used the decision
matrix for alternative location, you could
use this methodology for any real life situation.
You see the tricky part here is how do you
assign these marks to these candidates?
If a particular factor is let us say capital
cost, then the highest capital cost will be
the most undesirable, least capital cost will
be the most desirable and so on. So the manner
in which you assign these marks is basically
the process of normalization.
Now what about normalization? What we mean
in normalization is that depending up on the
objectives suppose our objective is capital
cost and we have investigated a number of
different alternatives then in the alternatives
the one which is the highest in terms of capital
cost should be given the least marks, i.e.,
is 20 the one which is the lowest should get
the highest marks which is 80 and the most
convenient way to represent this relationship
is a linear straight line or a normal straight
line. You might use a normalization curve
of this kind or a teacher who is giving a
normalization curve of this kind. So this
is exactly what normalization would mean.
It is not necessarily true that normalization
would be linear. Take the same example of
the capital cost for instance we have something
like this, the lowest capital cost is L and
the highest capital cost is H. The company
might be indifferent for instance, lowest
cost might be 2 lakh or whatever and say upto
3 lakh. The company says it does not make
much of a difference. You are indifferent
between 2 and 3 lakhs. So you give 80 marks
to all of them who have done this particular
factor and then from here it could be a straight
line, it could be a concave function or a
convex function as the case may be. The difference
between the concave and convex function would
be that in the convex function which you have
here, the drop is very steep in the beginning.
Slope is highest here and it tends to fall
and the minimum slope is here. So it is like
saying you are penalizing the candidate most.
That is capital cost. There is a fall in capital
cost. You are penalizing here and relatively
at this point, the rate of penalty is decreasing.
It is the reverse in the case of the other
function. Now what I am simply trying to emphasize
here is if you give careful thought to normalization,
this is a very important strategic decision
location and what is normalization? Normalization
curves represent your attitudes towards the
particular object.
For instance, if you have a factor like labor
attitude, you might want to classify labor
attitude into three categories, bad, medium
and good. You might say rested where the labor
is so restive. It is willing to pick up agenda
for every small provocation. So it is a restive
labor. You have a satisfactory labor. The
labor is willing to be cooperative and you
might have a cooperative labor which is willing
to do everything. Obviously this is the best.
So you give maximum marks. Let us say 80,
between these you give 60 between these you
give 20. So essentially the normalization
curve for such subjective factors will be
a staircase function of this kind where you
can decide the length or the height of the
stair in each case. It is not necessarily
true that the normalization curve is linear
or be portions of linear functions.
(Refer Slide Time: 22:34)
A normalization curve could also be nonlinear.
So a nonlinear function is Present, so this
is the least desirable. This is the most desirable.
The most desirable aspect is given the maximum
number of points. The least desirable is given
the least number of points and you can think
of what would be the nature of this curve
for your case. So the point is that once we
have developed the normalization curves for
individual objectives, this process becomes
very objective. All that you need to do is
develop the weights for the objectives like
we did through the triangular matrix, determine
the normalization curves and feed them to
a computer and then feed the data corresponding
to individual alternatives locations into
the program and then you can get the final
solution for various options. So the idea
here was that we were dealing with the practical
plant location problem. Practical plant location
problem has both subjective and objective
factors. We had here a mechanism to deal with
both subjective and objective factors but
there was no attempt at optimization.
What was the kind of problems that we were
considering? We looked through the feasibility
report or identified a number of locations
and we were trying to choose the best location.
So it was the problem of choosing the best
out of the available options. That is the
kind of the problem that we were considering,
however in facility location we have certain
mathematical models where the intention is
to determine the best or the ideal location
and that particular ideal location can then
motivate you to locate your facilities wherever
they are. Let us see the models and we looked
at some simple models, for facility location
in this context.
Let us talk about the problem which is known
in lecture as the single facility location
problem. The single facility location problem
is essentially the problem where you want
to locate one new facility and this problem
occurs very frequently in life. Here are some
examples of what we call the single facility
location problem. For instance you want to
determine the location of a new lathe in a
job shop and you already have 23 lathes. You
bring in another lathe, the 24th one and you
are trying to find out where it should be
located. It is a single facility location
problem because you are trying to find out
the location. A tool crib in a factory is
the place where we have the workers taking
their tools and deposit their tool every time.
So it is a common facility for all workers.
You might want to find out what is the best
location of the tool crib such that the total
travel distance of all these workers is minimized
which means total time is minimized. This
means their productivity is maximized because
they are wasting less time in computing, in
that sense you could talk about the location
of a new warehouse for a company warehouse.
You could talk about the location of the hospital
or a fire station or a police station. All
single you could talk about is the location
of the new classroom building on a college
campus, single facility location problem,
a new airfield for a number of bases and you
can talk about the component in an electrical
network. You know electrical network these
days have a large number of electrical components
put onto one board. Suppose it is decided
that you improve the design characteristics,
you want to put an additional resistor somewhere.
Where should that additional resistor be and
it is going to be connected to some of these
components. So you are trying to say where
should I put up the additional resistor such
that the total length of the cable or the
length of wire is minimized? This is again
a problem of a single facility location.
You want to talk about installation of a new
appliance in a kitchen; this is again a single
facility location problem. You want to find
out where copying machine should be placed
in the library, assuming that in a library,
different readers from different locations
may have statistical data on an average 20
percent of the users, from first floor and
30 percent from this floor, come here for
this particular thing. So you can determine
where the optimum location for the copying
machine should be or if there is a new component
on a control panel you have a big switch here
Larson and Tubro switch here. It is huge one
and we are trying to find out where new component
should be installed which also happens to
be a single facility location problem. So
the single facility location problem is actually
a problem, in fact that is why it is called
single facility. We are not talking about
single plant location because when you recall,
when we were discussing the issues in locations
were specified that often tend to speak in
terms of facilities and depending on whichever
facility it is you have to determine the optimum
location.
For this problem the statement mathematical
statement can be built up as follows: we say
that we have m existing facilities at locations
P1, P2, Pm whose locations are a1b1, a2b2
and so on up to am bm, so we know the location
of the m existing facilities and the new facility
is to be located at some point X which is
x y. You want to determine this (Refer Slide
Time: 28:44) and where it should be located.
The new facility, the other existing facilities
are fixed that is their assumption and dX
Pi is an appropriately defined as the distance
between X and Pi. X is the new facility you
want to locate and Pi is one of the existing
facilities. So the distance between them can
be called as dX, Pi and this distance could
be defined in various weights.
It could be Euclidean distance which is a
straight line distance. It could be the Rectilinear
distance which is the Manhattan distance between
these two points, it could be the square Euclidean
distance, it could be what we call a generalized
distance or it could be a distance on a network.
In fact this would define a variety of models
which are available even for the simple problem,
the single facility location problem. What
is the objective of this exercise? The objective
is to determine the location X for the new
facility so as to minimize transportation
related costs, that is what you want to do
and what are these transportation cost related
to? The transportations related to cost are
the sum from i = 1to n, the summation of wi
into dX, Pi where wi is the weight associated
with the ith facility which is the product
of the cost per unit distance and the expected
number of annual trips between X and Pi. If
you recall our discussion of the varianon
frame where we had determined weights corresponding
to each of the points, the interpretation
of wi is the same. It is a weightage given
to the ith point. How important it is in terms
of the interactions that take place between
new facility and that particular facility.
That is the objective function. This is general
problem; a general statement of the problem
is this.
So essentially if you look at the problem
in a graphical perspective what is really
required is that we have points P1, P2, and
P3 and so on up to Pn or Pm. This is the case
and it may be spread out. These are the existing
facilities. We are interested in finding out
an optimum location X. This optimum location
X should be such that the total cost of movement
between all these should be minimized. That
means what we are trying to say is that we
are trying to minimize the total cost of travel
or transportation between the various facilities.
There could be many examples which we can
construct for instance, if these facilities
are hospitals in the city, let us say Delhi
has 10 hospitals, these are the 10 hospitals
that you have in the city and the problem
is that you are trying to find out the location
of a centralized blood bank facility. This
can be called upon by any hospital in case
of emergency or whatever it is.
So what we are trying to say is that we should
determine the location such that if you know
roughly that during a particular day there
are roughly 5 trips, here 20 trips, here 10
trips, here 10 trips, here 30, and so on which
you, from the past historical data use the
information to determine the optimum location
of the new service facility. Similarly you
might say for instance if I want to find out
the location of a hospital which will cater
to the needs of different people in the localities
and these localities have these weights in
terms of number of people falling sick. Let
us consider an order of magnitude proportional
to population, assuming that all people are
subjected to same kind of health conditions.
So if you do that then again the problem of
finding out the location of this hospital
is basically a single facility location problem.
Now what we would like to do is first understand
the various commonly used distances that we
talked about.
For instance if the location of the new facility
is at X and the ith existing facility is located
at the point Pi which has coordinates ai,
bi then the rectilinear distance between these
2 points is actually this (Refer Slide Time:
33:52) distance. This distance and then this
distance (Refer Slide Time: 33:54) and mathematically
the rectilinear distance will be represented
by x – ai mod + y – bi mod. Now you must
understand that there are a large number of
situations in real life where the rectilinear
distance would be an appropriate one to consider,
for instance all movements within the factory
are generally rectilinear because in a factory
on the shop floor you can typically move along
a set of perpendicular heights. So if a worker
has to go from one place to the other he has
to take of the perpendicular route this way
and then go this way.
That is the rectilinear distance and therefore
if you are dealing with a problem of let us
say machine location within a factory, or
you are talking about location of some other
tool crib in a factory or if you are talking
about the location of a let us say even canteen
within a factory. The distance measure that
you think that is most appropriate is a rectilinear
distance measure and therefore this is a very
important distance measure especially in the
context of location on the shop floor, locations
within the factory. Of course if you happen
to travel to New York for instance the distances
are rectilinear that is why it is called Manhattan.
What you have is you have a large number of
parallel streets and these are intersected
by a number of other parallel streets and
all that you have therefore is the movement
is always rectilinear and in fact that is
the word Manhattan and rectilinear comes from
it. In our context Delhi would not be rectilinear.
If you go to Chandigarh for instance the movement
from one place to other is generally rectilinear
because the layout of the city is such that
you move about one round about another and
there are parallel streets and so on.
So it is essentially rectilinear if you are
talking about location of a facility in Chandigarh.
Rectilinear distance could be any problem
which is an important distance measure. The
next important distance that we consider is
what we call Euclidean distance measure. Euclidean
distance measure is the shortest distance
between two points.
The Euclidean distance from the point X which
you want to determine to the existing facility
Pi, ai, bi, you have this particular distance
which is the shortest distance between 2 points.
It is governed by this function x – ai whole
square + y – bi whole square and the square
root of this. This can be conveniently calculated
in this fashion. Where do you think Euclidean
distance will be appropriate in the location
problem? Where do you think you could consider
where things take place? Let us say generally
straight line generally and if you are trying
to talk about this, what would happen? For
instance if you are talking about the location
of an airport, you know that you are going
to expect flights from a large number of cities
in India and abroad here and flights going
out. So that would determine the weights for
the cities and since you travel almost a straight
line, you could say that the determination
of the optimum location of the airport could
be (Refer Slide Time: 38:00) but there are
other considerations like determination of
the airport. But definitely from the point
to view a minimization of the total travel,
this would be an optimum situation.
Then where else you think this would be appropriate?
It all depends up on whether naval applications,
whether you travel straight or you travel
all over the sea, how you travel and so on.
For instance suppose you travel by this trolley
car or a ropeway, suppose if in the mountains,
the government wants to decide up on picnic
spot and it was to find out the location of
a ropeway and this way you could probably
visit location on one hill and the other hill
wherever it is and different locations as
it is. Then which particular location will
minimize the total cost of the cableway?
Obviously it will be Euclidean distance. So
you could have a very large number of situations
wherein if you are talking about electrical
circuit, you want to fix a particular component
and the component is to be connected by a
wire to a number of different components assuming
of course that if it could be done on a Euclidean
way in that particular component, then the
location which tries to minimize the cost
of wire, the cost of cable etc but also be
using the Euclidean. Finally let us look at
the problem where you are talking of squared
Euclidean. This under root sign is missing
so we are talking about the square of the
Euclidean distance. Square of the Euclidean
distance is just the distance but the square
of it.
Square Euclidean distance location problems
are also very relevant in many situations.
They are relevant mainly in problems which
involves radiations. The radiation loss is
typically proportional to the square of the
distance. You may remember your thermodynamics
and see that the heat loss from a particular
source is proportional to the square of the
Euclidean distance from that particular source.
Now this is something very important today
because this is in the context of let us satellite
location problem or in the context of suppose
you want to locate a satellite in space and
the satellite has to serve a number of existing
location on the earth, it has to serve New
Delhi, Kolkata, Hyderabad, Singapore etc.
So you have a number of m points which it
has to serve and let us say you know the weightages
for these points so the idea is that the optimal
point for the satellite would be the one if
you want to minimize the total radiation loss.
You want to minimize the total radiation loss;
it should be located, such that this particular
distance criterion is actually this particular
criterion. So the distance measure may be
any other because you travel anyway so I have
to go from here to here, or I can go this
way, I can go this way, I can travel on a
network in any particular manner and so on.
So it could be other or any other network.
Those can be commonly used distances so what
we do is normally the network location problem
is a practical problem because there you define
exactly the distances from one node to the
other on the network. You can look at the
network and try to solve the location problem
on the network.
Now let us try to look at this particular
problem of rectilinear distances. In a rectilinear
distance problem our objective function is
simply Z which is the total cost, which is
the summation from i = 1 to n, wi into x – ai
+ y – bi mod. That is what it is, that is
the rectilinear distance. The only interesting
thing here is that this particular function
could be sort of broken up into wi into x
– ai mod + wi into y – bi mod and this
can then be written as two separate summations.
The summation for x – ai mod and the summation
for y – bi mod and the interesting thing
here is that this is the function of x alone.
This (Refer Slide Time: 43:30) is the function
of y alone. So the problem of rectilinear
distances is that if you want to minimize
Z what you have to basically do is you have
to minimize f1 x and f2 y independently that
means optimum location for the rectilinear
distance location problem is determined simply
independently minimizing f1 x and f2 y. Now
you can determine the procedure for doing
this and rather than deriving the procedure
I would state the procedure here in fact in
this particular situation, the f1 x and f2
y are minimized, if you locate at the medium
location, that is the result. That actually
comes from duality theory. We can look at
the proof in the tutorials.
Let us take an example to illustrate what
we have been talking about and we will use
this frame work of the example on different
distance measure. For instance let us assume
that service facility to serve five offices
located at (0, 0), (3, 16), (18, 2), (8, 18)
and (20, 2) is to be set up. It is like saying
the number of cars transported per day between
the new service facility which you want to
set up and the offices equal 5, 22, 41, 60
and 34 respectively. So the question is what
location for the service facility will minimize
the distance, the cars are transported per
day? It is like saying that you have collection
centers for cars at 5 places and cannot place
south Delhi etc. You also want to have central
service facility. Where will you avail the
service? The people can deposit their cars
here and their experience shows that the number
of cars deposited per day is so much so where
should your service facility be? This is the
problem and we are assuming that the distance
involved is rectilinear.
So as I indicated to you, the answer to this
problem is that we can determine the x coordinate
and the y coordinate independently and the
x coordinate is nothing but a median location.
So this simply means if we arrange the entire
x coordinates in ascending order, these are
0, 3, 18, 20 and this is corresponding to
the existing facility 1, Corresponding to
the existing facility 2, this is corresponding
to existing facility 4, this is corresponding
to the existing facility 3, and 5. So ascending
order of the x coordinates and we determine
the weights. Weights are the number of cars
that come here, 3, 22, 60, 41, and 34. Determine
the cumulative weight, this should be 3, rather
this should be 5. This is error somewhere,
so misprint. So you have 5, let us say 5 is
the cumulative weight here and then 27 and
then 87 and then 128 and then 162. What needs
to be done is if the total cumulative weight
i.e., 162 is the sum of the weights, half
of that is 81. So you find out where the cumulative
weight changes, that is this is less than
81 and this is greater than 81.
This becomes greater than 81 here for the
first time. So this row determines the optimal
solution. A very simple straightforward and
therefore x star = 8. So we have determined
the optimum x coordinates for this particular
problem. The rectilinear distance location
problem is merely a median location. So this
is how you determine the median location then
we can do a similar procedure for the y coordinate.
When you do the y coordinate what happens
is that if you arrange the y coordinate in
ascending order 0, 2, 16 and 18, you find
that this corresponds to the first facility.
Both the facilities 3 and 5 share this coordinates
so we write both of them here and 2 and then
4 in that order and then the weights which
are there are 5, 14, so this is 5 in the previous
slide, it should have been 5. This is 5, so
this particular value should be 5 (Refer Slide
Time: 48:19). Now we have 80 again, you have
the total cumulative weight which is 162,
half of that, this is less than this, this
is greater than this (Refer Slide Time: 48:30),
so where the cumulative weight first exceeds
half the value, that row is here, so corresponding
to this we can identify that y star = 16,
it is very simple. So you observe that we
can determine the x star and the y star value
independently by similar procedures by just
identifying the median and we have identified
the median. So in this particular case we
now have
in fact determined both x star and y star.
So x star is 8 and y star is 16, so 8,16 becomes
the optimum location for the service facility,
that means this will minimize the total cost
of travel, that is the optimum solution or
the ideal solution for the location of the
service facility for this particular problem.
Now let us look at the case where you find
that the distance measure is, let us say square
Euclidean. We will not talk about the Euclidean
case now. We shall talk about it later but
let us talk about the squared Euclidean case
that is the satellite location problem. So
the location is also another interesting problem
here. You know it would be like trying to
say that suppose in the squared Euclidean
problem, the optimum location is in fact in
this case, centroid location. This can be
proved very easily. So the centroid location
for this problem is simply x star = summation
wi ai divided by summation wi, y star is equal
to summation wi bi divided by summation wi.
So for the same problem that we considered
earlier for the Euclidean distance, for the
rectilinear distance case, we can easily determine
this summation wi in the denominator. It is
162 which is the total weight. Sum of the
weights and x star is 12.12; y star is 9.77.
So if your distance measure is a squared Euclidean,
it would be best to locate the new facility
at 12.12 and 9.77 and obviously this differs
from the earlier median location that we determined
of 816. I am just trying to tell you that
if you are still not very clear about when
you should use the squared Euclidean case,
suppose your set of 5, 6 friends are celebrating
a bonfire in winter, imagine the situation
and they are standing or sitting in a certain
location around bonfire, then the question
is which is the best position for the bonfire
such that the total loss of heat energy is
minimum for all these guys. So if that is
to happen, the bonfire should be at the centroid
of all these points, where the people are
sitting. That is exactly where the satellite
location problem is in terms of whatever it
is.
So this can be determined very simply by saying
12.12 and y star is also is equal to 9.77
and therefore you can determine the centroid
location very easily.
In this particular case if you now look at
the Euclidean distance locations which is
the third problem that we are trying to talk
about, you recall that one simple way of solving
this problem is by using the mechanical analogy
that was developed by varianon in the frame
which we call a varianon frame. All that we
have done was all these points are raw materials
sources and markets so all the total points
are actually plotted here to scale and then
you take the required number of strings, tie
them to a common knot, and pass one string
through each of these holes which you have
drilled here. Then you can hang a weight.
This is equal to the weight corresponding
to that particular point. You allow the system
to come to equilibrium and when that happens,
the location of P is actually the solution
to the Euclidean distance location problem.
As we had seen the other day, normally this
method of constructing the varianon frame
and the strings models is quite cumbersome.
So mathematical procedures are available by
means of which you can compute this particular
point but there are certain mathematical complications
in this analysis and therefore the resort
has to be made to iterative heuristic procedure
for getting this particular point. So getting
this point mean that you start with a trail
point P and the trail point P most of the
solutions is the solution to the centroid
problem you can start with 12.12 and 9.77
and then keep iterating in certain fashion.
We will then talk about the algorithm in the
tutorials, how it is done. But essentially
this is an exact solution of the Euclidean
distance location problem which you can see
from here and I think that gives you a broad
idea of how these problems are. Yes, I think
so far all the problems that we have considered;
it can be termed as minisum problem that means
it comes to the objective function.
In all cases the objective was to minimize
the sum of the total travel from the facility
to all other facilities. If you are talking
about locating a central service station,
so you are talking about the cost of movement
from the service station to the first facility
from the service station to second facility
and so on. This sum was there. So all the
three problems that we have considered so
far were actually minisum problems where you
are trying to minimize the total sum. Now
in many instances especially in emergency
location problem it is not appropriate to
think of a mini sum objective.
It is better to think in terms of what we
call a minimax objective. For example it is
like saying if these are the resistances of
different people in different locality and
you are trying to find out the location of
a fire station, The location of the fire station
should not be such, the total cost to this
plus this plus this plus (Refer Slide Time:
55:50) this should be minimum because when
a fire breaks out, the fire tender has to
run to that particular place. So really speaking,
the location of the fire station should be
such that it should be nearest to the farthest
point.
You are trying to minimize the maximum distance
from that particular in all emergency location,
mimimax problems are quite common. For the
location of emergency facilities our objective
would be to minimize the maximum distance
just to give a motivation without going into
details. For instance these were the points
and you want to locate a facility. The idea
is that what would be a minimax location?
A minimax location will be we try to enclose
these in a circle and the circle which has
the minimum diameter. The center of that circle
which is let us say this one (Refer Slide
Time: 52:61) encloses these points. This is
the circle which encloses all these facilities
with the minimum diameter. This circle is
larger and there could be other larger circles.
Basically what we are seeking is this circle
and the center of this is optimum location.
Now graphically it is very wonderful to look
at this particular procedure and there are
algorithms for instance there is a beautiful
algorithm by Elzinga and Hearn which is actually
based on this analogy. So this is just to
tell you that if the objective function changes,
the problem is no longer a minisum problem
but a minimax problem. Finally let us look
at this complication.
For instance we determine an ideal location
by these mathematical procedures, if we determine
an ideal location what may happen is that
the ideal location may not be available. There
might be a building, there might be a river
running through it or there might be other
complications and you cannot locate because
in solving the problem, in determining the
ideal solutions, we have taken into consideration
the feasibility of these locations. So what
is interesting is that we can build cost contours.
These are lines of constant cost. So this
is the minimum cost of optimal location. Cost
increases by 5 percent, by 10 percent, by
15 percent, by 20 percent whatever it is and
you have lines of constant cost. This will
help you to choose an alternative location.
These are very much like lines of constant
height on a map; on a geographical map you
have lines of constant height. Similarly you
have lines of constant cost and this mapping
once is done would give you ideas as to which
side you should shift, where is the cost lesser,
where is the cost more and there are procedures
to develop the cost contours. In fact in the
tutorial exercises you will have an opportunity
to develop these cost contours. Finally let
us see what we have done in this particular
lecture
We started with looking at a practical problem,
a case study and we saw that the decision
matrix approach to handle multiple objectives
in plant location was in fact very worthwhile
approach to consider all the objectives and
consider the feasible solution. Basically
this problem could be termed as a problem
of choosing the best amongst options. Then
we have the single facility location models.
We talked about the rectilinear distance,
the squared Euclidean distance, the Euclidean
distance where the objective was to generate
the best from the infinite options which are
available and finally we talked about the
notion of minisum and minimax problems where
the objectives could change depending up on
the context. Finally we saw our cost contour
that can help to accommodate practical constraints
that is moving from ideal to a feasible solution.
So with this we conclude this particular lecture
and in the next lecture we will go over to
the facility layout problem which is the next
important problem in the context of facility
location.
Thank you