Our message is, it's
not OK to be gay.
It will warp the mind, destroy
the soul, and damn the nation,
damn the nation.
Westboro Baptist Church of
Topeka is an Old School, or
Primitive Baptist, church.
DENISE HALL: You know,
he's quite a showman,
and he knows that.
They've gotten a big long
run out of this.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Make a sign.
God hates fags.
That's all you've got to do.
SHIRLEY PHELPS-ROPER: This
generation teaches their
children it is in fact
OK to be gay.
That is a lie.
STEVE DRAIN: It's amazing how
much Bible a little child can
know and retain.
LIBBY (PHELPS) ALVAREZ: All we
ever knew growing up, all we
ever talked about, was the
ministry of the WBC.
And they expect everyone to
bow down and do everything
they want them to do.
FRED PHELPS: Do your worst!
I dare you!
Try to stop us!
MALE SPEAKER: Westboro Baptist
Church of Topeka, Kansas
presents the Old School
Baptist Hour
with Pastor Fred Phelps.
FRED PHELPS: This
is Fred Phelps.
Westboro Baptist Church of
Topeka is an Old School or
Primitive Baptist Church.
Many people nowadays do not
know what an Old School or
Primitive Baptist is, but in
early America, they abounded
and were well known.
John Leland, who, with James
Madison, drafted the First
Amendment to the Constitution,
was a
Primitive Baptist preacher.
MALE SPEAKER: Through the years
that Vice has followed
this story, no character stood
out more to us than the family
of Steve Drain, the only
members of the Westboro
Baptist Church not
related by blood.
STEVE DRAIN: Came up here to
do a documentary film on
Westboro Baptist Church.
I always thought that
it would be an
interesting subject matter.
I went around one Thanksgiving
weekend knocking on doors.
Thursday, Friday, Saturday,
Sunday, asking people what do
you believe, and why
do you believe it?
The overwhelming conclusion that
I was reaching was that
people have no idea what they
believe and why they believe
it, but they keep on
doing it anyway.
MALE SPEAKER: 12 years ago,
Steve Drain was a 35-year-old
aspiring filmmaker who wanted
to expose the Phelps and the
Westboro Baptist congregation
as frauds, or as he put it,
snake oil salesmen.
STEVE DRAIN: So then I thought,
you know what?
I'm going to go one step
further, and I'm going to ask
the pastors, the men in charge,
the men of the cloth,
so to speak.
Now, what happened was I came
up here to start doing these
interviews.
They threw me a curveball.
I was supposed to interview a
lot of other people and then
work my way up to Gramps
and talk to him
there toward the end.
Well, when I was halfway between
here and Lawrence,
driving over here for my first
day, they said Gramps
wants to talk now.
Pastor Phelps wants
to talk now.
And I sat down with
him, and we only
stopped to change tape.
It was still mini-DVD
back then.
Well, I talked to that
guy for four hours.
That interview was
just so bad ass.
I went back to Florida, and I
researched every answer that
they gave for every single
thing that they gave.
And this sounded like these guys
weren't going to give a
false answer.
It sounded like these
guys weren't going
to pervert the scripture.
That's in fact what it was.
MALE SPEAKER: Fred Phelps was
born in 1929, in a small city
of Meridian, Mississippi
to a railroad
policeman and homemaker.
After the untimely death of
his mother from cancer in
1935, Fred was raised
by his great aunt.
FRED PHELPS: You want
to go to hell?
No!
Get real!
MALE SPEAKER: After graduating
from high school, Phelps was
accepted to the United
States Military
Academy at West Point.
However, after attending a
Methodist revival, he turned
his attention to
the scripture.
Over the next few years, Phelps
bounced around between
several divinity schools until
in 1951, he met Margie M
Simms, who he married
later that year.
In 1964, Fred Phelps graduated
from law school at Washburn
University in Topeka, Kansas,
where he settled with his
growing family and founded the
Phelps chartered law firm.
Over the course of the next
decade, he made quite a name
for himself as a prominent
civil rights attorney.
SHIRLEY PHELPS-ROPER: During the
civil rights movement, at
KU, there were lots of sit-ins,
and those black
students would be arrested.
And there was a prosecutor over
in Douglas County that
would prosecute them.
So one of the first things my
dad did when he got out of law
school was go over there and
defend those students.
MALE SPEAKER: Phelps took cases
on behalf of African
American clients alleging
racial discrimination by
school districts, racially-based
police abuse,
and unconstitutional raids
on African American
establishments.
FRED PHELPS: They couldn't get
a white lawyer to go to
Lawrence and defend
Gale Sayers and
those 102 black students.
So they came to me.
God Almighty, you understand,
never said it's an abomination
to be black.
KATHERINE PHELPS: Their rights
were at stake, and he didn't
care they didn't
have the money.
He took the time to represent
their voice.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Fred Phelps is
good at raising Cain in the
courtroom and just about
everywhere else.
It's earned him the wrath of
some, the respect of others.
STEVE DRAIN: This
is a humble man.
This is a bright, a very bright
man, who, if he would
have embraced the world rather
than humbled himself to the
scripture, I guarantee he would
at least be on a federal
court bench somewhere, if
not the Supreme Court.
I mean, this guy's a
really smart guy.
MALE SPEAKER: In 1977, a formal
complaint was filed
against Phelps by the Kansas
State Board of Law Examiners
for his conduct during
a lawsuit against a
Kansas court reporter.
During the trial, he brutally
cross-examined her for a week
and accused her of a variety
of perverse sexual acts,
ultimately reducing her
to tears on the stand.
Phelps prepared affidavits
swearing to the court that he
had eight witnesses whose
testimony would convince the
court to rule in his favor.
The court reporter, in turn,
obtained sworn signed
affidavits from the eight people
in question, all of
whom said that Phelps had never
contacted them, and they
had no reason to testify
against her.
Phelps had committed perjury,
and on July 20, 1979, was
permanently disbarred from
practicing law in
the state of Kansas.
LIBBY (PHELPS) ALVAREZ: We
started picketing at Gage Park
because a couple of my cousins
were propositioned by
homosexuals.
FEMALE SPEAKER: At about 9:30, a
procession of vehicles would
begin circling the park.
People familiar with Gage say
they see the same cars night
after night.
LIBBY (PHELPS) ALVAREZ: We tried
to get the government
bodies to clean up the park so
they weren't trying to get
little children into the
bathrooms with them.
And it didn't work, so
we started picketing.
FRED PHELPS: It wouldn't take
much, we thought, to drive
those openly promiscuous
homosexuals out of Gage Park.
Boy, were we wrong.
LIBBY (PHELPS) ALVAREZ: We
would take out those big,
rectangular, long brown
tables, and
we would have picnics.
The law was that you had
to walk in a circle.
So we would do that.
The grass would die.
TIMOTHY PHELPS: The first big
sign that was made, I made it.
And it said God hates gays.
And it sure got attention.
DENISE HALL: You know, it used
to just be here in Topeka.
They would do all these things,
and they didn't get
noticed much of any
place else.
LIBBY (PHELPS) ALVAREZ: Remember
the fax [INAUDIBLE]?
I'm surprised they didn't hand
deliver it before that.
DENISE HALL: And they would send
out these horrific faxes
about people, and if anybody
would say anything about them,
they would send out more
faxes about people.
And it got to be--
in our office, when my husband
was alive, we'd get these
faxes in, and he would just
turn around and fax
them back to them.
Then it got to the place where
they would shut off their fax
machine when they would
send these faxes out.
And he'd try to fax them back,
and they'd turn the fax
machine off.
So then we couldn't
fax them back.
TIM PHELPS: Yeah, they sent
out underground picket
schedule, weekly picket
schedule.
And at my house, they would
print it off and post it in
the kitchen.
You knew where you had to be,
if you were supposed to go,
and whatnot.
FRED PHELPS: I would that free
grace were more preached
because it gives men something
to believe with confidence.
The great mass of professing
Christians
know nothing of doctrine.
Their religion consists in
going a certain number of
times to a place of worship.
But they have no care for truth
one way or another.
I speak without any prejudice
in this matter.
TIM PHELPS: 2004, 2005, it's
right where it's hitting big
on God hates America.
No 4th of July, none
of the other stuff
that we used to do.
LIBBY (PHELPS) ALVAREZ: Then
they started ramping up with
the military, and the picketing
the funerals, and
things like that.
Everything started ramping
up and getting
more and more extreme.
MALE SPEAKER: In 2006, Westboro
organized a picket at
the Westminster, Maryland
funeral of Matthew Snyder, the
US Marine who was killed in
Iraq, featuring banners
stating thank God for
dead soldiers.
They soon found themselves back
in court when a lawsuit
was filed shortly after by
Albert Snyder, the deceased
Marine's father.
Snyder won a $10.9 million
judgment against the Westboro
Baptist Church.
FEMALE SPEAKER: We thank
God for the $10.9.
FEMALE SPEAKER: The $10.9.
FEMALE SPEAKER: The
$10.9 million.
CHILDREN: Thank God
for $10.9 million.
FEMALE SPEAKER: I thank God for
the $10.9 million verdict
because it's a small price to
pay to get this message,
America is doomed, in front of
the eyes of whole world.
You can't pay for worldwide
publicity that cheap.
MALE SPEAKER: The Snyder
lawsuit, if your appeals are
exhausted, will you willingly
pay the damages?
SHIRLEY PHELPS-ROPER: No.
No.
Here's what you need to do.
You need to forget
that lawsuit.
That lawsuit has a purpose.
This nation intended it unto us
for evil, but God intends
it unto us for good.
MALE SPEAKER: In 2011, the US
Supreme Court decided eight to
one that Westboro's actions
constituted protected free
speech, and the judgment
was overturned.
Albert Snyder was later ordered
to pay Westboro's
legal costs.
SHIRLEY PHELPS-ROPER: If it
wasn't for the fact that I
believe every word of those
scriptures and I know
everything that our God does
is proper and perfect and
righteous, I'd almost feel
sorry for those people.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Recorded
yesterday at 5:06.
MALE SPEAKER: You fucking piece
of shit cocksuckers.
I don't give a fuck if you're
a bunch of lawyers or not.
I'm telling you now, the next
time I hear of you desecrating
a soldier, the whole lot of you
are going to fucking die.
I'll fucking stick a bomb in
every fucking house you own.
I'll fucking blow up the law
office, and I'll fucking cut
your fucking neck,
Fred Phelps.
MALE SPEAKER: It was during
the editing of his
documentary, "Hatemongers" that
Steve claims he underwent
a supernatural conversion.
After much thought,
contemplation, and discussions
with his wife Luci, Steve packed
up his two daughters,
Taylor and Lauren, and moved the
family to Topeka, Kansas.
STEVE DRAIN: They
both play piano.
The banjo and cool hat's
cooler for pictures.
She's starting to play
a little guitar.
I play guitar.
When we bought this house, it
was in pretty rough shape, but
the location was great.
So you know, we wanted
to be by the church.
So little by little, we've
changed it up.
We like to kind of keep
it kind of colorful.
We've got our little signs
of the times deal there.
We went to Sundance Film
Festival in Utah, and we were
picketing Kevin Smith, "Red
State." At Sundance, when we
were over there fussing at
Kevin Smith, I told those
fags-- they came over there--
and I told those fags, because
they were asking me mockingly,
how do I go to heaven, Steve?
I said, take a piece of barbed
wire, could be sharp, could be
rusted, I don't care, and
lop your junk off.
Do a lot of editing in there.
Do a lot of the website
work in there.
It's kind of messy.
And the living room here.
Matter of fact, last time Louis
Theroux was here, this
is where I showed Louis Theroux
the really bad Jew
parody video with the guys with
the little [INAUDIBLE].
You never saw that?
Two Jews fighting
over a penny.
Got to do something.
Check this out.
MALE SPEAKER: All right,
welcome back.
So now, joining us live via
satellite, [INAUDIBLE].
MALE SPEAKER: I'm real sorry
about what happened to your
son, Mr. Snyder, and I
assure you, God had
nothing to do with it.
JOE STRAMOWSKI: Your Joel Osteen
kinda sounds like a
George W Bush.
STEVE DRAIN: I know.
I just use what I got, dude.
JOE STRAMOWSKI: It's a
good George W Bush.
MALE SPEAKER: Since making his
profession of faith and
accepting Baptism into the
Westboro Baptist church fold,
Steve has since become its
Public Information Officer,
basically its propaganda
minister in chief.
MALE SPEAKER: [SINGING]
Shame taught your children
God's a liar.
Shame made [INAUDIBLE]
STEVE DRAIN: Well, the
way we do it is
we're writing parodies.
So we're trying to replace those
lyrics with lyrics that
are Biblically sound.
Of course, it has
to fit a hook.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Check
them out now.
FEMALE SPEAKER: [SINGING]
Pimpin' on your G-O-D.
God's gonna stand there
and watch you burn.
But that's all right because
you wouldn't heed His word.
STEVE DRAIN: When we make our
choices of songs, that really
revolves around mostly
popularity.
It's mostly mainstream stuff.
The whole idea of our doing
parodies is to preach.
So we're trying to get as many
ears on songs, as many eyes on
videos as possible.
Well, we have the Feel Good
Inc. We did Fear God.
MALE SPEAKER: [SINGING]
Don't stop.
Get it.
It's only [INAUDIBLE]
Watch as God annihilates.
Ha ha ha ha ha.
STEVE DRAIN: Sometimes a
classic thing like the
Beatles, you know.
MALE SPEAKER:
[SINGING] [INAUDIBLE]
the Jews.
[INAUDIBLE] the Jews.
STEVE DRAIN: We did Michael
Jackson for a little while
around the time that he died.
That was kind of a big thing.
Most of what people got mad at
us for was we were using
"Thriller" dance moves for "Beat
It" and "Bad" parodies.
It's just, that's kind of
a cool thing to do.
So they were like chasing
us for that.
We were like, really?
Yeah, we know that.
FRED PHELPS: You taught these
kids from the time they
started school that
it's OK to be gay.
So therefore, you busted
their moral compass.
The same God that said thou
shall not kill said thou shall
not lie with mankind as a
womankind, and affixed the
death penalty for both sins.
And you taught them that God
didn't mean what he said about
one, so if it's OK to be
gay, it's OK to kill.
STEVE DRAIN: Hey,
I got an idea.
Let's rip the babies out of
the wombs of these fool
American women on the back
of their fornication.
And then let's break the moral
compasses of the kids that do
end up getting born, raise them
up for the devil, and
then hand them a gun and go send
them off to fight bloody
wars that we have no business
fighting in the first place,
and we certainly can't win.
SHIRLEY PHELPS-ROPER: You sit
them in your homes, in your
classrooms, in your so-called
churches, and you teach them
rebellion against the
standards of God.
STEVE DRAIN: Look, when we take
these kids out on these
picket lines, they see
the difference.
The mind starts working
pretty early.
They see the difference between
the way we conduct
ourselves and how we cleave
to the scripture.
We're sinners like
anybody else.
But the main difference between
God's elect and the
reprobate is we're ashamed
of our sin.
We're not proud of it.
We don't want to continue it.
We want to stop it.
SHIRLEY PHELPS-ROPER: This
generation has taught these
children it is in fact OK to
have sex early, often, with
anyone you want to, or any
animal that you want to.
There is special anger from
God about what you do with
your children because
the scripture
says they know nothing.
FRED PHELPS: And all such gifts
as accompany salvation
are reserved by that same
sovereign God for
his sheep, his elect.
MALE SPEAKER: Shouldn't they
have the chance to decide
first, before they're
out here?
REBEKAH PHELPS-DAVIS:
That's like saying--
that's like if you were to ask
me, shouldn't they have a
right to decide whether they
should go to school and learn
before you send them
to school to learn?
I mean, this is more important
even than that.
MALE SPEAKER: Any one of these
children, when they're a
little bit older, if they
decide that this is not
something that they want
to be a part of, will
they still be allowed--
are they still going to be a
member of these families, a
member of this community?
REBEKAH PHELPS-DAVIS: Don't you
understand that if they do
not believe this message that
the Lord our God has given us,
there isn't going to be a
discussion about how can I
stay, even if I don't believe
the way you do.
They will naturally go.
They will just go.
LIBBY (PHELPS) ALVAREZ: I was
there for almost 26 years.
I left a month before
my 26th birthday.
And talking about childhood,
we started picketing when I
was eight years old.
We thought it was great.
FEMALE SPEAKER: I just want the
American public to know
that with Barack Obama as your
president, he's going to lead
this nation to its final
destruction.
STEVE DRAIN: We understand
it's not like
you flip the switch.
It's not like you prepare the
kids, prepare the kids,
prepare the kids, and then
it happens to them.
It's happening to
them all along.
I mean, these kids go to the
elementary school, and they're
thought of as walking
picket signs.
LIBBY (PHELPS) ALVAREZ: Yeah,
because we're supposed to be a
testament to the other
kids in there.
Every time anybody looked at us,
all they would be thinking
is God hates fags.
TIM PHELPS: That word, yeah.
Those words.
LIBBY (PHELPS) ALVAREZ: And
you're going to hell.
Because you have to do
everything that they want.
They have absolute control
over everything.
And if you don't do what
they want, then
you are out of there.
Whenever somebody gets
in trouble, we can't
talk to them at all.
TIM PHELPS: It's
like isolation.
LIBBY (PHELPS) ALVAREZ: Yeah.
It's ridiculous.
STEVE DRAIN: Well,
I mean, they'll
definitely question things.
Any kid will question things.
But your job is to raise
somebody in the nurturing
[INAUDIBLE] the Lord.
There's a big difference, Joe,
between questioning things,
the natural inquisitive nature,
versus doing that from
a Bible perspective.
TIM PHELPS: The expectations
for us were higher, or were
really high for grades and
how you act in school.
And so that also is you're the
walking picket sign for those
words, along with this perfect
student child.
LIBBY (PHELPS) ALVAREZ:
Oh, yeah.
Exactly.
That's definitely it.
Yeah, they wanted people
to hate us.
And we were told that everyone
was going to hate us.
And if anyone acted like
they were our friends--
TIM PHELPS: They were lying.
LIBBY (PHELPS) ALVAREZ:
Yeah, exactly.
In their heart, they
really hate us.
In the back of my mind, I'd
always be worried about what
my family thought.
Like if I got put on the news,
I would worry about what they
would think I was saying,
and try to please them.
If there was a car ride, or if
we were on an airplane, we
would talk about why we were
picketing somewhere.
So we would all have the same
answer because they were real
big on everyone's of one
mind and one accord.
So we all have to say
the same thing.
STEVE DRAIN: Let's just take a
broad view of America from a
Bible perspective.
TAYLOR DRAIN: All of these
things that are happening
today, all these shootings,
they're from God's hand.
SHIRLEY PHELPS-ROPER: God
sent the shooters.
MARGE PHELPS: So now there's
been a rash of shooters.
STEVE DRAIN: God says, thou
shall not lie with--
SHIRLEY PHELPS-ROPER: Mankind
as with womankind.
FRED PHELPS: It is
an abomination.
SHIRLEY PHELPS-ROPER:
Global warming.
MARGE PHELPS: And hurricanes
and floods.
STEVE DRAIN: God says no
divorce, no remarriage.
SHIRLEY PHELPS-ROPER: You
are living in adultery.
STEVE DRAIN: It's
OK to be gay.
SHIRLEY PHELPS-ROPER: It is
in fact OK to be gay.
We're entitled to do what we
want with our own bodies.
MARGE PHELPS: That's like the
killer saying, I killed
someone last night, but
God forgives me.
I'm going to go kill someone
again tonight, but God
forgives me.
TIM PHELPS: And I know
with the little,
younger kids, they would--
what does this sign mean?
And they would explain
it to them.
And then so you have these even
younger kids who can just
spit off these words that
they probably don't even
understand.
LIBBY (PHELPS) ALVAREZ: It
wasn't a very pleasant place
to live, even though they act
like it's the most wonderful
place on earth.
TIM PHELPS: Well, to them
it probably is.
LIBBY (PHELPS) ALVAREZ: That's
a little bit ridiculous.
JOE STRAMOWSKI: Let's just
talk general politics.
Who's your pick for November?
STEVE DRAIN: Well, did you ever
see that "South Park"
episode, "Giant Douche
and Turd Sandwich?"
JOE STRAMOWSKI: Yes.
STEVE DRAIN: That's what the
deal is because there really
isn't a good choice.
I mean, there wouldn't be any
Advocate magazine if a
righteous man were leading
this nation.
You would literally have to shut
down whole agencies of
government.
You wouldn't be able to promise
billions of dollars
internationally to help fund
abortions, for instance.
You wouldn't be able
to do that at all.
You'd have to end
AIDS research.
You'd have to re- institute
the death penalty for
homosexuality.
DENISE HALL: That's just
something that Fred can say
that's so outlandish that he can
go, oh, I'm going to push
somebody else's button.
STEVE DRAIN: So that's why I
said to you a little earlier,
I got a little eye raise
even out of you, Joe.
You kind of have ice water in
your veins about stuff.
But you even raised an eyebrow
when I said they'd have to
re-institute the death
penalty for fags.
That's what the Bible says.