[GUNSHOTS]
THOMAS: Fuck me.
Fuck.
Damn it.
Get in.
[GUNSHOTS]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
THOMAS: For those of us who
weren't there, man, the
Vietnam War has always been
forbidden territory--
a searing national void whose
depths and horror we can never
know outside of grisly Fogerty
scored movies and Mark Baker's
"Nam." Even playing Vietnam as
kids seemed off limits unless
you did it under the
auspices of Rambo.
To full on reenact it would be
the ultimate heresy, a slap in
the face of all the vets who
died or were captured in the
US military's first
defeat, right?
But they do it in
North Carolina.
And you know who does it?
Other vets and a bunch of
regular reenactors.
I think, uh.
I think we're ready for war.
Over the last 50 years, war
reenactment has gone from
something Elks lodges did on
the weekend as an excuse to
get away from their wives, to
an obsessive pastime where
hardcore reenactors spend
their entire free time
shopping, sewing, and
researching to make the
experience as true to
life as possible.
As the intensity of the
reenactments has grown, the
wars reenacted have raced
forward in time, from the old
favorites of the Revolutionary
and Civil War, to World War I,
World War II, and every
so often Korea.
Vietnam, however, is tricky.
For starters there weren't
really battles.
Most of the fighting was done
on an ad hoc day by day and
night by night basis.
To solve this problem, the
reenactors we're with built a
mock firebase out somewhere in
the shit, picked an arbitrary
year in the war, and just
dedicated themselves to
defending it from Viet Cong
assault all night.
Are you still in the service?
RUDY SCHULZ: No, I
retired in 2005.
I was in the Army.
I got restarted in reenacting.
I missed the camaraderie.
But once you get out there and
you get the feel for it, it's
like, wow these guys
were studs.
THOMAS: Even just a little,
little taste of it.
RUDY SCHULZ: Just a
couple of days.
And these guys were out there
for 40 days, 50 days in the
snow, nothing.
And you're like, wow it
sucked for two days.
They had to do it for a month.
You know, war sucks.
It's true nobody
wants to do it.
THOMAS: Well, except kind
of, you guys for fun.
RUDY SCHULZ: It's true.
THOMAS: Well, cool.
Thank you very much.
RUDY SCHULZ: Oh,
you're welcome.
THOMAS: Good luck on recon.
Then there's the issue of
finding someone to play the
Vietnamese.
In our case, the reenactors just
grabbed a bunch of kids
from the local college and
surrounding towns, which is
kind of how Ho Chi Minh did it
when you think about it.
Nice.
This isn't your first
reenactment though?
CHRIS EVANS: I've
been reenacting
since I was about 15.
THOMAS: Damn.
How did you end up as Charlie
on this little foray?
CHRIS EVANS: Well, to put it
blank, you can't play Cowboys
and Indians without Indians if
you understand my meaning.
You got to have both sides to
do something like this, and
we're just more willing
to do both sides.
THOMAS: So you're NVA?
ZACK SEVER: Yes.
THOMAS: Right.
OK Like is there any
sort of particular
attraction to Vietnam?
Like does that resonate with
you in a particular way?
ZACK SEVER: Yeah.
My great uncle was a
First Lieutenant
in a Calvary Division.
THOMAS: OK.
Does he know you're doing
this, this weekend?
ZACK SEVER: No.
He doesn't know I'm
doing this.
I don't think he'd be very
happy if he did.
THOMAS: So I'm supposed to be,
basically, a civilian reporter
in [INAUDIBLE].
I guess I'm kind of half-dressed
right now.
How am I doing though, so far?
ZACK SEVER: I mean, you're
doing pretty good.
The reporters would be out there
in the army OD greens
wearing helmets.
They would have a big old PRESS
written on and around
their helmet.
THOMAS: That's what I need.
ZACK SEVER: They'd have a--
THOMAS: Instead of a goth band
from the '80s button.
ZACK SEVER: Yeah.
THOMAS: Hey, thank
you so much man.
ZACK SEVER: Yeah.
No problem.
THOMAS: Happy hunting today.
ZACK SEVER: Thank you.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
THOMAS: All right.
Tape rolling.
Good morning, Vietnam.
We are outside a firebase.
The men you see milling
behind me are
members of the 89th Infantry.
I don't know if the rest of this
unit has gotten up and
gotten dressed.
It feels like they're taking a
collegiate Saturday approach
to this war.
We've seen formations of VC,
irregular troops moving
through that sort of area
towards our, I'm thinking
that's the, north east.
It is pouring rain which is
great for the realism but
sucks for, I guess,
the reality.
Perfect weather to absorb
the misery that is
this ongoing war.
Happy [INAUDIBLE]
1968.
-Yeah, we're going.
-Just skirting it.
-No, we're going in.
[INAUDIBLE]
-Should be roughly silent
movement with all the rain.
Whenever you're ready.
-This guy right here, Mooch,
he'll be the last guy.
Give us about five yards.
THOMAS: So five behind Mooch
is going to be our maximum.
Since there's no predetermined
outcome, unlike traditional
reenactments, this means America
could win the battle
or maybe even the war.
[GUNSHOTS]
THOMAS: The first thing we
learned about war reenactment
is that it's fucking terrifying
having guns fired,
even ones loaded with blanks.
[GUNSHOTS]
THOMAS: The second thing
we learned was a common
reenactor's dilemma called the
GI effect, which is basically
that people playing Americans
don't like to die so sometimes
they just don't.
DON WHITE: Most everybody out
here is an amateur military
historian and that's the main
reason we do this hobby.
About half of my reenacting
group are actually military
veterans or active duty.
SGT. WILSON: The real soldiers,
sailor, airmen,
Marines, they all go through
horrible hardships to protect
this country.
We want to make sure that when
we're out here and we're doing
these reenactments, that
we're not doing a
disservice to them.
THOMAS: The realism of the
combat makes it even more
psychologically intriguing
that ex-combatants would
submit themselves to this
guaranteed flashback trigger.
Does anybody ever have
any problems with it?
Like having come from combat
basically going
into simulated combat?
DON WHITE: We have some
guys once in a while
that have some problems.
I'd say it's about
40% of them.
Their first event back they'll
actually go sit in the camp
for that event or have some
issues with the--
THOMAS: Yeah, it'll take them
time to acclimate to that.
SGT. WILSON: The horror and the
terror is just shards of a
veteran's experience
in the military.
And if we can focus on the
positive aspects as well as
the hardships, the veterans,
they really appreciate that
and they really like that.
THOMAS: We've been asked along,
actually, by this recon
unit made up of Special Forces
guys that are going back out
into the woods trying to flush
out the dudes who are lighting
up the firebase.
[GUNSHOTS]
They are lighting this
fucking forest up.
-[SPEAKING VIETNAMESE]
-VC eat shit.
-They're wiped out.
Pizza.
-All right then.
Let me go.
Let me grab a quick
[INAUDIBLE]
just so that they understand.
THOMAS: This is a part of the
war you don't very often get
to see, and that's--
Oh, no, no.
This is--
Right.
No, no, no.
We understand that.
You obviously get breaks
and things.
We'll head back and hopefully
not see you again.
CHRIS EVANS: You'll see
us again as soon as we
get our guys back.
THOMAS: All right As night fell,
we snuck away from the
American unit we were embedded
with and fell in with a bunch
of VC and NVA regulars who were
planning a nocturnal raid
on the firebase.
-When we were young, we'd do
like little pranks, right?
So we'd phone up a Chinese
restaurant, we go, do you have
one young guy?
And literally this guy
said, he looks,
I'll look in the menu.
He looks in the menu.
He goes, no, we don't
have one young guy.
And I said, well, do you
have an old one then?
And hang up the phone.
-One young guy?
-One young guy.
-Oh, jeez.
THOMAS: Just a bunch of VC
hanging out in a tobacco
field, teaching each other
how [INAUDIBLE].
I mean, it's not a rice
paddy but whatever,
you're in North Carolina.
-This is your team.
Anybody with a red scarf,
you're NVA.
If you get killed, stay there.
The Americans are going to check
you, search you, then
they're going to
leave you, OK?
After they check you.
Girls--
they know that you all are
girls, don't worry about it.
THOMAS: It begins.
-Come on you fucking gook.
THOMAS: Charlie's fucking
everywhere.
Our firebase is under attack.
-Cut the camera off.
[GUNSHOTS]
-Next.
THOMAS: So we just witnessed
a war crime.