JOSH KALIS: My pops
was moving from
Michigan to Dallas, Texas.
And they didn't want me to be
part of the move, because I
was a bit of a troublemaker.
So him and my mom, who lived in
New York at the time, sent
me to skateboard camp
at Woodward.
And it was there that I met Tony
Mag and filmed a couple
things while at Woodward.
And then he was like,
hey, we're going to
put you on H Street.
And that was it.
Dude, I was super psyched.
I was hyped to get on, but at
the same time it was like all
my favorite skaters, Mike
Carroll and Sean Sheffey and
Sal Barbier and all the illest
dudes rode for H Street.
And they all left right
as I got on.
So I was kind of like, well.
I didn't really give
a shit, man.
I was getting free
H Street boards.
That was tight.
At some point, my mom moved
from New York to Philly.
And when I would visit her,
I would go skate the city.
And this was before me
and Stevie really--
we were just little
skater dudes.
STEVIE WILLIAMS: Oh, man.
The first time I met Josh, I was
with my cousin Russell and
my man Terrence.
And we were skating this skate
spot called Rat Curves.
And Bam Margera and Mike
Maldonado used to skate for H
Street back in the day.
They showed up.
It was like Mike, Bam, Bam's
brother, Bam's dad, and Josh.
And they introduced us, like,
oh, this is Josh.
He's from outside of Philly.
He skates for H Street.
We were like, what?
That's dope.
And he was good.
But I never really tripped off
of it until he came to LOVE
and started skating.
And that's when I
seen him skate.
I was like, damn, that
dude is sick.
And for some reason me and
him just hit it off.
I was good and he was good, but
I never even heard of him
before, though.
I was probably like
11 years old.
JOSH KALIS: What would
you call this?
MALE SPEAKER: A shrine.
JOSH KALIS: Shrine?
My LOVE shrine?
Does it look like a shrine?
It does, huh?
Damn.
I wasn't really going
for the shrine look.
We skated together
all the time.
And we just clicked at LOVE.
STEVIE WILLIAMS: Coming
downtown, I was looking
forward to seeing Josh.
That made me want to
get sponsored.
And he was already sponsored,
so he would just give us
boards, wheels.
And one day we were skating,
and I learned kickflip
noseslides.
And then he learned kickflip
Then he learned kickflip
noseslides and
ollie heel flip it.
He had every trick.
He could do everything.
RICKY OYOLA: I don't
know how Josh came.
I don't know if it was
a relative, or--
but yeah, he came.
And he was really good, man.
He was really good.
I wish dudes like that would
skate our way, too.
There still wasn't anybody who
was exploring the city like we
always did.
JOSH KALIS: Top of the food
chain in Philly was Ricky.
I was definitely
hierarchy shit.
Because Ricky had rules where
you couldn't film unless you
were pushing switch switch.
Like if you're doing switch
mongo, you ain't fucking
filming it at LOVE.
That's when Ricky and those
dudes ran LOVE.
And they had their rules.
And they had their
whole thing.
You know what I'm saying?
At the time, the very first
"TransWorld" article on
Philadelphia was there then.
And a few of us shot
some stuff.
And it was told, don't
use that shit.
DGK didn't exist for a while.
And then he turned that other
side of LOVE park into DGK,
the Dirty Ghetto Kids.
And it was because of that.
STEVIE WILLIAMS: At that
time, there was
two different cliques.
It was our clique, the DGK
clique, and then it was Ricky
Oyola and all of those dudes.
RICKY OYOLA: I don't think a
lot of those dudes, the DGK
dudes, I don't think they liked
the fact that Matt and I
were the ones who were most
known and Philadelphia was
kind of ours.
We created that.
You know what I mean?
So it was kind of ours
in such a way.
STEVIE WILLIAMS: Whoever came to
Philly was supposed to hang
with Ricky and Matt and
all of them dudes.
And, see, Fred Gall, when
he came, he didn't come
and hang with us.
He went to hang with Ricky.
And Josh was never their dude.
Josh was like--
he took to us.
So every time he came to the
city, he came over and
chilled with us.
MALE SPEAKER: [BEATBOXING].
STEVIE WILLIAMS: He always had
the swag, but he wasn't the
white dude that tried
to act black.
He was just the white
dude with swag.
Everybody liked him, from white
people to black people.
The girls loved him.
He was Josh.
Everybody knew he had value.
No matter what city he was in,
he brought value to that city.
At the end of the day, he was
taking all their shine.
And Ricky was supposed to
be the king of Philly.
And you got all of these dudes
following his lead and shit.
And then here come Josh
that's like, I'm not
following your lead.
I'm actually rocking with
the ghetto kids.
And they definitely didn't
like that shit.
JOSH KALIS: Me and Ricky got
along pretty good until he
thought I fucked his ex-chick.
And then that started up a whole
fucking shit storm of
beef between me and Ricky.
And that carried to
San Francisco.
It carried all over the place.
We had crazy beef.
RICKY OYOLA: Yeah, yeah.
There were some issues and stuff
like that, some just
stupid shit that went down.
STEVIE WILLIAMS: I think just
that situation was easier for
Ricky to say, fuck you, Josh.
Get out of my city.
And Josh left.
It wasn't like, we going
to retaliate.
Josh just left.
And I was like, damn.
There go our town hero, our dude
to get our free boards.
It was over.
JOSH KALIS: Rumors were I
wasn't allowed there.
And I went back on that
Invisible tour and was like,
hey, bro, here I am.
And Ricky was like, you know
what, you're going
to be pro, I'm pro.
We shouldn't just fucking
be at each other's
throat every time.
So just respect.
If I'm here, don't be here.
If you're here, I
ain't coming in.
And we just kind of rode it
out like that for a while,
until when I moved back to
Philly then we squashed it.
And Ricky found out I didn't
fuck the chick and apologized.
And it was all good.
RICKY OYOLA: Look,
I'm older now.
And I just thought back.
It was always kind of
like this fake beef.
Because it really
wasn't any beef.
There wasn't any.
We're two different people.
I'm from the woods.
They're from the city.
Skating was something
we had in common.
But we didn't skate
the same way.
And LOVE park was their
playground that hooked them
up, got them on DC.
And look where they're at now.
Just his tre flips--
tre flips are my
favorite trick.
And he's seriously got tops.
He's got one of the best ones
ever, to tell you the truth.
Stevie's got it also.
Stevie's got a great
switch flip.
He's just really good.
Josh's style is what I like
more than anything.
His big spins and
tail slides--
I wish I could do that shit.
I mean, I don't want
to spend two years
trying to do it once.
That's going to be a shitty
two years of my skating.
I might do it.
But that's no fun.