- So you're telling me that none
of these kids will work.
- No, he wants a fresh face
to move his product,
And these kids are too recognizable.
I just...
Oh-ho-ho.
I love this kid.
This is the one
in that chocolate commercial.
- The one who slaps the lady.
- And grabs the chocolate and says...
You eat that, you eat this next.
- He's so cute.
- Hey, mom. Hey, Gigi.
- Hi, sweetie.
- Smile.
Tilt your head.
The other way.
- Okay, you're not thinking
what I think you're thinking.
- That's what I'm thinking.
- Okay, it's not gonna work.
Kevin, go upstairs and take a shower.
You smell like hot dog water.
- Give me one good reason why not.
- Because Kevin
is not child model material.
He's not gonna change
into all those outfits.
He hates changing
his own clothes as it is.
- I can be very persuasive.
- Maybe to a grown man
but not to a 12-year-old.
You ain't got nothing he wants,
Unless there's a ps3 in your purse.
- Hmm.
- Hey, Gigi.
- Hey.
- Baby.
- Hmm?
- I got to talk to you
about something.
- Okay, what's that?
- So remember how I was telling you
About this guy at work, Devon?
- Oh, the sales guy.
- Well, we got to talking,
And it turns out he sells all
the ads that run on the station,
And he wanted to talk to me,
Because he thought I should know
that all the sponsors
Really like what I'm doing on-air.
- Oh, that's good.
- Yeah, that's good, right?
And then he was like,
"yo, we probably should
get together sometime."
And then I was thinking,
he talks to all the people
That need to know that people like me.
And then I was like, "cool."
- Nick, is this story going somewhere?
- Look, I invited Devon
and his wife over for dinner.
- Oh, okay, great,
But we probably should have
gone out for drinks first,
Get to know them before
we have them in our house.
- Ohh, you're right.
I'm sorry.
- That's okay. So when is the dinner?
- Tonight.
- What?
- At 7:00.
- Nick.
sync and correct by dr.jackson
www.addic7ed.com
- Whoo!
Ahh! Good.
So like I said, Kevin,
All you have to do is
change your clothes and smile.
- Yeah, while some weird dude
takes pictures of me.
- Okay, Kevin, honey, you got to think
About what this could do
for you, right?
I mean, your face will be
In every single frame
this company sells.
I mean, boo, you will be famous.
- Yeah, until I'm grown and broke,
Because my accountant
stole all my money,
And then I'll have to work
as a security guard at the mall
And marry some woman
who doesn't really love me
And pushes me down a flight of stairs
And then waits 30 minutes
to call the paramedics.
Ring a bell?
- We don't know if that's true.
Okay, how much?
- 200.
- 150.
- 175.
- 205.
- Okay, you obviously don't know
how this works.
- Or do I?
- Fine. Deal.
- Suzanne.
- Hmm?
- This chicken is off the hook.
No, seriously.
Here's the chicken,
and here's the hook.
It's off, you know?
This chicken is so good
That if I were lost
on a deserted island
And a rescue boat
with destiny's child,
The Kardashian's, Charlie's angels,
And the pussycat dolls pulled up
And they said they had a spot
for me but not this chicken,
I would let that boat keep on going,
And I would stay on that island
with this chicken.
- Now, if you want
an amazing roasted chicken,
You have to try Harrison's.
You might find it a little too pricey,
But it is to die for.
- I guess we'll have to try
Harrison's, honey.
- I guess so.
It's to die for.
- So, Suzanne, you must be impressed.
Devon's been talking
to some very important people
About your husband.
- And no matter what I say,
they refuse to fire him.
Just kidding.
Your husband is gonna be the man
over there one day.
- Whoa, whoa, whoa.
You know, one day, I will be the man,
But right now, you are the man.
- That's a compliment
coming from you, the man.
- Okay, I accept.
I am the man.
- No, you're not.
I'm the man.
Just kidding.
- Katie, remember, if Rico asks you,
I don't like him,
unless you find out from bo
That Corey doesn't like me first.
Then if Rico says he likes me,
Yeah, you can then say that
I might or might not like him.
Okay, see you at school tomorrow.
Bye.
- Lindsey, come here.
I want you to meet some friends.
This is Devon and mara Sawyer.
- Hi, I'm Lindsey. Nice to meet you.
- Hey, Lindsey.
- Hello.
- Cool. Mom, I'm just gonna do
some homework upstairs.
- Okay.
- It's nice meeting you guys.
- All right, bye, baby.
- Bye.
- Nick, Suzanne,
what a lovely young lady,
So well-mannered,
Seems like she has
a good head on her shoulders.
- Thank you. That means a lot.
- You know,
Lindsey's a very popular name
For boys in Scotland.
- It's also quite popular
for girls in rehab.
- Really?
So when's the last time
you were there?
- No, no, no, no, no, no, no.
I will not have you insult my wife
And ask her when she
was last in rehab.
It was Tuesday.
- Oh, man, you are nuts. You are nuts.
- So where are the kids in school?
- Lindsey goes to
Meredith Frasier high,
And our son Kevin
is at curt flannel middle.
- Oh, no, no, no, no.
Devon, you just have to get them
into weakly.
- Weakly?
- Weakly prep, 7 through 12.
- You know, the station owner,
Mr. Waters,
His kids go there,
And so do both
of the evening anchors'.
- Isn't it hard to get in?
- Not for a family like you.
I'll put a good word in
with the board.
- Suzanne, all I can tell you is...
- Ah, I know, it's to die for.
- Like these Greens.
If I was trapped on a desert island
With these Greens
And a rescue boat
with the girls gone wild,
The laker girls, and the girl
with the dragon tattoo came up
And they said, "we have room for you
But not the Greens," I...
- I already know.
I know you would stay
on the island with the Greens.
- What the hell are you talking about?
No, I'd get on the boat.
What are the odds
of a third boat coming by?
These Greens are good,
but I'm not stupid.
- So you didn't hear any of that?
- Hear any of what?
- The woman spent the whole night
Trying to one-up me.
you just have to get
your hair done at royale's.
your coffee from Louise's.
when you die, you just have to
be buried at Justin's cemetery.
It's to die for.
- I get it. You don't like her.
But I am still looking
into this school.
This could be a real good
opportunity for the kids.
- Nick, the kids
aren't switching schools.
They're doing fine where they are.
- Are you saying that because
you don't like the school
Or because you don't like the people?
- What's the difference?
Those are the people at the school.
- I'm sure there was
somebody you hated
At the Beyonce concert,
but we still went to that.
- Nick, the woman didn't say
anything about the school.
All she talked about
was who went there.
- Okay, fine.
You don't want do it;
I won't push you.
It's just your children's education.
- Fine. We will look into it.
But I don't like you right now.
- And yet you're still here.
- How many more of these things
do I have to wear?
- These things are called outfits,
And you have 11 more to go.
- Hey.
- Hi.
- How's it going
on the child model front?
- How's it look like it's going?
I mean, look at me.
I look like Chris Brown,
the early years.
- Let's go.
- All right.
Baby, this school
looks pretty good, right?
- Okay, I will admit it.
I was very skeptical at first,
but it is a really nice school,
And they get 100%
of their graduates into college.
- Mm-hmm.
- In my school, they couldn't get 100%
Of the class to graduate.
Some of those fools are still there.
- Well, it looks like our chances
Of getting into this school
are actually pretty good.
- What makes you say that?
- Baby, Devon's on the board.
- Why wouldn't he mention that
in the first place?
- Maybe he was waiting for us
to make the first move.
- Hmm.
- Look, all we need to do
is fill this out,
Get the kids' transcripts,
recommendations,
Physicals, pictures,
and get it into Devon.
Anything else I'm forgetting?
- How about telling the kids?
- Nah.
- What's wrong with the school I'm in?
- Nothing.
It's just that we have to think
about your future.
- I think about my future.
I was gonna finish
High School, college,
Get married, have some kids,
But now I'm gonna end up
a part-time stripper,
Pregnant, on drugs,
with a tattoo on my back
And a piercing in my lip
All because I rebelled against you
When you made me change schools.
- Give it a chance.
You haven't even been there.
- I think it's awesome.
Every class has smart boards.
Every kid gets their own laptop.
Plus they have to wear a uniform.
You know what that means?
That means I can literally wear
The same thing to school every day.
- You still have to wash it.
- Yeah, maybe eventually.
- All the girls there are snobby,
And all the guys there are corny.
- You're not going there for the boys.
You're going there for the grades.
- Do you have any idea how girls work?
Honey, everything
you're saying is true,
But next year,
you're gonna be a junior,
And that's the one
that counts the most
when it comes to college admission's
- Oh, my God.
Their P.E. Class is skiing.
They even have a class where
you don't have to go to class.
- Whatever.
It's not like I have a choice.
- They have fencing?
This school is awesome.
Do you think I can get my own sword?
- Mr. And Mrs. Kingston-persons,
Thank you so much for joining myself
And the rest of the board
this afternoon.
As the head of the board,
I'll be conducting the interview.
If anyone has anything to add,
please chime in.
- I'd like to chime in.
I would just like to say
that this school is so nice
That if my kids were stranded
alone on a desert island
And all they had was an x-box,
another x-box,
A flat-screen tv,
a box of cell phones,
Drake, and no curfew
And this school showed up
on a ship to pick them up,
They would go with this school.
They would...
They would go to this school,
because it's nice.
What are y'all writing?
- Suzanne, let's start with you.
- Uh, first of all,
I'd just like to say,
Before we get started,
he was just kidding.
- Now, it says here you read
our school newspaper.
How did that come about?
- Well, before we get to that,
It says here that you have
an annual school trip.
Do you guys go to yellowstone
by any chance, and if so...
Because there's a very real chance
That we might encounter a bear...
Can I bring my sword?
- So why do you
want to come to weakly?
- Can I be honest?
- Please do.
- I don't.
My parents are forcing me
to come here.
No offense.
I already have friends at my school,
And there's this guy
that I really like.
His name is Corey,
and I wouldn't see him,
Because I would be across town.
And I already had to move once
when my mom and dad broke up,
But I don't want
to have to start all over again.
And I don't know
about this uniform thing.
I just bought
three new pairs of jeans,
And they are really cute.
- So when I say a word,
Tell me the first word
that pops into your mind.
- Got it.
- President.
- Obeezy.
- What?
You know, like, Kanye West is yeezy,
And Lil' Wayne is wheezy,
I always thought that if Barack Obama
Was a hip-hop artist,
People would call him bareezy obeezy.
- Right.
- Left.
- Please tell me you're ing.
- I wish I could.
- So she's supposed to be your friend,
But she calls you on a three-way
With a guy that you like on the phone?
- Lame, right?
- Totally.
- I know.
- Yeah, but there's gonna be
girls like that
Everywhere you go,
so why not come to weakly?
- I don't know.
I'm still not sure about
this whole uniform thing.
- We have free-dress Fridays.
- Hmm.
- Mrs. Kingston-persons,
What would you say your mission is
In regards to coming to weakly?
- My mission would be to give
my children a great education.
I hear the ones here are to die for.
- Mm-hmm.
Mr. Kingston-persons,
what's more important to you,
The academic aspect of school
or the social aspect?
- Both.
There's nothing worse
than a brilliant guy
With no friends.
Can you say evil genius?
- Can you say Facebook?
- What?
- The inventor of Facebook,
Mark Zuckerberg,
The world's youngest billionaire,
Was a brilliant college student
with no friends.
- So was Osama bin Laden.
- Osama bin Laden, yeah, that's funny.
So you're equating weakly
with terrorism.
- No, no, I'm just saying
it can go either way.
I mean, like,
Stephen and Alec Baldwin,
You know, same background,
two different dudes.
- You know,
the baldwins went to weakly.
- Really?
- No.
- Oh, hey, Gigi.
- Hey, hey.
Hey, hey, hey, hey,
where have you been?
- Gigi, he had his school
interview today, remember?
- You know what?
His future might be important to you,
But his present, it's important to me.
Let's go. We have a photo shoot.
- How can you be a stage mom?
You're not even a mother.
- Yes, she is.
- Hey.
- Nick, stop it.
- Let's go.
- Mom, how are you just gonna let...
- Boy, I'm paying you. Upstairs.
Ring a bell?
- Baby, it's here.
- What?
- The letter from weakly.
- Oh.
- Ohhh, yeah.
Here we go.
Congratulations.
we have carefully considered
your applications for admission
to weakly prep
and are proud to inform you
that you will be placed
on our waiting list
for possible admission next semester.
- Next semester?
- Thank you for your interest
in weakly prep.
- Maybe it's a mix-up.
- Are you kidding me? Seriously?
Nick, they don't want us,
which is fine e by me,
Because I didn't want to do this
in the first place.
- Look, you know what?
They didn't get rejected.
I mean, they're on a wait list.
- Wait for what, till they
graduate from another school?
Now, you can keep drinking
the kool-aid if you want to,
But I will not keep putting
my kids through this.
- Aww, you watch.
It'll be real good.
You gonna help me with the bags?
- Sure. I'll put it on my wait list.
- Kevin, let's go.
We have a photo shoot in 30 minutes.
- Not so fast.
I've been doing a little research,
And I think there's a couple
things we need to discuss.
- Okay, well,
we can discuss that in the car.
Let's go.
- Did you know that the entire
amount of money you paid me
Is less than what most
male models make in an hour?
- They're grown.
You're not union.
- Union scale is still about
fives times what I'm being paid.
- You agreed to the price.
- You took advantage of me.
- No, I didn't.
I didn't know anything
about those rules.
- You do now.
- So what are you saying?
- All I'm saying is,
Since we're only halfway
through the project
And you need the other half done
Before you can deliver
to your clients,
I have what is called
a bargaining chip.
- And what exactly do you intend
to use this bargaining chip for?
- For two new video games
in addition to the cash.
- How much are they?
- More than $50, less than a lawsuit.
- You cannot sue me.
- Not me, your clients.
- Fine. Deal, Kevin.
And does your mother know
how evil you are?
- No, and if you know
what's best for you,
You'll keep it that way.
- We are so happy to have you with us.
We are beside ourselves.
Here we are, and here we are
beside ourselves.
Domo arigato.
- Thank you.
- Thank you. Thank you. Thank you.
Thank you. Thank you. Thank you.
Domo, domo.
- Devon, can I talk to you
for a moment?
- I'll be with you in just a moment,
Mr. Kingston-persons.
Thank you so much. Baby?
- Do you guys like Chinese?
Because I know a place
that is to die for.
- Thank you.
N.K.P., what it do? What it do?
- Oh, now it's N.K.P.?
Last time, it was D.O.A.
- D...
Ahh, lol, omg.
Oh, come on.
I hope this little dog and pony show
Didn't get to you.
You know how it is.
- No, I don't.
Why don't you tell me how it is,
D. E.V...O.N.?
- Look, man, I want you in here
as much as anybody,
But this board is tough,
So I had to play the bad cop
so they didn't think
I was trying to get somebody
in here who didn't belong.
- Yeah? Well, it worked.
- Congratulations. You in.
- We didn't get in.
We're on the wait list.
- Oh.
I may have laid it on
a little too thick.
You ever done that,
Just lean into it a little too hard?
- No.
- Okay, you know what?
I'll talk to a few people.
- You're the head of the board.
Who are you gonna talk to? You?
- Nick, I know you're upset.
- Yeah, I'm upset.
Man, you got me down here.
Look, my kids are fine where they are.
They don't need weakly, and obviously,
Weakly doesn't need them.
- Nick, I'm gonna t.
You might like it. You might not.
- Really?
- If there was a problem,
it wasn't with the children.
I talked to the counselors.
They loved them.
- Then who was the problem with?
Me?
Oh, there's something wrong with me?
- Nick Diesel, let me be honest.
You have a bad attitude.
- I have a bad attitude
Because you and your wife
brought me and Suzanne
in front of the board
And acted like
you weren't in our house
Eating collard Greens
and chicken a week earlier.
Look, if you had introduced us
to the board
Like you wanted us in, we'd be in.
- Nick, wait, wait.
Please, reconsider.
Look, I admit it.
I overdid it.
I'll talk to the board.
- You got a lot of faces, man.
Pick one, and stick with it.
- You're kidding, right?
Oh, you're kidding.
You're... Nick.
N.K.P.
Ni... okay, walk out,
and he's gonna come back in.
Okay.
- How'd the smack down go?
- That fool tapped out.
- You want a sandwich?
- Yeah, I'll take one.
- Well, you just have to have
the Turkey, lettuce, and tomatoes
with the spicy mustard.
It's to die for.
You know, I thought Devon was cool.
- Honey, he's a salesman.
He just sold you.
- Man, you make it sound so dirty.
- Nick, don't feel bad.
You have this tendency
to see the best in people.
It's what you do.
I feel like you saw the best in me,
even when I didn't see it in myself.
So occasionally,
if you have to be hoodwinked,
Bamboozled, run amok,
played, suckered,
Punked, hustled...
- Are you through?
- No, I got a couple more:
Carried, dissed, mugged, had,
Or just plain turned out...
- Turned out?
It's a school application,
not a prison assault.
- Well, next time,
If you just listen to me
in the first place,
You wouldn't be in this position.
- I hate it when you're right.
- Mm.
- And I don't like you right now.
- Mm, and yet you're still here.
- I don't want to talk about it.
- Oh, Kevin,
the pictures came out cute.
- I don't want to talk about it, Gigi.
- What's wrong?
- Nothing.
Kevin made me look great
in front of the client,
But now he doesn't want anyone
to see the pictures.
- Hey, man, come on, Kev,
show us the pictures.
- People are gonna see them
anyway when the frames come out.
- Fine, but no video game
is worth this.
- Here we go.
- Ohh, baby.
- Ohh, look at your head.
- He's so cute.
- Look at that head.
That head is...
sync and correct by dr.jackson
www.addic7ed.com