This is the state Capitol, building in Lansing,
Michigan. There`s a crowd gathered in front,
and this is what that crowd looked like a
close. Protesters, thousands of them, holding
up signs and chanting. At least three schools
around the state were closed, because teachers
went to Lansing to be part of this. The chants
were going on inside the capitol, too.
UNIDENTIFIED MALES AND FEMALES: Veto! Veto!
Veto! Veto!
AZUZ: They are saying, veto, because they
are protesting against legislation, that was
up for a vote yesterday. That legislation
passed, and it was headed to the governor`s
desk next. He said he`ll sign it, and when
he does, Michigan will become the 24th U.S
state with Right-to-Work laws. Now, what that
means is that workers in Michigan won`t have
to join a labor union or to pay union dues
in order to get or keep a job. People who
support these laws say they give workers more
choice and can attract more business. Critics
say that right-to-work laws make unions weaker
and keep wages lower.
Nelson Mandela, political activist, world
leader, Nobel Peace Prize winner, here`s Mandela
at the U.S. Capitol building in 1990 and this
is where Mandela was yesterday, a hospital
in his home country of South Africa, checked
in there over the weekend. Authorities say
doctors were treating the 94-year old for
a lung infection. Mandela had abdominal surgery
earlier this year and had a serious respiratory
infection last year. Nelson Mandela was once
called the world`s most famous political prisoner.
He spent 27 years in jail, fighting for equality
for black South Africans. After he was released
in 1990, he continued his efforts to unite
his country. His work earned him that Nobel
Peace Prize and in 1994, he won South Africa`s
first open election, becoming the country`s
first black president.
Is this legit? "Zwolf, doce and dvenadzat`
all represent the number twelve.
Yep, in order, those are the German, Spanish
and Russian words for 12.
Well, considering today`s date, 12/12/12,
we thought we`d get in on the fun, so with
the year winding down, we are going to take
a look back at 12 newsmakers from the past
12 months.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
CROWD (chanting): Huria! Huria!
AUNG SAN SUU KYI, ACTIVIST AND POLITICAL LEADER:
We hope that this will be the beginning of
new era where there will be more emphasis
on the role of the people in the everyday
politics of our country.
MICHAEL PHELPS, AMERICAN SWIMMING CHAMPION:
I finished my career how I wanted to. Now,
looking back, I can (inaudible) everything
I`ve ever wanted to.
MALALA YOUSUFZAI, PAKISTANI TEENAGER: I thought
that I must stand up for my rights, the right
of education, the right for peace.
FELIX BAUMGARTNER, AUSTRIAN SKYDIVER: (inaudible)
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: 725. (cheering and applause)
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: ... the world record holder.
MITT ROMNEY, FORMER GOVERNOR OF MASSACHUSETTS:
This is the time of great challenges for America,
and I pray that the president will be successful
in guiding our nation.
BARACK OBAMA, U.S. PRESIDENT: With your stories
and your struggles, I return to the White
House more determined and more inspired than
ever about the work there is to do and the
future that lies ahead.
(applause)
(END VIDEO CLIP)
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: Today`s "Shoutout" goes
out to Mrs. Marx`s social studies classes
in Freeland, Michigan. Which of these professional
sports leagues plays an 82-game season? You
know what to do, is it Major League Soccer,
National Football League, Major League Baseball
or National Hockey League? You`ve got three
seconds, go.
In a standard NHL season, teams plays 82 games.
That`s your answer and that`s your "Shoutout."
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: But so far this season, NHL teams haven`t
played any games, and they are not going to
for at least a few more weeks. All those games
have been canceled through the end of the
year, the all star game scrapped. This year`s
outdoor winter classic game, gone, all because
of a labor dispute between the league and
its players. And two sides are trying to work
out a new deal. It would include things like
how players contracts are set up, and how
long those contracts can last. Eight years
ago, a similar dispute led to the entire NHL
season being canceled.
Kareem Abdul Jabbar set a lot of records in
the basketball court. But the Hall of Famer
has also said, quote, "I can do more than
stuff a ball through a hoop. My greatest asset
is my mind." He is hoping his new foundation
will send the same message to young people.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
KAREEM ABDUL-JABBAR, NBA PLAYER 1969-89: We
are trying to get the Skyhoop Foundation off
the ground and set up to give kids a shot
that can`t be blocked, and that has to do
with their education, no matter what happens
to a young person, if they have good educational
foundation, they can do what they want to
do with their lives.
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: Education, it`s very important
to you.
ABDUL-JABBAR: Yes, it is. Too many young people
think that the only thing that they can do
is be LeBron James or Denzel Washington or
Jay-Z, and if they can`t do that, they are
lost. That`s not it.
Any kid that wants to grow up and be me is
facing incredible odds, there are only 450
NBA jobs available for athletes. That`s it.
We live in a country of many millions of people
and there are 450 jobs of that type. So, most
kids are not going to make it. Because if
they just do the math, it would become very
obvious to them, but they all use the exception
as a rule. We need to flip that around and
give them an idea of what they want to do.
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: There`s kids watching right
now that think I`m going to be the next Kareem
Abdul Jabbar. I`m going to be the greatest
basketball player ever. Your advice to them
is what?
ABDUL-JABBAR: Dream your dreams, pursue your
dreams, but don`t have that to be the only
thing that you pursue. I`m going to still
a quote from the United Negro College Fund,
"A mind is a terrible thing to waste," don`t
let your intellectual development suffer because
you want to play sports. You can do the both.
(END VIDEOTAPE)
AZUZ: Well, finally today sometimes it`s all
about the details: This man from Washington
State decided to go big when it came time
to propose to his girlfriend. No simple down
on one knee and ask business. This guy used
his tractor to plow his proposal into a 200
acre field. Then he flew his intended fiancee
Jody over it in an airplane. There was just
one problem: the Jay in Jody was facing the
wrong way, so, you could give him an A for
romance and F for handwriting. His little
slip up didn`t distract her from the question
at hand, and she said, yes. There are a lot
of ways to propose, you could go with type
A, or type B, that guy went with type O. Still,
they decide to write their own vows. He might
want to leave that to his bride. We`ve plowed
through all our time for today, more stories
and more puns cropping up tomorrow on CNN
STUDENT NEWS. See you then.