Disappearing from our planet
at an alarming rate
Lions, cheetahs, leopards, tigers
In fact, at this moment,
there are more tigers
in captivity,
than there are left in the wild.
Really?
We have to stop
the decline of big cats now
before we end up talking about
lions
and leopards
the way we talk about dinosaurs.
Book of Extinct Animals
Here's the good news...
We can do something about it...
Right now.
National Geographic
Big Cats Initiative
is already making progress
towards reversing the trend
with real solutions
that really work.
like...
helping communities
protect their livestock from hungry lions
so herders
don't become hunters.
We've started making a difference...
(but we can do more.)
Now we need you
to join us.
Take action.
Lend your voice
share with friends
Let's create one big loud
roar.
Cause an uproar
to save big cats today.