the world, and the culture
and politics behind them.
We've saved the best until last,
a fashion week in the
capital city of chaos.
This is Lagos, Nigeria.
It's home to 8 or 15 or 18
million people, depending
which census figure
you believe.
And like anywhere with a large
population density, it's not
without its troubles.
Civil, state-sponsored
homophobia, religious tension,
and widespread corruption are
among the many factors that
have led to calls for the
resignation of longstanding
president, Goodluck Jonathan.
MALE SPEAKER: Actually,
such elements of
society should be killed.
FEMALE SPEAKER: With that in
mind, we prepared ourselves
for Nigeria Fashion Week with
not a little trepidation.
But like all the fabulous placed
we've visited so far
this series, we were sure we'd
find something beautiful
behind the depressing
headlines.
There are many different fashion
weeks held throughout
the year in Lagos.
But we were here for what we
were assured was the official
Nigeria Fashion Week.
First stop was the headquarters
of the
organizers, Legendary Gold.
We've arrived at the Legendary
Gold offices.
And this is the hub of
the fashion week.
We're going to inside
and get legendary
services valuable as gold.
The fantastically named
Lexy Mojo-Eyes
is the man in charge.
He also looks like Don
King, if Don King
had gone into fashion.
FEMALE SPEAKER: What does
fashion mean to you?
FEMALE SPEAKER: The models
are assembled
for a fitting session.
And things were getting
very naked.
And so I went in search
of the boys.
MALE SPEAKER: (SINGING) Before
you choose to use, before you
choose to use, use your device
so you don't have rain drops
falling from your eyes.
[INAUDIBLE].
Gonna have to pay the price,
pay the price.
FEMALE SPEAKER: In what
way are you quirky?
[LAUGHTER]
FEMALE SPEAKER: That's girly?
FEMALE SPEAKER: I thought
this was more serious.
MALE SPEAKER: Becuase
I love Africa.
Africa is the best
place to be.
And when you come closer, you
find out that we are friendly
people, good people.
For example, in Nigeria right
now, are we not friendly?
FEMALE SPEAKERS (IN UNISON):
Welcome to Nigeria Fashion
Week, [INAUDIBLE].
[CHEERING]
FEMALE SPEAKER: The fashion
itself was being held at a
slightly rundown looking
government building where
Prince Charles himself had
laid the first stone.
It's quarter past 12:00.
Which is a bit worrying, because
the show is supposed
to start at 12:00.
And so far, there's no show.
There's about six models
backstage who still haven't
had their hair and
makeup done.
And there's no audience.
We went to check out the
backstage progress.
Tempers were already rising.
FRED EBOKA: I told you,
you sit here.
Isn't it?
You are going back this way.
FEMALE SPEAKER: This way.
FRED EBOKA: Yes, exactly.
So you go now.
And you follow.
Come back.
[INAUDIBLE]
just stand here.
That's what I tell you.
I do not want drama.
I don't want drama, because
I'm full of drama.
[LAUGHTER]
FRED EBOKA: My standards
mustn't go down
because I'm in Nigeria.
Standards should be the same
to you all over the world.
But for some reason--
FEMALE SPEAKER: It's
not very good.
FRED EBOKA: --I have to adapt
myself to a certain degree.
People can wait.
And they have such patience.
I don't have that kind
of patience.
Don't deny me attention.
Otherwise I go very crazy and
a drama, drama queen.
FEMALE SPEAKER: However, Lexy
didn't quite see the problem.
FEMALE SPEAKER: If you want
something to start at 12:00,
you tell people to get
there at 8:00 AM.
[LAUGHTER]
FEMALE SPEAKER: And sure enough,
two hours after the
first show was scheduled to
begin, the glamorous crowds
started to roll in, each one
making sure to take a turn on
the red carpet.
MALE SPEAKER: Whoa!
FEMALE SPEAKER: [INAUDIBLE].
FEMALE SPEAKER: Whoa!
The thing just collapsed on me.
Oh my God.
It's going to fall off.
So if I move, it's all over.
But then they kill this
beautiful lady.
Go, let's go.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Anyone
got matches?
FEMALE SPEAKER: This year's
theme was going green.
This is understandable
given Lagos's
critical pollution issues.
Energy efficient light bulb hats
and dresses made out of
leaves ere made to look
surprising elegant by the
gorgeous girls.
And the boy's helped out by
donning what looked to be
lederhosen made of hay.
One designer who stood out
was self-taught Dabo, who
specialized in pairing
recycled plastic and
traditional fabrics
with sexy results.
FEMALE SPEAKER: I love this.
Quite sexual.
Do people say to you,
oh my God, Dabo?
DABO: Yeah, Dabo [INAUDIBLE].
[LAUGHTER]
FEMALE SPEAKER: I'm trying it.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Look, they're
all going to laugh at us.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Whilst the
girls maintained a
professional front, the boys
just seemed to be having a
great time admiring their own
beauty and other attributes.
FEMALE SPEAKER: So the more
hard you work, the bigger
penis you have?
FEMALE SPEAKER: Guys are
more vain than girls.
MALE SPEAKER: Yeah.
FEMALE SPEAKER: I'll
give it to you.
FEMALE SPEAKER: If men wore
makeup in the street, what
would happen to them?
FEMALE SPEAKER: It wasn't just
social discrimination the gay
community had to worry about.
Homophobic sentiment
had recently been
enshrined in law.
FEMALE SPEAKER: We'd met Datari,
a fellow Englishman
backstage, former stylist to UK
boy bands such as Boyzone.
He'd come to Lagos to pursue
business opportunities.
However, the recent developments
meant he was
considering going
back to the UK.
DATARI: If you're really camp,
then trust me, you can't
survive in Nigeria.
Why do you think I wear shirts
and hats all the time?
I'm the butch, you
know what I me?
I wish I could train my voice.
Because that's, like,
a giveaway,
you know what I mean?
If you're gay, you either get
killed, or you go to prison,
you get disowned
by your family.
That's why most Nigerian celebs,
or Nigerian guys go
abroad to end up staying there
and claiming asylum.
Someone calls the police.
And all of you get humiliated,
put you on TV.
No only are you out
to the government.
You're out to your family,
to your friends.
I mean, you've lived a
lie all your life.
And then all of a sudden,
you're on TV for what?
For being gay.
Eventually, if you come out of
prison, you can't even go back
to your home town
anymore because
everyone knows about it.
[INAUDIBLE]
stoning you, calling
you names.
Trust me, you'll get caught.
FEMALE SPEAKER: After meeting
Datari and having him tell us
how the majority of gay people
in Niger have to conceal their
sexuality for fear of going to
prison, we started to wonder
how many other people at this
fashion event were hiding
their true identity.
BLESSED: Your face,
you make it ugly.
Yeah, you don't do it
with your fine face.
FEMALE SPEAKER: This is our
friend Blessed, the
hairdresser.
FEMALE SPEAKER: From the moment
we arrived, wherever we
went, Blessed went too.
To the extent that we could
barely talk to anyone else.
Off camera, he told us some
surprising things about the
gay community.
He invited us to come visit his
neighborhood so that he
could talk a bit more freely.
First, we met his mother
and his nephew.
And then he took us to some
of his friends' houses.
BLESSED: This is [INAUDIBLE]
apartment.
Yes.
FEMALE SPEAKER: After that, he
took us to the biggest street
market in Lagos.
BLESSED: We are in [INAUDIBLE]
Market.
FEMALE SPEAKER: This is one of
the most hectic, overcrowded
markets in the world, with
thousands of people passing
through it at all times.
And then, Blessed too us
somewhere he could confess a
few things about his
relationship
with the fashion world.
We're at a salon where
Blessed used to work.
And they're going
to do my nails,
because they need doing.
Why did you become
a hairdresser?
FEMALE SPEAKER: But you are
not gay, obviously.
BLESSED: Don't say it.
FEMALE SPEAKER: I
won't say it.
FEMALE SPEAKER: In the
fashion industry?
FEMALE SPEAKER: Lagos is a
deeply God-fearing city, with
the church having a firm hold
over the population.
Even some of the fashion
photographers haven't quite
reconciled their faith with the
decadent display of flesh
at the fashion week.
All the models were, like,
running around naked.
How did it feel?
Despite Justice's revelation
that we're all going to hell,
we return for the finale and
caught up with some fellow
sinners on the red carpet.
Including my favorite,
the stylish
queen mother of Nigeria.
FEMALE SPEAKER: I can tell.
FEMALE SPEAKER: And then, Mr.
Nigeria, Deji Bakare, who
describes himself as a
rapper and a singer.
FEMALE SPEAKER: [LAUGHS].
What I love the most about
Nigeria Fashion Week was how
the designers and models
celebrated
traditional African beauty.
There were no blonde hair
weaves, no plastic surgery,
limited influence by
Western design.
This was truly a celebration
of pure Nigerian beauty.
And backstage, it was
a celebration of
pure Nigerian chaos.
This guy is the winner of
Nigerian Big Brother 2011.
His arrival backstage caused
further chaos, with the
models, their friends and
hangers on all clamoring to
get a private audience
with their idol.
FEMALE SPEAKER: But because this
was the final show and so
much was at state, the head of
security was called to come
and eject him from backstage.
But instead, the security
guy let him off in
exchange for an autograph.
FEMALE SPEAKER: And here he
is thinking about it.
Hm, maybe in a minute.
Nah, I'll just get his autograph
and let him stay.
Despite the general madness,
Nigeria Fashion
Week ended on a high.
But just as we thought our
Nigerian fashion adventure was
over, we were invited to this.
Nigeria's Next Supermodel is
a tribute to Tyra Banks's
America's Next Top Model.
Although we're not really
sure if Tyra's ever
actually seen it.
It's run by Joan, former
Miss Nigeria.
JOAN: This is my house
here on the left.
And of course, the small
bungalow is where we do a lot
of our stuff for the girls.
FEMALE SPEAKER: And they've been
living there, have they?
JOAN: Yeah, yeah.
The girls have been here.
FEMALE SPEAKER: That's
[INAUDIBLE].
FEMALE SPEAKER: The dozen or
so finalists in the contest
had been living in her garage in
Lagos, undergoing a sort of
modeling boot camp.
Along with her nephew, David.
DAVID: Three, two,
one, let's go.
FEMALE SPEAKER: The finale of
Nigeria's Next Supermodel was
being help in a luxurious hotel
on the [INAUDIBLE] of
the lagoon.
Here we are.
We were here to witness
the dreams of one
young girl come true.
So already this is very
different from
Nigeria Fashion Week.
This is really kind of slick.
It's a bit swanky.
[INAUDIBLE].
FEMALE SPEAKER: The crowd
promptly arrived
dressed to be seen.
FEMALE SPEAKER: After four hours
of dress rehearsals,
yelling, people being kicked
out then let back in--
FEMALE SPEAKER: --the audience
were finally allowed to take
their seats.
FEMALE SPEAKER: They waited
another hour.
The models finally emerged,
only to exit the room
immediately.
We had no idea what
was going on.
But we figured it was best
to follow the talent.
Where are you going?
FEMALE SPEAKER: We were
in the venue.
The audience arrived all
in their glad rags.
The models walk out, pile
into this tiny van.
And now they're going
on a yacht.
I don't know what the audience
were thinking
about the whole thing.
Yeah, but we're all right.
We've got the models.
We've got them.
We're going into this weird
building, which looks like--
don't know.
It's a very unusual situation.
MR. PERFECT: One, two,
three, four.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Upon reaching
the docks, Mr. Perfect, the
choreographer, promptly engaged
the models in a kind
of military style marching
[INAUDIBLE], all whilst
wearing six inch heels.
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
FEMALE SPEAKER: How many times
have you rehearsed?
MR. PERFECT: Three times.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Just three?
MR. PERFECT: Yeah.
We'll make it.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
FEMALE SPEAKER: Out on the deck
of the yacht, looking
around at these wonderful
girls dancing under the
enormous African sky, all
worries we had about what the
hell was going on disappeared.
[CHEERING]
[SINGING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
FEMALE SPEAKER: Of all the
moments I've experienced on
this first season of Fashion
Week Internationale, from
blackouts and bomb shelters in
Islamabad, being eaten alive
by mosquitoes on a cattle truck
in Cambodia, and who can
forgetting witnessing live
ass surgery in Colombia?
I think that being there on
that yacht in Lagos was
something that will stay
with me forever.
And that's why I momentarily
lost control of my senses.
[SINGING]
Every night in my dreams--
FEMALE SPEAKERS (IN
UNISON): [SINGING]
I see you, I feel you.
That is how I know you go on.
All across the distance and
spaces between us, you
[INAUDIBLE]
to show you go on.
Near, far, wherever you are, I
will believe that my heart
will go on.
Once more, you open the door.
And you're here--
[AIR HORN]
FEMALE SPEAKERS (IN
UNISON): [SINGING]
My heart will go on and on.
[CHEERING]
FEMALE SPEAKER: After all that
time on the yacht, I'd almost
forgotten what we were there
for, until the contestants
sprung into action.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
FEMALE SPEAKER: Before the final
results were announced,
Joan's nephew David took to
the floor to performance a
song he'd prepared specially
for the occasion.
[APPLAUSE]
DAVID: [SINGING]
[INAUDIBLE] can't you see?
You were made to fly far
above the clouds.
You were made to fly.
JOAN: These three girls are
the ones that [INAUDIBLE].
[CHEERING]
JOAN: Second runner
up is [INAUDIBLE].
Ladies and gentlemen, the first
runner up, [INAUDIBLE]!
[CHEERING]
[MUSIC PLAYING]