BUT THAT IS OKAY. YOU ARE THINKING AND THAT
IS THE
MAIN POINT OF THE EXERCISE, IS TO GET THIS
CONE
BROUGHT INTO THE LAB.
TODAY'S LECTURE, WHAT I WANT TO DO IS TO
CONTINUE TO EXPLORE THE PRIMARY PLANT BODY
AND TALK
ABOUT THE CELLS AND THE TISSUES THAT MAKE
UP THE
PRIMARY PLANT BODY. MOST OF YOU THINK, GOSH,
THIS IS
REALLY GOING TO BE A DULL TOPIC BUT WHAT I
WANT TO SAY
AT THE OUTSET THAT MOST OF THE THESE CELLS
AND TISSUES
THAT WE TALK ABOUT TODAY, YOU HAVE, IF NOT
DAILY
CONTACT WITH MOST OF THESE YOU HAVE WEEKLY
CONTACT
WITH MOST OF THEM. AND SO, WHAT I WOULD LIKE
TO DO IS
SHOW YOU EXAMPLES THAT ARE RELEVANT TO YOUR
DAILY
LIVES AND AT THE SAME TIME INTRODUCE YOU TO
THE
DIFFERENT CELLS AND TISSUES THAT MAKE UP THE
PLANT
BODY. NOW, AFTER THE EMBRYO FORMS THE FORMATION
OF
NEW CELLS, AND TISSUES BECOMES RESTRICTED
TO THE
MERISTEMS. AFTER EMBRYO FORMATION NEW CELLS
OR NEW
CELL PRODUCTION, IS RESTRICTED MORE OR LESS
TO THE
MERISTEMS.
WE SAID LAST TIME THAT A MERISTEM WAS A ZONE
OF
HIGH CELL DIVISION ACTIVITY. MERISTEMS ARE
ZONES OF
HIGH CELL DIVISION ACTIVITY AND THAT THERE
WAS A SHOOT
MERISTEM AND A ROOT MERISTEM.
THESE CELLS, WHICH ARE ABLE TO DIVIDE, WHICH
WE
SAY ARE COMPRISING THE MERISTEM, BASICALLY
WE BELIEVE
COULD DIVIDE FOREVER. THEY, AS LONG AS THEY
ARE NOT
DAMAGED OR INFECTED BY SOME PATHOGEN, WE THINK
THESE
CELLS CAN DIVIDE FOREVER. FOR THOSE OF YOU
WHO ARE
FAMILIAR WITH THE TERM "STEM CELLS" THIS IS
STEM CELLS
IN THE ANIMAL SENSE, STEM CELLS. MANY PEOPLE
BELIEVE
THAT MERISTEM STEM CELLS ARE EQUIVALENT TO
ANIMAL STEM
CELLS. THAT IS, THEY HAVE THE CAPACITY TO
DIVIDE
LITERALLY FOREVER. NOW, THE ACTIVITY OF THE
MERISTEM
YIELDS CELLS WHICH WE SAID WERE PRIMARY.
THEY CAN TRACE THEIR ORIGIN
TO THE MERISTEMS.
THIS IS AN IMPORTANT POINT, CELLS WHICH CAN
TRACE THEIR ORIGINS TO THE MERISTEM ARE SAID
TO BE
PRIMARY. AND, THESE CELLS TOGETHER FORM THE
PRIMARY
PLANT BODY.
WE WILL TALK ABOUT THE PRIMARY PLANT BODY
TODAY.
MORE IMPORTANTLY, I WILL GIVE YOU AN EXAMPLE
OF
IT IN A MOMENT, MERISTEMS ARE RESPONSIBLE
FOR THE
CELLS WHICH YIELD ELONGATION OF THE PLANT
BODY.
LET ME GIVE YOU AN EXAMPLE OF WHAT I MEAN
BY
MERISTEM STEM CELLS ARE RESPONSIBLE FOR THE
CELLS THAT
LEAD TO THE ELONGATION OF THE PLANT BODY.
LET'S HAVE AN AXIS HERE. WE CAN START WITH
THIS
AXIS AND THIS WILL BE THE SHOOT APICAL MERISTEM
AT ONE
END, AND THIS WILL BE THE ROOT APICAL MERISTEM
AT THE
OTHER END.
AND FOR OUR DISCUSSION TODAY LET'S JUST PUT
A REFERENCE POINT HERE, WE WILL CALL THIS
A REFERENCE
POINT. LET'S SAY WE PUT A MARK OF INK ON THE
PLANT OR
TIED SOMETHING AROUND THIS PORTION OF THE
PLANT. NOW
WE WILL WAIT FOR SOME TIME, AND NEW CELLS
ARE GOING TO
BE PRODUCED AT THE SHOOT APICAL MERISTEM AND
THE ROOT
APICAL MERISTEM. THIS WILL BE BY MITOSIS.
IF WE
WAITED FOR SOME TIME WE WOULD FIND THAT THE
AXIS WAS
NOW LONGER.
HERE IS OUR REFERENCE POINT AGAIN, THE AXIS
IS
STILL LONGER.
AND IF WE WAITED FOR SOME MORE TIME, THE AXIS
WOULD BE EVEN LONGER WITH THE SHOOT APICAL
MERISTEM
HERE, THE ROOT APICAL MERISTEM HERE AND
OUR REFERENCE
POINT HERE.
THIS IS KNOWN AS ELONGATION GROWTH.
AND THIS ELONGATION GROWTH COMES ABOUT DUE
TO
THE ACTIVITIES OF CELLS THAT ARE PRODUCED
BY THE
APICAL MERISTEM AND THEN THEMSELVES ELONGATE.
SO,
WHEN A PLANT GROWS IN LENGTH, THAT IS A RESULT
OF
CELLS THAT HAVE BEEN PRODUCED AT THE TWO TIPS,
THE
APICAL MERISTEM AND THOSE CELLS THEMSELVES
ELONGATE TO
INCREASE THE LENGTH OF THE AXIS. THIS IS THE
PRIMARY
PLANT BODY AND IT IS IMPORTANT.
NOW, WHAT I WOULD LIKE TO DO IS TO BEGIN WITH
THE DISCUSSION OF THE VARIOUS CELL AND TISSUE
TYPES
WHICH MAKE UP THE PRIMARY PLANT BODY. AND
FOR OUR
DISCUSSION TODAY WE CAN DEFINE A TISSUE AS
ONE OR MORE
CELL TYPES DISTINGUISHED STRUCTURALLY OR FUNCTIONALLY
OR WITH BOTH CHARACTERISTICS.
I WOULD LIKE TO BEGIN OUR DISCUSSION WITH
THE
FIRST TISSUE TYPE; WHICH IS REALLY ONLY
A CELL.
AND THIS TISSUE TYPE IS CALLED PARENCHYMA.
THIS IS BELIEVED TO BE THE FIRST CELL TYPE
EVOLVED FROM WHICH ALL OF THE OTHER PLANT
CELLS WERE
DERIVED.
NOW, LET'S BEGIN WITH SOME CHARACTERISTICS
OF
PARENCHYMA CELLS. THE FIRST CHARACTERISTIC,
THIS IS
IMPORTANT ONE, YOU WILL SEE THIS SHORTLY WHY
SO IMPORTANT, IS THAT THEY ARE ALIVE WHEN
FUNCTIONAL.
SECOND CHARACTERISTIC OF THE MANY, BUT I WILL
CHOOSE 3 THAT ARE PROBABLY IMPORTANT FOR TODAY'S
TALK,
IS THAT THEY HAVE THIN WALLS. THIN WALLS.
AND THIRD
THAT THEY CAN BE STIMULATED TO DIVIDE.
AND THIS STIMULATION TO DIVIDE OFTEN INVOLVES
THEM IN REPAIRING WOUNDS.
SO, IF YOU CUT INTO A PLANT AND YOU MAKE A
WOUND
OR A CAR BACKS INTO A TREE AND MAKES A GAUGE
OR WOUND
PARENCHYMA CELLS STIMULATE AND DIVIDE AND
REPAIR THAT
WOUND. NOW LET'S DISCUSS SOME OF THE FUNCTIONS
OF THE
PARENCHYMA CELLS. THESE LIVING CELLS WITHIN
CELL
WALLS. FOR OUR PURPOSES THEY HAVE TWO MAIN
FUNCTIONS,
ALTHOUGH IN SPECIALIZED CASES THEY HAVE OTHER
FUNCTIONS. THOSE TWO FUNCTIONS ARE:
1. THEY FUNCTION IN PHOTOSYNTHESIS. THAT IS,
PHOTOSYNTHESIS OCCURS IN PARENCHYMA CELLS
AND SECONDLY
THEY FUNCTION IN STORAGE.
USUALLY THE COMPOUND WHICH
IS STORED INSIDE OF THEM IS STARCH.
MOST OF YOU HAVE HAD INTIMATE CONTACT OR
INTIMATE KNOWLEDGE OF PARENCHYMA CELLS IN
THE FORM OF
A POTATO. IF WE COULD PEEL THIS POTATO ALL
OF THE
CELLS THAT ARE INSIDE THE POTATO, ALL OF THE
STARCH-FILLED CELLS INSIDE OF THE POTATO ARE
PARENCHYMA CELLS. THE POTATO IS BASICALLY
MADE UP OF
SIMPLE THIN WALLED CELLS WHICH FUNCTION TO
STORE
STARCH. THIS IS THE FIRST CELL TYPE WHICH
WE BELIEVE
IS THE TYPE FROM WHICH ALL OF THE OTHER CELLS
IN THE
PRIMARY PLANT BODY ARE EVOLVED FROM. NOW
LET'S
CONSIDER THE SECOND CELL TYPE:
AGAIN, ONE IN WHICH MANY OF YOU HAVE HAD CONTACT
WITH WITHOUT REALIZING IT. IT IS CALLED COLLENCHYMA.
IT HAS ALL OF THE CHARACTERISTICS OF PARENCHYMA
CELLS,
THAT IT IS ALIVE. BUT IT HAS ONE STRUCTURAL
DIFFERENCE. IT HAS VARIOUSLY THICKENED WALLS.
VARIOUSLY THICKENED WALLS. AND AS A RESULT,
AND I WILL
SHOW YOU SOME PICTURES OF THESE THICK WALLS,
IT
FUNCTIONS IN SUPPORT.
EXAMPLES OF COLLENCHYMA CELLS THAT I BELIEVE
ALL
OF YOU ARE FAMILIAR WITH ARE FOUND IN CELERY.
IN
CELERY, THIS STRUCTURE THAT WE EAT IS PART
OF THE
LEAF, PART OF THE PETIOLE. THE LEAF HAS BEEN
CUT OFF.
WE DON'T EAT THE LEAF BUT THE COLLENCHYMA
CELLS ARE
WHAT GIVE THIS PETIOLE ITS SUPPORT BUT MAKE
IT RIGID
AND UPRIGHT. IF YOU BREAK A CELERY AND HAVE
THESE
STRANDS, STRINGS THAT YOU PULL OFF THESE STRINGS
ARE
COLLENCHYMA. THESE ARE THE ONES WHICH GIVE
THIS
PETIOLE ITS SUPPORT, GIVE IT ITS RIGIDITY.
COLLENCHYMA CAN OCCUR IN BUNDLES OR STRANDS
OR THEY
CAN OCCUR SEPARATELY. NOTICE THEY ARE AT THE
PERIPHERY TOWARD THE OUTSIDE OF THE CELERY.
IF YOU
WERE AN ENGINEER THAT IS WHERE YOU WOULD WANT
TO PLACE
YOUR SUPPORT, IF YOU WERE DESIGNING A BUILDING.
THIRD
CELL TYPE, WHICH I WANT TO CONSIDER, IS ALSO
DERIVED
FROM THE PARENCHYMA. BUT, IT REALLY CONSISTS
OF TWO
CELL TYPES WHICH MAKE IT UP AND SO I AM GOING
TO GIVE
YOU A GENERALIZED NAME AND THEN CONSIDER THE
TWO CELL
TYPES WHICH MAKE IT UP. IT IS CALLED SCLERENCHYMA.
SCLERENCHYMA DIFFERS FROM PARENCHYMA AND COLLENCHYMA
BY, THE GIVE-AWAY IS THIS NAME. THE WORD SCLERENCHYMA
COMES FROM THE GREEK WORD SKLIRA, WHICH MEANS
HARD.
SCLERENCHYMA CELLS HAVE IMBEDDED OR AS PART
OF THE
CELL WALL A HARD COMPOUND KNOWN AS LIGNIN,
KNOWN AS
LIGNIN. THIS GIVES THE WORDS SKLIRAS, AND
MAKES THE
CELLS HARD. THEY FUNCTION IN SUPPORT. WE
BELIEVE
ALSO IN PROTECTION. I WILL SHOW YOU THE, WHY
WE THINK
IT IS INVOLVED IN PROTECTION.
THERE ARE TWO DIFFERENT KINDS OF SCLERENCHYMA
CELLS, BOTH OF WHICH YOU ARE FAMILIAR WITH,
ALTHOUGH
PROBABLY THE NAME OF ONLY WHICH YOU WILL BE
FAMILIAR
WITH WHEN WE START THIS DISCUSSION. SCLERENCHYMA
COMES
IN TWO TYPES OF CELLS, THEY COME IN CELLS,
WHICH YOU
KNOW OF AS FIBERS. AND THE SECOND GROUP SCLEROID.
LET'S FIRST TALK ABOUT FIBERS. FIBERS ARE
ELONGATED
CELLS, ELONGATED CELLS WITH OVERLAPPING END
WALLS.
SO, YOU CAN PRETEND LIKE THIS IS A FIBER,
ONE FIBER.
AND HERE WOULD BE A SECOND FIBER AND HERE
WOULD BE THE
OVERLAPPING END WALLS. THEY TEND TO OCCUR
IN BUNDLES.
AN EXAMPLE OF A PRODUCT MADE FROM FIBERS THAT
MOST OF YOU AWARE OF IS ROPE. ROPE IS GRITTY
AND
TOUGH AND COARSE BECAUSE OF THE LIGNIN WHICH
IS
DEPOSITED IN THE FIBERS AND WHAT GIVES THE
ROPE ITS
STRENGTH ARE THE OVERLAPPING FIBER. NOW,
IN SOME
INSTANCES THE FIBERS DON'T BECOME LIGNIFIED,
THEY
DON'T GET LIGNIN DEPOSITED INTO THEM UNTIL
THE PLANT
GETS QUITE OLD. IN THAT PARTICULAR SITUATION
HUMANS
HAVE EXPLOITED THIS SITUATION FOR MILLENNIA
AND
ILLUSTRATED BY THIS PLANT HERE. THIS IS THE
PLANT
WHICH IS KNOWN AS THE LINUM PLANT. WHICH IS
WHERE
VERY FINE LINEN COMES FROM. IN LINUM LIGNIN
DEPOSITION IS DELAYED.
THIS RESULTS IN THE PRODUCTION OF SO-CALLED
SOFT
FIBERS. THEY AREN'T HARD AND COARSE LIKE YOU
WOULD
FIND IN THE ROPE.
THE FIBERS, AS I WILL SHOW YOU A PICTURE OF
AND
SOME OF YOU MAY HAVE ACTUALLY HAD EXPERIENCE
WITH THIS
OCCUR IN BUNDLES IN THIS LINUM PLANT. SINCE
EARLY
DAYS, SINCE BEFORE THE EGYPTIANS, THIS PLANT
WAS GROWN
AND THE FIBERS WERE COMBED OUT OF THIS PLANT
ON VERY
FINE TOOTH COMBS. THEY COME OUT IN BUNDLES
AND THEY
ARE USED TO MAKE FINE LINEN, LIKE HANDKERCHIEFS
AND
VERY FINE TABLE CLOTHS, SCARVES. THESE ARE
WHAT ARE
MADE OF FINE LINEN OR MADE FROM THE LINUM.
EVENTUALLY
THESE FIBERS WILL BECOME, HAVE LIGNIN IN THEM
BUT NOT
FOR A LONG TIME. NOT LIKE THE FIBERS THAT
MAKE THE
ROPE. NOW, HERE IS AN EXAMPLE WHERE FIBERS
ARE
ACTUALLY INVOLVED IN MAKING THE SHAPE OR SUPPORT
OF
A PARTICULAR, IN THIS CASE, IT IS A LOOFAH.
SOME OF
YOU KNOW WHAT LOOFAH SPONGES ARE. LOOFAH IS
A MEMBERS
OF THE SQUASH OR GOURD FAMILY WHAT IS DONE
IS THAT THE
ORGANIC MATERIAL WHICH CAN BE EASILY DIGESTED
OR
DEGRADED AWAY IS EITHER DEGRADED AWAY WITH
ACID OR BY
MICROBIAL ACTIVITIES, LEAVING BEHIND ESSENTIALLY
THE
STRUCTURE OF THE GOURD, WHICH IS ALL FIBERS.
THESE
FIBERS HAVE (INAUDIBLE) IN THEM FOR THOSE
OF YOU WHO
HAVE USED IT. AND ARE USED FOR WASHING YOURSELF
IN
THE BATHROOM. SO THIS PARTICULAR GOURD AND
MANY OTHER
FRUITS THAT WE WILL TALK ABOUT HAVE THEIR
SHAPE AS
A RESULT OF FIBERS. AND WHAT YOU ARE LOOKING
AT NOW
IS THE FIBER MESH NETWORK THAT GIVES THIS
GOURD ITS
SHAPE. SO THESE ARE FIBERS, COMMERCIALLY EXTREMELY
IMPORTANT THEY ARE USED BY US ON A DAILY BASIS.
SECOND GROUP OR TYPE OF CELLS WHICH MAKE UP
THE
SCLERENCHYMA IS LESS FAMILIAR TO MOST OF YOU,
BUT I
GUARANTEE MOST OF YOU HAVE USED THESE IN MANY
WAYS.
THESE ARE THE SCLEROIDS. THESE TEND TO FUNCTION
IN
PROTECTION. ALTHOUGH NOT ALWAYS. WE ARE NOT
QUITE SURE
SOMETIMES WHY THEY FUNCTION. THEY TEND TO
BE SHORT,
ROUND, SOMETIMES, AND SOMETIMES EVEN POINTED
CELLS.
SHORT, ROUND, POINTED CELLS.
THEY HAVE VERY THICK WALLS.
AND SOME EXAMPLES
OF WHERE SCLEROIDS ARE USED, ARE FOR EXAMPLE,
IN THE
SHELL OF WALNUTS. THE REASON THE SHELL IS
SO HARD IS
BECAUSE IT HAS SCLEROIDS OR THE CELLS WHICH
ARE PART
OF THE SHELL WALL HAVE SCLEROIDS IN THEM.
AND IT
MAKES THIS PROTECT THE DEVELOPING EMBRYO ON
THE
INSIDE.
SOME MORE COMMON USES OF SCLEROIDS THAT YOU
MAY
OF ARE IN PEARS. WHEN YOU EAT PEARS THE GRITTY
NATURE
OF THE PEAR IS THE RESULT OF SCLEROIDS. THESE
STONE
CELLS THAT ARE LOCATED IN THE PEAR AND GIVE
IT ITS
GRITTY TEXTURE. SOMETIMES THIS GRITTINESS
MAY TURN OUT
TO BE SOMETHING WE EXPECT. FOR EXAMPLE, FIG
NEWTONS,
WHEN YOU EAT FIG NEWTONS AND YOU GET A LITTLE
GRITTY
NATURE YOU ARE ACTUALLY CHOMPING ON SOME SCLEROID
THAT
ARE IN THE SEED OR THE FRUIT OF THE SMALL
FIG. AT ONE
TIME THEY DISCOVERED A FIG WHICH DIDN'T HAVE
SCLEROIDS
AND THEY TRIED TO MAKE FIG NEWTONS OUT OF
IT AND
PEOPLE WOULDN'T BUY IT. BECAUSE THEY EXPECTED
FIG
NEWTONS TO HAVE A GRITTY NATURE. NOW WHY HAVE
THESE
SCLEROIDS? WE THINK THAT THE SCLEROIDS WHAT
THEY
PROBABLY DO ARE USED TO RETARD INSECTS FROM,
NOT IN
THE CASE OF THE WALNUT, BUT IN THE CASE OF
THE FIG
NEWTON OR THE PEAR TO RETARD INSECTS FROM
EATING THESE
PARTICULAR FRUITS. YOU CAN IMAGINE IF YOU
WERE AN
INSECT AND YOU HAD MANDIBLES, IF YOU BIT INTO
SOMETHING LIKE THIS AND YOU ENCOUNTER ONE
OF THESE
STONE CELLS IS MIGHT RETARD YOU OR SLOW YOU
DOWN FROM
GETTING INTO THE FRUIT. WE THINK THEY HAVE
A FUNCTION
WITH REGARD TO THESE PARTICULAR TYPES OF PROTECTIVE
MECHANISMS.
LET ME SHOW YOU A FEW SLIDES, IF WE CAN GET
THIS
TO GO FOR US, A FEW SLIDES OF SOME OF THESE.
OKAY, FIRST SLIDE IS MEANT TO SHOW YOU, TO
REMIND YOU OF THE APICAL MERISTEM LOCATIONS
WHERE
PRIMARY GROWTH IS PRODUCED. EVERY BRANCH,
AXIS WHICH
GROWS IN LENGTH HAS APICAL MERISTEM AT ITS
TIP. ALL
OF THE ROOTS, WHICH ARE GROWING IN LENGTH,
THE MAIN
TIP OF THE ROOT, WHICH IS GROWING IN LENGTH.
ALL OF
THEM HAVE APICAL MERISTEM. AND THIS IS AN
IMPORTANT
POINT THAT YOU HAVE TO REALIZE. ALL THINGS
THAT GROW
IN LENGTH HAVE TO HAVE A APICAL MERISTEM.
HERE ARE
SOME PARENCHYMA CELLS NOW. NOTICE THAT THEY
ARE
RELATIVELY THIN-WALLED. THEY ARE ALIVE AND
APPEAR TO
BE EMPTY. HERE ARE PARENCHYMA CELLS WHICH
CONTAIN
STARCH. THEY ARE COMPLETELY PACKED WITH STARCH
AS YOU
FIND IN POTATO. THESE DARK, SORT OF STAINED
BODIES ARE
STARCH. NEXT SLIDE SHOWS YOU SOME COLLENCHYMA.
WE
ARE LOOKING DOWN ON A COLLENCHYMA CELL. IN
THESE
PARTICULAR COLLENCHYMA CELLS THEY PUT THICKENING
OF
THE CELL WALLS ONLY IN THE CORNERS, NOT IN
BETWEEN.
THIS IS AN INTERESTING EXAMPLE. HERE WE CAN
HAVE
SHEATHS OF COLLENCHYMA. THIS IS A STEM WHICH
HAS BEEN
CUT ACROSS AT SECTION AND HERE ARE SHEATHS
OF
COLLENCHYMA, WHICH I WILL SHOW YOU IN A HIGHER
POWER.
HERE YOU CAN SEE THICKENED CELL WALLS, AGAIN
AS YOU
WOULD FIND IN THE CELERY WHICH WE BELIEVE
PROVIDES
SUPPORT.
HERE ARE FIBER. THIS IS A CROSS SECTION, CUT
ACROSS THE STEM OF THIS PLANT WHICH IS UP
HERE IN
FRONT, THE LINUM PLANT. IT IS NOT NORMALLY
RED INSIDE.
THIS IS STAIN OR A DYE WHICH HAS BEEN PUT
ON, BUT I
WANT TO CALL YOUR ATTENTION TO THE BUNDLES
OF FIBERS
WHICH ARE LOCATED TOWARDS THE OUTSIDE. HUGE
NUMBER OF
FIBERS, IF WE LOOK AT THE FIBERS A LITTLE
HIGHER
POWERED HERE, YOU CAN SEE, THERE ARE TREMENDOUS
FIBERS, THEY HAVE A VERY SMALL INSIDE CYTOPLASM
AND
VERY THICK WALLS. IN THIS CASE THEY ARE SOFT
FIBERS.
HERE ARE SOME SCLEROIDS NOW, WHICH WE BELIEVE
FUNCTION
TO PROTECT PLANTS FROM INSECTS AND OTHER SMALL
ANIMALS. YOU CAN SEE THESE CELLS ARE, THEY
HAVE LOTS
OF POINTS ON THEM AND THESE POINTS WE THINK,
THIS IS A
CAMELLIA LEAF, THESE POINTS WE THINK ARE PROBABLY
WHAT
KEEPS ANIMALS FROM EATING IT. HERE IS A SCLEROID
FOUND IN A WATER PLANT, A WATER PLANT, THE
LEAF
PROBABLY TO RETARD ANIMALS IN THE WATER FROM
EATING
THE LEAF. HERE ARE THE SCLEROIDS THAT YOU
WOULD FIND
IN THE PIT OF A PEACH. IN THIS PARTICULAR
CASE, THE
PEACH PIT IS ESSENTIALLY ALL SCLEROIDS AND
IT IS
A VERY, DIFFICULT FOR US TO BITE INTO AND
OF COURSE IT
WOULD BE FOR AN ANIMAL AS WELL. THE SEED WOULD
BE
PROTECTED.
THESE ARE THEN THE FIRST GROUP OF CELLS, THE
PARENCHYMA, THE COLLENCHYMA AND THE SCLERENCHYMA.
THEY ARE MORE OR LESS SIMPLE CELL TYPES. NOW
WHAT I
WOULD LIKE TO DO IS BEGIN A DISCUSSION OF
OUR FIRST
TISSUE. OUR FIRST TISSUE. AND THIS TISSUE
CONSISTS
OF A LARGE NUMBER OF DIFFERENT CELL TYPES
AND THIS
FIRST TISSUE IS THE VASCULAR TISSUE. THE VASCULAR
TISSUE IS INVOLVED WITH TRANSPORT. INVOLVED
WITH
TRANSPORT. AND THE VASCULAR TISSUE CONSISTS
OF TWO
DIFFERENT CELL OR TISSUE TYPES, AND WE ARE
GOING TO
SPEND TIME FIRST CELL TYPE IS KNOWN AS XYLEM.
AND
THIS IS INVOLVED MAINLY WITH WATER TRANSPORT.
AND THE SECOND CELL TYPE IS PHLOEM. THIS IS
MAINLY INVOLVED WITH TRANSPORT OF NUTRIENTS.
LET'S BEGIN BY TALKING ABOUT THE XYLEM.
THE FIRST THING I WANT TO SAY, WHICH IS CENTRAL
TO OUR DISCUSSION OF HOW THE XYLEM WORKS,
IS THAT
THESE CELLS ARE DEAD WHEN FUNCTIONAL.
WE WILL EXPLORE THIS STATEMENT A LITTLE MORE
IN
A MOMENT.
THERE ARE TWO CELL TYPES WHICH ARE THE MAIN
TRANSPORT TYPES IN XYLEM AND I WANT TO GIVE
YOU THEIR
NAMES. THEY ARE KNOWN AS TRACHEIDS OR TRACHEARY
ELEMENTS. YOU WILL SEE IT REFERRED TO IN BOTH
WAYS IN
YOUR BOOK OR -- THE SECOND CELL TYPE IS KNOWN
AS
VESSEL ELEMENTS OR VESSEL MEMBERS.
NOW WHAT I WANT TO
SAY TO YOU ABOUT THESE TWO CELL TYPES, IN
GYMNOSPERMS
WE ONLY FIND TRACHEIDS.
WHEREAS, IN ANGIOSPERMS,
BOTH TRACHEIDS AND
VESSEL ELEMENTS ARE INVOLVED IN WATER TRANSPORT.
THIS IS PROBABLY AN EVOLUTIONARY CHANGE. WHEN
WE EVOLVED UP TO ANGIOSPERM WE DEVELOPED AN
ADDITIONAL
TYPE OF CELL FOR THE TRANSPORT OF WATER
AND THAT CELL
WAS THE VESSEL ELEMENT. LET'S LOOK FIRST AT
A
TRACHEID. A TRACHEID IS GENERALLY A THIN CELL.
A THIN CELL, TRACHEID, WITH OVERLAPPING END
WALLS.
THIS IS CONTRASTED WITH A VESSEL ELEMENT.
VESSEL ELEMENT, WHICH I WILL ABBREVIATE AS,
VE,
VESSEL ELEMENTS. VESSEL ELEMENTS ARE WIDE
AND SHORT
OR SHORTER. LET'S NOW DRAW A VESSEL ELEMENT.
HERE IS
ONE VESSEL ELEMENT, ONE VESSEL ELEMENT HERE.
NOW WATER TRANSPORT OCCURS BECAUSE VESSEL
ELEMENTS ARE CONNECTED TOGETHER.
SO, THIS IS ONE VESSEL ELEMENT. HERE WOULD
BE
A SECOND VESSEL ELEMENT AND HERE WOULD BE
A THIRD
VESSEL ELEMENT.
3 VESSEL ELEMENT CELLS CONNECTED TOGETHER.
THIS WHOLE STRUCTURE IS CALLED A VESSEL.
WHOLE STRUCTURE IS CALLED A VESSEL. HOW DOES
A VESSEL ELEMENT FORM AND WHERE DO WE GET
THE VESSEL
TO FORM FROM? BASICALLY, IT STARTS OUT WITH
INDIVIDUAL LIVING XYLEM.
INDIVIDUAL LIVING XYLEM. AND THEN WE HAVE
A TERM THAT MOST OF YOU HAVE HEARD ABOUT BEFORE,
WE
HAVE PROGRAM CELL DEATH.
ALL OF THE CYTOPLASM
DISAPPEARS IN THE CELLS AND THE END WALLS
DISSOLVE TO
MAKE THIS VESSEL.
SO BASICALLY, YOU HAVE A TUBE, YOU HAVE A
PIPE,
A WHOLE PIPE RUNNING THROUGH OR SERIES OF
PIPES
RUNNING THROUGH THE PLANT AND YOU ACTUALLY
CAN TAKE
A STEM OF A PLANT, WHICH HAS LOTS OF VESSELS,
FOR
THOSE OF YOU SITTING UP HERE IN THE FRONT,
I WILL BLOW
INTO THIS END AND MY BREATH WILL TRAVEL DOWN
THROUGH
THE EMPTY VESSELS, WHICH ARE DEAD, AND YOU
SHOULD BE
ABLE TO SEE BUBBLES EMERGE FROM THE BASE THERE.
FOR THOSE OF YOU WHO ARE THERE. YOU COULD
USE
IT AS A STRAW BUT YOU WOULDN'T BE ABLE TO
SEE IT. SO,
THIS IS A VESSEL. AND VESSELS CONDUCT WATER
AND THEY
ARE DEAD WHEN FUNCTIONAL. A VERY IMPORTANT
POINT.
THE
OTHER CELL TYPE, WHICH MAKES UP THE VASCULAR
TISSUE,
NAMELY THE PHLOEM. THE PHLOEM, THE PHLOEM
CONSISTS OF
A CELL TYPE NOT LIKE THE TRACHEID VESSEL,
BUT IS A
DIFFERENT CELL TYPE. THE PHLOEM CELL TYPE
TRANSPORTING NUTRIENTS IS CALLED A SIEVE ELEMENT.
WHICH WE WILL ABBREVIATE, SE.
NOW WHAT IS A SIEVE ELEMENT AND WHERE DID
WE GET
THIS NAME FROM?
LIKE THE VESSEL ELEMENTS, THE SIEVE ELEMENTS
ARE
CONNECTED IN A ROW.
EACH OF THESE IS A SIEVE ELEMENT.
WHERE DOES THE NAME SIEVE COME FROM? I WOULD
LIKE ALL OF YOU TO WATCH WHAT I AM GOING TO
DO HERE
BECAUSE THIS WILL EXPLAIN TO YOU. IF WE PRETENDED
LIKE THIS ERASER WAS ONE OF THESE SIEVE ELEMENTS,
LIKE
SO I AM GOING TO TAKE THIS ERASER AND TURN
IT SO YOU
CAN LOOK AT THIS END WALL OF THE SIEVE ELEMENT.
IF
YOU COULD LOOK AT THIS END WALL, THAT IS,
THESE WALLS
HERE, AND ON, YOU WOULD FIND A ROUND PLATE
WITH PORES
IN IT.
THIS IS CALLED THE SIEVE PLATE. IT LOOKS LIKE
A SIEVE. THIS IS THE BASIS FOR THE NAME SIEVE
ELEMENTS.
HOW DOES THIS SIEVE ELEMENT FORM?
WELL THE VERY FIRST THING WE HAVE TO SAY IS
UNLIKE THE XYLEM, WHICH IS DEAD WHEN FUNCTIONAL,
THE
PHLOEM IS ALIVE WHEN FUNCTIONAL. ALIVE WHEN
FUNCTIONAL.
THIS CREATES SOME PROBLEMS. IF THESE CELLS
ARE
ALIVE WHEN FUNCTIONAL THAT MEANS THEY HAVE
CYTOPLASM
AND NUCLEUS AND ALL THEIR ORGANELLES, HOW
WILL THEY BE
ABLE TO TRANSPORT LOTS OF NUTRIENTS FROM ONE
END OF
THE PLANT TO THE OTHER? WOULDN'T THAT GET
ALL MIXED
UP WITH THE CYTOPLASM. WOULDN'T THE CYTOPLASM
KIND OF
CLOG IT UP AND PREVENT VERY EFFICIENT TRANSPORT?
IN
ORDER TO APPRECIATE HOW THE SIEVE ELEMENT
WORKS, EVEN
THOUGH IT IS STILL ALIVE, I WANT TO TALK TO
YOU ABOUT
ITS ORIGIN, AND YOU WILL GET A FEELING FOR
THAT. HERE
IS THE SIEVE ELEMENT, MOTHER CELL. WITH TIME,
AND IT
HAS A NUCLEUS IN IT, WITH TIME, WE GET A DIVISION
OF
THE SIEVE ELEMENT MOTHER CELL.
BUT, IT IS NOT AN EQUAL DIVISION. IT IS UNEQUAL
DIVISION. A DIVISION. AND THEN WE HAVE A NUCLEUS
HERE, TOO.
THESE TWO CELLS ARE GIVEN SPECIAL NAMES. THIS
IS CALLED THE COMPANION CELL. THIS WILL BE
THE NEW
SIEVE ELEMENT.
BUT SOMETHING HAPPENS BECAUSE WE TALKED ABOUT
THE PROBLEM OF HAVING IT CLOGGED UP. SOMETHING
HAPPENED. IN THE FORMATION OF THE SIEVE ELEMENT,
WHAT
WE HAVE HAPPENING IS THAT THE NUCLEUS NOW
OF THE SIEVE
ELEMENT AND OTHER ORGANELLES BEGIN TO DEGENERATE.
SO
WITH TIME WE GET DEGENERATION OF THE SIEVE
ELEMENT
ULTRA STRUCTURE, SIEVE ELEMENT ORGANELLES.
SO, WE WIND UP WITH TWO CELLS, THE COMPANION
CELL AND THE SIEVE ELEMENT NOW. HERE IS THE
COMPANION
CELL, AND HERE IS THE SIEVE ELEMENT. AND ITS
NUCLEUS
IS GONE. MOST OF ITS ORGANELLES ARE GONE.
BUT IT IS
STILL ALIVE.
NOW, HOW CAN SOMETHING STAY ALIVE IF IT DOESN'T
HAVE A NUCLEUS TO CODE FOR NEW PROTEINS TO
REPAIR OR
CODE FOR OTHER PROTEINS TO WORK ON THE FUNCTION?
THIS IS WHERE THE REAL KIND OF REMARKABLE
LESSON COMES
IN. THOSE ACTIVITIES WHICH NO LONGER CAN BE
CODED FOR
BUT WHICH ARE NECESSARY FOR THE SIEVE ELEMENT
CELL TO
REMAIN ALIVE, THOSE ACTIVITIES ARE TAKEN OVER
BY THE
NUCLEUS OF THE COMPANION CELL. THE COMPANION
CELL
ENCODES FOR MANY OF THE ACTIVITIES THAT WOULD
HAVE
GONE ON IN THE NUCLEUS OF THE SIEVE ELEMENT.
WHEN THE
COMPANION CELL DIES, THE SIEVE ELEMENT DIES
AS WELL.
LET ME NOW SHOW YOU SOME PICTURES OF THE VARIOUS
CELL TYPES WHICH MAKE UP THE VASCULAR TISSUE.
WE WILL
BEGIN WITH THE XYLEM AND I WANT TO AGAIN SHOW
YOU THE
XYLEM CONSISTS OF, IN THIS PARTICULAR CASE,
TRACHEIDS,
WHICH WE SAID ARE ELONGATED CELLS, RELATIVELY
NARROW
AS COMPARED TO VESSEL ELEMENTS OR VESSEL MEMBERS
WHICH
ARE SHORTER CELLS, RELATIVELY WIDER. POINT
WHICH I
DIDN'T MAKE BUT YOU CAN SEE IN THE PICTURES
IS THAT
END WALL OF THE VESSEL ELEMENT IS OPEN. THE
VESSEL
ELEMENT IS OPEN. THERE IS NO OPENING ON THE
TRACHEID
ELEMENTS BUT COMMUNICATION OCCURS THROUGH
SMALLER
HOLES WHICH ARE KNOWN AS PITS. IF WE LOOK
AT HOW
VESSEL FORMS, AGAIN WE HAVE A LIVING SERIES
OF XYLEM
CELLS WHICH IN TIME ELONGATE AND THEN THE
NUCLEUS AND
CYTOPLASM UNDERGO PROGRAM CELL DEATH AND THE
END WALL
BEGINS TO DISSOLVE AWAY BEFORE THE CELL COMPLETELY
DIED UNTIL WE PRODUCE THIS TUBE, THIS TUBE
WHICH
REPRESENTS THE VESSEL.
THE NEXT SLIDE WILL SHOW YOU SCANNING
ELECTROMICROGRAPH PICTURE OF A POINT WHERE
TWO VESSEL
ELEMENTS ARE MEETING. THIS WOULD BE THE POINT
WHERE
THE TWO MEET AND IT IS AN OPEN PORE WHICH
ALLOWS WATER
TO MOVE AT VERY HIGH VELOCITIES THROUGH THE
VESSEL.
HERE IS A VESSEL ELEMENT, WHICH HAS BEEN DISSECTED
OUT, YOU CAN SEE IT HAS ROUND AND THIS WOULD
BE THE
OPENING IN ITS WALLS. THERE ALSO CAN BE COMMUNICATION
BETWEEN TRACHEIDS AND VESSEL ELEMENTS THROUGH
SIDEWALLS, THROUGH PITS, WHICH WE DIDN'T TALK
ABOUT.
NOW, HERE IS A SIEVE ELEMENT AND A COMPANION
CELL
SHOWN ON ELECTROMICROGRAPH. FIRST THING TO
POINT OUT
IS THAT THIS IS THE SIEVE ELEMENT AND THE
SIEVE PLATE
IS LOCATED HERE, HERE IS ANOTHER SIEVE ELEMENT
HERE.
SO, WHEN WE HAVE A GROUP OF SIEVE ELEMENTS
ALL HOOKED
UP TOGETHER WE CALL THIS A SIEVE TUBE. A SIEVE
TUBE.
WHEN ALL SIEVE ELEMENTS ARE HOOKED UP TOGETHER.
NOW
WHAT I WANT YOU TO NOTICE FROM THIS ONE IS
THERE IS
DENSELY CYTOPLASMIC CELL NEXT TO IT. THIS
IS THE
COMPANION CELL. NOTICE RELATIVE TO COMPANION
THE CELL,
WHICH HAS HIGH LEVELS OF CYTOPLASM, THAT THE
SIEVE
TUBE MEMBER IS RELATIVELY EMPTY, AS FAR AS
HAVING
CONTENTS, BUT IT IS STILL ALIVE. IT STILL
HAS ITS
MEMBRANES. NOW IF WE PUT OUR EYE AT THIS END
AND LOOK
AT THE SIEVE PLATE, WE SEE THE SIEVE PLATE
HERE. THIS
IS WHAT YOU WOULD LOOK AT. THERE WOULD BE
ONE SIEVE
ELEMENT GOING INTO THE AUDIENCE AND ANOTHER
ONE BEHIND
THE BOARD. AND I WANTED TO SHOW YOU A SIEVE
UNDER
ELECTRON MICROSCOPE. THIS MAY NOT BE A TRUE
PICTURE,
BUT THERE ARE PORES, THESE ARE THE DIFFERENT
PORES IN
THE SIEVE PLATE. JUST TO SHOW YOU THE SERIES
IN THE
PRODUCTION OF THE SIEVE ELEMENT, WHICH MAKES
SIEVE
TUBE. HERE IS A MATURE SIEVE TUBE WHERE WE
HAVE THE
SIEVE PLATES OF THE INDIVIDUAL SIEVE ELEMENTS.
HERE
WOULD BE COMPANION CELL NEXT TO THE SIEVE
ELEMENT. IF
WE FOLLOW ITS PRODUCTION WE START OUT WITH
A MOTHER
CELL WHICH UNDERGOES AN ASYMMETRIC DIVISION,
AND THAT
ASYMMETRIC DIVISION, IN THIS CASE, RESULTS
IN
COMPANION CELL AND A CELL WHICH WILL BECOME
THE
SIEVE-TWO MEMBER. ITS NUCLEUS WILL BEGIN TO
DEGRADE
AND MOST OF THE CYTOPLASM WILL BEGIN TO DEGRADE
AND
SOMETIMES THE COMPANION CELLS DIVIDE AGAIN.
BUT THE
POINT IS, THAT THERE IS NO LONGER ANY NUCLEUS
IN THE
SIEVE-TWO, BUT IT IS STILL ALIVE.
THESE ARE THE ELEMENT WHICH MAKE UP THE VASCULAR
TISSUE. FINALLY, BEFORE I LEAVE TALKING ABOUT
THE
CELL TYPES OF THE PRIMARY PLANT BODY, I WANT
TO
INTRODUCE YOU TO THE LAST CELL TYPE. AGAIN
WHICH MOST
OF YOU HAVE HAD CONTACT WITH. THAT LAST CELL
TYPE WE
WANT TO TALK ABOUT IS THE EPIDERMIS. THE EPIDERMIS
IS
OUTER-MOST LAYER OF THE PLANT.
OF THE PRIMARY PLANT BODY.
AS A CONSEQUENCE, IT'S THE FIRST LAYER TO
ENCOUNTER ALL THE DIFFICULTIES WITH THE EXTERNAL
ENVIRONMENT; POLLUTION, ATTACK BY DISEASE,
ATTACK BY
ANIMALS, THESE ARE ALL ENVIRONMENTAL INSULTS
THAT THE
EPIDERMIS ENCOUNTERS FIRST. EPIDERMAL CELLS
ARE
DIFFERENT FROM ALL OTHER CELLS IN THE PLANT,
BECAUSE
THEY ARE NOT SURROUNDED ON ALL SIDES BY CELLS.
ONLY
ON THEIR SIDE AND BOTTOM ARE THEY SURROUNDED
BY THE
CELLS. BUT, ON ONE SURFACE THEY ARE COMPLETELY
EXPOSED TO THE OUTSIDE. SO THEY DIFFER FROM
OTHER
CELLS IN THE PLANT. NOW, BECAUSE THEY REPRESENT
THE
LAYER OF PROTECTION FOR THE PLANT
THEY DEVELOPED
A NUMBER OF CHARACTERISTICS WHICH ALLOW THEM
TO RESIST
THE ENVIRONMENTAL INSULTS WHICH ALLOW THEM
TO RETARD
SOME INSECT AND ANIMAL ATTACKS AND ALSO PERDATION
BY
VARIOUS DISEASES. THE FIRST WAY IN WHICH EPIDERMAL
CELLS RESIST IN ALLOWING PATHOGENS OR POLLUTANTS
TO
ENTER INTO THE PLANT IS THAT THE CELLS OF
THE
EPIDERMIS ARE VERY TIGHTLY JOINED TO EACH
OTHER.
SO IF YOU COULD LOOK AT AN EPIDERMAL CELL,
IT
ALMOST LOOKS LIKE A PUZZLE. WHERE YOU WOULD
HAVE
CELLS THAT ARE VERY TIGHTLY JOINED SO THAT
THERE ARE
NO SPACES BETWEEN THE CELLS. SO THEY HAVE
TIGHT
JUNCTIONS. THE SECOND WAY IN WHICH EPIDERMAL
CELLS
OFFER PROTECTION IS ILLUSTRATED BY THIS APPLE.
THIS APPLE HAS AN EPIDERMIS ON IT AND THOSE
OF
YOU WHO HAD TEACHERS WHO YOU WERE TRYING TO
IMPRESS
WHEN YOU WERE KIDS YOU USED TO BRING AN APPLE,
PERHAPS
INTO THE TEACHER. BEFORE YOU BROUGHT IT IN
YOU RUBBED
IT AGAINST YOUR SHIRT. THE APPLE BECAME SHINY.
THE
REASON THE APPLE BECAME SHINY IS BECAUSE THERE
ARE
WAXES SECRETED TO THE OUTSIDE. SO, THE EPIDERMIS
ALSO
SECRETES WAXES.
THESE WAXES MAKE UP A LAYER OR A THICK LAYER
IN
SOME CASES KNOWN AS THE CUTICLE.
THE CUTICLE.
WHAT DOES THE CUTICLE DO? IT PREVENTS WATER
LOSS. PREVENTS WATER LOSS FROM THE INSIDE.
SO, YOU HAVE A LAYER OF WAX SURROUNDING THAT
APPLE AND PRESUMABLY THAT APPLE WILL LAST
A LOT
LONGER, BE AVAILABLE A LOT LONGER FOR SOME
ANIMAL TO
DISPERSE THIS FRUIT, BUT IT WILL BE ATTRACTED
TO THIS
FRUIT BECAUSE IT STILL RETAINS ITS TASTE AND
ITS
FLAVOR BECAUSE OF THE CUTICLE. ALL PLANT PARTS,
NOT
THE ROOT SYSTEM, BUT ALL ABOVE GROUND PARTS
GENERALLY
HAVE SOME CUTICLE, SOME WAX SECRETED ON THE
OUTSIDE TO
RETARD WATER LOSS. NOW, LET'S PRETEND LIKE
THIS
BLACKBOARD IS A LEAF. YOU ARE LOOKING DOWN
AT THIS
LEAF. IT IS COVERED WITH CUTICLE. THE PROBLEM
THAT
YOU ALL KNOW ABOUT IS THAT THE LEAF IS ALSO
THE SITE
OF PHOTOSYNTHESIS. AS A RESULT OF PHOTOSYNTHESIS,
WE
ARE GOING TO HAVE TO BE ABLE TO GET CO2 INTO
A LEAF.
HOW DO WE GET CO2 INTO A LEAF, WHICH IS COVERED
BY
A CUTICLE, WHICH IS COVERED BY A LAYER, WHICH
PREVENTS
OR SLOWS DOWN THE MOVEMENT OF GASSES AND WATER?
SO
IF THIS WERE A LEAF, THE WAY THE LEAF DEALS
WITH THIS
PROBLEM, IS IT MAKES PORES. MAKES PORES.
AND THESE PORES ARE GIVEN A NAME WHICH ARE
KNOWN
AS STOMA.
MAKES PORES OR STOMA.
AND THROUGH THESE PORES CO2 CAN GO IN. THIS
IS
A LEAF WE ARE LOOKING ON, A LEAF SURFACE.
IT MAKES
PORES OR HOLES IN THE CUTICLE. THROUGH THESE
PORES
CO2 CAN GO IN. THERE IS A PROBLEM BECAUSE
AT THE SAME
TIME CO2 GOES IN THE THING THAT THE CUTICLE
IS TRYING
TO PREVENT IS ALSO HAPPENING. WATER IS GOING
OUT.
WATER IS GOING OUT.
SO HOW DOES THE PLANT DEAL WITH THIS SITUATION
THAT IT WANTS CO2 BUT IT DOESN'T WANT TO LOSE
WATER?
THIS IS AN IMPORTANT CELL TYPE WHICH DEVELOPS
IN THE
EPIDERMIS. THIS PARTICULAR PORE, WE WILL MAKE
ANOTHER
ONE OVER HERE, THIS PARTICULAR PORE, DEVELOPS
AROUND
IT, SPECIAL CELLS. WHICH ARE KNOWN AS GUARD
CELLS.
THESE GUARD CELLS CONTROL THE SIZE OF THE
PORE.
WE WILL TALK MORE ABOUT HOW THE GUARD CELLS
WORK LATER
ON. BUT, I WANT YOU TO APPRECIATE THAT THEY
ARE PART
OF THE EPIDERMIS. SO, WE HAVE TWO GUARD CELLS,
WE
HAVE THE PORE, AND TOGETHER THIS WHOLE STRUCTURE
IS
CALLED VARIOUS THINGS BUT THE SIMPLE NAME
A STOMATA. S-T-O-M-A-T-A, STOMATA. OR STOMATA
COMPLEX, DEPENDS ON HOW YOUR BOOK REFERS TO
IT. THESE
ARE MODIFICATIONS OF EPIDERMAL CELL. YOU HAD
A
QUESTION? IS THE CUTICLE A NON-LIVING LAYER?
A VERY
GOOD POINT. THE CUTICLE IS NOT LIVING. IT
IS SECRETED
BY THE LIVING CELLS OF THE EPIDERMIS CELLS
BUT IT IS
NOT LIVING. GOOD QUESTION. FINALLY, WHAT I
WANT TO
MENTION IS, BESIDES MODIFYING THE EPIDERMIS
TO HAVING
A CUTICLE AND HAVING THESE PORES, THERE ARE
A COUPLE
OF OTHER MODIFICATIONS OF THE EPIDERMIS. AND
AGAIN,
THESE ARE USUALLY MEANT TO PROTECT THE PLANT.
ONE
MODIFICATION THAT MANY OF YOU ARE AWARE OF
IS THAT
PLANT SURFACES ARE FREQUENTLY COVERED WITH
HAIRS OR
DIFFERENT TYPES OF THINGS WHICH GROW UP FROM
THE
SURFACE. THESE HAIRS ARE KNOWN AS TRICHOMES.
THEY ARE EPIDERMAL OUT-GROWTHS.
THEY ARE USUALLY INVOLVED IN PROTECTION. FOR
EXAMPLE, IF A LEAF IS COVERED WITH A SLIGHT
LAYER OF
HAIR THIS MAY ELEVATE AN APHID OR AN INSECT
WHICH MAY
WANTED TO COME IN AND ATTACK THE LEAF. IT
COULDN'T GET
DOWN TO THE LEAF SURFACE BECAUSE IT WAS HELD
AWAY BY
THE HAIRS.
HERE IS AN EXAMPLE OF EPIDERMAL HAIR THAT
MANY
OF YOU ARE FAMILIAR WITH, COTTON. COTTON REPRESENTS
EPIDERMAL HAIR WHICH GROWS OUT OF THE SEED
COAT.
EPIDERMAL HAIR GROWING OUT OF THE SEED COAT.
WHY
WOULD COTTON PRODUCE THESE HAIRS. ONE IDEA
IS THIS
MAKES SEED ATTRACTIVE TO ANIMALS TO USE FOR
THEIR
NESTS. AND AS A RESULT, THEY DISPERSE SEEDS
AS
A RESULT OF COLLECTING THE COTTON AND LINING
THEIR
NESTS AND LATER ON THE SEEDS GET A CHANCE
TO
GERMINATE.
HERE IS AN EPIDERMAL HAIR WHICH WE AS HUMANS
HAVE EXPLOITED GREATLY. OTHER REASON WHY PLANT
PRODUCE
EPIDERMAL HAIRS IS OFTEN TO REFLECT LIGHT.
LIGHT CAN
BE VERY DAMAGING TO PLANTS AND AS A RESULT
THE
PRODUCTION OF EPIDERMAL HAIRS CAN CAUSE THE
LIGHT TO
BE REFLECTED AWAY. AND I WILL SHOW YOU A PICTURE
OF
THIS IN A MOMENT. FINALLY, EPIDERMAL HAIRS
ON THE
SHOOT SYSTEM ARE EASILY FOUND BY MOST OF YOU.
IF YOU
HAVE EVER TAKEN A GERANIUM AND RUN YOUR HAND
AND
CRUSHED THE LEAF VERY SLIGHTLY, YOU WILL HAVE
A SMELL,
YOU CAN LEAVE THE LIGHTS ON FOR A FEW MINUTES,
YOU
WILL HAVE A SMELL ON THE LEAF, AND THAT SMELL
COMES
ACROSS ON TO YOUR FINGERS. THAT IS BECAUSE
OF
EPIDERMAL GLAND CELLS.
I WILL SHOW YOU A PICTURE OF THAT IN A MOMENT.
FINALLY, THE LAST MODIFICATION OF THE EPIDERMIS
THAT I WANT TO POINT OUT TO YOU IS NOT FOUND
IN THE
SHOOT SYSTEM, BUT IN THE ROOT SYSTEM.
AND THIS IS THE, LET'S PRETEND THIS IS THE
EPIDERMIS OF THE ROOT. THIS IS THE ROOT EPIDERMIS.
SOME ROOT EPIDERMAL CELLS WE WILL FIND DEVELOP
OUT-GROWTH. WHICH IS KNOWN AS A ROOT HAIR.
THIS ACTS
TO INCREASE WATER AND NUTRIENT UPTAKE BY THE
ROOT
BECAUSE IT PROVIDES AN INCREASE SURFACE AREA
FOR
TAKING UP WATER AND NUTRIENTS. SO, THE ROOT
HAIR IS
ALSO EPIDERMAL OUT-GROWTH OR EPIDERMAL MODIFICATION
WHICH COMES FROM THE OUT-GROWTH OF AN EPIDERMAL
CELL.
AGAIN, PROBABLY IT WOULD NOT THE EFFICIENT
FOR ROOTS
TO HAVE A CUTICLE IN THEM BECAUSE THEY FUNCTION
IN
WATER UPTAKE. OKAY, WE CAN DO THE SLIDES NOW.
FIRST
SLIDE I WANT TO SHOW YOU IS OF THE CUTICLE.
SECTION
OF A LEAF AND I WANT TO POINT OUT TO YOU EPIDERMIS
AND
ALSO POINT OUT TO YOU THE CUTICLE. HERE IS
THE
EPIDERMIS, THESE SMALL CELLS HERE. AND THESE
ARE
PARENCHYMA CELLS UNDERNEATH. AND HERE YOU
CAN SEE
THIS LAYER OF WAX, LAYER OF CUTICLE WHICH
IS
A NON-LIVING LAYER SECRETED BY THE UNDERLYING
EPIDERMAL CELLS. WE ARE LOOKING DOWN ON THE
SURFACE
OF A LEAF. PRETEND LIKE THIS WAS THE BLACKBOARD.
HERE
YOU CAN SEE THE VERY TIGHTLY JOINED EPIDERMAL
CELLS
BUT OCCASIONALLY SOME OF EPIDERMAL CELLS ARE
ASSOCIATED WITH THE STOMATA COMPLEX.
HERE IS THE PORE THAT WE TALKED ABOUT BEFORE.
HERE ARE THE TWO GUARD CELLS, WHICH CONTROL
THE SIZE
OF THE PORE. ANOTHER, MAYBE A CLOSER LARGER
EXAMPLE OF
THE GUARD CELL. AGAIN THE PORE AND THESE TWO
GUARD
CELLS AND OTHER REGULAR EPIDERMAL CELLS SURROUNDING
IT. THIS IS A SCANNING ELECTROMICROSCOPE PICTURE
OF
AN EPIDERMAL CELL, OF A STOMATA COMPLEX CELL
AND HERE
YOU CAN SEE THE PORE AND THE TWO GUARD CELLS
ON EITHER
SIDE, WHICH FUNCTION TO DETERMINE THE SIZE
OF THE
OPENING. LAST FEW SLIDES I WANT TO SHOW YOU
ARE CELLS
THAT ALL OF YOU HAVE USED BEFORE. THESE ARE
CELLS
WHICH ARE GLANDULAR HAIRS. THEY SECRETE A
MATERIALS.
THEY ALSO, BY HAVING SHARP POINTS ON THEM,
CAN ACT TO
INJECT TOXINS INTO ANIMALS THAT MIGHT COME
AND FEED ON
THE PLANT. SO, SOME OF THE HAIRS THAT YOU
GET ON YOUR
HAND WHEN YOU TOUCH A PLANT ARE ACTUALLY CONTAINING
TOXINS FROM THE EPIDERMIS. HERE IS GLANDULAR
HAIR
WITH THE SOLUTION ON THE TOP. HERE IS ANOTHER
ONE. WE
HAVE BROKEN OFF THE TIP OF THE GLAND AND NOW
THE
SOLUTION IS COMING OUT. THIS MAY BE TOXIC
AND
FRAGRANT IN SOME WAY. HERE IS COTTON. AGAIN,
COTTON
REPRESENTS OUT-GROWTH OF HAIRS FROM THE EPIDERMIS
OF
THE SEED COAT AND HERE IS A PICTURE OF THE
VERY
BEGINNING, HERE IS THE EPIDERMIS OF THE SEED.
THE
SEED WOULD BE DOWN HERE. AND HERE ARE THE
EPIDERMAL
HAIRS GROWING OUT AND THEY GET TO BE VERY
LONG. THEY
ARE JUST A SINGLE CELL. AND FINALLY, THIS
LAST SLIDE
IS KIND OF AN INTERESTING SLIDE I WANTED TO
SHOW YOU.
THIS SLIDE IS TAKEN IN THE ANDES ABOUT 15,000
FEET IN
ELEVATION. AND AT THAT ELEVATION LIGHT IS
EXTREMELY
BRIGHT AND CAN BE EXTREMELY DAMAGING TO
THE
PHOTOSYNTHETIC APPARATUS. THIS IS A MAN OBVIOUSLY
STANDING HERE AND THIS IS A CACTUS. THIS CACTUS
IS
COVERED ITSELF WITH EPIDERMAL HAIRS, WITH
EPIDERMAL
OUT-GROWTH TO REFLECT THE LIGHT AND ALSO TO
SLOW DOWN
THE LOSS OF WATER IN THIS VERY DRY ENVIRONMENT.
OKAY,
WE WILL CONTINUE TALKING ABOUT THE BODY NEXT
WEEK.