I think the best party I've ever
been to is a party that I
had that happened just by
chance, and it was probably
the luckiest day of my life.
I get a call from the head of
Victoria's Secret, and he
says, "We've never had a party
in Los Angeles, and we'd like
you to host a party for
Victoria's Secret at your
home."
And I said, "Well, what do you
mean by that?" And he goes,
"We will bring 25 supermodels
to your home, Victoria's
Secret models." I said, "Are
you joking?" He said, "No,
we're serious."
I go, "Who can I invite?" He
goes, "Whoever you want." I
said, "Well, I'm not inviting
many people." And I literally,
I think, invited 10 guys.
I have a disco in my house that
was built in the '70s.
25 supermodels and 10
guys in my house.
Three of the 10 guys ended up
marrying three of the girls.
Adriana Lima married the
basketball player.
Charlie Sheen happened to marry
the one girl that wasn't
a Victoria's Secret model--
happened to come with my
ex-girlfriend.
And the third girl, Orlando
Bloom married.
Three people at one party--
and there was only 10 guys
there, and 25 girls.
That has never happened.
It was the best party
I've ever been to.