Hot spots, buzzing with the energy
of millions of people.
For the first time in human history,
more of us live in cities
than in the country.
But these are cities
on a different scale.
In just 50 years,
we've seen the birth, the growth
and now the dominance
of the megacity.
Sprawling, seething, noisy,
polluted,
crammed with 10 million, 15,
sometimes even 30 million people.
These cities are complicated,
fragile places,
constantly on the edge.
These are places
of overcrowded squalor.
But these are also the most exciting
places on the earth.
Brim with optimism and fun
and energy.
Hey!
HE GRUNTS
Love them or loathe them,
fear them or embrace them,
the megacities are the human future
of the planet.
We have, at the last count,
created 21 of these
extraordinary urban sprawls.
Pulsing and beating entities,
giant organisms in their own right.
And these cities
and our experience of them
is shaped by how
we move around them.
Total chaos!
I would call it anarchy,
but that would be extremely unfair
on anarchists.
In this film, I'm going to be asking
how our megacities can survive
without having
a colossal heart attack.
Motorways, the freeways,
the railways below us
are the veins and the arteries.
But all round the world,
these arteries are getting
clogged up and congested.
They're gobbling ever more
resources...
That's some cow!
..and dumping grotesque amounts
of waste.
So, how does the metropolis
deal with all the stuff
its people don't want?
Solid fat!
Now I want to wipe my nose
but, on the whole, I think I won't.
And what length do people go to
to stop the modern metropolis
from drowning in its own excess?
It's unimaginable,
what he's just lowered himself into.
Why are our great cities
where they are
and why are they the shape they are?
All around the world,
you see the same pattern.
Coastlines and river mouths.
And there's no mystery
in why the great cities love to
dangle their feet in the water.
Because throughout history,
sea lanes and rivers
were the original superhighways
and even today, it's transport -
that basic need to get in and out -
that shapes and stretches
and sometimes even strangles
the cities of the world.
How to move millions of people
around a megacity 24 hours a day,
without bringing the place
to a shuddering halt
and without literally
choking its citizens to death,
is one of the major challenges
we will face in the 21st century.
I'm starting this journey
in one of the poorest,
most chaotic and overcrowded cities
of them all -
Dhaka in Bangladesh.
There's simply no money for fancy
subways or slick freeways here.
And with a population of 13 million,
and rising, to shunt around,
Dhaka is feeling the squeeze.
People still have to move around.
Whatever it takes.
And it's hot, intense
and rather dangerous.
Every great city depends entirely
on its transport system.
But if there's one choke point
all round the world,
it's the morning rush hour,
when millions upon millions
of people
struggle to get to their jobs
and, seemingly, will do
almost anything to make it in.
The megacities are the most
extreme example of this,
and the poorer ones
the most extreme of the extreme.
There are so many people trying
to move around this dense city
that it feels like there isn't
a rush hour, because the entire day
is one massive rush hour.
A rush day.
With just two train lines
to serve a population
the same size as London's,
and only one major highway,
the result is predictable mayhem.
So, how can you get around a city
of 13 million people effectively?
Actually, it's using one of the most
primitive modes of modern transport,
pedal power.
Because Dhaka is
the rickshaw capital of the world.
Noisy, stinking, slow
and extremely dangerous.
CAR HORNS BEEP
But for most people around the world
this is the reality
of urban transport,
not some dinky high-speed train.
There are well over half a million
rickshaws in downtown Dhaka,
that's roughly one
for every 20 people.
Hardly surprising, then,
that 80 percent
of all male newcomers to Dhaka
start out as one of these
human taxis.
They work ten hours a day,
seven days a week,
pulling some seriously heavy loads.
And so, as a new arrival, I think it
only right I should have a go.
Now, I'm a keen cyclist in London,
so how hard can this really be?
MAN SPEAKS BENGALI
TRANSLATION: It isn't the traffic.
He's saying it's difficult to ride
in a...
Straight line? Yeah. Yeah.
What are the most important rules
of the street?
TRANSLATOR SPEAKS BENGALI
The brake is the most important
thing. The brake's the most
important thing, OK.
Is it as easy as riding a bike?
THEY CHATTER IN BENGALI
I think that means it's not as easy
as riding a bike!
Here I go.
HE LAUGHS
Hey!
HE GRUNTS
CHILDREN CHEER
Apparently, there are 600,000
of these in the city.
And I'm beginning to get a sense
of how much human horsepower
it takes to move Dhaka around.
I'm supposed to keep to the left,
but it's so crowded here
I'm being forced
into the middle of the road.
And with a cab on the back,
it's difficult to judge exactly how
tight a gap I can squeeze through.
Oh, my God! Oh, I'm sorry.
Oh, I'm sorry.
What you soon realise is, you can
never get up a good head of steam.
You're constantly
stopping and starting.
And it's far harder and much more
exhausting than it looks.
That was both great fun
and really, really hard work.
More difficult than it seems.
I had a great time doing it
for about 20 minutes,
but I think that's about my lot.
These guys do it for, what,
ten hours at a time or more?
It's astonishing.
They're said to be
as fit as Olympic athletes
and I have to say,
I can well believe it.
Thank you. OK. Thanks, guys.
But Dhaka's reliance on rickshaws
means more than simply
back-breaking labour
for tens of thousands
of its citizens.
It also affects
the shape of the city.
Because if your only means
of getting around is by rickshaw,
then you are restricted to
travelling fairly short distances.
Which means, in turn,
that Dhaka is one of the most
densely-populated metropolises
in the world.
If you look at the map of any
old city and see how it grows,
you can see that it expands
in concentric rings
as the transport gets better.
From horses to bicycles,
to cars and trams
and trains and metro,
the bigger the rings,
the more effective the transport.
There's one very simple truth...
The better the transport,
the bigger the city can grow.
And today's megacities
have taken that simple truth
and pushed it
to the absolute extreme.
London. One of the planet's
first great metropolises.
With a population of 13 million,
including all its surrounding areas,
this city was built not on roads
but on steel.
In the early 19th Century,
London was 30 times smaller
than it is today.
With only horsepower
to move its people around,
it simply couldn't get any bigger.
And then a revolutionary new form
of transport started to reshape
this great metropolis
and all of Britain's
other big cities.
The oldest megacities, like London,
were only ever able to gobble up
the land around them
thanks to whizzy new technologies
like the train.
As the tendrils of train and tram
networks spread out from the centre,
the suburbs followed
and the population mushroomed.
And just when it looked as if
the train companies
couldn't demolish any more houses
to build any more lines,
they had another bright idea -
to go under the houses instead.
From the opening of the first
underground station in 1863,
in just 40 years, the population
trebled to six million.
London's roots would become
criss-crossed by a web of tunnels,
transporting more than
2.5 million people every day.
It was revolutionary.
And in the 150 years or so
since then,
the London Underground
has hugely expanded
and been rebuilt and patched up
and grown and copied.
But everything has its limits.
The number of people you
can squeeze through these tubes
has now reached its maximum.
It's a bit as if you were given
one pair of trousers for life
at the age of 12.
You get bigger and bigger
and, first of all, the trousers
start to squeeze a little bit
and then it's a really painful
squeeze.
Well, this wonderful piece
of world-breaking technology
has now become
London's painful squeeze.
That is the problem
with these arteries of megacities.
Very easily,
they become crammed and sclerotic
and they're on the edge of collapse
again.
The men who built
the London Underground
thought they had their city sorted.
Nothing lasts forever.
Success sucks in many more people
until it starts to feel
like failure.
That doesn't stop people
on the other side of the world
trying just the same thing,
though bigger and faster
than London.
This is the Shanghai Metro.
20 years ago, Shanghai didn't have
an underground at all.
Now it boasts the largest one
in the world,
and they've built it
at an awesome speed.
TRANSLATION: The total soil
excavated after completion
of the networks
will be around 22 million tonnes,
including all the soil that needs
to be dug out of the stations.
22 million tonnes!
I'm very proud of what we've done.
In the last few years, we've managed
to complete the same length of lines
that it's taken 100 years
for foreigners to build.
It's a great method of transport.
I'm sure London's engineers were
just as confident all that time ago.
But the Chinese Government
haven't stopped with a mere subway.
They've spent well over
a billion pounds
on a revolutionary new
overground train system
known as the Maglev.
These trains, built in Germany,
have no wheels.
Using magnetic levitation,
they literally float along the track
at extraordinary speeds.
We're doing 380 kilometres an hour.
385. 388. 390.
400 kilometres an hour.
425, six, seven.
431. We're now doing more than
431 kilometres an hour.
I think that's about
270 miles an hour.
This thing is flying.
It makes a British InterCity train
look like a horse and cart.
And just as the tubes
reshaped London,
it's thought that
these super-fast services
will reshape this entire area
of China.
It's too soon to say
how Maglev trains
might reshape China,
but experts are already talking
about giant urban areas
of perhaps 100 million people each.
This is how futuristic transport
can entirely reshape
the way we think now about cities.
Then again, I'm not so sure.
People's dreams
of futuristic freedom
rarely pan out
the way that's expected,
and there's no clearer example
of that
than what's become
the true curse of the megacity
the world over -
the humble car.
And the people of Shanghai
are in love with that.
In China, just 25 years ago,
private cars were banned.
Now they're joining the roads
of Shanghai alone
at the rate of 1,000 every day.
And China has become
the largest car market in the world.
Meet Shanghai citizens,
Wenbing Wu and his wife Jee Chen.
They've come to the BYD,
or Build Your Dream,
car showroom in Shanghai
to take a look at a new motor.
This would be the first vehicle
that they, or any of their family,
have ever owned.
As far as I'm concerned,
they have no idea of what
they're letting themselves in for.
TRANSLATION: We had to save
every month. We've been saving up
for a really long time.
Wenbing and Jee are typical
of the megacity-dwelling Chinese.
The thing about cars,
is that they are just so appealing.
Who would want to sit
on a sweaty subway
or cram into a crowded bus
when you can cruise
in air-conditioned comfort?
For many of us,
commuting by public transport
is such a gruelling experience
that getting a private car
is a tempting alternative.
But this is about more
than just getting from A to B.
It's about status.
Now, in a place like Shanghai,
having a shiny new car of your own
shows that you have made it.
For this couple,
it's clearly cost them a lot,
but they seem convinced that their
new car's going to be worth it.
Now we've managed to get a car,
all of my family
are really happy about it.
It's like you've realised
what you've been dreaming about
for so long.
So all of us are really happy.
If only we could take them by the
hand and lead them to the streets
of...
Mexico City, say.
For this really is a city
built on tarmac.
Here there are almost
20 million people
and nearly five million cars.
Traffic here is so heavy
that commuters can spend six hours a
day, a third of their waking lives,
sitting in their cars
just trying to get to work.
This is transport
not just shaping the megacity,
it's in danger of killing it.
The motorways, the freeways,
the railways below us
are the veins and the arteries
of any city.
We're in Mexico City, one of the
most congested places on the planet.
These arteries are getting
clogged up and congested.
And we know what happens
if you get too much of that.
You get an urban heart attack.
Mexico City's traffic cops
are fighting a war,
and they are not winning.
I'm with the police helicopter pilot
Captain Oscar Cardenta
to get a whirlybird's-eye-view
of the morning commute.
Just 7:30am.
Already jams are forming down below,
and they stretch as far
as we can see.
Right now,
we're going to be coming up on, uh,
on Periferico, which is usually
very busy at this time of day.
Mexico City's Periferico
is the city's major ring road.
If anything goes wrong here,
the police know it will spawn
rush-hour hell.
How can you help from the air?
I have a traffic specialist
and he's giving orders
to the people on the ground
to detour the traffic,
control the flow.
It isn't long before
Oscar spots trouble.
Something's slowing down
the traffic on a critical flyover.
Left unchecked, this could spell
gridlock, so he's straight onto it
and a team of motorbike
traffic police are despatched.
They're going to need to act quickly
because any hold-ups can degenerate
into city-wide chaos.
This time, it just turns out to be
a broken-down car.
The young couple driving it
have simply run out of petrol.
No hanging around for the AA here.
So dire is the congestion,
that in Mexico City
the police have learned
to improvise.
Unconventional, but it works.
So if we're all going to live
in the megacity, and it rather
looks like most of us will,
are we all condemned to a future
of choking jams
and sweat-packed tube trains?
No, I think that maybe
we don't want to turn our backs
on our low-tech past.
Maybe Dhaka and its half a million
cycle rickshaws
does have something to teach us.
Across the globe
and London is gearing up
for a three-speed revolution.
To get real change in the city,
you need two things.
You need pent-up demand
on the streets
and you need proper leadership.
When the two come together,
change can happen very, very fast.
A good example would be
the London bicycle scheme.
When this got going...
..a lot of people said,
"It's not going to work,"
and within the first ten weeks
there were a million journeys made.
# I seen you riding around
The streets at night
# On your bicycle #
There's no single magic bullet
that's going to solve the megacity
transport crisis.
We have to snaffle ideas
from all over the place,
taking smaller, smarter solutions
which, when you take them together,
can have an impact.
London's first large-scale
public bike-hire scheme
is part of that potential mix.
In the economy of the great cities,
they're always learning and copying
and stealing from each other.
And it's not just
from the hi-tech cities.
So Dhaka in Bangladesh
may be a nightmare,
but it's a nightmare
run on pedal power
and that's something that
modern cities are re-learning.
And so to have a transport system
that really works
you need everything.
You need the taxis and the cars
and the buses.
You need the trains
and you need bicycles
and, of course, decent places
to be able to walk safely, as well.
It's a bit like fusion food,
you know, that we eat all the time.
You bring in all sorts of lessons,
all sorts of flavours
and you mix them up
and with a bit of luck
and leadership,
you get a city that's moving again.
This is an example of how the
megacity can function at its best.
A bit of technological innovation,
some risk,
fingers crossed, and openness
to what's worked elsewhere.
And what goes for transport
goes for what is transported,
as well.
And not just people.
Moving all of those commuters
around,
that's just one layer
of the amazing web of activity.
Because these people
need to be clothed and fed
and kept warm and watered,
and that means
that the megacity's routes
stretch far beyond
the ordinary city boundaries,
to far-off generators
providing the electricity
or distant mountain reservoirs
providing the piped water.
But the greatest appetite is,
of course, for food.
The megacities are monstrous hungry.
24 hours a day, seven days a week,
they suck in an astonishing array
of food.
Flown, shipped and driven in
from all round the world,
and we expect it served how,
when and where we want it.
London is no exception. It's one
very hungry and thirsty megacity.
Every year, London eats
seven million tonnes of food
and downs 94 million litres
of bottled water alone.
London's total food footprint
is 125 times its size.
In other words, it requires
the equivalent of the entire
productive land of mainland Britain
to feed London.
Such is the megacity's demand
for fresh food,
we're forced to grow it
on an increasingly industrial scale.
Even the humble lettuce
gets the treatment.
This farm produces over
60 million lettuces every year.
And to do that, it takes a
well-drilled small army of pickers.
Plants get lifted, and then
creeping just behind is a machine
with yet more workers
bagging and packing.
Within another 24 to 48 hours,
they'll have been
whisked down a motorway,
unloaded, sorted, packed,
loaded up again,
and now they're in your fridge
perhaps.
Or they might end up here,
in one of the strangest supermarkets
I've ever been to.
It is supersized.
It looks like an ordinary
supermarket, but it plainly isn't.
The aisles are too big, the trolleys
in those aisles are too big
and the people doing the picking
are all dressed in uniforms.
Because the food that
they're choosing, they're not
going to take home and eat.
They're not going to wash with
the shampoo that they're selecting
or drink the drinks
they're taking off the shelves.
They are buying for online shoppers
and they're being told what to pick
and how to pick it by a computer.
So right now,
to help feed the megacity,
welcome to the mega supermarket.
The shelves of this unique
London Tesco online store
groan with 22,500 items,
spread over the equivalent
of three football pitches.
There are no bright and shiny signs
enticing you to buy here,
just series of numbers and codes
guiding the pickers.
When we pick,
we have to pick by location.
OK. So pick by location first...
It's the numbers of the aisles
you're looking for? Yes.
So you're looking for 61. Yeah.
D2. Right.
Almond milk. Almond?
That's the one. That's the one.
That's the one.
Sharon and her fellow workers
end up picking a total
of 1,800 orders every day.
That's like shopping
600,000 times for groceries a year.
Quite a lot,
it's a battle with the clock
to juggle up to six separate
customer orders at one go.
They've all booked
their delivery slots.
And how quick do you have to be
normally, when you're not surrounded
by people like me?
Erm, we've got a time bar
at the bottom
that tells us
how quickly we're going.
At the moment, it's red and...
You're not going fast enough? No.
I'm well out of time.
So they're possibly waiting for me,
but...
So there's a specific van
waiting for you? Yeah.
Being ordered around by a computer
might make this a seemingly
alienating job,
but I'm reassured there is
a personal touch, however small.
So, what happens if
you get to your number
and what they want isn't there?
We have to put a substitution in.
I mean, like, I've substituted
this morning, erm, red wine.
They wanted Cabernet Sauvignon.
Yeah. I substituted it with Shiraz.
Right. Shiraz is better anyway!
The megacity says,
"Make it bigger, do it faster."
These people are presumably
shopping online
because their own lives
are so stressed and under the cosh,
they haven't got time to shop
for themselves.
The result is that they produce
a whole other group of people
who are also rushing around,
shopping against the clock.
But it's a curious business.
What you choose to put in your mouth
or put down your throat
or clean yourself with,
these are intimate decisions
and we rely
if not on the kindness of strangers
then the choice of strangers.
The honesty of strangers.
The hard work of strangers.
Of course, all this consumption
inevitably has a consequence.
Our modern megacities spew out
huge quantities of waste.
Every year, London throws away
20 million tonnes of the stuff.
Trying to cope
with just some of the deluge
is causing a massive strain
for megacities.
An astonishing 40,000 miles
of sewers
lurk beneath Greater London.
Uncoiled and laid end-to-end,
they'd stretch twice
around the world.
But the original sewer system,
a Victorian labyrinth of 450 miles
of interconnecting tunnels,
still serves the city above.
And just like that other Victorian
innovation, the London Underground,
the sewers are struggling to cope.
The arteries of the megacity
are clogging up.
I came into television to start with
because I was looking for glamour.
HE LAUGHS
Now you've got it!
'Rob Smith's one of 39 flushers
'who maintain Central London's
sewer network, and they do it
the old-fashioned way - by hand.'
Are you ready to go then?
Ready to go. Come this way.
Here we go.
Here it is.
It smells exactly as you expect.
I don't have to describe it.
The Victorian sewer system
was built when London
was a mere toddler of a megacity,
home to only 2.5 million people.
150 years later,
it has to deal with the end product
of at least ten million.
The biggest headache for Rob
and the small army of flushers
is not just what
all those millions eat,
but what it's cooked in, too.
Wow.
HE CHUCKLES
Yeah. So, that's fat? That's fat.
Where does it come from?
About a couple of miles up
in that direction.
We've got Leicester Square,
Trafalgar Square.
So, is this fat from restaurants
and kebab shops and so on?
Exactly. Yeah.
Yeah, that's where it comes from.
So when we talk about, you know, you
eat too much fat, too many burgers
and chips,
your arteries get furred up...
Same with the sewers.
This is London's arteries getting
furred up with fat. That's right.
It's astonishing
and very, very disgusting, as well!
I suppose we'd better go
and take a closer look.
I think we ought to
now we're down here.
WATER GUSHES
That is truly foul.
Really hard. That's old fat, that.
Oh, right. We'll go back up the top.
Back up again? Yeah.
There we go. That's the product
of our fast-food burger-eating,
chip-eating, kebab-eating lifestyle.
Solid fat.
Choking up the sewers
underneath London.
Now I want to wipe my nose
but, on the whole,
I think I won't.
Across the globe, the consequences
of the waste crisis in Mexico City
are on an epic and al fresco scale
compared to London's sewers.
This is what's known
as the Grand Canal.
No gondolas, no palazzos
and no tourists either.
It's a hundred-mile-long open sewer,
designed to transport waste water
to the central sewage works.
I fear it is time for me
to experience sewer cleaning
on an altogether different level.
I'm told that at this moment,
clever people
are working on a form of television
that you can actually smell.
And all I can say is, be very glad
they haven't got there yet!
The reek here is unbelievable.
These canals were designed
100 years ago
to handle the run-off
from Mexico City's rainy season.
But their history
has been overtaken.
The modern mania
for casually throwing things away
reaches its inevitable consequence
here.
Clogged and festering, almost
everything gets tossed in here.
And the truth is, we are becalmed
on a sea of plastic,
dead dogs - there's one just there -
and much worse.
I am, quite literally,
up a certain creek
with a paddle,
which is doing me no good.
I won't give you the statistics
about how much excrement the average
human produces each year,
you don't want to know,
except that it's lots,
or as the scientists would say,
lots and lots.
And so a city the size of this one,
with nearly 20 million people,
produces the equivalent
of an Olympic swimming pool-full
of excrement every minute,
and something has to happen to it.
But blockages can't be got rid of
from the relative safety of a boat,
or with a spade,
as in London's ancient sewers.
This calls for someone
with a diver's license, a cool head
and a very strong stomach.
When it comes to unclogging,
Ricardo Vazquez is the go-to guy.
Is it dangerous,
what you're doing now?
HE SPEAKS SPANISH
TRANSLATION: It's dangerous because
of all the pollution in the water.
Also because of the glass and nails.
Is there anything
you wish you hadn't found?
Dead bodies.
Two or three every year.
I hope you have a good day today.
I hope it's not too bad.
I should say that Health and Safety
have insisted
that I can't go down there.
And I think, for the first time
in my life, I'm thinking,
"Go Health and Safety!"
Once he's submerged,
the only contact Ricardo
will have with the outside world
is via a radio in his suit.
His suit is the only thing between
him and the highly toxic broth.
That's one of the most bizarre
things I've ever seen. I mean...
It's unimaginable,
what he's just lowered himself into.
With glass, nails, sewage
and maybe even the odd
decomposing animal to contend with,
it's a risky operation.
Ricardo now has to dive
to the bottom of the tank
and clear out the filters.
Down there, I'm told
it's completely pitch black.
So you can't see anything at all.
What you know is that horrible
things are blocking up the system.
And if they're allowed
to keep blocking it up,
the entire sewage system
starts to malfunction.
There's a metre of just solid trash
at this bottom of this, as well,
so there's no ground, if you like.
After five minutes,
a radio message comes from the deep.
He's found a tree.
While still submerged,
working by touch alone,
Ricardo sets about
dislodging the offending tree.
I can't think of somebody
who is more useful
to the people of Mexico City
than the man who's just gone
down there.
Blockage dealt with,
Ricardo's winched out for a shower
and a strong dose of disinfectant.
The size of the megacity
food-and-waste footprint
threatens the future of the planet.
But the metropolis has always been
a great engine for innovation
and radical change.
And the solutions aren't all
top-down or about civil engineering.
They can start off deceptively small
and simple.
Cooking oil.
In every city in the world,
this stuff is as common
as cigarette butts and beer cans.
It's everywhere.
Megacities produce millions
of gallons of it all the time
and it's normally seen as a problem.
You've seen what happens
when you stick it down drains
and that is not pretty.
But imagine if it was, in fact,
liquid gold.
An answer to transport problems.
It's a pretty weird idea,
but often, salvation...
is in the detail.
This restaurant has signed up
to a pioneering scheme
that takes all their waste oil,
which would simply get poured away,
adding to London's sewer blockages,
and transforms it
into something useful.
And it's all thanks to this man.
Every day, Nigel Jewison and his
team do their restaurant round,
picking up drums of dirty, used oil.
But the HQ for Operation Cooking Oil
is here,
down in the heart of old London.
Crammed in among
the grimy railway arches,
this mini refinery is a magnet
for London's cabbies.
Hundreds of them queue here
every week to get their fill.
You can see the lovely quality
of that oil. That's, er...
And this is how we like it.
Classy restaurant, classy oil.
That's not always the case, though.
There's a few restaurants I won't
eat at, even with their good names,
after seeing their waste oil.
So this is a very straightforward
filtration system.
Dirty oil becomes less dirty oil,
sits in these tanks
and becomes clean-ish oil,
and then, eventually, clean oil.
At which point, it can be made
into fuel for the taxis.
Hiya, Pete. How's it going?
Busy on the streets?
It's OK. It could be better!
It always can. Always better.
Hello there. Hiya.
Have you been doing it for a while,
using the biodiesel?
Is it good for you,
as a taxi driver? Fantastic. Why?
It's cheaper, for a start.
It's cleaner. Yeah.
With the new legislation coming on
the older cabs, it could be a way
to get us to last a bit longer.
Do you notice the lack of
black smoke and smells?
Definitely. But because it smells
of fish and chips,
you're always hungry!
If you go to classier restaurants,
it would smell of garlic and
all sorts of stuff. Garlicky cabs.
One of my dreams when I first
started up, when people started
talking about smells,
was that, if I could collect
all the Chinese restaurants, on
another round, Indian restaurants,
we could open up a filling station
with Chinese-smelling fuel,
Indian-smelling fuel.
So you could choose your
nationality of fuel!
It'd be brilliant, wouldn't it?
But it's good news for you guys.
I think it's very good. It's a shame
they can't put it in buses. Yes.
Coming to the amount of cooking oil
in the city centre, around London,
how widespread could this be
in fuelling taxis, fuelling cars?
If we can collect all the oil
in London, we could probably fuel
all the taxis,
which would be a fantastic thing.
Amazing. It would be.
If a great city like London had to
rely on the elected politicians
and the planners for its solutions,
I think it would be
a much less interesting
and more constipated sort of place.
Very often, the big ideas are found
in the little nooks
and side streets of the city.
And the job of the politicians
is to get hold of those ideas
and, using their taxes
and their rules,
to ensure that they then spread
and seed much more widely.
Putting old cooking oil to good use
is one thing,
but what about all the other stuff
we chuck away without a thought?
Well, that ends up here,
in a landfill site.
London is near to the bottom of
the European cities landfill league,
only recycling about 25 percent
of its waste.
And it's running out of space
to dump its growing, growling
mountains of rubbish.
The truth is that we in the West
throw away far too much.
I do. You probably do, as well.
And when we think about it,
we may feel a bit guilty.
And increasingly,
we're being kind of mildly bullied
by councils and government
to throw away less.
But when you come
to a place like this,
you realise why.
Perhaps we do have to learn
from those parts of the world
where they recycle everything
they possibly can.
In Dhaka, it isn't a case
of recycling with a conscience.
This is the extreme end
and it's driven by necessity.
Here, entire communities
are completely reliant
on salvaging the scraps,
the megacity's leftovers,
to carve out some kind of living.
It's sort of like when a large
animal is killed in the jungle
and the carcass
is picked completely.
And this is an urban version
of the same thing.
Rather than microbes
doing the picking, it's little boys.
Dhaka's main rubbish dump
is the size of a small town,
and a town with its own people.
Here, anything that can be
melted down or reshaped and reused
is bagged up
and carted off to be resold.
And when I say anything,
I really do mean anything.
What are you looking for?
TRANSLATOR SPEAKS BENGALI
Plates, cartons, bottles. Plastic...
Plastic. I can understand that.
And what does she do with them
when she's got them?
SHE SPEAKS BENGALI
TRANSLATION:
Takes it to the shops and sell it.
Everything there
is scrunched and dirty.
These are not bottles
that could ordinarily be recycled.
This is absolutely
the leavings of the leavings,
the scraps of the scraps,
the final pickings
after everybody else
further up the food chain
has taken what's worth something.
Here, even the insidious plastic
shopping bag is given another life,
melted down and recycled.
In a sort of most unpleasant way,
I suppose,
poverty is very efficient.
Everything is used.
This might seem like
a rather hardcore solution
to the waste problem
of the metropolis,
but perhaps the Dhaka necessity
for re-use and recycling
has lessons for us at home.
The longer all of us live in the
city, the more disconnected we get.
More of our food is processed
and pre-packaged.
It arrives in cartons
and little plastic boxes.
And instead of being sure
about when something has gone off
and it's no longer acceptable,
we rely on those rather timid
sell-by dates.
"If in doubt, chuck it out."
Which is a wasteful way of living
and of eating.
Dinner with Simon and Fran,
another pair
of metropolis innovators.
They call themselves freegans.
There's bread here.
That's 1.30 for that.
1.30 that'd cost in the shop.
It's good bakery bread.
Nothing wrong with that at all.
Large whites.
Can you find a date on there?
The 16th. That's yesterday.
Bread doesn't just go off overnight.
What are these? Diet Pepsi.
I'll just pass them to you.
There's a lot of it.
You'll be belching for a week! Yeah!
It makes me feel gaseous
and horrible!
Just look at this!
Twice a week for the past two years,
Simon and Fran
have sifted through the skips
of the back of London's high-street
stores and they've yet to go hungry.
Apart from the fact that
it's good news for you,
does it make you angry?
It does. Because of the waste.
Because there's people in the world
who are starving, and we have an
abundance and we throw it away.
What's that? Hold on a minute.
What have you got? Ha-ha!
Chocolates. Chocolate. OK.
Not bad.
Why would that be thrown away?
I have no idea. What's the...?
February.
Chocolates don't just go off.
'I don't generally make a habit
of routing through rubbish bins,
and it does feel a little odd.
'Legally speaking, however,
what's thrown away is fair game.'
And so to the getaway vehicle!
THEY LAUGH
What's the range of stuff
that you're picking up?
Meats. A lot of meat that we find.
Yeah. Cheese. Milk.
Yoghurts. Yoghurts.
What would you say to people who
say, "It's past its best-by date?"
Use your common sense
and have a look at it.
Best-by date, obviously it's saying,
"If you want it perfect,
eat it before then."
But, you know,
the food's still perfectly edible.
Have you ever been unable
to feed yourselves
by freegan...
lifting of stuff out of bins?
Not in London. No.
There's too much abundance and
waste to not be able to do it. Yeah.
Simon and Fran's fight
against the waste footprint
is only half the battle.
Managing to work out
how to supply a metropolis
with all the resources it needs
requires an equally smart way
of thinking.
Food often travels
thousands of miles
before it arrives on our plates.
It's inefficient, it's wasteful.
But to find a solution, perhaps
we need to travel back in time.
Away, at last,
from the madness of the megacity.
Birdsong, nature...
Back in the countryside.
Except that
I'm not in the countryside.
I am inside Mexico City
and we're on our way to see
its famous floating farms.
They go right the way back as an
idea to the original Aztec city,
which was built on a lake.
And the way they fed themselves was,
the created little floating islands,
and on those islands, they grew
the plants they needed to eat.
In the 16th century, Mexico City,
or Tenochtitlan,
was the largest city in the world.
The Aztecs' floating islands,
or farms, were vast rafts
made out of reeds,
fertilised with mud from the lake,
and organic waste.
The result was highly productive.
An amazing two-thirds
of the city's food
was grown within the city limits.
DOG BARKS
Now we're in the 21st century,
one of the questions is,
could we go right the way back?
Could we learn to grow more of our
own food actually inside the city?
Pedro Castillo
is keeping traditions alive
from before the Spanish Conquest.
It's a beautiful. Claro.
His fertile little holding
of vegetables
is home to livestock and
an abundance of fruit and vegetables,
which are all sold back
to downtown Mexico City
a couple of miles away.
Why did they start to grow the food
on the island?
And is it a good way of growing
food, to have a floating farm?
HE SPEAKS SPANISH
TRANSLATION:
It was more about necessity.
It was the lack of space, the lack
of room to cultivate their crops
that brought them here.
And then they noticed
it was very good for farming.
So, you yourself,
what do you grow here
and where do you sell what you grow?
They grow lettuce, spinach, tomato,
corn, radish.
< HE SPEAKS SPANISH
Normally, they sell it in the market
here in Xochimilco,
but right now, they're selling to
very selective restaurants
in Mexico City. Very good.
Pedro makes a mean tamale, that's a
kind of corn dough served in leaves.
Mm. Very good.
And like all good farmers, Pedro does
a nice line in home brew, as well.
This is a traditional tipple
which is made out of cactus sap.
It's got a kind of caramel taste.
And it would be extremely rude
not to sample it properly.
It is damn fine!
Mm! Very good.
HE SPEAKS SPANISH
TRANSLATION: You're offering it
to the mother earth.
Of course, this is very much
a Mexico City story.
You don't get tamales
and floating farms most places.
But perhaps there's a lesson here.
Because although
they're built by humans,
cities depend on nature.
We're inside nature,
we're part of nature.
And the great cities that we build
thrive or die
because of the natural world
around them.
We tear up the past
and we ignore nature at our peril.
Just like Mexico City, London
used to grow a substantial amount
of its own food
within a few short miles
of the centre.
This fertile farmland,
known as the breadbasket of London,
is better known today
as Heathrow Airport,
where food, very often similar food,
now arrives from South America,
Africa, Asia.
I'm not saying we should rip up
and plough what we've built over,
but we do need to be more clever
about how we use what we've got.
If the future shape of metropolis
seems to be ever more dense
and increasingly high rise,
then, maybe, some of the answers
to feeding the city
have to be urban ones.
For decades, people have imagined
a science-fiction future.
A vertical city
and farms in the sky.
It's not entirely far-fetched.
Architects are already hard at work.
Nearer to hand, inside
this inner-city London terrace,
the seeds of something pretty big
could be growing.
Like most ground-breaking ideas,
they start small.
This is a mini hydroponic
and aquaponic farm.
There is no soil here.
The plants are grown under light,
in mineral solutions and water,
fertilised by fish droppings.
Fresh eggs are laid daily
in a rooftop coop.
I'm under no illusion
that a few salad plants and hens
are going to solve the food crisis,
but think how much neglected space
London has to offer
a whole city of potential
21st century urban farmers.
Farmers like Paul Smith.
Our big plan is to grow food
all around the city,
in warehouses, empty buildings
and old derelict spaces.
When you're growing
inside a building,
the best way to make use
of the space is to grow upwards,
create vertical installations,
layers of food within buildings.
This a movement
happening all around the world
that we hope to be part of.
We're trying to demonstrate
you can get the best of both worlds.
You can have an ecological
food system in the city,
and if you do that,
we'll have a much lower
food footprint for everybody.
If we can get enough people
growing food in cities,
it'll be one part of the picture.
The city has an absolute,
in our view, critical role
in fulfilling the future food needs
of a place like London.
Over the next century,
disasters permitting,
the growth of the megacities
will stretch onwards.
In the last hour, in the time that
it's taken to watch this programme,
7,500 people have moved
from the country to a big city.
In that hour,
the world's slum population
has gone up by 3,000 people.
Shanghai's underground,
already the longest in the world,
will have grown
by a further five metres.
And so is the inexorable rise
and the dominance of the megacity
a cause for despair or hope?
There's no single answer
to any of this.
We need the planners. We need
the Shanghai-sized ambitions.
But we also need
the kick from the streets.
We need the stroppy cyclists,
the backyard innovators,
and the idealistic freegans
trying new ways of living.
Because cities don't belong
to the town hall or the architects
or the commissars.
Cities belong to citizens.
Are they going to be
new urban nightmares
or are they going to be places
where we dream new dreams
and bring them into effect?
Well, that's up to me. And you.
Subtitles by Red Bee Media Ltd
E-mail subtitling@bbc.co.uk