A lot of young people are out looking for
a job, but not working one. A new report says
youth employment in the U.S. is at its lowest
level since the Second World War. We are talking
about people ages 16 to 24. The Annie E. Casey
Foundation says that only half of them had
jobs in 2011, and if you just look at teenagers,
only one in four had a job last year. In the
year 2000 almost half of them did. The reasons
- the lingering effects of the great recession.
A lot of the entry level jobs the young people
used to count on like those at clothing stores
or restaurants, for example, are going to
more experienced or more educated workers.
One side effect is that young people aren`t
getting the early work experience that would
help them later on.
Some organizations want to give students the
chance to get that experience, but not through
job - at school, and not during regular classes
either. This is part of something called the
time collaborative, and for around 20,000
students it means they are going to be spending
more time at school. We are talking about
more than 40 schools in five states. Next
school year, they are going to be open an
additional 300 hours, so it works out to about
90 minutes extra a day on average. It won`t
necessarily mean more time in science or language
arts classes, though that it`s possible. The
organizers say the extra time could be spent
on internships, on apprenticeships or music
or arts programs. One goal would be to help
low performing students do better. An analyst
says the program could help increase test
scores, but it can also increase dropout rates.
He said that if the extra time looks and feels
like the rest of the school day, then those
at-risk students might not go for it.
A middle schooler who spoke to one of our
affiliates said students don`t want more time
in school. She said students want to get a
break from learning. What do you say? We want
to hear your thoughts on this. Let`s say your
school adds the extra time, an extra hour
and a half. How would you want to spend it?
More academics, the focus on music and drama
programs, getting internship or apprenticeship
credit. Tell us and tell us only your first
names on our blog cnnstudentnews.com.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: See, if you can I.D.
me. I was born in London in 1926 and I still
live there. I have a royal title, but I don`t
actually run my country`s government. I ascended
to the throne in 1952.
I`m the United Kingdom`s Queen Elizabeth II,
and I have one younger sister, but no brothers.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: Now, here is why that last part`s important.
If Queen Elizabeth did have any brothers,
even if they were younger than she, she wouldn`t
be queen. It all has to do with the order
of succession. In the U.S. , succession has
to do with who takes over as president if
something happens to the current president.
Well, for the British monarchy, succession
is about who becomes king or queen. This is
Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge. She is married
to Prince William, Queen Elizabeth`s grandson
and the couple is expecting a baby. Now, you
might have heard about that. Right now, the
British order of succession goes from the
queen to William`s dad, Prince Charles, and
then to Prince William. For more than 300
years, the law said that a monarch`s first
born son was heir to the throne. If he had
big sisters, he jumped in line ahead of them.
But the royal rules of succession are changing.
From now on, the firstborn child will be heir,
so William and Catherine`s baby will be next
in line for the throne and it won`t matter
whether it`s a boy or girl.
Just eight days left for you to send us an
"I-Report" and maybe get a place on our show.
We want to know how are you celebrating the
season of giving. You have to be at least
13 years old. The video has to be 30 seconds
or less, and no music, just you and the camera.
Please make sure to watch for our email. After
you submit your video, you get all the details
in the "Spotlight" section at cnnstudentnews.com
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: Today`s "Shoutout" goes
out to Mrs. Ross` CWP class at Eastmont High
School in East Wenatchee, Washington.
The word "camouflage" comes from what language.
You know what to do, is it Latin, Celtic,
Greek or French? You`ve got three seconds,
go!
Camouflage comes from a French word that means
"to disguise." That`s your answer and that`s
your "Shoutout."
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: And that`s what camouflage is meant
to do: to disguise. Usually military troops
or their equipment although you probably know
somebody who just like to wear it from time
to time. Now, you know camo when you see it.
You might think that the patterns in it are
kind of random, but that`s actually not the
case. Chris Lawrence explains why there`s
a lot to look at when you are designing clothing
to make people disappear.
(BEGIN VIDEOTAPE)
CHRIS LAWRENCE, CNN CORRESPONDENT: A lot is
riding on the next generation design to outfit
troops. It`s only been eight years since the
Army spent $5 billion on camo that critics
say didn`t fool anyone. Soldiers complained
to the point the Army abandoned its one size
fits all universal pattern.
(on camera): So, they were looking for camouflage
that they could use everywhere.
GUY CRAMER, HYPER STEALTH/ADS: Correct. And
it didn`t work anywhere.
LAWRENCE: Guy Cramer is one of the designers
competing to win the Army`s next multimillion
dollar contract. This summer, he showed us
the science behind every shape, size and shade
of these pixels.
(on camera): You now have your camouflage.
CRAMER: So we are trying to trick the brain
into seeing things that aren`t actually there.
LAWRENCE (voice over): Digital patterns recreate
shapes already found in nature. And 3-D layering
creates depth and shadows where non exist.
That`s today`s design. But developers already
have one eye on tomorrow.
CRAMER: What`s coming up down the road, and
very quickly, is the Harry Potter cloak.
RUPERT GRINT, ACTOR: What is that?
LAWRENCE: With that fictional cloak, Harry
isn`t just camouflage, he is invisible.
DANIEL RADCLIFFE, ACTOR: My body is gone!
LAWRENCE (on camera): How invisible are we
talking here? If I walk into a room with the
soldier wearing one of these cloaks?
CRAMER: You wouldn`t see him at all. He would
be completely invisible to you.
LAWRENCE (voice over): This is not make believe.
The military has seen the so-called quantum
stealth technology. It works by banding the
light around an object, even concealing most
of a person shadow. Imagine what that could
do for a sniper hiding in the field or the
American pilots who ejected over Libya when
their fighter jets crashed last year.
CRAMER: They could actually pull out very
similar to what they carry with a survival
blanket, throw it over top of them. And unless
you walked right into them, you wouldn`t know
that they were there.
LAWRENCE: So, what was once firmly in the
world of make believe, could quickly become
quite real.
(END VIDEOTAPE)
AZUZ: All right, and this one is going to
sound a little strange at first: a plan to
stop bullying by encouraging fighting. It
makes a little more sense when you find out
that one of the program`s organizers is a
mixed martial arts` champion, and his goal
is to keep fighting in the ring instead of
at his school. Have a look.
(BEGIN VIDEOTAPE)
ROB MCCULLOUGH: Hey, I`m Rob McCullough, and
we can make an impact on bullying. This campaign
is about anti-bullying and it`s about the
epidemic that`s going on nowadays in our schools.
And it`s about kids being picked on, kids,
you know, being bullied and for them to find
a safe haven through sports. Anti-bullying
is similar to what we are doing with L.A.
Boxing. We go to schools in neighboring areas
that we have gyms, so that we know that there
is a safe haven for these kids to go to.
I dealt with bullying growing up as a kid,
because I was always the new guy at the school.
I was always moving.
The message I`m trying to convey to these
kids at the assemblies is that with a little
hard work and motivation and a positive mental
attitude, you can, you know, you can literally
do anything you want to do.
Some of the people that we`ve had do assemblies
with us, is Dana White, the president of the
UFC, TRT`s Michael Bisping, Rampage Quinton
Jackson. The list goes on. We are not fighting
because we don`t like each other or because
we are bullying each other, we are fighting
because it`s a sport. Sport did that for me,
and it did that for a lot of my friends that
are professional athletes.
It gives you something to focus on.
Join the movement, impact your world.
(END VIDEOTAPE)
AZUZ: You can learn more about Rob McCullough`s
fight against bullying by clicking the "Impact
Your World" link on our home page. Our last
story today is sweet. It`s a gingerbread house.
It`s the White House. It`s both. It`s the
work of a woman in Alabama who calls herself
"the gingerbread lady. Normally, it takes
her about 12 hours to finish one of her confectionary
creations. This one took 12 days. OK, it might
just be a replica of a real life building,
but it`s filled with a lot of personal touches,
so it`s definitely not just like some cookie
cutter copy. We don`t know how much it would
sell for, but making it probably took a lot
of dough and the story delicious, getting
to make puns at the end, that`s just the icing
on the house, yo. I hope you enjoy the rest
of your day. For CNN STUDENT NEWS, I`m Carl
Azuz.