CHADD MCKEEN: In a time where
our economic stability is--
it's in shambles.
We're in trouble.
And if we're not willing to
look at possible solutions
outside the box, we're doomed.
If money could grow on trees,
wouldn't we start growing
those trees?
Well.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
I really get a feeling
you can't imagine
when you help somebody.
You have somebody come
in here who's dying.
And they say, hey man, I'm
dying, and they tell me I got
x amount of months to live.
I'm not even going to be
able to enjoy the last
six months I have.
And they say, I don't want
to take these pills.
They make me constipated.
I can't eat.
I can't sleep.
And to give them a medicine and
say, OK, you have what?
OK, cool.
This one.
And you give that to them.
And they come back
a week later.
And they go, oh my god.
You have no idea.
I stopped taking all
my pain pills.
I've stopped taking all
my insomnia pills.
I stopped taking this.
I stopped taking that.
And that's incredibly
rewarding to me.
Medical marijuana is legal on
a state level in 17 states.
It is illegal federally,
period.
What this all originally
started out
with was a great idea.
Proposition 215 was basically
an idea that people who were
dying from wasting and pain
issues, like cancer or AIDS,
benefited greatly through
the use of cannabis.
That's Prop 215.
Now the problem with that is it
was written so vaguely, it
was just a real simple, simple
piece of legislature.
And it really got whored
out, so to speak.
And people began to realize they
could take advantage of
the looseness of the way this
was written and make it a
profitable situation, people who
really didn't care about
medical issues.
We decided to start Otherside
Farms out of selfish reasons,
to be honest.
I wanted to find a way to
cure my wife's cancer.
My wife was fighting cancer,
and the chemo
wasn't really working.
Hi.
And she actually saw firsthand
on one of her biopsy spots
that it worked.
I had some Rick Simpson oil, and
I put on a Bandaid, and I
said let's put this on there.
So I put this right there,
and in 36 hours--
36 hours--
it disappeared completely.
This stuff works.
It's irresponsible to not take
advantage of the situation.
That's kind of weird, too,
because it's supposed to be
95% Chocolate Thai.
You'd think it would be
more of a prevalent.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Smells
more melony to me.
CHADD MCKEEN: Smells
super melony.
Mm, smells so good.
Now a letter went out from the
Department of Justice to all
city attorneys.
It basically says, if you
have someone that has
1,000 plants or more--
250 kilos, I think it is,
that's like 400 pounds.
Crazy, dude.
400 pounds, dude.
If you have someone in your
city that you think falls
within these parameters, let
us know and we'll come help
you check them out, raid them,
and you know, the whole thing.
6:00 in the morning on
January 17, I hear a
pounding at my door.
My wife ran downstairs, opened
the door for them, and said,
hey, I've got a sick
child upstairs
on a breathing machine.
If you're going to shoot
me in the back,
shoot me in the back.
I'm going to go take
care of my kid.
And so she ran back upstairs
to take care of Trevor.
They stood at the door,
got my daughter
out, put her in handcuffs.
16-year-old.
And I looked at him like, hey,
you didn't have to come in my
house like this, man.
(IMITATING COP VOICE) Come
downstairs, sir.
And I went down there, and they
threw me in handcuffs.
So I gave them the combo to my
gun safe that's upstairs,
where they found probably
a half a pound of shake.
And that's all they got
out of our house.
No guns, no other drugs, no huge
dashes of cash, no huge
stash of marijuana.
They took the keys to
our dispensary,
opened everything up.
And you know what they
got out of my store?
Huge safe.
They got it open.
They open it up.
One jar.
And they killed a couple
hundred plants.
They got me with ounces.
They got me with a couple
hundred plants.
I was stunned.
I was absolutely stunned.
So afraid they were going
to come again.
Because they could come take
whatever they want.
This is America.
This is not supposed
to happen here.
This is not supposed to
happen here, man.
You see here, this is
our storage room.
Every facility I have always has
a nice storage room where
we keep stuff-- tools
and whatnot.
The way things are in our
society today, we've gotta get
kind of sneaky about things.
I got to go through this kind of
stuff, and risk my freedom
like a superhero, to help
save people's lives.
But I got to do what
I got to do.
This room is being prepped.
Those plants are all going
to come into this room.
Every time that the plants
get taken out,
this all gets cleaned.
It's like a lab.
So, this is cool.
Shh, the babies are sleeping.
We want to come in so the
light doesn't hit them.
You guys see how big these
fucking plants are?
Things are massive, dude,
like a half pound
each off these guys.
In the state of California, it
used to be that you could have
six mature plants or twelve
immature plants per patient.
Well, then people started making
tinctures and started
making the Rick Simpson oil,
where you need 16 pounds of
quality marijuana to make
one ounce of this
stuff that cures cancer.
Now we've got a whole different
situation, because
those six plants aren't going to
take care of the way I want
to do my medicine.
So California Supreme Court
said that you can't put
limitations on a patient's
medicine.
So now you can grow as many as
you can justify growing.
We still went by the six
and twelve guideline.
I wasn't going to push
the envelope.
That's why our plant
count was down low.
We grew trees.
I waited and I had a system.
That's why they're all in
different sized things.
It's math here.
This is all math.
I've maximized every
square inch.
I figured out how to tax this.
I figured out how
to create jobs.
Isn't that worthy of at
least a conversation?
I mean, why do you kick the
door open of the man that
invited you to his house?
How do you raid that man?
I don't understand.
I was doing everything the way
you're supposed to do it.
This shouldn't have
happened to me.
Hey, I'm going to keep
doing things my way.
That's the bottom line.
You got to kill me if you want
me to stop helping people.
Because I actually get off
on the fact that you
want to stop me.