issue of the crazy cat lady.
Because for one thing, I feel
like I'm right on the cusp of
that myself.
VANESSA GADBERRY: So my name
is Vanessa and this is
Squirrel the kitten.
She's deaf.
She has to experience the world
by running up to things
which also makes her
very dog-like.
She's very curious and just has
to get into everything.
The hard thing about a deaf
cat is you can't call her.
If she looks over, there's a
chance that she'll respond to
the sign language I've
been teaching her.
But otherwise, if she doesn't
look over, you're kind of SOL
for getting her attention.
We go to a lot of events.
We've gone to, pretty much,
every animal walk that the
Twin Cities has had this year.
We went to Pride and
walked in Pride.
I loved it.
It was amazing.
Cats and gays, what
could be better?
And I had decided after much
research to dye Squirrel's
tail temporarily with some
organic food dye.
I tried to get everyone that
took a picture and give them
Squirrel's business card.
Because I was like, I'd
really love to see
the pictures online.
We made them because we'd go
to events and people would
want to like her Facebook.
But I think ultimately they
just forgot by the
time they got home.
So we made a little takeaway
for them to remember.
And the photos have already
started being posted to her
Facebook fan page.
-She was running around at
the festival last night?
VANESSA GADBERRY: She's
doing great.
-Could you tell us a little
bit about that experience?
VANESSA GADBERRY:
It was amazing.
I've seen all the
videos already.
I was like, oh, once we
start the videos I
might be kind of bored.
Because I watch cat
videos for hours.
Like I could--
-Hours?
VANESSA GADBERRY: --reanact
some of them probably.
It was awesome, because there
was actually videos I haven't
seen before.
And it was amazing that YouTube
cats celebrities were
flown in and traveled, and I
wasn't expecting that at all.
We got pictures with Squirrel
and Lil' Bub together.
But we also met the little girl,
who is now grown up, who
narrated Kittens Inspired
by Kittens.
And personally, that YouTube
video changed my life.
-Kittens inspired by kittens.
VANESSA GADBERRY: Bub's
owner was super chill.
-Yeah?
VANESSA GADBERRY: He
was awesome, yeah.
Guys are sexy that like
animals and know
how to treat animals.
I feel like you can't
trust someone who
doesn't like animals.
Who doesn't like animals?
-[SINGING]
RO: I'm Ro.
KAI: I'm Kai.
RO: These are our cats.
This is Artemis.
He's our newest cat.
He's about a year old.
Artemis is like the brave little
boy, and he'll get in
all the adventures.
KAI: Arlo is this
one down here.
RO: I didn't introduce Arlo.
KAI: He doesn't really
care about anything.
RO: That's if you hit her but
really hard a bunch or like
grab her fat on her tummy
and go like this.
This is Lucian.
He's Siamese mix and
he's two years old.
And he knows how to sit, and he
has freckles and the most
beautiful eyes.
Oh, and Lucian gives kisses.
KAI: Eww, it's going
to be salty.
RO: I think my first favorite
one is the one where the
kitten's sliding down and the
mom goes and gets him.
OK, my next favorite is that one
with the cat attacking the
automatic feeder.
Have you seen that?
It's so funny.
KAI: I really like the one they
played last night where
she's going behind the wall, and
then every time she comes
back she sees the cat
closer to her.
I think that one is
really funny.
RO: And for Halloween, they're
going to be the four different
houses from Hogwarts.
Lucian's going to be Slytherin
because he, kind of, looks
like Malfoy.
KAI: I don't know Harry
Potter very well.
I just know the cats.
RO: Dimitri.
KAI: Oh, no.
RO: Oh, no.
That's another part
of having cats.
It's not all fun and games.
KAI: Oh, baby.
RO: Will you get it?
KAI: Yeah.
We don't have any
paper towels.
RO: Oh, there's like, ewww.
Oh, God.
WHITNEY ROGERS: My name is
Whitney Rogers, and I got Pax
last August so about a year
ago, a little bit over.
And I got her from a local
breeder in St. Louis Park.
-Did you want a Rex?
WHITNEY ROGERS: Very
specifically.
They have a very low shedding,
they don't shed
very much at all.
You can bathe them which will
cut down even more.
But they're very good for
people with allergies.
They have a very long life.
It's a relatively new breed
so they don't have high
incidences of any kind of
disease or inherent health
problems either.
And once I got her, I
was totally hooked.
She is quite possibly
the funniest.
And I like it because Kittles
will pretty much just watch.
I try to film her sometimes.
We've got a couple funny
films of her.
But it's hard, because I try
to get my boyfriend to put
them online, and he thinks the
whole thing is kind of hmm.
I think he just doesn't want
to admit how much of a cat
person he is, because he tries
to be a little bit tougher
than he is at home.
Even though they say this cat's
really high energy, you
might not realize that she will
climb you and jump on
your shoulders regardless
of what you're
wearing or not wearing.
And she'll like to sit up there,
and sometimes they lose
their balance.
It can be a slippery
slope really.
And be prepared to
get some scars.
She definitely is getting
more notoriety.
A lot of my friends know about
her, and we'll take pictures
and post them on Instagram and
at least tell me about it so I
can tag myself in it.
A few of his friends that came
over were like, this is the
weirdest cat we've ever seen
in our entire lives.
She just looks so strange with
that huge head and huge ears.
I have written two or three
songs about cats, only one
since I've gotten her though.
My band has a curse word
in the name so--
-What's the name?
WHITNEY ROGERS: It's Shit
Beast Kitchen Club.
And we've been doing stuff
for a really long time.
Yeah, this is me like three
or four years ago.
This was before we figured out
how to work most of the stuff
in the studio also.
I'm pretty proud of it.
-How high can she jump?
WHITNEY ROGERS: I'd say
about between five
and six feet or so.
I'd say, pretty much, four and
a half to five is, sort of,
her average.
Most of the cat videos that are
on the internet are pretty
funny or have some intrinsic
entertainment value to them
but also raise more awareness
about rarer breeds, care,
troubleshooting any possible
problems your cats might have,
and, sort of, parenting
almost.
I really love cats.