EDDIE HUANG: Hell Valley?
Why?
LOUIS HUANG: Because
of the smell.
EDDIE HUANG: Oh my god.
All right, we just made a quick
pit stop at the famous
Taiwanese hot springs,
and it smells like
Eva Devine's butthole.
She ate a cum burrito.
That bitch is disgusting.
Let's go, Dad.
LOUIS HUANG: Whatever.
[MUSIC - TIDUS, "DELANCEY"]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
EDDIE HUANG: The first time
I went to Din Tai Fung, I
was 12 years old.
And I'm telling you, this was
the single greatest bite of
food I've ever had in my life.
You experience it and you're
like, yo, I can't explain it.
There's something in the
motherfucking water.
Bagels from New York, burritos
from San Francisco--
this is that shit, and
it is definitely a
transformative food.
And I can't say that
about many things.
I've been working out a lot.
Do I look like I lost weight?
LOUIS HUANG: No,
you look good.
EDDIE HUANG: Yeah, I look
like I lost weight.
SERVER: [FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
EDDIE HUANG: [FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
Whoa, yo, yo, yo, instructions
to eat soup dumplings.
Wait, they say to poke
a hole though.
That's bullshit.
Hooligans poke holes.
This is wrong.
LOUIS HUANG: To cool off the
soup inside the dumpling.
EDDIE HUANG: No, but remember
when your friend taught us the
first time we came here?
We put it in the vinegar and
just let it sit in the vinegar
to cool by itself.
Then you don't need to
poke a hole, right?
LOUIS HUANG: That was
my brother-in-law.
EDDIE HUANG: That was
your brother-in-law?
LOUIS HUANG: That was
my brother-in-law.
EDDIE HUANG: Yo, original
Jedi, that guy.
But see, isn't that a better
technique than poking holes?
LOUIS HUANG: Why poke a hole?
You don't have to.
EDDIE HUANG: Why poke holes?
There's other things to poke.
Your brother-in-law saved the
poking for someone else.
LOUIS HUANG: This
needs to be cut.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
EDDIE HUANG: So the trademark
of these soup dumplings is
every single soup dumpling
here has 18 folds.
You can see every single
distinguished fold,
super hard to do.
And you see how they're
perfectly bite-sized?
You go to a shitty place like
Joe's Shanghai Soup Dumplings
in New York.
They're like giant, nasty
soup dumplings.
Big and flat, like large
areolas, like Paula Abdul
saucer nipples.
These are nice little
dumplings.
How is it?
LOUIS HUANG: This is awesome.
This is awesome, great idea.
EDDIE HUANG: I like
these better.
So, I got a surprise
for you, Dad.
This just came out today.
The cover came out today.
You see?
LOUIS HUANG: Oh really?
EDDIE HUANG: That's you.
LOUIS HUANG: "Fresh
Off the Boat"
EDDIE HUANG: Yup.
LOUIS HUANG: "Eddie Huang--
A Memoir."
EDDIE HUANG: You could cry.
You like to cover?
LOUIS HUANG: Yeah, very
much, very much.
Show her.
See?
That's the cover of his book.
It's coming out next Chinese
New Year, in February.
He's got a million
dollar book.
EDDIE HUANG: Million
There we go.
LOUIS HUANG: Make sure
you buy it, OK?
Amazon.com--
you can buy Eddie
Huang's memoir.
EDDIE HUANG: Love it.
This is my hype man.
What other hype man got
a perm like this?
This dude's killing this perm.
LOUIS HUANG: I thought I'd dress
up for this occasion.
EDDIE HUANG: I know.
Dad, do the [INAUDIBLE].
Go like this, go like this.
Go like this, do the
[INAUDIBLE].
No, no, one hand like
this-- the mirror--
I'll teach you.
Do the Rico, the [INAUDIBLE]
just like this.
LOUIS HUANG: Next time we
do this, I'll wish I
still had my hair.
EDDIE HUANG: You still
got plenty of hair.
The Soul Glow is treating
you well.
Ready.
LOUIS HUANG: It's amazing,
I was so disappointed
when he quit law.
Because that was three
years' hard work.
I was very proud of him.
When he graduated, he got
a job right away.
He passed the bar on
the first try.
I was very happy that he's
set for his life.
And then six months later,
he broke the news.
He said, I quit.
I thought, I don't have to worry
about Eddie anymore.
His [INAUDIBLE]
got his career all set.
But I'm glad he made a decision
and did what he liked
to do, what he loved to do.
So it's very, very brave,
very courageous.
Yeah, I'm proud of him.
EDDIE HUANG: He's about
to do some shit.
All right, one, two, three.
Awesome, good.
LOUIS HUANG: Thank you.
SERVER: Thank you.
LOUIS HUANG: You have
a customer now.
Those are the Japs.
EDDIE HUANG: [LAUGHS]
Got em.
All right, ready to
go see grandpa?
[MUSIC PLAYING]
LOUIS HUANG: Basically what we
do is respect the god, the
sky, the earth, everything
else in between.
Bless all these people here.
They accompany us here today
to pay respect--
me and my son, Eddie--
to pay respect to my father.
And they are the working
crew, and I wish
everybody give them blessing.
Thank you so much.
Thank you.
The incense, the smoke and
everything, is a message.
It's a communication between
the sky, the earth, and
everything else in between.
WOMAN: [FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
EDDIE HUANG: [FOREIGN LANGUAGE].
Grandpa kind of looks
like Chow Yun-Fat.
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
[MUSIC - CLAUDE DEBUSSY,
"CLAIR DE LUNE"]
EDDIE HUANG: So the thing
is, I only met this
grandfather one time.
But ever since I was a kid, of
all the people in my family,
he was definitely
my role model.
This was the one man in both of
my families on either side
that everyone only had
good things to say.
LOUIS HUANG:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
EDDIE HUANG: Grandpa, this
money here is for you.
Don't spend it all
in one place.
Don't let anyone jux you.
Got you.
[MUSIC - CLAUDE DEBUSSY,
"CLAIR DE LUNE"]
So we burned him some money to
buy Ewings, because they don't
have Ewings here.
But now we're going to burn him
some things at the store.
LOUIS HUANG: Mercedes.
EDDIE HUANG: Yeah, of course.
We gotta get the red one, the
red whip, cherry red Benz.
LOUIS HUANG: And the iPhone.
EDDIE HUANG: [FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
[MUSIC - CLAUDE DEBUSSY,
"CLAIR DE LUNE"]
EDDIE HUANG: I would
talk to this
grandpa when I was asleep.
And my dad doesn't know, my
mom doesn't know, but I'd
always be like, man, I
want to be like you.
It's funny like, 21st century,
we came and we showed grandpa
the cover of our book
on an iPhone.
It's ill, man.
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
LOUIS HUANG: [FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
EDDIE HUANG: All right, I always
grew up playing ball
with my dad.
And he don't know it right
now, but he's about
to get balled on.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
EDDIE HUANG: We're in
Taipei, balling.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
EDDIE HUANG: Yo dad, this
is what you say.
This is "Fresh Off the
Boat" in Taipei.
I'm Louis Huang and
this is my seed.
We out.
That's it.
You got it?
Let him do it.
No, we'll see.
If it doesn't work,
I'll do it.
LOUIS HUANG: I need
an attitude.
EDDIE HUANG: Yeah, you got it.
Just be yourself, dad.
LOUIS HUANG: Yo, this is "Fresh
Off the Boat" Taipei.
I'm Louis Huang.
This is my seed.
EDDIE HUANG: We out.