-Come on, I see the
pig's teeth.
-Let me touch it.
-Who killed it?
EDDIE HUANG: Chef Creole.
[LAUGHS].
[MUSIC - TiDUS, "DELANCEY"]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
EDDIE HUANG: 'Sup, Hasai FOBs.
We are here in Little Haiti,
about to see the world famous
Chef Creole.
CHEF CREOLE: What?
What?
EDDIE HUANG: We're going to
tailgate with him and his
friends.
-Good job, Chef.
That was delicious, man.
EDDIE HUANG: Then we're
going to hit the
water, get on a boat.
Palm trees are sexy, dude.
Palm trees are very sexy.
And see how Haitians
do in Miami.
Peace, peace, y'all.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
EDDIE HUANG: What's
up, Chef Creole?
CHEF CREOLE: Hey!
What's up?
EDDIE HUANG: It's good.
How are you doing?
CHEF CREOLE: How you doing?
EDDIE HUANG: Good, good, good.
Thank you for having
me here today, man.
Really excited.
CHEF CREOLE: I feel
bad for you.
When you're coming from
New York, it's cold.
EDDIE HUANG: Yeah.
CHEF CREOLE: Look at you.
EDDIE HUANG: Oh, you saw me.
I was tanning on the
street earlier.
CHEF CREOLE: Yeah, I was like
Eddie's out of his mind!
He's up here in Miami,
getting butt naked!
EDDIE HUANG: A panda escaped
from the zoo.
I like it.
CHEF CREOLE: Do you?
EDDIE HUANG: Conch.
CHEF CREOLE: We got conch,
got shrimp, got lobster.
Let's go in the kitchen and play
around for a little bit.
EDDIE HUANG: Let's do it.
CHEF CREOLE: You know, Little
Haiti's real interesting.
You know it's a Creole
culture.
And one of the things that
people need to understand is
that Louisiana is Creole.
EDDIE HUANG: Yes.
CHEF CREOLE: The language
of Haiti is Creole.
EDDIE HUANG: Creole, yeah.
CHEF CREOLE: The Louisiana
Creole that you know about,
it's the same Creole that's
here from Haiti.
Look at this.
This is what I call
big time cooking.
EDDIE HUANG: Red
beans and rice.
CHEF CREOLE: Red beans
and rice, baby.
In Creole, it's called
[INAUDIBLE].
Look at this.
EDDIE HUANG: Mango snapper.
CHEF CREOLE: Look
at this snapper.
Hey look, this ain't just
snapper that we just take, put
it under hot water and give
it to the people.
Bull shit, man.
Got to clean the damn thing.
Clean it right.
Then we got to cut it so
all the seasonings
get right up in there.
See all the fish
we're cooking?
EDDIE HUANG: Yeah.
CHEF CREOLE: I mean, we're
into production, baby.
This is bang, bang, bang.
EDDIE HUANG: A lot of people
say, Chef, when he cooks he
puts his foot in it.
And you know something?
It's true.
It's not nice to say on TV.
CHEF CREOLE: No, that's the best
compliment someone could
tell you is you put your
foot in the shit.
Well, look at that bad boy.
EDDIE HUANG: He's smiling.
CHEF CREOLE: He's smiling.
EDDIE HUANG: He's
still smiling.
What temperature are you
going to do this at?
CHEF CREOLE: This is at 250
to 275, eight hours--
slow!
EDDIE HUANG: There you go.
CHEF CREOLE: Slow, baby!
We come under here,
look at that!
EDDIE HUANG: Wow, get
up in the guts.
CHEF CREOLE: This is how
we do business, baby.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
CHEF CREOLE: I've always learned
in life, you got to
build your army.
OK, watch your hands now.
Watch your hands.
And your army is what you call
your support system.
EDDIE HUANG: Yeah.
CHEF CREOLE: The best support
system you could have is
grassroots.
If for some reason you're not
pleased with the next level--
you're like, look guys, this
is a little bit too
superficial for me.
EDDIE HUANG: Look at you,
you've got the promo!
CHEF CREOLE: I got the promo.
We don't play, baby.
We rock and roll.
At least you're not going
to be shunned out.
Because the first adopters, they
will always keep it real.
They'll always get your back.
EDDIE HUANG: You nailed
it on the head, man.
The grassroots and your first
supporters-- those are the
people you do it for.
That's your family.
The other thing I wanted
to ask you about is
gentrification, right?
I really want to see it happen
with people like you opening
Chef Creole's.
Serving the community
that's here.
Providing an environment that
other people can also enjoy.
CHEF CREOLE: Right.
EDDIE HUANG: But it's very, very
evident from jump, when
you come to Chef Creole, who
that restaurant is inspired by
and who you are paying
tribute to, and
they will never change.
Because he got money.
He got money.
He look expensive.
-See that stomach right there?
That stomach is expensive.
But for these prices, I tell
you, I'm fed and we're good.
The family is here,
everyone's here.
The family over here,
family over here.
EDDIE HUANG: And I think
that's the thing with
gentrification that people
have to remember.
It's like, who came before?
What are the traditions
of this neighborhood?
How can we come in and
integrate into this
neighborhood, not come
in and take it over.
Do it in a way that everyone
can participate, because
that's what you do with
your restaurant.
CHEF CREOLE: Something that I
would normally sell for $12, I
would turn around and say look,
we're in the 'hood.
We're in the 'hood.
I'm going to run a
special, $4.99.
Now we're talking business.
Now you've got the people that
encompasses that area, now
you've got them involved.
EDDIE HUANG: And you're
investing.
You've invested in
these people.
CHEF CREOLE: Let's go.
-I'm excited.
Chef Creole is bringing
us a pig.
That things about,
what, 100 pounds?
Can't wait.
We're hungry.
I've got all my friends waiting
for me at the tailgate.
That's where we party
like rock stars.
CHEF CREOLE: Yeah!
Yeah!
EDDIE HUANG: Very good.
-Oh, that shit just looks
beautiful, man.
Look at that thing.
It's gorgeous.
Can't wait to get some onto
this bread right now.
EDDIE HUANG: There's some
real Axe Body Spray
vibrations out here.
CHEF CREOLE: The game's about
to start and we're going to
get out of here, man.
We're going to go in the
water and get some
real natural salt.
You know what I mean?
[MUSIC PLAYING]
EDDIE HUANG: Ready, let's go.
Everything's better
on the water.
CHEF CREOLE: Everything's
better on the water.
All the negativity that followed
you jumped off a
bridge away because they knew
you were coming here.
EDDIE HUANG: I don't know,
my producer's still here.
[LAUGHTER]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
CHEF CREOLE: That's the island
over there, guys.
You see it?
[MUSIC PLAYING]
CHEF CREOLE: OK, one, two,
three, four, five, six, and we
got seven on the--
one, two, three, four, five.
Can't lose none of the puppies
in the litter, baby.
EDDIE HUANG: You know, we rarely
put chefs on "Fresh Off
the Boat." Because I want to
get into culture in ways
outside of the restaurant,
outside of chefs.
But sometimes the best
way into a story
is a chef, you know?
This dude grew up on
these streets.
He reps it hard.
He reps his family.
And I feel blessed just
to be a part of it.
To come and see how in a lot
of ways they've kind of
recreated their own
Haiti in Miami.
And that's the goal of the
show is to try to go find
these underdogs.
Try to go find these stories
that other people thought were
inappropriate for food shows.
This is how people live.
This is how people eat.
This is how culture is created,
preserved, and survived.
So I hope you all enjoyed it.
I hope you all enjoyed Miami.
And I hope overall you all enjoy
the real life reality
that we give you on "Fresh
Off the Boat." All right?
It's your boy, Eddie Huang.
We out.
[MUSIC - TiDUS, "DELANCEY"]
[MUSIC PLAYING]