The king of Aperitvo.
This was invented in Florence and the last
name of the guy that invented it was Negroni.
So, first up we've got Gin, right next door
to our modifier which is a sweet vermouth
and then our beautiful bitters. This is good
for stimulating the stomach. Settling the
stomach. It's also good at the end of the
meal to settle the stomach when you eat nice
things.
So, we're gonna go 25ml of gin. And you've
got here, if you see through the bottle, we've
got things like the Juniper berries. That
has to be in the gin as the main ingredient
of course, but you've got lemon peel, coriander,
angelica. All these things grow in my garden,
it's great!
Orrice, no idea what that is but I'm sure it's lovely.
Then 25ml of the sweet vermouth.
So real.... oooh. Ok, not all of that, just half of that!
Sorry I got over excited. It's only natural.
25ml of the bitters. Bitter flavours is very
much a part of very historical, old cooking
both in Britain but absolutely in Italy. You
know all of these kind of botanical, vegetables
and stuff, they're bitter. And bitters is
a very old fashioned part of your palate.
So, 3 equal parts of those great spirits go
in. Now we need to have some dilution of this
cocktail. It's very strong at the moment.
So we're just simply gonna put in a few ice
cubes , use a spoon and just move it around.
So we're just kind of watering down that cocktail,
just a little bit and you know what, that's
probably enough!
So all we have to do now is a little smile
of orange. So a nice fresh orange. And a little
tip - remember we've got bitterness in the
white, well actually we don't want that. But
here in the skin is the oils, the essential
oils, the beautiful flavour. So I'm just gonna
hold it up and I'm just gonna squeeze it and
as I bruise that skin, right, the juice will
come out and it will go through the oil and
that's all. Just a little smile, a little
squeeze, nothing more, nothing less. We'll have another little stir and I'm just gonna top it up with
a few nice ice cubes. That's the job done!
Happy as Larry! There we have a beautiful
classic cocktail. All we gotta do now is have
a little sip.
Spectacular! But of course,
life is too short just to have this great,
classic cocktail. So, if I took the Gin out,
right, and swapped it for Vodka, that would
be called Negroski! So of course look, there's
beautiful things you can do. Top it up with
Prosecco or some soda water. You can lighten
it even. Even beautiful with food! So guys,
cheers! Until next time! Happy stirring! Bye!