SHANE SMITH: This is a shrine
to Jesus Malverde, who's the
patron saint of drug
smugglers, narcos.
So we're going to
light a candle.
This is freaking me out
because I'm very
superstitious.
That's him there.
Patron saint of the
drug dealers.
They all come in here.
They say a prayer.
They write a prayer on here and
they say, please let me
get across the border
with my drugs.
Literally, religion about
drug dealers.
Now the whole time I was hanging
out with the LeBarons,
I found myself wondering, how
do you actually protect
yourself against narco lords
who employ whole armies of
assassins whose sole job is
to kill their rivals.
Well, the LeBarons started by
adopting military-style
tactics and setting up
checkpoints, roadblocks, and
watch towers.
BRENT LEBARON: We hit a real big
low, you know, when they
killed Benjamin.
It was a real big blow to
our entire community.
SHANE SMITH: Right.
BRENT LEBARON: I was really
close to Benjamin.
Knew him really well.
SHANE SMITH: After Benjamin was
killed, you set up your
own community watch, your
own night watch.
And then you built this
up and you have people
watching every night.
BRENT LEBARON: Every night.
SHANE SMITH: What are
you watching for?
BRENT LEBARON: Pretty much
suspicious vehicles.
We pretty much know everybody,
and so if it looks like a
vehicle I've never
seen before, then
it was getting checked.
SHANE SMITH: This watch hut
looks down on one of the main
drug trafficking roads.
BRENT LEBARON: One
of them, yeah.
SHANE SMITH: The only
people here with
weapons are the criminals.
BRENT LEBARON: Pretty much.
SHANE SMITH: The drug cartels.
BRENT LEBARON: Rumor got out
that we had high-powered
rifles and snipers
and whatnot.
SHANE SMITH: And 50 cals
up here and stuff.
BRENT LEBARON: Well you know
how rumors can spread.
Which was a benefit for us.
SHANE SMITH: Yeah, it's good.
It's a good rumor.
BRENT LEBARON: It was a really
good rumor for us.
I believe that the watch tower
is one of the key points to
keeping the bad guys
away from our town.
Also the Feds and the military
are in our town.
This is their base.
We actually had a roadblock, to
where there was one way in
and one way out.
SHANE SMITH: So you have
barricades, checkpoints, and
watch towers.
BRENT LEBARON: Yeah.
I would say our valley right
here is quite a bit safer than
a lot of areas.
SHANE SMITH: Casas Grandes,
which is about 30 minutes
away, they're still having
kidnappings and stuff there.
BRENT LEBARON: Here and there.
Before it was literally
two, three a week.
SHANE SMITH: Wow.
It's a lot.
BRENT LEBARON: That's
a lot, yeah.
We were never pinpointing drug
cartels or anything else.
But when it came to them now
kidnapping our family members,
that's what we took
a stand against.
When it comes to protecting our
family, if we have to die
doing it, we're going to.
SHANE SMITH: So the LeBarons
made their colony into a
little fortress, using the
same counterterrorist
techniques that the US Army uses
in Iraq and Afghanistan.
And because of it, the killings
and the kidnappings
in the Mormon areas actually
died down.
But road blocks and security
checkpoints are only going to
get you so far.
At some point, if you're
fighting the narcos, you're
going to need guns.
If Benjamin was taken by a bunch
of guys with weapons--
they were unarmed--
how are you supposed
to defend yourself?
CAR DRIVER: Well, there's really
no law in Mexico that
gives you the right
to bear arms.
Legally, the quickest
and the best way is
through a gun club.
SHANE SMITH: Now in
Mexico it's nearly
impossible to own a gun.
In fact, one of the only legal
ways to do so is to go through
the extremely difficult process
of starting a gun club
or a shooting range.
Why don't you have
your own shooting
club in Colonia LeBaron?
CAR DRIVER: Our ex-mayor
wouldn't sign
the papers we needed.
We had all the first
members on a list.
Well, he turns around
and it shows it
to our bad-boy buddies.
SHANE SMITH: You're trying to
arm yourselves, and he's
working for the cartel.
So you can't arm yourselves.
CAR DRIVER: Exactly.
Pretty much.
SHANE SMITH: Where is he now?
CAR DRIVER: He's in prison.
SHANE SMITH: There's 15 million
illegal assault rifles
estimated in Mexico.
I mean, the thing is,
if you have 20 guys
with assault rifles--
I think I'm going to go for
one of those turkeys.
Oh yeah, I'm going to
get one of them.
So the LeBarons finally decided
that if it continued
to be illegal to own weapons,
which meant criminals were the
only ones that had guns, that it
was time to change the law.
Alex LeBaron, who is now a
Congressman, is determined to
protect his colony from
the cartels, no
matter what it takes.
Even if it means a shoot out
with the Mexican military.
ALEX LEBARON: They went
into our farm.
We thought they were
criminals.
We shot one of them.
It was a very sad incident,
but it gained a lot
of respect for us.
SHANE SMITH: You outshot
the military.
ALEX LEBARON: We outshot
We got phone calls from heads of
the criminal organizations
after that incident.
And they told us they were proud
of us to some degree.
People in drug organizations--
and including in the same
military-- know that we have
weapons, because we've
been saying it.
SHANE SMITH: Sure.
ALEX LEBARON: We have illegal
weapons in our community.
Come in and find them
if you want.
We buy them in the States.
We know we traffic
them illegally.
But that's the only
way to defend
yourself in this country.
In order to get access to a
weapon in our country it would
cost you up to $10,000, and that
wouldn't even be through
a legal way.
SHANE SMITH: So the majority of
the weapons being used by
the narcos--
ALEX LEBARON: Yes.
SHANE SMITH: --are coming
from America.
ALEX LEBARON: Absolutely.
SHANE SMITH: And the money
is coming from America.
BRENT LEBARON: Absolutely.
I think the Americans need to
really understand that any
policies that are implemented
in the United States impact
our country.
SHANE SMITH: So the money
for all these guns
is coming from America.
The guns themselves
come from America.
The coke is being sold in
America, but the war is being
fought in Mexico.
And considering 1,300 people
were killed in the region just
this past August alone, in
northern Mexico self defense
has truly become a matter
of life and death.
One of the things that we were
worried about was people
knowing that we were here.
They've just announced to the
whole town that we're here
shooting, in a town where they
used to have three or four
kidnappings a week.
I'm going to get drunk.