PONTUS ALV: In the '70s, Malmo
was a big industrial city.
And building big oil ships, like
big tankers, that was the
main business.
In the '80s, there was the
big financial crash.
So there was no work,
there was no
jobs, there was nothing.
Malmo had quite a big
skate scene back
then in the late '80s.
That was when the big trend
came from the States.
When my parents got divorced
and moved to another city,
like a small village called
[INAUDIBLE], that's where I
started skating.
Basically, my dad picked me up
after school, drove me 45
minutes to Malmo to go to the
skate park, go to the spot.
He would sit there all day,
wait for me, watch
me skate, go back.
And we would do that every day,
pretty much, after school.
I always try to skate
something different.
I always try to make something
different,
find something different.
For me, it's like the atmosphere
around the spot is
just as important as
the spot itself.
The first place we built
was Savanna Side.
This is where it all started.
Well, it's right there.
Used to be all empty here, just
old factory foundation.
When we built the park, we
didn't have any plan for it.
Everything is just kind of made
up, just everybody got a
little piece in here.
We use to skate the trains as
well sometimes, street gaps on
top of the trains.
This here, we skated here every
day for two months,
three months.
People are not so
into this place.
Not many people come
here to skate.
This is the New York banks.
If you don't have it,
you got to build it.
This is kind of like
the spot in London.
I know Bobby Puleo has a couple
tricks, the nosegrind
into these brick banks, kind
of like the same idea.
I mean, if you want to have
something good to skate, you
want to have something that is
interesting, fun, you've got
to build it.
I mean, you don't find these
kind of things on the streets.
And here, I've got everything
I need in one small place.
And it's perfect, you know.
We go skate.
And I got the camera with me.
And whatever happens happens.
But we always end up having
some photos, some footage.
And then we just do something
with it, you know.
NILS SVENSSON: You have to
be creative to find new
stuff all the time.
That's what's great
with Pontus.
That's exactly what
he's looking for.
And that's exactly what
I'm looking for.
"Strongest of the Strange," it's
quite a slice of history
from Malmo skating
right there.
You could see the development
we've done with the DIY stuff.
I think it was really inspiring
for a lot of people
that you can really create
your own skate scene,
basically, just by bricks
and concrete.
PONTUS ALV: I think a lot
of people, it was really
refreshing to see that video,
with the whole DIY documentary
thing inspired a
lot of people.
I got kids from all over Europe
sending me emails like,
hey, I love that video,
I love what you did.
And look what me and
my friends built.
There's so many bowls have been
built just because of
that little section
in my video.
This is what remains.
There's a lot of history
here in this place.
It was quite famous when
it was up and running.
This place used to be fucking
homeless city.
We talked to the landowner when
he kicked out all the
homeless people here.
They said, yeah, you
guys can stay.
But we've got to clean
up the area.
The homeless people here, they
were so angry at me.
They're like, yeah man, we've
been living here for eight,
nine years.
And you guys get to stay.
They kick us out.
And yeah, they were throwing
fire bombs over the
fence into the bowl.
This bowl has got destroyed
a couple of times,
and we fixed it.
And one day came, someone
smashed it.
The first you get bulldozed,
you get really bummed.
But I'm so used to it now.
In a way, it's good, because
you get new stuff to
skate all the time.
Tear it down, and build
another one.
And tear it down, and build--
it's like a little war I got.
If you have an idea, do
it, and do it now.
This session today might
be the last one.
It might be the last time
we skate here together.
That brings something extra to
the spot, rather than just a
public state park, that
it's there for you.
Back in the '90s, Malmo was
a ghost town, kind of
like worn down city.
Skating-wise, wasn't
anything going on.
I mean, skateboarding in
the '90s was dead.
We used to skate here
all the time.
Then for some reason, they put
this for the people that go
from the bus, so it's
not slippery.
So they kind of fucked up the
spot, because this ledge was
the main thing to skate.
MARTIN NILSSON: In the
'90s there was this
square right there.
We called it Plaza.
We had ledges.
We had this.
We had some stairs.
I mean, it wasn't perfect,
and nothing is.
But it was our spot.
And I wouldn't go as
far as saying it
was American standard.
But in our heads, we were
like, yeah, this is
really a good spot.
When we started, we were
10 or 15 guys.
Pontus was 11.
And one guy was,
back then, 25.
Everybody hated us.
Story of most skaters'
lives in the '90s.
-Yes.
MARTIN OTTOSSON: This was
in the early '80s.
There was a Swedish band
called Magnum Bonum.
They made a hit song called
"Skateboard." I used to listen
to it every day when I was
playing on my swing.
I moved here in '95.
The official reason
was for studies.
But I wanted to go here because
of skateboarding.
It was only one group
of people.
It was us.
We didn't have anybody else to
look up to or learn from.
MARTIN NILSSON: We probably
spent skating
three hours every day.
When it was raining or too cold,
we could just go down,
because under here is
a parking garage.
When the shopping mall is
closed, we could skate up
here, the luxury part
of the garage.
And most of the time, we used
to just skate down there,
because otherwise we
got kicked out.
TOBIAS HENRIKSSON:
We came down here
first time maybe '91.
We used to skate here a
lot, every day from 7
o'clock 'til 9:00.
There are some other garages,
but not as good as this.
This is warm and perfect
flat ground and curbs.
Perfect to do manuals
and stuff here.
That's the way it
was back then.
We never turned the
camera off.
One guy missed, the next guy
would jump in, do the line.
Pontus, he's five years younger
than the rest of us.
I remember when he took off
in '94, maybe, when he was
getting really good.
It was cool when he went to San
Francisco and skated for
Mad Circle, because Mad Circle
was so big at that time.
-Were you guys pretty
proud of him?
TOBIAS HENRIKSSON:
Yes, we were.
Still are.
PONTUS ALV: [INAUDIBLE], and
he's the one who started up
Mad Circle with Justin.
I met him at the skate
park in Gothenburg.
And he saw me skate.
And he was really stoked.
Basically, yeah, he got a
camera from [INAUDIBLE].
He came down one day.
And I'm going to film you.
And I was like, OK, cool.
Because I was thinking
you have to make
everything first try.
So I got, like, I don't know, 15
lines first try, like bam.
And then he sent the
tape to the States.
Justin saw it, and he's
like, this is it.
Him and Blabec came
over, we skated.
And then they said, yeah, I'll
fly you out to San Francisco,
and it was on.
I was, like, 15.
My mom said, you got
to bring a friend.
So I brought one of
my friends over.
Justin picked us up.
And we lost our luggage.
Me and Scott Johnson didn't
really get along that well.
But me and Bobby were tight.
Coming from this little town,
just straight to fucking your
dream company, like from nothing
down here to going
straight into the heart
of San Francisco.
This is the church.
It's called Johannes Church.
This is where I had a line in
the "5 Flavors," opening
switch 180 up, and
backs a flip out.
This was the main
meet up spot.
Back in those days, all you
needed, like, flat curb and
wax it up, and [SWISH].
JOHN DAHLQUIST: We spent
a lot of time here.
Pretty much one full summer
in '93, we'd meet up
here, skate all day.
Road trip would be to go down
to that parking lot.
PONTUS ALV: This parking lot
used to be covered with these
white ledges.
We used to skate here a lot.
This is for the good old days.
In my second video, I had 50-50,
and then transfer to
the other side.
Mad Circle ended.
I got back to Europe, I wanted
to quit skating.
But then I just started to skate
again with friends and
got into it, and just called up
Jeremy and said, I want to
work with Cliche, and want to
build something up in Europe.
And me and Jeremy started
working on the whole Cliche
Europa project.
It seems like since I left the
industry, things have just
been going so much better.
The more you're away from
skateboarding, the
more people want you.
Now it's like, oh, we
want an interview.
We want photos.
We want to publish your stuff.
When I was in the States,
when I was with
Cliche, you try so hard.
And then it's like you're just
another guy doing it.
People always want something
they can't get.
-Do you like it?
PONTUS ALV: It's all right.
-Let me see.
Let me see it.
PONTUS ALV: Hello.
-Go ahead.
-Yeah, that's good.
PONTUS ALV: That's good?
JEREMY BUTTERWORTH: Get,
go, come here.
That's right.
Not quite used to all this
hype around here.
Cameras on, it's like,
oh, how's my hair?
My name's Jeremy Butterworth.
I'm from Australia originally.
I first came to Malmo in 2005.
I had to help work on the
Stapelbadd project.
This one's being built here in
Oxie because I think it's kind
of a rough neighborhood, so
they need something to do.
And it's just another good
excuse to get Malmo another
skate park.
It's only 20 minutes away.
DAVID TOMS: I didn't really even
know where Malmo was when
I first got my job.
Just turned up here and
was blown away by the
skateboarding that I saw and the
DIY feel that was going on
here with Pontus building
spots everywhere.
The government really, really
encouraging of the scene.
They're just a really positive
towards the building of parks
and the acquisition
of money for the
skaters to build parks.
JEREMY BUTTERWORTH: We just
came out here with a few
things in mind.
And after years of experience
in building parks, we can
really plan and [INAUDIBLE].
It's a lot of fun.
And you get to be more creative,
where you just come
out with a spray paint can,
and just X on the ground.
All right, we're
starting here.
There's always more to add on
to some of the parks we've
build before.
So we're just going
to keep on going.
And we're never going to stop.
-Do you have a favorite
skate park here?
DAVID TOMS: I'd have
to say Stapel.
-Who rips that place
the hardest?
DAVID TOMS: Jeremy.
He's the man.
JOHN MAGNUSSON: This park was
started being planned 2001 and
was finished end of 2005.
One of the main goals for this
skate park was to make people
want to come here and explore
what we have, to make it grow
and make more people part
of the skate scene.
I moved to Malmo in 1998, mostly
because of skating,
because the big indoor
park just opened up.
The scene in Malmo in 1998 was
far away from where it is now.
There was this crew with
Tobias, Nils, Pontus,
[INAUDIBLE], John, really
tight crew of 20 people.
And they were kind of the guys
behind the indoor park also.
Three years after I moved down
to Malmo, we kind of started
to think together, the idea to
create something like the
indoor park but outside.
It's built and designed
by an American guy
called Stefan Hauser.
We've been working a lot with
skate parks ourself.
But this was kind of
knew, the concrete.
So we brought in someone that
we believed and help us out.
We want to have a little bit
inspiration from Burnside and
Santa Rosa.
At the moment, these concrete
parks in the States were
looking a lot of vertical.
So we said, don't build
everything vertical.
Trying to keep it a little
bit lower, make it
epic, a lot of flow.
My favorite part of the
park is everything.
And you can just skate it for
two hours, and you don't have
to do one single trick.
Check it out, my son's skating
it at the moment.
[SPEAKING SWEDISH]
I don't know.
He has 23 finger boards.
Everything here comes from the
skateboard organization called
Bryggeriet.
And we take care of
the outdoor parks,
Stapelbaddsparken and the
smaller Sibbarp Skatepark, and
the new one now.
The city pays us to
take care of it.
And we have a really good
cooperation with the city.
We had a lot of big events
here, like Quicksilver
Bowlriders and Malmo Ultra Bowl
and stuff, so that we do
it together with them.
NILS SVENSSON: How it's changed
here in Malmo, it's
hard to understand, really.
But the city is so into
what we're doing.
They have had so much positive
feedback that they just see it
as such a good way of
marketing Malmo.
And now when they design parks
and plazas and stuff, now they
think, yeah, of course we should
include skateboarding.
And it's worth a lot
for them, I think.
[SPEAKING SWEDISH]
-I read some stupid thing in
some skateboard magazine.
JOHN DAHLQUIST: I'm the teacher
here at the skateboard
part of Bryggeriets Gymnasium,
the high school
for skating in Malmo.
Right now, we have
142 students.
And it's three years,
16 to 18.
During school hours, it's
just students here.
And then the park
opens at 4:00.
They do a lot of skating.
And they skate from 9:00 in the
morning until they close
here at 9:00 at night.
At the beginning of first year,
we have something that
we call basic training.
But it shows pretty fast that
what's basic to one person is
not to another.
There's everything from beginner
to pro, pretty much.
There's room for everyone.
NILS SVENSSON: This place
generates a lot of talent and
keep skaters together.
The new generations are
the kids that are in
this school, I think.
[CHEERS]
FERNANDO BRAMSMARK: I think
I started to skate
in the sixth grade.
It's like four years, or
something like that.
-Did your parents give you a
hard time about coming to a
skateboarding high school?
FERNANDO BRAMSMARK:
I don't think so.
They only say, ah, enjoy.
Don't miss any lessons.
-What's your favorite class,
your favorite lesson?
FERNANDO BRAMSMARK: I think it's
skate, the skate lesson.
JOHN DAHLQUIST: There is two
street courses in the vert
ramp and the bowl.
They're served these great
state parks and great
opportunities.
I guess some of them think,
why would you want to go
street skate?
There's cracks in the streets
and ledges that aren't made
from steel.
Actually, I have to
sometimes yell at
people for not skating.
But I would never set
any rules to how
anyone should skate.
There's never a moment of
everyone having to do 10
kickflips, or anything
like that.
Skateboarding has to be free,
and never set any rules to how
someone's going to skate.
-[SPEAKING SWEDISH]
LOVE ENEROTH: It's kind of
unpopular, this spot.
If I propose that we go here to
someone, they're like, uh,
let's go somewhere else.
There used to be water.
And I don't know why there's
no water here now.
LOVE ENEROTH: My name is Love
Enertoth, co-founder of
Bellows Skateboards.
And I do the creative
graphics and stuff.
I moved here, like, '97 to
just pursue skating.
At that time, there wasn't
really any skate companies.
There was more like shops,
like G-Spot, for example.
Seven years ago, probably, I
went to Barcelona and sort of
stayed there, and went
to France, too.
And I was riding for Antiz.
-Was it tough leaving Antiz?
Or were you over it?
LOVE ENEROTH: Yeah, was tough,
because I was kind of getting
frustrated, not at them
but at my situation.
I didn't just want
to skateboard.
I wanted to do something
creative.
-Bellows is like a second
generation European company.
Or even third, right?
You know--
LOVE ENEROTH: The Cliche.
-They were the first,
and then Antiz.
And then now it's
like people--
LOVE ENEROTH: Now it's
a lot of companies.
We started out as a team.
It was actually me, Martin, and
Johan Florell, a friend of
ours who actually passed
away recently.
But it was us who started it
together, and with Mika.
We just brainstormed how
do we want a skateboard
company to feel like.
And so we came up with this.
You shake your head
really fast.
And then the flash will
freeze your face.
So we thought that it
would be funny to
do a series of portraits.
I think Mika had the
fever that day.
He couldn't shake his head,
so he was just blowing
air out of his lips.
The best skating here is, I
guess, the summer months from
probably May until the end of
September, like early October.
A lot of the spots
is in the summer.
So there's a few in
the downtown area,
but not that much.
So you've got to go on the
train for 20 minutes.
[SPEAKING SWEDISH]
LOVE ENEROTH: This is a
suburb of Stockholm.
And this is the backside of
where we're going to skate.
And I don't what this is.
Little kids just put
some shit here.
SARAH MEURLE: My name
is Sarah Meurle.
We're skating with my teammates
from Bellows and a
friend of ours called
Friedrich.
I came here at the beginning of
the summer, and I was out
skating with Mika every day.
He doesn't stop.
LOVE ENEROTH: We got
Sarah on the team.
She's like the first one who's
not from Stockholm.
Her board is coming
out, actually.
SARAH MEURLE: It's
going to be a--
LOVE ENEROTH: A sunflower.
SARAH MEURLE: --a sunflower
that Love had drawn.
I went to school and all
the boys were skating.
And I thought it seemed
really fun.
And I just kept on skating
with the other boys.
If you go to my house,
it's on a dirt road.
And there's nothing
at all to skate.
So in the attic, me and my dad
built a little quarter pipe
just next to my room, a small
little bank on the other side
so you could kind of
go back and forth.
I got sponsored by Streetlab,
the skate shop in Malmo.
But I was small.
But it was really fun.
And I skated for them for
a couple of years.
And then I started to
get other sponsors.
The first time I was on
an airplane was 2
and 1/2 years ago.
And since then, I've been
to so many places.
-All because of skating?
SARAH MEURLE: Yeah,
pretty much.
-That's a pretty good deal.
SARAH MEURLE: Yeah.
GREGER HAGELIN: I think
it's Friday afternoon.
It's like people
are still here.
Yeah, hey, bro, [INAUDIBLE].
-[INAUDIBLE].
GREGER HAGELIN: [INAUDIBLE]
was one of the guys
that we met back
in the days in G-Spot.
He was a great skateboarder
back then.
-Still am.
GREGER HAGELIN: Still
am, yeah.
So we met back in the day.
So now he works here.
There's a lot of old
skateboarders working here, or
young skateboarder, whatever
you want to say.
Down here, we have the financial
department, the
design department, and the
marketing department.
And this is what we call
our lounge room.
You guys play ping pong?
Skateboarding is the most
important subculture ever.
If you've been skateboarding for
10 years, whatever you do
with the rest of your life,
you're going to still have the
same mentality, always remember
being a skateboarder.
My generation, a lot of those
guys got into it because it
was kind of trendy.
Then it died out.
After that, I started my own
skateboard company, actually a
mail-order company out
of my apartment named
Bam, Backside Airmail.
Called Backside Airmail, Bam,
and our amazing stuff and make
sure it get the best skateboard
products in three
to four days.
And that the [INAUDIBLE]
skateboard staff was
me, myself, and I.
But It was kind of funny,
because all the skaters in
Sweden called and they were
like, you almost become a
friend to everybody.
It's like, hi, how are you?
Me and Pontus started working
together back in '93.
I actually had a skateboard camp
down in Gothenburg, and
Pontus was there.
Pontus Karlsson actually
had his own mail order.
And we started talking, maybe
we should open up a
distribution company together
and open up a store.
The reason why starting
G-Spot was [INAUDIBLE]
skateboarding and have
a good time.
And making money wasn't
that important.
We did a lot of crazy stuff.
But we've never been doing
anything to be mean.
To be in Sweden, you could
actually do whatever.
Of course, the police came and
knocked on the door and told
us to stop selling liquor
and not have parties.
But we didn't really
give a shit.
-Was G-Spot known as
the best shop?
JEAN-PASCAL STRUWER: It was the
only shop to begin with.
Through hanging out at the
G-Spot skate stop, I got to
know all the skaters and
the cliques that
were hanging out there--
Jens Andersson, Pontus Karlsson,
Pelle Fredell, a
couple more.
Actually, I made the
first video.
It was called "G-Spot
Forever."
JENS ANDERSSON: Early '90s,
the core group of
skateboarders in Stockholm
couldn't be
more than 25, 30 people.
Skateboarding was really
in for a change there.
And it was really ugly, fashion
wise and tricks wise.
The natural street skateboarding
scene in
Stockholm has never
been that good.
It has a very poor
architecture for
skateboarding.
MARTIN KARLSSON: The ground is
rough, so mini ramps was where
people learned how to skate.
JEAN-PASCAL STRUWER: Right now,
we are in a park called
[INAUDIBLE], which is a
legendary skate spot in the
Stockholm skate scene.
It was one of the places where
we hung out during the
summertime.
We would go to this mini ramp
and buy beers and hang out and
laugh and have fun.
JENS ANDERSSON: In the early
days of Stockholm street
skating, there was people from
different social backgrounds.
I mean, there were people
from the really
upscale parts of Stockholm.
And there were people from
the more rougher
neighborhoods as well.
MARTIN KARLSSON: Some of the
skaters moved in from
different parts of Sweden, and
we lived collectively.
It was a strange period.
No one really knows how anyone
got by financially.
JENS ANDERSSON: Sell some
boards, some sweatshirts, and
maybe sell something
else as well.
Well, the main spot, for
sure, was Sheraton
Hotel, as we call it.
But it's not really part
of Sheraton Hotel.
It's just a delivery area
for some shops.
It was outdoor but still
has a ceiling over it.
So you were able to skate
there all year round.
But there was these high metal
curbs and a manual
pad, and that's it.
And everybody was skating there
10 hours a day, and
coming in from all over Sweden
just to skate this spot.
[CLAPPING]
MARTIN KARLSSON: You get that?
Always when you cut yourself
down here, you're like, what
was that I cut myself on?
JENS ANDERSSON: And you kind
of remember the feeling you
had when you were skating
back then.
-When we looked at the book "The
Sheraton Years," that was
like the golden age for you
guys in terms of fun?
GREGER HAGELIN: It was, like,
I mean, there's four
generations of skateboarding.
Jens did send that book to me.
So I it at my office in LA.
And I opened that book-- it
was a Friday afternoon--
and started reading it.
And I started to remember.
And I started feeling really
sad, because skateboarding was
very small at that time.
And the same crowd of people
went to every contest, went to
every spot, went out drinking
every night together.
And it was a very, very special
time, for sure.
JENS ANDERSSON: There
was a lot of
pictures to choose from.
And we decided to go with the
more insecure teenager on the
way of growing up kind
of direction.
I never really had an intention
of being a skate
photographer.
But at the time, I always had
a camera in my backpack,
shooting regularly just
the people around me.
Rather than trying to get the
perfect skate photo, I'm just
trying to document the time
we were spending together.
There was definitely a turning
point when the new
skate park opened up.
JENS ANDERSSON: YMCA.
The chief for the YMCA, he was
really into doing stuff for
kids and teens, and trying
to put his mind
into subcultural stuff.
MARTIN KARLSSON: So we had
something for the graffiti
people and for the
skateboarders.
And he even had a pub for
skinheads down in the basement.
They had taken skateboards from
the skateboarders and
snapped them in half and
put them on the wall.
That was how crazy it
was, that place.
Ali Boulala, back then he was
so lightweight, so small he
could jump down anything.
When we started skating with
him, he cried every time he
skated, because he was so
frustrated when he didn't
skate good enough.
You know, he was a huge Mike
Carroll fan at this time.
I think this is the day
after he watched
the Chocolate video.
And Mike Carroll does the
feeble in Hubba Hideout.
And he's just like, oh,
I got to do that.
And he learned it.
But he was always really aware
of what was going on in
skateboarding, trick-wise,
style-wise.
He always made the
right moves.
Greger drinking 40s,
Santa Monica beach.
JENS ANDERSSON: The G-Spot era,
I think that was very
important to the fact that skate
wing was getting back in
the limelight again.
And it was really cool.
And there was different
companies that could offer
money and sponsor stuff.
We could step out of
the garage, you
know, out of the darkness.
-Would you bring a lot of the
skaters to the ASR Trade Show
in Long Beach?
GREGER HAGELIN: Yeah, sure.
It's like our team, we used
to bring them there.
So [INAUDIBLE], Andreas,
Ali Boulala, and
all those guys, yeah.
Back then it was like we were
part of this business
just to have fun.
And then we did that business
from '93 to '99.
And then we decided
start up WESC.
This is a collaboration we do
with Be@rbricks, Medicom Toys.
And going to be released
in January.
You're from New York, so you'll
probably know Stash.
-Yes.
GREGER HAGELIN: He's From
Brooklyn as well.
And this is a pair
of his denim.
But this is with a gold
thread in it.
And if you should sell
them, should
probably cost about $5,000.
So we don't sell those.
Then we had G-Spot.
G was for a Swedish
word and name.
[SWEDISH]
is like all of us together.
And then [INAUDIBLE], it's
actually the same
feeling about us.
I came down to [INAUDIBLE],
that skateboard place.
And my son, he was 12 at that
time, and he was down there
skateboarding.
And every good skateboarder he
saw came up, hi, how are you?
How are you?
And he's like, how can you
know all those guys?
Yeah, that's skateboarding.
It's like you met them once,
and you know them for life.
-Is your son aware of all the
generations of skateboarding?
Does he see all the
old pictures.
GREGER HAGELIN: He's 13.
He thinks everyone
back then sucked.
Of course, it's like in 10 years
from now, he'll probably
respect it, but you know.
-Yeah, that's typical.
-Pelle Fredell, he's my
father, Pelle Fredell.
He gives me everything
I want, man.
-[SPEAKING SWEDISH]