In between takes, the girls
would blast, like, pop music,
and Drake and stuff,
and dance.
They would be doing that mostly
to keep themselves up
and keep themselves in character
and the momentum.
Selena's character
is a little more
naive, and more religious.
The other girls are
super hardcore.
I mostly knew her at that point
from just peripherally,
and from her show on Disney.
But it seems to have built over
the course of the making
of this film into something
approaching mania.
I think she was nervous to do
this sequence, because it
required a lot of dudes
rubbing up on her.
I don't think she'd ever
had that happen, so
it was pretty intense.
I remember there were a lot of
dudes wanting to hump her, but
she was a trooper.
Looks like Vanessa and
Ashley in ski masks.
The pink ski masks with the
unicorn patches was their
robbing mode.
Kind of [INAUDIBLE] gangster.
The real robbery scene, where
they're robbing tourists and
stuff, they were pretty
amped up.
I usually shoot the scene from
beginning to end, and just let
them go through it
all in real time.
And so it was really like
they were doing it.
This is the girls getting
arrested, the
party at the motel.
And this was hard, because there
was paparazzi around,
and sometimes there would
be more people
around than crew members.
There's Selena and Rachel.
Rachel was kind of trying to
protect her, I think, in real
life and it even just became a
character trait in the film.
They kind of became
close friends.
-[INAUDIBLE] miss something
out there.
HARMONY KORINE: Selena is crying
in this sequence, and
she was freaked out
in real life.
I didn't tell her about what
was going to happen.
This was something that I'd
been saving in my mind for
about three or four
months before.
I didn't want her to
be prepared for it.
I didn't want her to be thinking
about it, so we just
kind of threw it on her.
And she was pretty freaked to
do the sequence, but I think
it's her best scene
in the movie.