[MUSIC PLAYING]
JACK: Babe, it was a joke.
What do you want?
You want me out of the car?
JILL: Oh, see.
Now you're just being silly.
Always, Jack, you go too far.
Always you take things
too far by one step.
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
-Hello, sir.
JACK: Hey there.
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
JACK: And I'll get this
as well, thanks.
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
JACK: Thanks.
-Thank you.
JILL: I don't believe it.
I don't believe I give
in for chocolate.
That's so lame.
[SCREAMING]
Oh my god!
JACK: Oh shit!
[INAUDIBLE]
It's OK.
JILL: Shit!
There's a fucking spider!
JACK: It's OK.
JILL: Get it off me.
JACK: Hey.
JILL: Get it off.
JACK: Calm down.
It's fake.
It's a toy.
Look, look.
-Oh my god.
What happened?
[SIRENS]
-I was driving, driving
down from [INAUDIBLE].
[INAUDIBLE]
-Give me some room.
JACK: Is she-- she gonna--
-Hello, can you hear me?
Mate, just take a little
step back.
[INAUDIBLE] some
oxygen on you.
-Dolly, look at me.
We're going to put some
oxygen on you, OK?
JACK: Is she going to be OK?
-What's her name, mate?
JACK: Her name's Jill.
-Jill.
Jill?
-Come on, mate.
OK?
JACK: OK.
-Big, big, deep breaths,
sweetheart.
[INAUDIBLE]
Keep your eyes on me.
Yeah, that's right.
Just take deep breaths.
Just keep looking at me.
JACK: Jill.
[INAUDIBLE] mate, just
give us a break.
All right, buddy?
Just stand back.
-Just stand back, just
a couple of steps.
We'd really appreciate
it, mate.
-Now can you talk to me and
tell me where do you
feel the most pain?
Jill?
Jill, it's OK.
Keep breathing.
Keep your eyes focused
on me, sweetheart.
[MUSIC PLAYING]