RYAN DUFFY: Whereas in America,
hip-hop long ago
migrated from the ghettos to
the gated communities, in
Venezuela it's all of the guns,
none of the glamour, and
more of the violence.
So we headed back to Petare to
meet up with El Prieto, the
king of Venezuelan hip-hop.
EL PRIETO: [RAPPING IN SPANISH]
RYAN DUFFY: As a former member
of the massively popular
hip-hop collective Guerrilla
Seca, Prieto commands the
respect of Petare and was an
ideal insider tour guide
through the city's most
dangerous slums.
Did you just catch that teenager
with a handgun?
MALE SPEAKER 1: Did
you just see that?
MALE SPEAKER 2: He's
our security.
RYAN DUFFY: Oh, he's
with security.
All right.
Don't worry.
The teenager with the handgun
is our security apparently.
We headed up to El Prieto's
house where his underage
security detail was
standing guard.
How are you doing?
I'll shake that hand without
the gun in it.
Can you talk a little bit about
the way that growing up
here has influenced
your music career?
EL PRIETO: [SPEAKING SPANISH]
RYAN DUFFY: Sorry, that little
child has a huge gun.
Right behind that wall.
Sorry, it's a little
bit distracting.
EL PRIETO: [SPEAKING SPANISH]
RYAN DUFFY: It's not something
I'm used to
seeing all the time.
I understand it's different
for you.
EL PRIETO: [SPEAKING SPANISH]
MALE SPEAKER 3:
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
EL PRIETO: [SPEAKING SPANISH]
RYAN DUFFY: Considering all
the 13-year-olds we saw
carrying guns, this seemed like
a reasonable prediction.
Before we left, Prieto quieted
the streets so he could show
off his freestyle skills.
EL PRIETO: [RAPPING IN SPANISH]
RYAN DUFFY:
[MUSIC PLAYING]
RYAN DUFFY: Prieto's optimism
was a nice closing note.
But he was also flanked
by a bunch of guys
with guns at the time.
While all these guns look great
in his music videos, in
the streets of Caracas they're
a terrifying reminder of
Venezuela's epidemic of
violence, and could very well
be the undoing of Chavez's
socialist revolution.
[MUSIC PLAYING]