RAY LATYPOV: My brother,
Nurulla.
JIM DIMASCIO: I came aboard
serving as our Chief Operating
Officer in charge of marketing,
and Ray serves as
our CEO, and Nurulla serves as
our Chief Technology Officer.
Ray and Nurulla, they invented
Virtusphere for the immersive
and virtual reality
experience.
The Virtusphere is a new,
innovative technology that
really is a locomotion
simulator.
And just to define locomotion,
it doesn't have anything to do
with trains, but the
movement of people.
The ability of being able to get
inside and walk or run in
a north, east, south,
or west direction.
It's a 10-foot sphere in its
diameter, and sits on a round
base of 11 sections of steel.
So it's affectionately
nicknamed the
hamster ball for humans.
Virtusphere could really bring
a brand new experience.
And again, not to keep going
back, but also to get some
exercise, so that you're not
just sitting at your PC in a
chair for extended periods of
time, whether it be one hour
or four hours.
But once you're inside
Virtusphere, you're really
going to get an interactive
experience with exercise.
And that's a win-win in today's
modern economy.
It's actually been a very
effective start, as we are a
true start-up in the new
locomotion simulation business.
We're very excited to have you
here today, and we're very
much looking forward to showing
you our technology.
And now we're approaching the
office of Virtusphere, And
very excited to get everybody's
impression of our
Virtusphere technology.
This is Virtusphere.
This is how it works.
A person can get inside,
and can start walking.
And change directions, which
is much different than a
conventional treadmill.
You can go in any direction,
and with a little practice,
you can jog.
And that's the physics of
Virtusphere, and that's just
the beginning.
A person can get exercise,
as you can even tell.
After a person gets out of
Virtusphere, you know you've
gotten a little bit
of a work out.
But that's just the physics of
Virtusphere, and how you can
walk or right.
Now what we're going to show
you is the technology part,
and this is the real fun part.
Hey, Ray.
Hey, Nurulla.
JIM DIMASCIO: Sounds good.
RAY LATYPOV: Here's our--
to go inside.
Should we close that?
JIM DIMASCIO: Today, most people
play the game via their
couch, their PC monitor,
their desk chair.
But with Virtusphere, you truly
get immersed into your
virtual reality experience.