who uh... respects people's individual
rights that's why did you know outfits
from now
on the rights of a number of issues and
uh... one of the main issue based on the
come on the right side is civil
liberties of course that film strikes at
as opposition to the confirmation of
uh... of bread
uh... in arizona talk about sal
the about
the g_o_p_ an evangelical being to deter
to go to war
i'd like to hear
i think that it is important that what
we talk about war
that i think part of republicans
problems and frankly it a true some in
the evangelical christian movement i
think it appeared to be here for war
i tell them you know when i read the new
testament and when i read about jesus i
don't see men being involved he was
really involved with the war of his days
in fact people rebuked him for not being
the king they wanted they wanted
somebody stand up to the romans
blessed are the peacemakers not listed
on the war makers
that is about four hours
i did not see that coming did you think
you're going to do that i was gonna be
some lip service he but right at them
and use their own uh... bible against
them it sounds just rational enough to
eliminate any chance he has a huge
kicking out and
yes that's the only reason tracklisting
do you start going its own writings
chances those rationale is he doing that
financial reports did when he was in the
dates
and i remember watching it missed before
i get really political river him saying
line against nation building outside
what is even talking about
take a look it up but that meant and of
course as soon as he became president he
started nation building so is this that
i'm going to make uh... plead to the
moderates on the libertarians out there
to make them think i'm not a war monger
then as soon as he becomes president of
a war monger
added up the estate
aramony's seems to me that catalyst your
desire to lose the magellan also their
vote for it offered as opposed to the
reporting
soul maybe he's doing that they will
restrain you get the middle to come
what regarding the presidency has
captured by military vessel
yeah it was as a democrat
republican
or maybe even a bit the libertarian i
don't know uh...
they're good war monger hazardous so
much money the
today
yes uh... with escaping it
uh... with with ron paul on this issue
uh... at least easily get allot of
sympathy
everyone because who is really fear of
the warranty other that those were were
permitted to making money on that
and how still he's approx removes cell
dollars so maybe you want to the
campaign contributions
but he would get uh... support from
republicans issue
and i think
uh... he's reposition himself
pretty well because
just in terms of style as appearance
his dad kar raha seemed a little bit
uh... means losing presidential directly
since he was a small blouses for us to
package whatever it is the susie you
happiest of people into some of them
program policies
livermore livermore brother prosperity
and if you can't just say about saint
james' steam yet
perhaps the middle
to cometh inside
had a remarkable work there is a
franchise with the government could like
people like me compensate for the
government
i'm sick of uh... the democrats
increase you mean this plot
government that we have whatever the
problem and and samson yes
uh... that we can't even on an issue
where ninety percent of the american
people are for like backwards
we're not gonna get a because reno we
live in a blue talk with the right this
is one of the talk was it looks like
ladies and gentlemen one the american
people overwhelmingly want something and
they don't get why because
there's a handful of people with money
you don't want a and that's it
philosophically manholes
striking the right time to reposition
himself well
now is a reading stories playing i think
in twenty sixteen an
who knows practical
pride when that battle anyway
i think he's
the smart about it
i'd like to strike at the center you
know if i can assure disrespect in
tennessee but i think that you might be
interesting to groups their think that
fishery that he
would in some my pathetic will sense get
the support it but one i think that you
might be addressing the willingness of
the republican base to be whipped up
into a frenzy of fear over say iran may
be in the next couple of years like they
gathered or war now but i think that
they can be convinced like a war in the
next couple of years and also he will
lose but he said the donors but he's
also been a lose the media lately has
already and from what i've seen a lot
like krauthammer bill kristol things
like that i think he's already lost
foxnews and i think that in america for
the most part another people support the
people there told the support let me or
twelve year old girl you like to pop
stars are told like and when you are
voting a republican nominating contest i
think that you support the people you
told the support
i think that it'll be too easy for them
the cast him as just as crazy as from
paul in fox news over the course of next
two years nude howard dean
lot of people love them but they cast
his grades aren't many losses on a
supporter i was very easy when it is the
military industrial complex and they got
rid of them right away
saying wait a bigotry eliot spitzer he
went against wall street they got rid of
him right away and he has every
nefarious waiting given be they were
using of the patriot act to get him for
being in a person's unbelievable that is
crazy will see it
forty agree with the u_n_ and we'll see
and i think what brand policy try to do
is write you know circumvent all of that
but directly to the people are saying
that'll be democracy inaction but will
see i but i think
your largely correct that
he doesn't have the donors he doesn't
have fox news
he can't win the nomination