TODAY. FRANKLY, DOESN'T NEED TO COME ACROSS
IN THE ECOLOGY
SECTION BECAUSE A BIG PART OF WHAT I'M PRESENTING
TODAY
IS ETHOLOGY. THE SCIENCE OF ANIMAL BEHAVIOR.
I'M PRESENTING
IT HERE IN ECOLOGY BECAUSE I DO THINK IT FITS.
AND I THINK THE
LINK BETWEEN ETHOLOGY AND ECOLOGY CAN BE MADE
STRONGER AND
WILL BE MADE STRONGER IN COMING YEARS. BUT
ALSO, YOU DON'T GET
ETHOLOGY IN ANY OTHER PLACE IN THIS COURSE
OR REALLY IT'S HARD TO
GET IN AN INTRODUCTORY COURSE IN THE DEPARTMENT.
WE'VE GOOD
ADVANCED COURSES IN IT. SO I THOUGHT IT WAS
IMPORTANT TO BRING IN.
BUT I CANNOT CUT BACK ON IT AND THAT IS SOME
OF WHAT GOES TODAY.
I'M GOING TO START BY LOOKING AT THE LEVELS
OF ORGANIZATION
CONCEPT. IT'S THIS ORIENTING GENERALIZATION
THAT'S USED IN
BIOLOGY FOR DEMARCATING THE BOUNDARIES BETWEEN
FIELDS OR
DEMARCATING BOUNDARIES BETWEEN NATURAL PHENOMENON
OF THINGS WE
STUDY. WE'LL GO OVER THAT FIRST. AND THEN
LOOK AT THE FIELD OF
ETHOLOGY. I TEND TO STUDY ANIMALS MORE THAN
I STUDY PLANTS SO
YOU GET A BIAS FROM ME TOWARD ANIMALS. BIO
1B HAS BEEN BIASED TOWARD PLANTS AND
I'LL TRY NOT TO MAKE NOT TO MAKE
APOLOGIES FOR MY OWN BIAS TOWARD ANIMAL. A
LOT OF EXAMPLES YOU'LL GET ARE
FROM ANIMALS. ETHOLOGY THE SCIENCE OF INDIVIDUAL
BEHAVIOR, OR
THE SCIENCE OF ANIMAL BEHAVIOR IS REALLY FOCUSED
ON ANIMALS
BECAUSE BEHAVIOR REALLY, ANIMALS ARE OUTWARDLY
MUCH MORE
COMPLEX THAN PLANTS ARE. YOU CAN SPEAK OF
PLANT BEHAVIOR OF THE
EXTERNAL ACTIVITY OF A PLANT. THAT'S IT'S
BEHAVIOR IF YOU
DEFINE BEHAVIOR IN THAT WAY. BUT REALLY ETHOLOGY
IS THE FIELD
OF STUDY OF ANIMALS. WE'LL LOOK AT EXAMPLES,
TIME PERMITTING, OF LEARNING
PROBLEM SOLVING COGNITION AND THEIR RELATIONSHIP
TO ECOLOGY. HOPEFULLY
GETTING INTO SOME BEHAVIOR ECOLOGY AND OPTIMAL
ORIGIN, IDEAS AND
FINISHING WITH THE ECOLOGY OF SOCIAL GROUPS.
I WILL MOVE BRISKLY TO TRY TO GET THROUGH
THIS MATERIAL.
A LOT OF IT IS JUST FUN, STICKING WITH THE
THEME OF TRYING NOT TO GO TOO FAST IN TERMS
OF INFORMATION COVERED IN THE BEGINNING OF
THIS COURSE. SO LET'S
JUST HAVE FUN AND LOOK AT PICTURES AND THINK
ABOUT THESE
IDEAS.
WHAT I REALLY HOPE IS YOU'LL THINK ABOUT IT
AFTER CLASS AND
DISCUSS IT IN YOUR DISCUSSIONS AND LABS, SOME
OF THESE IDEAS.
THE LEVELS OF ORGANIZATION CONCEPT. YOU GO
TO ALMOST ANY BIOLOGY
TEXTBOOK AND YOU'LL SEE SOMETHING ABOUT THE
BIOLOGICAL HIERARCHY
OR CONCEPT OF LEVELS OF ORGANIZATION. IT'S
THE WAY WE ORIENT
OURSELVES IN SCIENCE OFTEN. OUR DEPARTMENTS
ARE DIVIDED ON THE
BASIS OF THE STUDY OF THESE DIFFERENT LEVELS.
JOURNALS ARE
DEDICATED TO THE STUDY OF THE PHENOMENON AT
VARIOUS LEVELS HERE. AND IN THE PHILOSOPHICAL
SENSE
THIS SCHEME, THIS HIERARCHY IS THOUGHT TO
REPRESENT THE ONTOLOGY
OF NATURE, THE ACTUAL STRUCTURE OF EMPIRICAL
NATURE. SO WE LOOK
AT IT HERE TO TRY TO DETERMINE WHERE WE'RE
WORKING. AND WHAT
ECOLOGISTS STUDY IN THIS HIERARCHY. YOU HAVE
AT THE ONE EXTREME
ATOMS, THE BUILDING BLOCKS OF MOLECULES WHICH
THEMSELVES GO INTO
THE COMPOSITION AND CONSTRUCTION OF THE ORGANELLES,
THAT BUILD
THE CELLS, THAT ARE THE FUNDAMENTAL BUILDING
BLOCKS OF ORGANISMAL
STRUCTURE. VARIOUS CELL TYPES CONSTRUCTED
INTO TISSUES AND THE
TISSUES THEMSELVES ASSEMBLED INTO ORGAN SYSTEMS
THAT MAKE UP AN
ORGANISM. SO ONCE WE GET TO THIS HALF OF THE
HIERARCHY, WITH
THE ORGANISM AS A SORT OF A PIVOT BETWEEN
THESE LOWER LEVELS, THESE LOWER
AND SMALLER AND INCLUDED LEVELS WITHIN THE
ORGANISM, WE EXTEND IT ABOVE THE ORGANISM
TO ECOLOGICAL SYSTEMS
TO GROUPS OF ORGANISMS AND THEIR ENVIRONMENTS.
THAT IS A TREE. IT'S HERE. IT'S MAYBE A MAPLE
TREE, SOME
KIND OF MAPLE. IT'S AN INDIVIDUAL ORGANISM.
THAT IS ONE
INDIVIDUAL. IT'S A PLANT, IT'S A TREE, IT'S
A MAPLE TREE. IN
OUR HIERARCHY, THAT WOULD CONSTITUTE AN ORGANISM,
RIGHT?
HAVE A BUNCH OF THEM TOGETHER IN A SMALL FOREST,
YOU HAVE A
POPULATION. IF WE'RE SPEAKING OF THE SAME
SPECIES OF MAPLE, THIS
IS A POPULATION OF ORGANISMS. WE TEND TO USE
THAT TERM ONLY
WITH REFERENCE TO MEMBERS OF SAME SPECIES.
BUT POPULATIONS DO
NOT EXIST IN ISOLATION. THEY EXIST AS COMMUNITIES
OF ORGANISMS,
OF MULTIPLE POPULATIONS. NOT ONLY ARE THERE
THE MAPLES BUT THERE
ARE THE OTHER SPECIES OF TREE, THERE ARE MICE
AND DEER IN THE
SYSTEM. BIRDS OVERHEAD. MICROBES IN THE SOIL,
EARTHWORMS,
THIS IS A COMMUNITY OF MANY POPULATIONS, MANY
SPECIES COEXISTING
IN A SINGLE LOCAL. YOUR EMPHASIS MIGHT BE
NOT JUST THE
BIOLOGICAL COMMUNITY OF THAT SYSTEM BUT THE
INTERACTING
BIOLOGICAL AND ABIOTIC SYSTEM. I'LL JUST HAVE
TO AVOID WRITING
ON THE BOARD TODAY.
THIS INTERACTING COMMUNITY OF ABIOTIC SYSTEM
IS WHAT PEOPLE
CALL AN ECOSYSTEM. OR A LANDSCAPE OR A SEASCAPE.
THIS
INTERACTING, BIOLOGICAL AND PHYSICAL SYSTEM
OFTEN TAKEN AT THIS
SCALE, A LARGE-SCALE.
AND SCALE IT UP FURTHER AND YOU HAVE THE WHOLE
EARTH, YOU
HAVE THE BIOSPHERE OR ECOSPHERE, ALL THE WORLD'S
ECOSYSTEMS AND
LANDSCAPES PUT TOGETHER.
THAT'S ALL FINE. I ONLY HAVE ONE DIFFICULTY
WITH THIS
FORMAT REALLY. AND IT'S A PARTLY A RESULT
OF THE EVOLUTION OF
OUR LANGUAGE AND OUR TERMS. BECAUSE PEOPLE
USE THE WORD
ECOSYSTEM QUITE A LOT THESE DAYS TO REFER
TO ANY OF THESE LEVELS. YOU
WILL HEAR SOMETIMES ABOUT THE CELLULAR ECOSYSTEM
OR YOUR OWN
PERSONAL ECOSYSTEM. YOU AS AN INDIVIDUAL.
OR WE CAN SPEAK OF
ECOSYSTEM OF THIS CLASSROOM. RIGHT? BECAUSE
ALL OF THESE
BIOLOGICAL LEVELS EXIST IN A PHYSICAL CONTEXT.
YOU CAN'T
SEPARATE A BIOLOGICAL PHENOMENON FROM ITS
ABIOTIC CONDITIONS AND
ITS ABIOTIC ENVIRONMENT. THEY'RE INSEPERABLE.
IN THAT SENSE
EVERYBODY BIOLOGICAL PHENOMENON IS ALSO A
ECOLOGICAL SYSTEM OR
FOR SHORT, AN ECOSYSTEM. JUST RECOGNIZE THAT
THEY'RE REALLY TWO
USES OF THAT WORD THAT ARE EVOLVING. ONE,
A DESCRIPTION OF THAT PARTICULAR LEVEL ALWAYS
BETTER BELOW A LANDSCAPE *SYNONAMOUS WITH
A LANDSCAPE AND BELOW THE BIOSPHERE. ANOTHER
MORE BROAD DEFINITION OF ECO
SYSTEM, AS A SHORTHAND FOR ECOLOGICAL SYSTEM.
WHEN WE USE IT
THAT WAY IN THAT BROAD SENSE WE'RE PERFECTLY
JUSTIFIED IN
REFERRING TO A SAY CELLULAR ECOSYSTEM.
I WON'T FOCUS ON THESE. THESE ARE JUST A COUPLE
OF TEXTBOOK EXAMPLES OF HOW THE
HIERARCHY MIGHT BE PRESENTED. SHORT ON TIME.
I'LL JUST
DELIVER THOSE TO YOU ON YOUR SLIDES. LOOKING
AT THIS ONE, WE
CAN PLAY A LITTLE GAME. I DON'T THINK PEOPLE
CAN SEE MY LASER
POINTER IN THE ADJOINING ROOMS. WHAT WOULD
THIS BE AN EXAMPLE
OF? IT'S NOT A GREAT PICTURE EXAMPLE, I WOULDN'T
THINK. BUT OF OUR LEVELS,
GIVEN WHAT ELSE YOU SEE HERE, CONTEXT. WHAT
WOULD THIS BE? A POPULATION.
IT'S A FAMILY. PROBABLY. IT'S A MOTHER AND
OFFSPRING BUT,
YEAH, IT'S A POPULATION. IF YOU CAN FOCUS
ON A POPULATION AT
ANY SCALE REALLY. WHETHER IT'S JUST FOUR OR
FIVE INDIVIDUALS,
PARENT AND OFFSPRING OR ALL THE SPECIES OF
FIELD MOUSE IN THAT AREA,
THAT WOULD BE THE POPULATION. THAT WOULD MAKE
THIS SUGGEST THAT
THIS IS THE COMMUNITY, RIGHT. MANY SPECIES
OF ORGANISM, *FAMILIADS
IN THE RAINFOREST WITH THEIR TREES AND FROGS
THAT ARE LIVING INSIDE THEM AND THE INSECTS
THAT ARE FLITTING ABOUT AND SO FORTH. THIS
WOULD BE AN ECOSYSTEM BECAUSE YOU HAVE
WATER THERE, I GUESS, AND SKY ABOVE REPRESENTING
THE ABIOTIC ENVIRONMENT. AND
THE INTERACTION OF THE WHOLE COMMUNITY OF
THE ABIOTIC ENVIRONMENT. THIS REPRESENTING
A
LANDSCAPE IN THIS CONTEXT. A LANDSCAPE, SOMETIMES
A TERM USED TO REFER TO MULTIPLE
ECOSYSTEMS AND THEIR INTERACTION. SO BE FLEXIBLE.
THAT'S ACTUALLY A HARD
LESSON TO LEARN COMING INTO BIOLOGY, IS THE
DEFINITIONS IN
BIOLOGY AND BOUNDARIES ARE OFTEN MUCH MORE
FUZZY THAN IN PHYSICS
OR CHEMISTRY. THAT'S THE REALITY OF BIOLOGICAL
PHENOMENON.
THEY EXIST VERY OFTEN WITH FUZZY BOUNDARIES
SO YOU NEED TO BE
FLEXIBLE WITH YOUR DEFINITIONS. WE CAN'T FORGET
THE WHOLE EARTH AND ITS ROLE, RIGHT.
GETTING INTO ETHOLOGY ABRUPTLY. THE SCIENCE
OF ANIMAL BEHAVIOR. IT
REALLY CAME TO FORM WITH THE WORK OF THESE
THREE INDIVIDUALS.
VON FRISH, LORENZ AND TINBERGEN, THREE EUROPEANS
WORKING VARIOUSLY IN THE EARLY AND MID AND
LATE 1900S. WHO WERE RECOGNIZED IN THE '70S
FOR THE
CONTRIBUTION THAT THEY'VE MADE. NOT RECOGNIZED
SO MUCH DURING
THEIR MOST ACTIVE PERIODS OF WORK BUT MUCH
LATER WITH NOBEL PRIZE FOR
THEIR WORK IN ANIMAL BEHAVIOR. THEY WERE CREDITED
WITH HAVING ADVANCED
THE STUDY OF ORGANISMAL BEHAVIOR BEYOND AN
OLDER AND STUBBORN DICHOTOMY BETWEEN VITALISTS
AND
MECHANISTS WHO REALLY WERE AT LOGGERHEADS
AND STRUGGLING TO MAKE
STRONG INROADS IN TERMS OF THE EXPERIMENTAL
AND FIELD STUDY OF ANIMAL
BEHAVIOR. ONE OF THE MAIN CONTRIBUTIONS OF
THESE GUYS WAS TO COUCH
THE STUDY OF ANIMAL BEHAVIOR IN AN EVOLUTIONARY
CONTEXT. TO ASK
QUESTIONS ABOUT BEHAVIOR IN THE CONTEXT OF
EVOLUTION AND ECOLOGY.
SO A COUPLE EXAMPLES OF THEIR WORK. STARTING
WITH VON
FRISH AND HIS STUDY OF HONEY BEES AND THEIR
COMMUNICATION.
THESE SLIDES ARE NOT, THESE TOPICS ARE NOT
PART OF YOUR
READING. THEY'RE IN YOUR BOOK SO YOU'RE WELCOME
TO REFER TO
YOUR PARTS OF YOUR BOOK THAT COVER THEM. BUT
THEY ARE NOT PART OF YOUR ASSIGNED READING.
THIS IS ALL TOO INTERESTING
JUST TO SKIP. I'M NOT SURE WHAT'S MORE AMAZING?
THAT BEES
ACTUALLY DO THIS OR THAT THIS GUY DISCOVERED
THIS. REALLY
FANTASTIC THE WAY HONEYBEES COMMUNICATE KNOWLEDGE
OF THEIR
ENVIRONMENTS. AND SPECIFICALLY THEIR FOOD
RESOURCES WHEN THEY
GET BACK TO THE HIVE. A BEE COMES BACK TO
THE HIVE AND IT'S A
BIG BUZZ OF ACTIVITY AND EVERYONE IS HUDDLING
AROUND WATCHING THE
BEE DANCE. IF IT'S SORT OF A ROUND DANCE LIKE
THIS, IT INDICATES THAT FOOD IS VERY CLOSE
BY AND GO SEE THIS FOOD..
WITHOUT MUCH ADDITIONAL INSTRUCTION. BUT IF
THE BEE PERFORMS A
A DANCE MORE STRUCTURED WITH THESE SEMI-CIRCLES
OF MOVEMENT, AND THEN THIS
LONG LINE WHERE IT WAGGLES, IT'S GIVING SPECIFIC
INFORMATION TO THE VIEWER ABOUT WHERE THE
FOOD SOURCE IS IN
RELATION TO THE SUN, IN RELATION TO THE POSITION
OF THE HIVE
ITSELF. SOMETHING ABOUT ITS DISTANCE GIVEN
THE DURATION OF THAT
LINEAR WAGGLE DANCE. IT COMMUNICATE THAT'S
TO THE OTHER BEES
AND OFF THEY GO. IF IT WAGGLES LONG, ALONG
THAT LINEAR
STRETCH THE NEXT BEE KNOWS TO FLY QUITE FAR
AND OFF IT GOES. JUST
INCREDIBLE.
HARD WON INFORMATION FROM VERY PATIENT OBSERVATION
UNDER A
HOT SUN, GETTING STUNG IN THE FIELD. THIS
IS WHAT THE SENSE
IN WHICH THIS IS ALL GROUNDED IN BASIC NATURAL
HISTORY. NIKO
TINBRGEN'S RESEARCH, WASPS, FOLLOWING WASPS
BACK TO THEIR NEST, NOTING THAT THEY SEEM
TO FIND THE HOLE THAT IS THEIR NEST.
BASED ON A LANDMARK SYSTEM AND SOME SORT OF
SPATIAL LEARNING PROCESS. SO HE SET UP A SERIES
OF LANDMARKS AROUND
PINECONES TO TEST THIS IDEA. ALLOWED THE WASPS
TO ORIENT WITH THOSE PINECONES TO COME BACK
TO THE NEST.
BUT SWITCHED IT UP ON THE POOR LITTLE WASP
AND MOVED THE PINECONES AWAY FROM THE NEST
SUCH THAT WHEN THEY CAME BACK NEXT TIME, SURE,
IT WENT TO ITS LANDMARKS
AND USED THOSE AND SOUGHT THE NEST INSIDE
THE RING OF PINECONES AND WOULD DO SO INDEFINITELY
UNTIL IT STUMBLED ON THE EXISTING NEST. AN
INSIGHT INTO HOW THEY'RE USING
SPATIAL MAPS TO FIND RESOURCES OR IN THIS
CASE THEIR SHELTER.
CONRAD LORENZ IS A BELOVED FIGURE IN BIOLOGY
IN MANY WAYS IN
PART BECAUSE OF ENDEARING PICTURES LIKE THIS
FROM HIS HOME WHERE HE REALLY HAD
GREAT INSIGHTS INTO ANIMAL BEHAVIOR AND EVEN
HUMAN BEHAVIOR. HE WAS A POPULARIZER
AND VERY WELL KNOWN. BUT THESE PICTURES OF
VARIOUS WATER FOWL
FOLLOWING HIM AROUND HIS PROPERTY ARE REALLY
KNOWN. THIS IS THE
PHENOMENON OF INPRINTING WHERE AN ORGANISM
GOES THROUGH SENSITIVE
DEVELOPMENTAL PERIOD EARLY IN ITS LIFE. WHERE
IT'S EXPOSED TO A
CERTAIN BEHAVIOR OF ANOTHER ORGANISM OR OBJECT.
USUALLY THE
PARENT OR SOME MEMBER OF SAME SPECIES, THAT
IT TAKES ON AS A
FIXED PATTERN OF BEHAVIOR ITSELF. SO IT'S
A MECHANISM DURING
THIS SENSITIVE OR CRITICAL PERIOD IN DEVELOPMENT
TO ADOPT BEHAVIORS
FROM OTHER MEMBERS OF THE SAME SPECIES. IN
THIS CASE IT'S JUST FOLLOWING AROUND
WHAT ITS JUDGED TO BE THE PARENT WHEN EXPOSED
TO AN OBJECT THAT'S
PARENTAL ENOUGH DURING THIS PERIOD. THERE
IS AN EXAMPLE IN YOUR BOOK HOW THIS PHENOMENON
OF IMPRINTING IS USED TO ASSIST
MIGRATION IN ENDANGERED SPECIES OF BIRDS TODAY.
I'M GOING TO SKIP THIS EXAMPLE ENTIRELY. ITS
A REALLY GREAT EXAMPLE OF HOW OF THE GENETIC
BASIS OF
BEHAVIOR. SO THE INNATE ASPECTS OF BEHAVIOR.
I'LL FOCUS INSTEAD ON THE INNATE ASPECTS ON
THE
LEARNED COMPONENTS.
SO WE'VE JUST LOOKED AT IMPRINTING AND SPATIAL
LEARNING AT THE TOP AND
MOVING CLOCKWISE, WE CAN SEE, DISCUSS SOCIAL
LEARNING AND ASSOCIATIVE LEARNING AND
COGNITIVE BEHAVIOR, BEHAVIOR IN COGNITIVE
LEARNING. LET'S LOOK
AT EXAMPLE OF SOCIAL LEARNING FROM THE PRIMATES.
SOMETHING WE, OF COURSE,
EXCEL AT SOCIAL LEARNING. WE'RE DOING IT HERE.
BY PRIMATES ARE ALSO EXCEL AT
THIS TYPE OF LEARNING. LET'S SEE IF WE CAN
GET A VIDEO TO
WORK. JUST AN AMAZING VIDEO OF THIS MOTHER
CHIMPANZEE IN THE
CENTRAL AFRICAN RAINFOREST. THERE'S A CAMERA
SET UP AND IT'S NEVER BEEN SET UP BEFORE.
YOU'LL SEE HER JUMP BECAUSE IT CLICKS.
THERE. SHE'S NOT -- SHE KNOWS SOMETHING IS
DIFFERENT ABOUT THIS
TERRITORY WHERE SHE'S BEEN FORAGING IN PREVIOUS
DAYS. SOMEONE SET UP A LITTLE BLIND WITH A
CAMERA. BUT SHE FEELS COMFORTABLE
ENOUGH THAT SHE CAN GO ABOUT HER BUSINESS.
SHE BRINGS A LONG HEAVY STICK TO
PUUNCTURE THE SIDE TO CREATE ACCESS AND TO
INCITE THE WORKERS INSIDE
THE NEST TO COME OUT. AND THEN A FINER STICK
THAT SHE'S BROUGHT IN HER MOUTH TO
PROBE THAT LARGER HOLE TO GET THE WORKERS
AND THE TERMITES
TO ATTACK IT AND GRAB ON SO SHE CAN EXTRACT
THOSE TERMITES
TO EAT THEM. HER INFANT IS HANGING AROUND.
AND OFTEN IN THESE
CASES WHETHER CRACKING NUTS OR FISHING FOR
TERMITES LIKE THIS, THE INFANT IS OFTEN RIGHT
ON HER
HIPS WATCHING VERY CLOSELY WHAT SHE'S DOING.
THEY'RE OBSERVING THE
PATTERN OF BEHAVIOR AND LEARNING FROM WHAT
SHE'S DOING. THE
OBJECTS SHE SELECTS TO PERFORM THE TASK, THE
MANNER IN WHICH
SHE GO ABOUT THE TASK. THIS IS A TYPE OF SOCIAL
LEARNING
THAT'S PARTICULAR IMPORTANT IN MAMMALS AND
PRIMATES AND HUMANS.
BUT YOU SEE IT SURPRISINGLY IN MANY ORGANISMS.
I DON'T KNOW OF
ANY PLANT EXAMPLES.
A MORE SIMPLE TYPE OF LEARNING PERHAPS, ASSOCIATIVE
LEARNING. YOU DO SOMETHING THAT ENDS UP BEING
UNCOMFORTABLE OR A RAT
EATING BAIT LACED WITH POISON THAT DOESN'T
KILL IT BUT MAKES IT SICK, WILL
BE INCLINED TO AVOID THAT ODOR THAT TYPE OF
BAIT THE NEXT TIME. ASSOCIATES THE EXPERIENCE
WITH SOMETHING
UNPLEASANT AND LEARNS FROM IT. BUT WHAT ABOUT
JUST BEING
CLEVER? HERE'S A CROW WITH A STRAIGHT WIRE.
THE WIRE IS
STRAITS SO IT CAN HARDLY PICK THE OBJECT UP.
SO FIGURE IT OUT.
SOME ORGANISMS CAN. AND CROWS AND RAVENS,
IT'S BENDING THE WIRE
NOW INTO A HOOK THAT IT CAN USE TO LIFT THE
OBJECT OUT. QUITE
WELL DONE. BECAUSE, IT'S SMART, RIGHT? I DON'T
HAVE ANY
PROBLEM CALLING THAT ANIMAL CLEVER. IT HAS
ITS OWN COGNITION
THAT'S, FLEXIBLE WITH DEGREES OF FREEDOM SUCH
THAT IT CAN PERFORM THESE KINDS OF REMARKABLE
TASK. IN SAYING THAT WE'RE REALLY NOT SAYING
ANY PHYSIOLOGICALLY
ABOUT THE RELATIONSHIP BETWEEN COGNITIVE BEHAVIOR
OR MIND AND
BODY OR ANYTHING LIKE THAT. YOU CAN STUDY
THIS EXTERNALLY WHILE
BLACK BOXING THE COGNITION LARGELY.
THIS WHOLE FIELD OF BEHAVIORAL ECOLOGY IS
WHAT WOULD LINK THE FIELDS OF
ETHOLOGY AND ECOLOGY. WE CAN DO MORE. AND
HOPEFULLY SOME OF
YOU WILL DO MORE AND MAKE CONTRIBUTIONS TO
FORMING THAT BRIDGE BETWEEN ECOLOGY AND ETHOLOGY.
IT'S REALLY RIPE FOR DEVELOPMENT. I'LL JUST
HINT HERE AT THE EVOLUTION OF THESE BEHAVIORS.
BUT THIS WILL
MAKE A LOT MORE SENSE TO YOU AFTER YOU HAVE
STUDIED EVOLUTION
ITSELF IN THE SECOND MODULE. SO CARRY THAT
SLIDE ACROSS THE
SEMESTER. WE'LL GET BACK TO IT.
IN THIS EVOLUTIONARY CONTEXT, EVOLUTION BY
NATURAL SELECTION
IS THOUGHT TO HAVE MADE EFFICIENT MANY THESE
BEHAVIORS.
SOME SPEAK OF OPTIMIZING THESE BEHAVIORS FOR
ACTIVITIES.
REDUCING THE COSTS AND MAXIMUMING THE BENEFITS.
YOU WILL SEE
SOMETHING LIKE THAT IN ONE OF YOUR LABS IN
A COUPLE OF WEEKS.
YOU'LL SEE A BIT OF THIS IN ACTION. HERE'S
AN EXAMPLE OF AN
OPTIMAL FORAGING, STUDY IN OPTIMAL FORAGING,
WITH CROWS AND A TYPE
OF SEA SNAIL, A WHELK. AN EXAMPLE IN YOUR
BOOK AND, LET ME JUST
BRIEFLY REVIEW HERE. YOU CAN LOOK IN THE BOOK
FOR DETAILS.
BASICALLY THE CROWS CARRY A HARD SHELLED SNAIL
AND DROP IT ON HARD
SURFACE TO CRACK IT. THEY PICK MUSCLES UP
AND DROP IT ON THE
PAVEMENT. CROWS DO IT. AND THE INVESTIGATORS
WERE INTERESTED
IN WHETHER THEY HAVE A PARTICULAR HEIGHT THEY
PREFER TO DROP THEM
FROM. AS YOU IMAGE, IT'S TRADEOFF BETWEEN
HOW HIGH YOU WANT
TO FLY AND HOW MANY TIMES YOU HAVE TO MAKE
THAT FLIGHT. IF YOU CARRY
ONE OF THESE SNAILS UP A METER AND DROP IT,
IT'S NOT GOING TO
BREAK. IT TAKES A LOT OF ENERGY TO FLY 30
METERS. BUT IT
MIGHT BE WORTH IT IF YOUR SNAIL IS SO NUTRITIOUS.
THERE ARE
TRADEOFFS IN THIS PROCESS. I'LL LET YOU REVIEW
THE SLIDE.
INVESTIGATORS FOUND THE MOST EFFICIENT HEIGHT
BASED ON THEIR
EXPERIMENTS, THE MOST EFFICIENT HEIGHT TO
DROP THEM FROM WHERE
YOU REDUCE THE ENERGY EXPENDED IN LIKELIHOOD
OF BREAKAGE AND MAXIMIZE THE
LIKELIHOOD OF BREAKAGE AROUND FIVE METERS.
AND MEASURED IN THE FIELD THE CROWS THEN AVERAGE
SOMETHING
SIMILAR IN THE HEIGHT IN WHICH THEY DROP THE
SNAIL. SUPPORTING A NOTION OF THEIR BEHAVIOR
HAVING BEEN, QUOTE UNQUOTE, OPTIMIZED IN SOME
SENSE. I'LL LET YOU THINK ABOUT
WHETHER EVOLUTION HAS DONE THAT. IS THAT VIA
EVOLUTION BY
NATURAL SELECTION THAT THAT BEHAVIOR HAS OPTIMIZED
OR IS THIS THE
CROW COGNITIVELY REALIZING THAT BETTER HEIGHTS
TO DROP THINGS FROM
DURING ITS OWN LIFETIME. OPEN QUESTIONS.
HAVING GLAZED THROUGH THESE, I REALLY ONLY
HAVE ONE MORE
SECTION TO COVER. AND HOPEFULLY WE KNOW THE
PROBLEM NOW IN THE
TECHNOLOGY ISSUE HERE SO IT WON'T HAPPEN AGAIN.
ORGANISMS ARE MEMBERS OF POPULATIONS. YOU
CAN'T JUST HAVE
AN ISOLATED ORGANISM OUTSIDE OF ITS POPULATION
CONTEXT BECAUSE THEY
NEED TO REPRODUCE WITH OTHER ORGANISMS. AND
SOME ORGANISMS NOT
ONLY EXIST IN POPULATIONS BUT LIVE CLOSELY
WITH ONE ANOTHER IN
HIGHLY INTERACTIVE SOCIETIES, SOCIAL GROUPS.
SO LET'S THINK A
LITTLE BIT ABOUT WHY, ABOUT THE COSTS AND
BENEFITS OF SOCIAL
LIVING, OF GROUP LIVING. WE EXCEL AT THIS
IN OUR CITIES AND
CLASSROOMS. WE DO PRETTY WELL AS A BUNCH OF
LITTLE PRAIRIE DOGS
GETTING ALONG WELL ENOUGH TOGETHER IN TIGHT
GROUPS LIKE THIS. PIGEONS,
GO OUT TO TOWN AND YOU'LL SEE THIS. WHY ARE
PIGEONS DOING THIS? GIVE ME
A COUPLE OF REASONS WHY YOU MIGHT SEE A SCENE
LIKE THIS.
WE'RE ALL IN HERE TOGETHER BECAUSE YOU GUYS
NEED CREDITS AND YOU NEED TO GRADUATE AND
WE ALL NEED TO BE IN THE SAME PLACE. WHY
ARE PIGEONS DOING THIS? SAFETY. YEAH. MAYBE
THERE'S SAFETY
IN BEING PART OF A BIG GROUP. IF IT WAS JUST
ONE PIDGEON OUT BY
ITSELF IT COULD GET HARASSED TO THE POINT
OF DYING BY A HAWK OR
SOMETHING LIKE THAT. WHEREAS IF IT'S PART
OF A BIG GROUP, MAYBE
INDIVIDUALLY, EACH IS LESS VULNERABLE. POSSIBLY.
WHAT ELSE? WHY MIGHT THEY BE
TOGETHER HERE? CHANCE OF FINDING A MATE. YEAH.
IF YOU'RE A
BUNCH OF ORANGUTANS SPREAD ABOUT THE FOREST,
LIVING SOLITARILY
YOU MIGHT HAVE A HARD TIME FINDING A MATE
UNLESS YOU CONGEAL INTO
A MORE LOCALIZED REGION. SAME WITH BIRDS AND
OTHER ORGANISMS.
IT MIGHT BE EASIER TO FIND A MATE WHEN REPRODUCTIVE
SEASON COMES
AROUND. WHAT ELSE? YEAH? MOST LIKELY FIND
FOOD. OR MAYBE THERE'S A GREAT PATCH
OF FOOD. PERHAPS ENVIRONMENTAL RESOURCES HAVE
LEAD THIS GROUP
TO EXIST HERE. SO NOT ANY REAL SOCIAL DYNAMIC
ITSELF. BUT THE
EXISTENCE OF THIS RESOURCE. THERE'S ANOTHER
SIDE OF IT THAT
I'LL HIGHLIGHT IN A MINUTE BUT MAYBE MORE
OF WHAT YOU'RE TALKING ABOUT
IN TERMS OF FINDING FOOD. ANYTHING ELSE I
SHOULD CONSIDER AS A REASON
WHY THESE GUYS MIGHT BE TOGETHER?
ONE THING, ON THE RIGHT ARE
SCHOOLING FISH. AND SHARKS MOVING THROUGH
THESE SCHOOLS OF FISH.
THAT GIVES YOU A SENSE OF THAT SAFETY-IN-NUMBERS
IDEA, PROBABLY
RIGHT? IF YOU'RE A SCHOOL OF FISH AND YOU'RE
A LITTLE FISHY OUT BY YOURSELF,
YOU'RE NOT GOING TO SURVIVE THE ATTACK OF
A BIG SHARK. BUT IF YOU'RE IN THIS MASSIVE
SCHOOL, THE LIKELIHOOD OF GETTING NAILED IS
LESS BECAUSE YOU HAVE SO MANY OF YOUR NEIGHBORS
AROUND YOU.
THE OLD SAYING ABOUT
WHEN YOU ENCOUNTER A GRIZZLY BEAR WITH YOUR
FRIEND IN THE FOREST, WHAT SHOULD YOU DO?
RUN
FASTER THAN YOUR FRIEND.
SO THE IMAGE ON THE LEFT IS, SHOWS SOME DATA
ABOUT FLOCKING
PIGEONS. AND THE DISTANCE WITH WHICH THEY
PERCEIVE A PREDATOR
IN RELATION TO THE SIZE OF THE FLOCK. THAT'S
SOMETHING CALLED THE MANY EYES
HYPOTHESIS FOR FLOCKING. BY BEING IN A BIG
GROUP YOU HAVE MORE
EYES, MORE PERCEPTUAL, A GREATER PERCEPTUAL
RANGE FOR PERCEIVING
THREATS AS YOU MULTIPLY YOUR SENSORY DEVICES.
PENGUINS HAVE
BECOME VERY POPULAR IN RECENT YEARS BASED
ON A COUPLE BIG FILMS. WHY ARE THEY HANGING
OUT
TOGETHER? THE REPRODUCTIVE ASPECT. BUT WHAT
ELSE? WARMTH.
THERMO REGULATION. BASIC PHYSIOLOGICAL BENEFIT
OF HUDDLING IN
SUCH A BITTERLY COLD ENVIRONMENT. BY MAINTAINING
CLOSE CONTACT,
KEEP THEIR TEMPERATURES UP.
LET'S THINK OF AT LEAST ONE NEGATIVE EXAMPLE
OF, I'VE DROPPED THE
NEGATIVE AMONG THE POSITIVE. AN EXAMPLE HERE
IN A MOMENT. DISEASE, AND SPREAD OF
PATHOGENS. THERE'S A MAJOR COROLLARY OF GROUP
LIVING FOR MANY
ORGANISMS. THE GREATER THE DENSITIES, THE
MORE RAPID AND LIKELY
THE SPREAD OF PATHOGENS AND DISEASE. TRUE
IN HUMAN SOCIETIES IN
MANY CASES TOO, RIGHT? BIRDS, FEATHER MITES
ARE A BIG PROBLEM FOR
BIRDS. MITES THAT NIBBLE AND EAT THE FEATHERS.
AND BIRDS THAT
LIVE IN LARGER COLONIES MAY EXPERIENCE INFESTATION
OF SUCH MITES BY
CLOSE GROUP LIVING. THESE YOU CAN SEE MORE
AND MORE AROUND
CALIFORNIA. IT'S THE LARGEST BIRD IN CALIFORNIA
EXCEPT MAYBE
THE CONDOR. I SAW A FLOCK OVER BERKELEY OF
WHITE PELICANS. WHEN YOU SEE THEM
IN BERKELEY THEY'RE GOING TO BE WAY OVERHEAD
AND FLYING FROM
POINT REYES. YOU SEE THEM MORE AND MORE. THEY'RE
FABULOUS
WHEN YOU SEE THEM IN THEIR OWN ECOSYSTEMS.
BECAUSE THEY'LL GROUP FORAGE. THEY'LL FORM
A
PHALANX LIKE THIS ONE ON THE BOTTOM. AND HERD
FISH INTO THE
SHALLOWS WHERE THEY CAN SCOOP THEM UP MORE
EASILY. BECAUSE
THEY'RE DIPPPING THEIR BIG BILLS AND HEADS
UNDER THE WATER TO
SCOOP THE FISH. THEY NEED TO HERD THEM TOGETHER
TO MAKE THAT POSSIBLE. AND
ANOTHER EXAMPLE AND A GOOD ONE TO LEAVE YOU
WITH. GROUP FORAGING THAT ENABLES RELATIVELY
SMALL
ORGANISMS TO CAPTURE NUTRITIOUS LOADS OF FOOD
WHEN WORKING
TOGETHER. SORRY FOR THE TECHNICAL DIFFICULTIES.
SEE YOU
WEDNESDAY. MY OFFICE HOURS ARE EVERYDAY AFTER
LECTURE.