Dan Kammen: We need a
wave of innovation,
not only for our way of life,
but also for the planet.
The consequences would
be enormous if we lose
this battle.
Thomas Goetz: I'm Thomas Goetz,
executive editor at Wired
Magazine. At wired, we look
at the innovators and
innovations that are changing
our world. In the next
hour, we'll see three stories
from acclaimed filmmakers about
the future of energy.
We'll explore cutting edge
innovations in how we drive,
how we live,
and, in our first story,
how we fuel our cars.
They're all ideas
that promise to
shape the path to
the world of 2050.
[♪...]
The world has right now,
close to a billion cars,
and we might double the
number of cars on
the planet by 2050.
So if we double the number of
vehicles, we really increase the
amount of fuel they consume, and
that's going to have a big, big
footprint in terms of our demand
for resources to move all
those vehicles around.
Kay Keasling: We're pulling
up carbon that's been stored
underground and
burning it in our
automobiles and putting all
that carbon dioxide into the
atmosphere.
If we don't reduce that, we
could have changes in the
climate that we could
never recover from.
There's a number of forecasts
for what type of transportation
economy we could move into.
One vision is that we would use
more and more liquid fuels,
another one is we'll use
more and more electricity.
Right now, more of the
industrial activity is
focused around liquid biofuels.
The thing about a fuel is, its
really unparalleled on a weight
basis how much energy
is in a gallon of fuel.
And even if batteries
develop as some of the
advocates hope they develop,
we're not going to see batteries
running large trucks
and we're certainly not
going to see an
electrified air flight.
We're going to need
transportation fuels for
those that will directly
replace the petroleum based
fuels that we're using today.
This has kicked off people
looking at a whole range of
other alternatives to
petroleum in your tank.
Isaias Macedo: Commercial
production of ethanol as fuel
started in Brazil
in 1975. When we
started the ethanol program,
nobody talked about reducing
emissions. This was
not an issue at that time.
First, and most important,
we didn't have money
to buy oil anymore after
the first oil short.
We were importers of oil.
And today, more than 50%
of all cars use ethanol
instead of gasoline.
Brazil made a very conscious
choice to try to find a way to
reduce their fossil
fuel dependence.
And they didn't have to look
very far because Brazil's
climate is ideal
for growing sugar cane.
Carlos Dinucci: when you
have sugar cane plantation,
you have only two
things to make:
sugar and ethanol.
My family has been in the
sugarcane business since 1955
and about thirty
years ago, I thought
"there's an opportunity
to make more ethanol."
Now, we're producing 120,000
cubic meters of ethanol.
Brazil today has very
close to 400 sugar mills.
The overall sales
is 30 billion us dollars.
And this number is increasing.
If you look at how they make
ethanol and how efficient the
process is, it's
really a model for all of us.
They grind the plant up,
extract the sugar from the
cane, the sugar goes into these
large fermentation tanks which
combine sugars together with
yeast that naturally produces
ethanol. They use the rest
of the plant to generate heat
to distill the ethanol
and turn it into fuel.
They also use that heat to
generate electricity renewably,
not putting excess carbon
dioxide into the atmosphere.
Brazil has gotten to a point
today where they're using about
40% less petroleum than they
would be otherwise, but Brazil
cannot supply the whole world
with ethanol because they
would have to cut very
strongly into food
production and into critical
natural areas like the Amazon to
make that happen.
This really boils down to the
fact that there's only so much
arable land, and growing fuel
for our gas tanks is yet another
demand on that landscape.
We cannot kid ourselves into
thinking that we've found a
general solution for
the world problem.
I think we have to face the
world in this way today.
We have no oil in very
large quantities anymore.
We have no coal transforming in
a clean way, in the meantime we
have to do the best we
can, and the best at
the moment is that
we can do biofuels.
Sugarcane to ethanol is an
incredibly efficient process.
You get out about
seven times the energy you put
into growing the sugar cane.
In the US when we produce
ethanol from corn, for every
unit of input of energy we get
about the same amount
of energy out.
So we're really
not gaining anything.
We need a better process.
We don't have to take what
nature's given us, we can
actually engineer plants and
yeast to be more efficient.
And that's the basis
for a lot of the work
that we're doing now.
What we need to look at though,
is which of the pathways to come
out of this are not
only good financially,
but those that are also
good for sustainability.
And this equation is
really wide open right now.
We are in a race
to develop fuels.
The race isn't with
other countries, the race
is against time.
Cristiano Borges: To meet the
immediate and future demands, we
made the energy solution
spring from the ground.
Luis Scoffone: Brazil is the
most efficient ethanol producing
country in the world. Sugarcane
alcohol from Brazil can reduce
the total carbon footprint by up
to 70%, compared with gasoline.
The biggest challenge for fuel
providers, and car manufacturers
is to reduce CO2 emissions
over the next twenty years.
Demand for mobility
will continue to grow.
We believe that
biofuels are very
important because they
help in an immediate way.
All forms of fuel are going
to be needed; hydrocarbons,
natural gas, biofuels,
all of them are going to
be part of the energy needs for
the future of transportation.
Brazil has been very successful
at taking a resource they had
and finding the process
to make that into
ethanol and people call
those first generation
biofuels. We have lots
of lab work around
the world that
are looking at the
second generation and that's
generally turning cellulosic
material from for example
weeds, into biofuels.
And the United States
is very much at the
forefront of the innovation
part of the equation.
For centuries we've been using
yeast to consume glucose and
produce wine and beer.
We're trying to do something
very similar, only we're
engineering the yeast
to consume that glucose
and turn it into a fuel
or drug or chemical.
We call this synthetic biology
and when i started in this area,
many of my colleagues
said "Oh Jay, this is
great work, but where's
the application, what
are you going to do with
these tools?" Who cares?
Malaria is an enormous problem.
In any one year,
a million or so people die of
the disease and most of them
are children under the age of 5.
So we thought this was a great
opportunity to engineer yeast to
produce an antimalarial
drug called artemisinin.
This drug is derived
from plants right
now, but its too expensive for
people in the developing world.
So my laboratory engineered
yeast to produce small
quantities of artemisinin, now
that process is being scaled up
and we'll have this drug
on the market shortly,
but at a substantially
reduced cost.
It turns out that that
anti-malarial drug is a
hydrocarbon and it's
very similar in
many ways to diesel fuel.
We thought, gosh we can
turn our attention now to
fuels. We can make a few changes
in that microbe to turn it into
a fuel-producing microbe.
If we imagine that glucose is
going to be our new petroleum,
we need a source
for that glucose.
So the crops that we're
looking at are crops like
switchgrass.
This is a native grass, it grows
without a lot of water and on
marginal lands. we could
turn it into energy farms.
The challenge though, is
that unlike sugar cane, it's
very difficult to get the
sugar out of that biomass.
So we use what we call a
pre-treatment process to extract
the glucose from the plant,
and then we feed that
glucose to a yeast
that we've engineered to
produce hydrocarbons.
And that yeast takes in the
sugar, and it changes its
composition and gives us
this high-energy molecule.
They float to the top,
you skim them off,
you put them in your tank.
But it takes a lot of work to
get from that small test tube
all the way up into
the million-gallon tank,
so we have to give it time.
But I think that some of the
discoveries that are happening
might be applied by
the end of the decade.
In terms of a sustainable
equation for the planet, the
role of biofuels
is quite tricky.
There are a variety of crops
that do not compete directly
with food, and finding
ways to utilize those
types of crops first,
that's very attractive.
So solving the science is
part of the story, but then
evaluating all of the new
fuels in terms of the land-use
impacts that they could
have, that is an even
harder story than
doing the good science.
Imagine that you could have one
process that could take in
sunlight and carbon dioxide
and turn it into fuel.
And imagine if that
didn't involve growing
anything at all.
Nate Lewis: The synthetic
biologists are trying to take
plants and make them do things
that they wouldn't normally do.
On the other hand,
materials chemists, like
myself, want to do artificial
photosynthesis to improve on the
process that nature does
in real photosynthesis.
We should follow the blue print
of plants converting sunlight
into fuel, but take the approach
that it could be much simpler.
All we really need
is a light absorber
that absorbs sunlight.
We also need a catalyst
like iron or nickel.
So when you see the hydrogen
coming off of the photo-active
material, that's an
example of a semi-conductor
breaking the chemical
bonds of water to make
hydrogen and oxygen.
Ultimately, our pieces are
going to be contained in
something that is easy to
roll out like bubble wrap,
where in would come
sunlight and water.
You would vent the oxygen
to the air, but the bottom
would wick out your liquid or
gaseous fuel, that then you
could collect and use for our
cars and planes and storage.
Our goal is within two years,
to have the first artificial
photosynthesis solarfuels
generator that we can hold in
our hands. and then, get
to scale beyond that time.
We're certainly not good at
predicting the future, but to
me, electric vehicles look
like a sustainable option.
We've heard proposals
about things as
far-fetched as nuclear power
planes, and even some proposals
to move freight around with
lighter-than-air vehicles.
And so if the
future in 2050 does
include a fair amount of oil,
what it means would be that we
haven't deployed
as many of these clean
technologies as we already
know are possible.
If you think about how long it's
taken for us to build up the
petroleum industry, we can't
hope to reverse that overnight.
It's a huge change in
our infrastructure.
Yes, we should have been
working on it 30 years ago.
We didn't.
We're trying to make up for
that, and that means basic
research needs to be done now
and by as many people as
possible. We have a long way to
go, but I'm confident
that we'll get there.
In the future, 3d maps are going
to help people get places more
efficiently.
As we just saw, the race to
produce cleaner energy is
charging ahead. In the
meantime, demand for
cars continues to climb.
By 2050, it's predicted there
will be two billion
cars on the planet,
and fuel consumption
will have tripled.
To keep pace, we'll
have to radically
change the way we drive.
Here's our next story,
'Driven by design.'
Asaaf Biderman: The
automobile came around,
in many ways it was the future.
We thought of it as one of the
more positive changes that had
happened to society.
Suddenly, our ability to get a
job changed, we can
live farther away with
bigger plots of land, with
better quality of living.
It all looked quite good.
But there are limitations
to swearing by the car.
If it gets congested,
your quality of
life drops immediately.
You have to spend
so long in the car.
It's a very inefficient
use of fuel consumption.
Things stop making
sense all of a sudden.
It doesn't bring you closer
to where you want to get, it
actually, sometimes
brings you farther.
Narrator: The average American
spends nearly 300 hours a year
in their car.
38 of them stuck in traffic.
Annually, congestion
consumes over $1 billion in
gasoline in the
United States alone.
The inefficiency
caused by traffic, both
financial and
personal, is enormous.
Dirk Sheehan and
Carmen White's story
is not that unusual today.
Carmen White: Dirk works an hour
and a half away in Warrenville,
Illinois. Generally he wouldn't
leave work until 6 or 6:30 and I
would say usual time for him to
get home is around 8.
You all done?
Thanks, buddy.
Dirk Sheehan: Usually when I
wake up I'm the only one up.
Sometimes the kids wake
up with my routine.
More often than not, I don't
see them in the morning.
I think about my commute
when I wake up.
I check the traffic report to
see if there's any delays.
The worst case
scenario, it takes me
two hours to get to work.
We are already so limited in the
amount of time he can spend with
the kids, and our
expenses are crazy high.
We're spending $400
a month on gas.
It takes away from our food
budget, and we never paid for
gas like that before. Ever.
If there's technology that would
allow me to spend less time in
the car, spend less
money on gas, and spend
more time at home,
I'd be all for that.
Mike Finn: The cost of traffic
is people's time, it's fuel
wasted, it's an emotional
toll, it's a frustration.
Utilizing the roads
more intelligently is a much
more efficient approach to
the inability to have
supply keep up
with traffic demand.
John Leonard: If you took a
satellite picture of the
highway, you can see that
there's actually
a lot of open space.
If we had the technology for
cars to drive more closely,
but safely, then you could
increase the utilization of the
road network.
What this means is that to be
more efficient, to use less
fuel, we need to see
the road differently.
We need cars that can
navigate through the urban
landscape in a
radically different way.
Cliff Fox: Maps in the future
are going to be able to help
people get places either more
safely or more efficiently.
Today, just helps you get
from point A to point B.
But, what if I want to get
someplace and use the least
amount of fuel possible?
Or, if I've got a hybrid
vehicle, and I want to make sure
I've got plenty of
charge to not only get
there but to get back home?
So, information
that is gonna help people
achieve the more efficient
or the safer route is
more detailed information about
the road than a lot of people
realize is possible
to collect today.
Here in Chicago, Nokia's
location & commerce unit is
developing the next
generation of mapping.
Lidar, sonar, 360-degree video,
all are components of what Nokia
calls - digital mapping.
We use 64 lasers that rotate and
they collect data in a 3D way
about the world.
It creates what we call a
point cloud of information.
That point cloud
allows us to measure distances
then between the points
that we collect.
That system combined with the
cameras, with higher precision
location detection
through inertial measurement
units, that whole data
system allows us to
collect 1.3 million
points of data per second.
Probably within 2-3 years,
you're gonna see 3D maps that
are gonna integrate the traffic
information into your
routing, to help you understand.
If I've got 5
different routes to take,
which one is the most efficient
today, given the way the
stoplights are running, given
the way traffic is running.
All of those factors are gonna
be taken into consideration to
make sure I've got the best
route.
But better mapping that can
integrate topography,
infrastructure, and density is
only part of the answer.
Another key to improving
transport efficiency is
building cars
that drive themselves.
Autonomous vehicle technology
has a tremendous potential to
improve efficiency of
our road infrastructure.
By removing humans from the
equation, we eliminate all the
things we do wrong behind the
wheel - speeding, changing
lanes too often, merging
haphazardly; and by marrying
them with sophisticated 3D maps,
we can make driving safer
and more energy efficient.
That next generation
vehicle is being
built right now by Swedish
trucking company, Scania.
Tony Sandberg: The solution, as
we see it, is that the vehicles
can utilize intelligent maps.
3D maps with
traffic information.
The vehicles will
be intelligent and
communicate with each other.
They will talk to each
other, they will talk to the
infrastructure.
And we will see
autonomously-driven vehicles.
The goal was to have multiple
robots and see if they could go
60 miles fully autonomously.
Helen Taylor:
My name's Helen Taylor.
My husband John and I,
we're very passionate about
fuel economy.
John Taylor: Yea it's great to
break world records, but that's
not the be all and end all now.
It's more important
to educate people.
Together we're showing
drivers around the world simple
techniques to improve
their fuel efficiency.
We run these education programs,
get people on the road with us,
and we finally tweak
their driving techniques.
Things like just
checking your tire
pressures before you
even get into your car.
For every one psi your tires are
under inflated, you're wasting
3% of your fuel efficiency.
And the difference
between 65 and 75 miles
per hour is a saving of 23%.
When you talk to the general
public, they're very surprised
that an energy company,
like Shell, is trying
to educate people on
how to save money,
how to reduce CO2 emissions.
And here we have Shell sending
us around the world to do that.
You always hope when you're on
this planet that you can make a
real difference
in people's lives.
When you get emails
from people saying "I've
saved this amount of money this
year, now I can put food on the
table", then you know you are
really making a difference.
By displaying traffic density
in the urban infrastructure
in a revolutionary way,
3D digital maps will help create
a more fuel-efficient future.
But these technologies are
limited by the drivers who sit
behind the wheel. Some
believe, that for cars and
trucks to be truly
energy-efficient, they will need
to drive themselves.
The technology's coming into
play, through sensors and
capabilities for cars
to drive autonomously.
In 2007, the United States'
department of defense held a
competition to see
if a completely autonomous,
self-driving vehicle
was possible.
DARPA stands for the Defense
Advanced Research Projects
Agency. They had a competition
to develop self-driving robots
that could drive
themselves in traffic.
The goal was to have multiple
robots, turn them loose
on a course, and see if they
could go sixty miles in six
hours, fully autonomously.
Driving may be one of the most
complex things we do every day.
Drivers make dozens of
decisions at any given moment.
One study found that drivers
Were exposed to over 1,300 items
of information per minute.
We make so many decisions when
we're driving without even
thinking about it.
So in creating our vehicle,
a great component of the
enterprise was
developing software to handle
lots of sensors,
feeding lots of data, and
generating a bunch of potential
paths that the vehicle might
follow. And even
though the robot doesn't have
the ability to predict
the future, by using this
fast random path generation,
the robot could anticipate a
potential accident
and choose a path to avoid it
because its always
thinking about what things
could the car do next.
No one expects millions of
cars driving themselves anytime
soon. But there is a
place where self-navigating
technologies are being
optimized to create the
vehicle of the future.
We're on the Scania test
track outside Stockholm,
where we have basically,
it looks like a highway but it's
a separate test track where we
conduct our own experiments.
Scania, the Swedish trucking
company, has recently begun
testing its next generation
of long-haul truck, utilizing
radar, sonar, and
intelligent mapping.
They've been able to drastically
reduce fuel consumption.
Jonas Martensson: We have this
example with platooning, where
will make use of the reduction
in air resistance, or air drag,
that you get from driving
close to each other with
heavy duty vehicles.
And in order to control
this, you need to know
where the other vehicles are,
their position, their velocity,
their actions
in the near future.
And to be very close to the
vehicle ahead of you, it
requires that you have
a very accurate control.
If you look at robotics broadly,
there's a wonderful set of
research of people
looking at schooling fish and
trying to develop the
ability for robots to work
together like that.
So there are wonderful
examples from nature of how
cooperation can lead to more
efficient resource utilization.
Jonas Hofstedt: You can see it
when people are competing in
Tour de France. They platoon
to reduce air drag.
They are not bicycling behind
each other that close because
it's fun, or because they are
racing, it is because they are
reducing air drag
sitting behind
the man who is leading.
A truck traveling 55 miles per
hour expends half its energy
just to move
the air around it.
At 65 miles per hour, that
number jumps to almost
two-thirds.
Even if platooning can reduce
the energy used by 10 percent,
the savings
would be substantial.
If a vehicle in front of another
vehicle wants to brake,
it immediately sends out
the brake message to the other
vehicles, so they actually
brake at the same time.
Hassad Alem: The way we do this
is by, we have an automated
system. so now for instance,
if i take my feet off the
acceleration pedal, and turn the
system on, the
velocity is automatically
governed by getting
information from the vehicle
ahead through
its wireless system.
We want these
vehicles to maintain a
short relative distance.
So through this system,
we can reduce fuel
consumption by utulizing
the air drag reduction by 10%.
and 10% would mean you
would be able to save
approximately 8,000 Euros
per single heavyduty
vehicle per year.
It may be sometime before
autonomous vehicles make up the
majority of cars on
America's highways.
Nevertheless, some of these
technologies are already
making their way into our lives.
Now this polar
baby wants to sleep.
Do you get to pick out books
every day or is it just...
I get to pick out
books sometimes.
Okay.
When we look toward the future,
the systems will absolutely make
it safer and more
efficient and less
costly for you and also
make your life easier
because you're spending
less time on the roads.
The city begins to talk, begins
to tell you where is there
congestion, what's going on
in different areas of town?
Suddenly the car
becomes a part of a
much bigger ecosystem.
We can look at how cars
interact with other cars,
how cars interact with
infrastructure and us, the
drivers, can start to make
smart decisions about
how to move around.
Suddenly, mobility becomes
a whole other thing.
Paul Goldberger: No matter how
much money they have, no matter
how much oil they have,
everybody has to go in
a different direction.
We've seen that changing
the way we drive can improve
transportation efficiencies.
But what if we change the way we
build and live in our cities?
That's the subject of our next
story, "Searching for Utopia".
We'll travel to the
United Arab Emirates, and
discover a city rising
out of the desert.
Let's take a look.
From the beginning,
we've dreamed of Utopia.
A place where we could live in
harmony with each other,
and in balance with nature.
Many have imagined it,
tried to design it, but the
dream always slipped away.
Then, I heard they were
building a new city called
"Masdar", near Abu Dhabi,
in the Arabian desert.
It sounded like an
unlikely place for Utopia,
and I wanted to see it.
The last half-century has been a
pretty bad time for the making
of cities, mostly.
The natural tendency has been
to accommodate to the automobile
more than anything else.
Try walking around
Abu Dhabi, it’s impossible,
you have to take
a car everywhere.
Dubai, the same thing.
They are among
the least pedestrian-friendly
places in the world,
they are not green by any
other measure either, and these
are not easy things to fix.
Masdar is still under
construction, and it doesn't
look like much from the highway.
But they claim it's going to
redefine the way cities are
designed, built, and powered.
Masdar City in Abu Dhabi, will
be the city of the future, and
the role model for the world.
Once you see what they've
envisioned for this
utopian city,
its very impressive.
It's carbon-neutral, pedestrian
friendly and powered by
renewable energies.
But I do notice, we're
going to have to change our
relationship with cars.
Car audio: Welcome
to Masdar City.
Austin Relton: We are driving in
the bowels of Masdar City in an
electric transportation system.
It's slightly unnerving to see
this for the first time and
"where are we going?"
the first big move the
architects at foster and
partners made was to put all
transportation underneath the
city, leaving the streets
of Masdar totally free
of cars.
The place reminded me
of a medieval city.
And actually, many design
elements are adapted from
ancient Arabic
towns and villages.
It's all about looking back
into history to move forward.
There are some very
very simple ideas
that have a huge impact.
This is a pedestrian zone,
there's no cars here.
This has enabled us to push
our streets together to take
advantage of the shade, channel
the cooling breezes through.
The whole scale here is based on
the human being, its not based
on the motor car.
As soon as you lift up the
pedestrian plane by seven
meters, you've suddenly
captured this breeze.
What you can see here on
the balcony is we've got a
modern interpretation of
an ancient Arabic screen.
What we must avoid is
direct sunlight hitting
any piece of glass.
As soon as the
sun hits the glass,
the heat's transferred into the
building and we have to use more
energy to cool it down.
Can this really make all
that much of a difference?
Yeah, absolutely.
For example, downtown Abu
Dhabi... sixty-meter wide
streets, black asphalt, mirrored
reflective buildings, no relief
from the sun.
On a day in September, the
air temperature in both places
was 39 degrees.
in Abu Dhabi, the
temperature measured
at the asphalt was 57 degrees.
in Masdar, the
temperature measured on the
ground, 33 degrees,
so we've actually lowered
the air temperature.
We're trying to do as much as
possible, with as little as
possible.
These simple design moves, cut
air conditioning needs by 60%.
But this place is also,
technically, very sophisticated.
The roof panels
not only provide
shade, they also
generate electricity.
And the walls
themselves are made of
glass reinforced concrete,
literally sand taken from the
desert.
Everything here is geared
towards maximizing energy
efficiency.
Masdar does represent a
whole different value system.
It represents an
acknowledgment that, eventually,
everybody has to go in a
different kind of direction.
No matter how much
money they have,
no matter how much oil they
have, no matter anything else.
All of the cities here
in this part of the world
have come out of nowhere.
There was nothing here
not so long ago, except
small settlements in the desert.
And then all of this oil
and all of this money,
and suddenly, you know, wham,
these cities started popping up.
But they sprung up
in a false love of a
Western model that was
already out of date.
The model of the late 20th
century automobile-based
energy-hogging city.
For most of the world, energy is
very expensive. But the United
Arab Emirates is sitting
on 10% of the world's
oil, and energy is cheap,
so cheap you can
run a ski slope in
a shopping mall,
and build the world's
tallest skyscraper.
But even here, cheap energy
won't last forever, and the
people behind Masdar are
determined to find alternatives.
Martin Haigh: One of the most
crucial aspects of our energy
odeling and scenario
quantification is how much
energy in total is the
world going to use in 2050.
Wim Thomas: The scenarios team
is a bunch of people with rich
imagination, I would say.
Adam Newton: We have political
scientists, economists,
geopolitical experts.
Really we try to simplify
the complexity all
around us.
Jeremy Bentham: We in the
Scenarios team are currently
putting a lot of attention into
cities and city development.
A lot of megacities are going to
be built in the coming decades.
We're talking about the
equivalent of a new city of a
million people every week.
That is an incredible demand.
Most of the world's resources
are consumed by the cities.
What if we could offer a
blueprint for a better
city? Public transportation,
information, energy.
We understand demand will
rise, we understand the
current supplies will
struggle to keep pace.
So we have to of course, find
ways of bridging the gap between
the demand and the supply.
Decisions that we take now are
going to have a major impact on
decades to come.
There's enough oil under
these sands to last 150 years.
But fundamental to the
Masdar ideal, is getting
energy from renewable
sources, from
geothermal and wind, and most of
all, from a source they have in
abundance in the
desert: the sun.
This field of solar panels
makes more than enough
electricity to run Masdar, and
the excess power is sent to the
Abu Dhabi grid.
But silicon panels are
expensive, and the price of
solar power needs to drop if
its going to be competitive
from Africa to Asia to Arizona.
in the future, Masdar hopes to
get energy from this prototype
called the solar beam down.
Uusing highly reflective
mirrors, the solar beam down may
generate power more cheaply and
ecologically than silicon
panels.
The mirrors bounce the suns rays
up to the tower, and then down
to a point. reaching a
temperature of 600
degrees, steam can
be generated to run
turbines to make electricity.
There's just one problem:
neither of these solar
technologies work at night.
So Masdar needs to
draw power from the grid
when the sun goes down, and that
power comes from natural gas.
The reality is, it’s just not
yet possible to power Masdar
entirely without fossil fuels.
The great challenge with Masdar,
will be "how do you make
it a place that will
not be just this ideal city that
no other place could actually
aspire to, 'cause it
doesn't seem real."
What Masdar has to be is a
laboratory that develops things
that then can be applied in
existing cities all around the
world, because that's
where it will pay off.
There's no pay off if
it's just about itself.
The payoff is "how can
everything it's trying to
do matter in the
rest of the world?"
Right now, there's only a store,
two restaurants, a bank, and a
few hundred students
living here.
It's too early to tell if Masdar
will work as a city when it's
finished, but much has
been achieved: they are
carbon-neutral, and largely,
powered by renewable energies.
Solutions here won't
work everywhere
though, many cities are in cold
climates, and cooling is not
their energy problem.
They need to let sunlight
in, not keep it out.
Cities like Los Angeles or
Houston are built around cars.
Can Masdar's lessons
be applied to them?
Still, its a step
in the right direction.
And, its impressive
that this step is being
taken by a country that
doesn't need to take it.
I met a guy who said "actually,
they did need to take it."
He took me to the
desert to explain.
Muhamad Alkhalil: God says...
[arabic]
God talks about man's
place in, in the universe.
That this world is a trust.
And god offered this
trust to the mountains, to the
heavens, to the land, to earth,
and all refused it, refused to
take this trust.
But man being adventurous, vain,
maybe too ambitious, being man
accepted it.
Now, accepting it,
there is a responsibility.
Taking responsibility
isn't always easy.
Utopia may be
unattainable, but we
must reach for it, and Masdar
does give us a clue to what
cities will be
like in the future.
They may not look
quite like Masdar,
but they will be shaped
by the same concerns.
By energy.
Where it comes
from, and how its used.
The way we've been building
cities lately is unsustainable.
We can't go on
building them that way.
But to say that we can't
build cities the way we have
been building them doesn't mean
we can't build
cities in the future.
In fact, we have
to build cities.
Cities are the essential
statement of human civilization.
So, we will continue to make
them, but we have to make them
in a different way.
what we've seen is that the
world of 2050 won't look
drastically different from
the world today, but the
challenges of a
growing population and
increased energy use
demand real solutions.
Its innovations like those we've
just seen that will be critical
in charting our path
to the world of 2050.