We'll fold in pistachio
and cubed fat
back that's been blanched.
And then pump it into a
beef bung, tie it up.
It's done.
You'll be amazed how big
this thing can get.
Crank, baby crank.
Oh, yeah.
This is like 15 pounds.
My name is Brad Spence.
And I'm the chef at
Amis restaurant.
I grew up in South Jersey,
and it's like all
Italians over there.
So I always loved
Italian food.
To me, Italian American
food is soul food.
So I always had that love.
I always knew that I
wanted to do it.
But I knew nothing really
about Italian food.
I knew a little bit about it.
And then once I started working
for Marc, he taught me
everything.
Marc Vetri started Vetri, which
is an 8 to 10 table
Italian restaurant.
He's the master.
It was really when I went to
Vetri that I really started to
understand what Italian food was
all about, and traveling
to Italy and working there.
And that's when it all clicked
after a couple years of
working for Marc.
Marc was looking to open
more restaurants.
I was like, yeah, let's go
[INAUDIBLE], let's go
[INAUDIBLE].
Every day, [INAUDIBLE], let's go
look for space, bugging him
for a year.
Finally, he was like, relax.
I think he realized that
it was time for me
to have my own thing.
So that's when we went out and
shopped around for spots.
We definitely have the
Roman classics.
We have the cacio e pepe.
Tonnarelli that we make here,
black pepper, a little bit of
olive oil, a little bit of
butter, and pecorino cheese.
That's a classic Roman pasta
that you're going to have in
every trattoria in Rome.
And then we do some
nontraditional stuff, like the
veal tongue.
Which again, I've never
had that in Italy.
But it's something that
it feels like you
would have in Italy.
This is definitely one of those
dishes when my family
comes in, I don't tell
them what is.
And they're like, what was that
thing in the beginning?
What was that little crispy
piece of meat?
I'm like, oh, that
was veal tongue.
That was veal tongue?
Oh my god.
That was my favorite thing
of the whole night.
But this is something
that we've kind of
become known for.
It's going to be one of
our signature things.
So we went out with Craig,
my sous chef.
He's actually been here since
the very beginning.
He's one of those guys
that comes in and
works his ass off.
He's awesome.
And then my brother-in-law,
Kevin, who has nothing to do
in the food business.
He doesn't know how
to cook anything.
But he's been really close to
me for the last 10 years.
We are going to Paesano's
sandwich shop.
It's only been open for
a couple years.
but eventually it will become
an institution.
It's my buddy, Peter
McAndrews.
He just really cares about
what he's doing.
It's just not a sandwich.
It's really something special.
And it's really fucking good.
PETER MCANDREWS:
I got Peronis.
You guys got Tecate and shit?
BRAD SPENCE: I don't know
what the hell this is.
This was in our basement.
I just threw it on ice
for these guys.
Do want us to help you out?
We'll go back there.
Two Irish guys cooking
Italian food.
He was kind of disappointed
in the way
sandwiches were in Philly.
So he was like, fuck it.
I'm going to open
my own place.
So he opened it up.
And as soon as he opened,
I would hear some people
talking about it.
You got to go to this place.
We went one time.
I took all the guys
in the kitchen.
We went there and got
every sandwich.
They were just awesome.
He makes everything there.
He makes his own bread.
He makes all his own roasted
meats, and stuff.
It's good stuff.
PETER MCANDREWS: This
is called the
South Philly microwave.
You wrap it up in the paper
for a minute, kind of melt
[INAUDIBLE].
Once you have Paesano's
tastes like pussy.
Sad thing is I'd rather
eat good food than be
with a woman sometimes.
BRAD SPENCE: Definitely.
NATHAN BAYNES: People walk in
and they're like, yeah, you
got steak sandwich?
I go, look, I understand
that you are under the
misconception that the Philly
steak is the thing to have
when you come to Philly.
That's the sandwich,
the Philly.
But trust me when I
say that what you
should have is the Paesano.
It's like, do you want
pussy in your mouth?
Do you like eating pussy?
Then you're not going
to go wrong.
BRAD SPENCE: I hear you man.
NATHAN BAYNES: We want
to go triple X rated
with what we're doing.
BRAD SPENCE: You are.
Look at the sandwiches
up there.
PETER MCANDREWS: This is
called the Liverace.
Goofy name, but it's chicken
fried chicken livers.
And it makes your mouth
sing like Liberace.
But it's chicken livers with
sopressata, garlic mayonnaise,
orange, a little gorgonzola.
It's almost like
chicken wings.
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
BRAD SPENCE: The Liverace is
definitely one of my favorites.
You take a bite and it's
just unbelievable.
And there's much fat, and so
much salt, and so much flavor.
And it's pretty intense
when you eat it.
This is insane.
Oh my god.
KEVIN GRIFFIN: Right
to my bad heart.
I might have a heart attack.
You watch out for me.
BRAD SPENCE: All right guys.
We're going to be back at Amis
at like 11:30, 12:00.
You guys can stop back and
we'll do the fucking
mortadella sandwich.
PETER MCANDREWS: Don't
do anything I
wouldn't do in my absence.
I used to smoke and rollerblade
off [INAUDIBLE]
Drive.
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
-Later, Pete.
BRAD SPENCE: So next, we're
going Han Dynasty.
It's our good buddy,
Han Chiang.
He has a Szechuan restaurant.
Hopefully he won't
be too drunk by
the time we get there.
He'll blow himself up with
a wok, or something.
What Han always wanted
to do was do
traditional Szechuan food.
It's dishes that are hundreds
of years old.
And wasn't going to change it
for the American palate.
HAN CHIANG: If they
listen, great.
You're going to have the best
authentic meal of your life.
All my chefs are from China,
from this region.
Because if you're not used to
the food, if you don't know
how it's supposed to
taste like, you
can't cook it, period.
So we're going to start
bringing out food.
Is that all right?
First, we're going start
out with beef and
tripe with chili oil.
-What level spicy is this?
HAN CHIANG: This is like a 10.
-Oh good, good.
Because I was going to say
it's fucking spicy.
HAN CHIANG: Dan dan noodles.
-Yes.
-Yeah, dude.
Dan dan noodles.
BRAD SPENCE: You always go
tableside when you do them,
toss them like that?
HAN CHIANG: Because Americans
are too stupid to mix
everything.
BRAD SPENCE: So it's
traditional
to the United States.
HAN CHIANG: I'm working myself
as a slave to mix noodles.
Dan dan mother fucking
noodles.
-Oh shit.
HAN CHIANG: AKA crack.
Chinese food is made for
family style, to share.
I'm Chinese.
I'm 33 years old.
I never had a meal not shared
in my fucking life.
[INAUDIBLE]
eat, and shut the fuck up.
BRAD SPENCE: He's pretty intense
about the dishes.
They're all awesome.
And it's all real simple.
It reminds me of what we do
here, minus all the spice.
It's just one or two ingredients
on the plate.
And it's awesome ingredients.
It's always good.
KEVIN GRIFFIN: I've
got to be honest.
I don't always hear totally
fresh when I hear about
Chinese food.
That's Chinese food in America.
-Exactly.
It's a different concept.
HAN CHIANG: Has a very
low price point.
They usually buy really
shitty meat.
How the fuck they sell a lunch
special for $4.50?
KEVIN GRIFFIN: That's kind
of fucking scary, dude.
HAN CHIANG: How the
fuck they do that?
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
HAN CHIANG: McDonald's can't
even beat that price.
How the fuck they do that?
You really trust a Chinese
family selling you $4.50 for a
lunch special?
BRAD SPENCE: Han is
like, he's crazy.
He's saying crazy shit.
Luckily, the group I was with,
they're just as crazy.
But if you hang out with
somebody that's not used to
Han, they're like, what the
fuck's wrong with this guy.
Is he all right?
KEVIN GRIFFIN: You
looking for love?
HAN CHIANG: No.
I'm looking for somebody is
excellent at stripping, and a
video gamer.
-Video gamer.
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
BRAD SPENCE: So you need
a stripper video gamer.
KEVIN GRIFFIN: Why the
video game part?
HAN CHIANG: I mean, as a video
gamer, my greatest fantasy is
have my dick sucked while
I play video games.
-No, that makes sense.
-Let's roll.
HAN CHIANG: I just
speak my mind.
KEVIN GRIFFIN: Actually that
is your only fault.
You speak your mind.
You really should keep that
shit to yourself.
HAN CHIANG: No.
CRAIG PARAHUS: Never.
HAN CHIANG: Never.
CRAIG PARAHUS: No filter.
HAN CHIANG: No filter.
HAN CHIANG: That's why
I love this channel.
Go fuck yourself, Munchies.
BRAD SPENCE: You guys ready for
encased meat, sliced with
mayonnaise?
CRAIG PARAHUS: I'm more worried
about encased meat
than my sex life.
BRAD SPENCE: So what I made for
them, it was a sandwich.
I got a mortadella,
poached that.
PETER MCANDREWS: It looks
like a cow's penis.
BRAD SPENCE: And then we make
our own sesame bread.
I split that, scooped
out the bread.
And then we made something
called samurai sauce, which is
basically mayonnaise and chili
paste mixed together.
So we put that on the bread.
-Its like a big vagina.
BRAD SPENCE: And then I took the
hot mortadella, and just
sliced that.
-That's the most beautiful
thing I've seen since I
watched granny porn yesterday.
BRAD SPENCE: Put that down, and
then escarole, pecorino,
raw red onion, a little
olive oil and black
pepper and chili flake.
And then just served that up.
PETER MCANDREWS: That fucking
sandwich is awesome.
I said it earlier to you, I
think I love fucking food more
than pussy.
Fucking [INAUDIBLE]
pussy more than food.
[INAUDIBLE]
there's no way around
that shit.
Irish guys love food
more than pussy.
BRAD SPENCE: Han is like, when
you're hanging out with him,
he's one step away from
somebody beating
the shit out of him.
But it's also funny when you're
hanging out with a guy
like Peter, who's
just as crazy.
When the two of them get
together, that makes me even
more nervous because I'm afraid
that one of them's
going to knock the
other one out.
Peter last night was
busting his balls.
I was waiting for Han just to
fucking punch him in the face.
And then Peter was going to
have to beat his ass.
It was going to be a big mess.
HAN CHIANG: Can I get a
couple knives here?
BRAD SPENCE: It's kind of funny
to see them hanging out.
Let's get a cheers before
somebody gets stabbed with a
[INAUDIBLE] knife,
or some shit.
[INAUDIBLE].
-Cheers.
PETER MCANDREWS: Thank
you, everybody.
BRAD SPENCE: All the chefs in
this city, for the most part
are really cool.
We work our ass off.
And one of the perks is, when
you go out, people to take
care of you, which
is a cool thing.
I love doing it.
It's part of the joy of the
business, is to be able to
take care of somebody
that works their ass
off the same as you.
PETER MCANDREWS: Han, salud.
HAN CHIANG: Peter.
PETER MCANDREWS: How do you
say that in Chinese?
HAN CHIANG: [CHINESE]
[CHINESE]
[MUSIC PLAYING]