and of course uh... previous reports
came from weeks within the white house
that's what we believe that they were
true in terms of reporting it 'cause it
was the white house bragging about it
all now
michael's a couple of n_b_c_ news has
the white papers a sixteen page memo
that justifies killing u_s_ citizens
would throw strikes
so
is it as they
is short of something that they knew all
in the most dire circumstances and
somebody's about the launch against the
united act out a few why dot we have to
take out the sitting quietly important
are clearly
as you read the memo to becomes obvious
that of course that's not what happened
so let me begin quoting it too
the threat posed by allocated a explain
and its associated forces demands a
broader concept of p
imminence in judging what a person
continually planning terror attacks
presents
i love lawyerly language he had a sale
that means
i'm is an eminent thread
does it mean an imminent threat
it doesn't have to be immediate
except threat
whenever
as long as somebody in the executive
branch is decided
yelling all like that guy he might be
someone at some point
big is asap
now here are the so-called limitations
it does not require the u_s_
to have information about a specific
imminent but i guess the u_s_
uh... that those of a limitation this
seems like the exact opposite
simple go-ahead bombs away number two
it requires that they can to return a
suspect
not be feasible
but as a memo explains later
or be in undue burden on our troops
well he now would have been impaired and
trying to capture that guy
or perhaps at post country didn't agree
so we excuse somebody within the host
country because it was an undue burden
okay
and number three
operation complies with the fundamental
law of war principles
and that's where it's
as a whole memo violates the law war
principles
but it says at the end worried
were following the law war principles
why
because we said so
now new laws of war allow you to
excuse someone
who is not an imminent threat
and not on the battlefield and not the
jury came in many ways
now
they don't
but we just said they did so trust us
where the government
mhm i don't think so
so uh... that
that leads to while who's in making this
decision while don't worry we've got
more information on that
is a cough explained several different
quotes put together her from the white
paper
and informed
high-level officials their forbidden of
course the was right
and for my little official of the u_s_
government
may determine did the targeted american
has been
recently involved in activities
posing a threat of violence that
and there is no evidence suggesting that
he has renounced or abandoned such
activities
so women high-level official within the
imperial government
who has decided that you
have some activities at some point
well the reason is not defined
that uh... is a cause of concern for us
and as far as we know
you're not rebels those things that we
found somewhat suspicious
this doesn't involve you get interested
in we finding out
hey you know what what were those
activities and what were you planning
certainly this involves your execution
now remember during the bush years they
used to have a euphemism for torture was
enhanced interrogation
we fought a long battle to make sure it
was called a was torture
now
these are not executions there targeted
killings
all r_t_c_
no here's what they are
assassinations
and executions
these are you would have said is is
remembered for u_s_ citizens
have already been assassinated
including as sixteen-year-old
that was the branches are all walked
these slander
and one robert gibbs was asked about it
former white house spokesperson he said
well then they should know who they're
associating with
but he was an associating with an that
was is that it wasn't even in the same
strike
it was in a different strike
but trust the government don't worrying
what we execute
sixteen year old u_s_ citizens
i'm sure we had a good reason
that since there was another threat well
your physician any information about the
strike
well we continue here with this of
orwellian words a decision maker
determining
whether al qaeda operational leader
presents an imminent threat a violent
act against the united states must take
into account that certain numbers of al
qaeda are continually plotting attacks
against the united states
units and i want
we don't have to have information that
they attack is imminent or immediate or
any such thing
ever understand it had been al-qaeda
they're constantly planning
so we can tell them that anytime
because we have seen they were
they are in mid-atlantic
how've much broader can this possibly be
if you allow the president to do this
what won't you allowed to do
these are u_s_ citizens there excuse me
al-qaeda would engage in such a tax
relief
to accept that they were able to do so
this is from amma
in other words
well
what it might not have particular
evidence in this case
but trust us iftikhar they work be
attacking us that's what we come up with
a chance to
well that's great
so we're actually u_s_ citizens abroad
based on three crops
but trust the government we've got a
good man in charge oquawka hunter got
maggie he would make a mistake worried
he won be malicious about this
that's what we trust the cake that's
what he has arctic ordained by god
all-white he's supposed to be a
president
now we're supposed to be a democracy we
settle messed up back in a magna carta
they're setting us back
aids under two years bush did it
all but i was going at once
was never executed u_s_ citizens like
this
dick cheney thought now that's a bridge
to fall
and now a part of the way
yes bush
stardust femina strode yes he said the
entire planet as a battlefield which is
outrageous which means a tissue people
on-site basically because all i have an
imminent danger everything's a
battlefield obama took at at what a step
further
the memo continues
the u_s_ government may not be aware of
al qaeda plots as they're developing and
those cannot be cabinet
that none is about the car
all for christ sake when you thought it
could be anywhere
we're not confident that a plot is not
happening
so we decided to executed u_s_ citizen
artist verdict might be happening
all the political will
and yet it continues
a lawful killing in self defense the
memo explains
is not an assassination
are well when you put it that way
i didn't know your acting in
self-defense just in case the guy was
going to do something else that's
but we're not really sure about
but yet security before he had a chance
to do it
well then that would make a lawful
killing right because the courts to
decide
no judicial review
ne for america's excuse so far
had a trial or you've been any due
process in terms of the judiciary we
never went to the judiciary
it would just that budget reducing the
executive department deciding that you
know what
we'll talk to you that seems like due
process the guys i hired to work for me
as lawyers have agreed that i can tell
that guy
well are you not possible you check with
the guys you hire whose project depends
on and and bring with you
and of course are
beloved attorney general eric holder
summarize all this
earlier in a speech that he made last
year
depressants
ten judicial process for another one in
the same particularly when it comes to
national security the constitution
guarantees due process
he does not guarantee judicial process
stephen colbert joke crown about of said
well
it could be a process of
brock reverses
could be a trial by fire
ways that you will recall our this is
not process
the new processes for a while back
together on this edition retail acti
got bad luck
after due process