SUROOSH ALVI: Yesterday, we came
here with the police for
the operation that felt like
we were on the set of Cops.
We're back here today, much to
the chagrin of the cops, who
say that it's too dangerous to
be here because this is a
Taliban town, and this is where
everyone gets kidnapped
from, and that we shouldn't
be here.
But we wanted to find out from
the people who live here
exactly what they thought of
the operation yesterday.
So let's go see.
Our fixer was very nervous about
being a sitting duck in
the middle of Orangi Town, to
the point where he refused to
get out of the car.
He said we were asking
for trouble.
We promised we'd only ask two
quick questions and then get
the hell out of there.
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
MALE SPEAKER:
SUROOSH ALVI:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
MALE SPEAKER:
SUROOSH ALVI: Let's go.
Let's bounce, people are
watching and making
calls, so let's go.
As soon as we approached those
guys, the vibe suddenly
changed, and I had a sinking
feeling that we had overstayed
our welcome.
Let's get the fuck
out of here.
Get in, quickly.
The last guys, I think,
were Taliban.
The last two people
I went up to, they
refused to talk to us.
I looked over at my corner, and
there was a guy glaring at
me on the phone, making a call
to someone else, which was our
cue to leave.
We didn't get kidnapped in
Orangi Town, so we decided to
push our luck by visiting the
place where the kidnapped
victims are reportedly held--
the dump.
The air was thick with
smoldering rot.
There were millions of flies,
and the stench was unbearable.
MALE SPEAKER: God dammit, man.
I think they're up my pants
SUROOSH ALVI: Look at this
cute little guy.
Hey, little buddy.
How's life living off garbage?
Oh.
Ugh.
Fuck.
We're here--
fuck.
We're here-- hold on.
MALE SPEAKER: Standing still is
a problem with the flies,
definitely.
SUROOSH ALVI: Yeah.
We're here, an hour outside of
Karachi, in the largest waste
dump in Karachi, and some
say the largest
waste dump in the world.
It's just like maybe out of a
film about the future and
post-apocalypse and this
is all that's left.
And when the gangsters kidnap
people, the best place to
bring them is just on the other
side of this garbage
dump, because no one ever
comes out there.
I mean, why would they?
It's brutal.
It's like hell on Earth.
I knew that going to one of the
largest garbage dumps in
the world--
70 million square feet
and counting--
would be a miserable experience,
but I was shocked
at just how miserable it was.
When Pakistan became a nation
in 1947, Karachi was home to
about 450,000 people.
Today, there are almost 18
million people producing about
8,000 metric tons of
trash every day.
Scavengers here burn that crash,
sending god knows what
into the air over Karachi, in
order to extract the tiniest
bits of metal that they can sell
to recyclers for pennies.
The UNHCR reports that as many
as 20,000 children spend their
days here in the dump, most of
them refugees from the war in
Afghanistan.
Another effect of the war in
Afghanistan has been a major
increase in the flow of heroin
into Pakistan, and at rock
bottom prices.
Come on, let's go.
MALE SPEAKER: All right,
we're coming, man.
SUROOSH ALVI: We're going
to buy some heroin.
We're going to buy some
dope with these guys.
And it's weird, because we're
like, hey, can we watch you
guys shoot up and
buy some heroin?
They're like, sure, why not?
Sounds like a perfectly
good idea.
While one gram of heroin can
cost more than $200 in the US,
here in Karachi, it
costs about $0.80.
Wow, we just lost them
dropping down.
This is the shop for heroin.
Even at these ridiculously low
prices, the market for illegal
opiates in Pakistan is more than
$1 billion annually, with
roughly 160 metric tons of
heroin coming in every year,
feeding the habits of over
four million addicts.
We headed back to these guys'
favorite place to shoot up--
the middle of a busy street.
Now we've got some heroin
zombies on our tail.
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
MALE SPEAKER:
SUROOSH ALVI: Since we were
having such a heavy day, our
fixer decided to take us
someplace that he thought
might cheer us up.
So we're going to see some
crocodiles that they say are
hundreds, if not thousands,
of years old.
Are those things fake or real?
OK, I don't know what the
fuck is going on, dude?
I don't know why I'm here.
Oh, what's in its mouth?
No, thanks.
I am not going in there.
You can go ahead.
Aw.
BASIM USMANI: These crocodiles
are actually disciples of a
famous Punjabi saint
named Ganjshakar.
They're famous for eating
gulab jamuns and halva.
They're the only crocodiles in
the world that eat desserts.
SUROOSH ALVI: That's random.
That's a great sound effect.
Why is there a crocodile
farm museum here?
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
SUROOSH ALVI: After that weird
interlude, we headed back to
the hotel to rest up for one of
the scariest appointments
we'd ever made--
a meeting with a target killer.