GRADO: I remember when I was
about 12 years old, I used to
speak to these wrestling
on the internet.
And I would tell them that I
was a wrestling journalist.
And say, oh, I'm a Scottish
wrestling journalist.
I'm 30 years old, and give me a
wrestler's phone number, and
I'll phone them.
I would take my pocket money,
right, change it into pound
coins, and go to a phonebox,
and I would phone these
wrestlers in America.
The phone rang, and I was like
hi, this Graeme from Scotland.
I would like to do
an interview with
you, is that OK?
How did you get my
number, bro?
Uh, I'm--
I'm--
a wrestling journalist.
I'm just looking to
get a few words.
Is that OK?
[GRUFF VOICE]
Dude, don't you phone
here again.
How'd you get my number?
I shat myself and hung up.
The reason why I've never ever
been booked on big shows is
because of my physique.
I mean, I've not exactly
got the best
wrestling body there is.
Which kind of annoys me, because
I hate seeing other
wrestlers that look like
a bag of shite.
My first ever training session
was when I was 14 years old,
which was about 10 years
ago this year.
But you would never believe
I've had 10 years
of wrestling training.
If you see me wrestle now, you'd
probably think I've been
wrestling for about
six months, do
you know what I mean?
I would stop wrestling every now
and again, just because I
had a bad match and thought
I've stunk that ring out.
I never want to do that again.
It was embarrassing.
And when I was at school,
obviously, a lot of people
heard that I was training
to be a wrestler.
And there were some people who
thought that was really cool.
But there was always other
folk that thought
that's a lot of shite.
That's fake.
That is gay.
And to be honest with you, you
just keep your head up and
think to yourself, get
yourself to fuck.
All people really need to do is
go on the internet and find
a respectable training school
out there that will train you
to the highest standard.
UK DOMINATOR: My real name
is Dominic Hepburn.
My alias is the UK Dominator.
Now, anybody can get in the
ring, anybody can wrestle.
But that doesn't make
a wrestler, does it?
What makes a wrestle is people
hating you, people loving you.
So face shows, do you
know what I mean?
If you want a really evil look,
it's like you want to
look at somebody, you want to
make them hate you for that
look, or you want to make them
love you for that look.
Because if you go out to a ring
and you don't give the
right persona out there, who's
going to take to me?
Who's going to boo me?
Who's going to really
look at me?
Nobody.
FEMALE SPEAKER: I am one of
the wrestler's mums--
Johnny Sicko.
I'm looking forward to it.
DANGER DAN: I'm PWA trainee
Danger Dan.
And you have entered
the Danger Zone.
That's it.
ANNOUNCER: It's showtime!
[CHEERS]
UK DOMINATOR: Look at
the child, you go,
is this your mum?
Child goes, yeah.
And she's as ugly
as you, mate.
You go on the mic, and you turn
around and you say, I've
wrestled all over the world.
But I've never seen so many fat,
overweight people in one
place at one time.
You, you, you and all you!
Your worst enemy!
You see, I have three rules
before I start wrestling.
The first rule-- when I
tell you to sit down,
you will sit down.
What do they do?
They get up.
MALE SPEAKER: Hammer him!
UK DOMINATOR: Second rule-- when
I tell you to shut up,
you will shut up.
What do they do?
They shout.
MALE SPEAKER: Boo!
UK DOMINATOR: My third
and my final rule--
you will show me respect, the
respect that I deserve.
And if you don't, I don't care
if you're a six-year-old kid,
or I don't care if you're
a 66-year-old old man.
I'll come out of this ring, and
I'll smash every one of
your faces in.
I'll come out of this ring
and smash your faces in!
And by that time, you've got
them shouting, and you've got
them screaming.
And if that don't work, mate,
get out of the business.
It's as simple as that.
DAN WALSH: So I call myself Dan
"The Pretty Boy" Walsh,
all the ladies love
me kind of thing.
Whereas my fitness is probably
not as good as most people, I
make it up with my character.
My character's a lot better
than most people's.
I can go out there and change,
and I'm that guy.
Yeah, baby!
You want some of this
in your mouth, huh?
Get out of my face now.
This one here, he claims
job seeker's allowance.
MALE SPEAKER: Well, then,
I'm a security guard.
And I could beat you up,
you fucking prick.
DAN WALSH: Where I come from,
Kensington, London, we don't
look inbred like each and
every one of you.
You're looking at the
future of WWE.
I'm going to get paid loads of
money, get all the girls to be
kissing some of this.
And then I won't have to see
your faces ever again.
I think I could be
a WWE superstar.
I think I've got the gimmick.
I've got the aura about me,
and I want that lifestyle.
I grew up watching wrestling,
and I was watching them, and I
want to be like them.
And so from the age of like,
say four, I was mesmerized.
Most people say that
you should grow out
of it kind of thing.
But I looked at it more from
the business point of view,
saying I want to do that
to make money.
You know, these guys
are celebrities.
I've always wanted to
be a celebrity.
My whole life I've felt like I'm
never going to fit in to a
normal 9:00 to 5:00 style.
And that's my motivation and
drive to get out of these kind
of shows and get up
to the next stage.
And there's nothing wrong with
them, don't get me wrong.
I've learnt my trade, and I'll
never forget my roots.
But there comes a point when you
turn around and say this
ain't for me anymore.
I don't want to do
the lifestyle
of most normal people.
I want to leave a legacy, that's
what I've always said.
I want to be in books that
people read in 2,000 years,
saying this was a professional
wrestler back in 2000.
You know, that's kind
of cool to me--
hopefully.
I don't know if you've seen
The Wrestler, the movie?
I sometimes feel that's going
to be me if I fail.
And it scares me, mate.
Seeing him living in the
trailer, and doing
drugs kind of thing.
Still living the dream
in a sports hall
with like 20 people.
MALE SPEAKER: I watched The
Wrestler up until maybe
two-thirds of the way through.
I'm just like, yeah,
I can't watch this.
It's kind of awkward.
I'd got the long, blonde hair
at the time and stuff.
And I was in the gym, and
some guy walked in.
He goes, you look like Mickey
Rourke out of The Wrestler.
Should I really take that
as a compliment?
This is a guy who's had a
botched face lift, and you're
telling me I look like him.
It's like, cheers!
It looks like I've
had a stroke on
both sides of my face.
When I was doing 350 shows a
year, me and the persona
starting getting a little bit
blurred at times, and I was a
complete and utter arsehole.
And I can be honest with that,
like, people hated my guts.
When you've talked to the other
guys, they'll probably
say a similar thing like the
wrestler is just an extension
of their personality.
Well, obviously, I'm
not a transvestite.
GRADO: I want some of this
promo on the beach.
This is my pal Jordan.
JORDAN: Hi.
GRADO: He films all my promos
and edits them and puts them
together before I put
them on YouTube.
JORDAN: I just use my camera
phone and some software we got
for free on the internet.
GRADO: So get the fucking
phone out and film me.
It's yourself!
Sports--
sport-- blah, la, la.
Just keep going.
Maybe with my bumbag as
if it's like my belt.
JORDAN: A belt?
Aye.
GRADO: Aye.
You remember when you were a
wean, and you wanted to grow
up and be the biggest sports
star in the world?
Boxing fans would grow up as
fanatics, wanting to fight for
the heavyweight title in
Las Vegas, Nevada?
Tennis, you wanted to verse
every cunt in Wimbledon?
I'm telling you.
JORDAN: You can't say cunt.
It's a PG thing.
GRADO: Oh, PG, fuck.
That do?
JORDAN: Obviously, it looks
better with music over the top
of it and edit it.
GRADO: All right, once we get
music in, it will look better.
Fuck, I'm cunted.
There's a speedboat.
It's yourself!
I didn't really decide to
make it my catchphrase.
People just kind of
clicked onto it.
It's just a kind of quick way
of saying, it's yourself.
How are you doing?
Hi!
There's old Jeanie.
It's yourself, old Jeanie.
How are you doing?
I don't know when I shout it's
yourself, it's just like
something that they can
relate to Grado.
It's just like The Rock, where
The Rock says if you smell
what The Rock's cooking.
ANNOUNCER: If you smell what
The Rock is cooking!
GRADO: It doesn't actually
mean The Rock is actually
making something for
you to smell it,
you know what I mean?
It's just he's saying it.
It's just his catchphrase.
It's just like me.
It's yourself!
ANNOUNCER: Good evening
Sudbury!
Welcome to Pro Wrestling Eve!
Before we start I just need
to check one thing.
And that's are you ready?
[CHEERS]
HANNAH: First time ever in
wrestling history, twins
versus twins.
It's Blossoms versus
the Owens.
Obviously, they have all the
cool twin poses and stuff.
We like baking and cupcakes
and British things.
Hanna, Holly.
HOLLY: Yes.
HANNAH: The Blossom Twins.
HANNAH: We spent five years
around the UK, and we've just
come back from two years in
America, in Kentucky.
MALE SPEAKER: Whoa, you're
tagging with the Blossoms?
MALE SPEAKER: You better
believe that I am.
MALE SPEAKER: Hey,
I want a cupcake.
MALE SPEAKER: Get away!
That's for Team Cupcake only.
And tonight, that's us.
Ain't that right, ladies?
HOLLY: Yes.
MALE SPEAKER: What do
you say we go get
ready for this match?
What do you say?
Woohoo!
HANNAH: We've had a few
different outfits.
I think when we went over to
America we decided it would be
fun to sort of do more
of the British thing.
I know people are going to tell
you're British as soon as
you open your mouth, but it was
just something as a way of
saying this is where I'm
from and this is us.
HOLLY: First time rocking
this gear.
HANNAH: New for this show.
MALE SPEAKER: Touch me, and I'll
punch you in the face,
you dirty old git.
MALE SPEAKER: Dick!
MALE SPEAKER: What?
What?
MALE SPEAKER: Rubbish.
MALE SPEAKER: What?
FEMALE SPEAKER: Go home!
Go home!
FEMALE SPEAKER: Fuck off!
MALE SPEAKER: Rockstar!
FEMALE SPEAKER: Go home!
MALE SPEAKER: You suck!
MALE SPEAKER: Nice
clothes, nob.
If you were that important, the
audience would be facing
you, you ugly nob!
MALE SPEAKER: Wrestling fans are
probably the most unique
fans in the world.
There's no question about it.
MALE SPEAKER: Come
on, wrestle!
MALE SPEAKER: It's what I
call a physical theatre.
That is, a performance sport.
It is entertaining through the
medium of getting hurt almost.
MALE SPEAKER: That's what I
love about professional
wrestling, you know?
Because this is going back to
the days of Shakespeare when
people would come
and see this.
We just hit people with
car doors instead.
FEMALE SPEAKER: You want the
fucking outcome, ref?
GRADO: When I was younger, there
used to be a promotion
that came to Irvine, which
was along the road.
And there was a woman wrestler
on that show
called Klondyke Kate.
And I tell you, she was probably
ten times scarier
than any of the men wrestlers
that were there.
And I remember I was watching
the wrestling in the crowd
with my friends and had
a bag of popcorn.
And I took one bite of
popcorn and launched
it at Klondyke Kate.
And the look she gave me
haunted me for years.
HANNAH: We're teaching
assistants,
we're nursery nurses.
But it's the contrast at first
when people think oh, you're
sweet and you're cute.
And then you go and wrestle and
it's like-- but their kids
absolutely love it.
And for the kids at school who
go, my teacher's a wrestler.
It's kind of fun for them.
MALE SPEAKER: Heartbreak
Twins.
That's what they need
to be called.
They're lovely, aren't they?
GRADO: This is Molly, she's
my biggest supporter.
She watches all my matches.
She's got all my DVDs.
My dog, she's the biggest fan.
Aren't you, hun?
My hands are stinking, man.
I thought I used to get
called Grado in
primary school, right?
And then I never, ever
get called it
through secondary school.
Then I went on a boy's holiday
to Magaluf one year.
And on the last night, me and my
best mate ended up getting
chucked out of the hotel.
So we thought, come on, we'll
go and get tattoos.
So when I went to the tattoo
parlor, I said
put Grado on my arm.
Put Grado on my arm.
The next morning I woke up,
I couldn't believe it.
I tried to scratch it off.
I thought, nobody even
calls me Grado.
There's nothing worse than
somebody having a name
tattooed on their arm that
nobody even calls them.
So I was telling everybody,
you better start
calling me Grado now.
And it just kind of clicked
on and everybody
kind of calls Grado.
And it's just worked its
way into my wrestling
character as well.
So a stupid night in Magaluf
getting a daft tattoo's
actually worked out
quite well for me.
FEMALE SPEAKER: My son has been
into wrestling since ever
I can remember.
Just recently we went
to the Civic Centre.
We went to that and it was a
good night although I wasn't
too pleased because he got a
chair over his head and he
ended in A&E.
GRADO: Somehow I managed to
hit him with my finishing
maneuver, "the Wee Boot."
We started trending.
With the click of a button,
three towns wide, we starting
trending hashtag, Wee Boots to
Asses, Wee Boots to Asses.
FEMALE SPEAKER: He's just
always been like that.
We've always said he's going
to be on the stage one day.
So there he is, he has to
get his own wee stage.
GRADO: Just getting my gear.
That's my wrestling singlet.
I've got my toothbrush in there
as well, because there's
nothing worse than wrestling
somebody with bad breath.
And I've got my deodorant
as well.
Aye, spray and all.
There's nothing worse.
That's one of the reasons you
don't like it and all, because
sometimes you can smell
the wrestlers, man.
Some of them are stinking
men, honestly.
Some of them you just want
to say get a wash.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Exactly.
GRADO: Honestly, some of the
hygiene in British wrestling
man, gives you the boke.
Let's do this!
Come on!
MALE SPEAKER: Go Grado!
Grado!
GRADO: I'm bringing
the title home!
I'll bring the title home!
Come on!