stealthy hunters‥
and unparalleled predators
engage in a never-ending
struggle for survival
But among these species
12 rule supreme
These predators are swift‥
powerful‥
and often lethal
Prepare to come face to face
with Africa's Deadly Dozen
In many people's minds
this is the last truly wild continent
Its 30 million square kilometres
contain some of the world's
most extreme landscapes‥
‥the Serengeti
a vast arena for the delicate ballet
of life and death‥
‥the Okavango
an oasis emerging from
the parched Kalahari Desert‥
‥and the Great Rift Valley
an unforgiving terrain and
the scorching 'cradle of man'
These brutal cauldrons forge creatures
of incomparable strength and power‥
creatures found nowhere else on Earth
Most of Africa's wildlife
and its people
live south of the searing Sahara Desert
And in this region
one predator in particular reigns
the snake
Africa plays host to the greatest
diversity of snakes in the world
400 in total
with over 90 of them venomous
And these toxic serpents
are built for the kill
Each is uniquely specialized
to capture its prey
Sleek cobras stalk‥
while muscular vipers lie in wait‥
and still others take to the trees
But if threatened
all of these predators
will lash out with a hiss of death
And among them
this is the quintessential
deadly serpent‥
embodying all that's lethal
without even baring it fangs
It's known as Naja Nivea
the cape cobra
and anyone who corners this snake
is likely to pay with their life
The one and a half metre cobra
is neither the biggest nor the
widest-ranging venomous serpent in Africa
It's only found in one region
the southwest
but this includes the heavily-populated
country of South Africa
And it often appears
in prime ranching territory
so human encounters are all too common
Every year, the cape cobra kills
more people in South Africa
than any other snake
Its speckled skin enables it
to almost disappear within the landscape
until it's stumbled upon
by an unlucky rancher or shepherd
When trapped
it raises the front of its body high
and spreads its trademark hood
in a display of intimidation‥
then it strikes
The rush of venom immediately
attacks the body's nervous system
It paralyzes the muscles
and triggers coronary
and respiratory failure
Just one bite can kill up to six people
And the cobra doesn't just strike once
It continues to strike
until the threat has moved away
flooding its victim with toxins
Another venomous snake
also lurks among the branches
and this one is practically invisible
It's the eastern green mamba
Africa's emerald giant
Resting in the canopy
it's easily missed
But when it's on the move
it's clear
what makes this serpent so deadly
The green mamba stretches
up to two metres long
Its slender contours and camouflage
mean it's perfectly suited
to a life in the trees
where it sleeps‥
mates‥ and feeds
The green mamba hunts a sinuous band
from coastal Kenya south to Zimbabwe
where it lurks in scrub bush and forests
It's nearly invisible to the birds
rodents and small lizards it pursues
Its ever-vigilant eyes never close
because fixed transparent shields
serve in place of eyelids
Its attention is drawn by movement
One misplaced hand
and the mamba springs to life
Victims of its bite feel a burning pain
As the venom spreads it eats away tissue
potentially causing gangrene
and leaving behind a permanent scar
Fortunately green mambas often
choose escape over confrontation
and only a handful of deaths
have ever been recorded
But another mamba also lives up here
less shy than its green cousin‥
and this one is lethal
It's the black mamba
The black mamba follows
a trail of aerial clues‥
tasting the air as it goes
Its target is an abandoned hatchling
Potent venom floods
the tiny bird's system
killing it swiftly
This mamba is a far more
dangerous snake than the green
Not only is it found across a much
larger swath of the continent
from Ethiopia to Namibia
but it also hunts on the ground
And that places it
in direct contact with humans
It only takes one encounter
with a black mamba
to realize what makes this snake
so terrifying
Not only is it extraordinarily toxic
it's the longest
and fastest snake in Africa
A black mamba can reach burst speeds
of five metres per second
faster than most people can run
Incredibly, the mamba can also lift
half of its 3.5m body off the ground
and return to the trees
Every harvest season
orchard workers venture into
the realm of the black mamba
Surrounded, the snake
will first try to escape
But if it has nowhere to go‥
it will defend itself
Flashing its ebony-coloured mouth
it strikes
The victim is infused with a complex
torrent of paralyzing toxins
This venom attacks the body's muscles
and heart and lung function
And when the muscles stop
asphyxiation sets in
Death can occur in as few as 20 minutes
Before anti-venom
the black mamba's bite
was almost 100 per cent fatal
But today
hospitals can save most victims
if they can get there in time
But while the black mamba
may be Africa's most feared snake
it's not the deadliest
That distinction goes
to the master of concealment‥
the puff adder
It kills more people in Africa
than any other snake
It earns this dubious distinction
because of its huge range
which covers nearly half the continent
from tropical Senegal
to Eritrea and South Africa
Most encounters are accidental
because victims often
don't see the well-hidden adder
Slow and muscular
it can't use speed to escape
So instead, it relies
on its method of attack
This heavy snake launches
its one metre body into the air
and towards any unwise intruder
Centimetre long hollow fangs
inject a venom
that starts to destroy blood cells
and tissue almost immediately
Most people do survive the encounter
But the adder's range
and the sheer number of bites it inflicts
reap a deadly toll
that results in more fatalities
than any other African snake
But people aren't the only casualties
Undetected, this adder remains frozen
Although its victim
is only centimetres away
it has no idea of its impending death
The adder attacks when the target
is unable to use teeth and claws
in self defence
Its lower jaw widens
to accommodate larger prey
When the meal is finally devoured
its jaw flexes back to normal
Africa's snakes inhabit almost
every corner of the continent
brilliantly adapted for life
both on the ground
and high above
In the Savannas of eastern
and southern Africa
water is the most precious commodity
And within these pools
live two of Africa's most lethal animals
both armed to the teeth
Every year, Nile crocodiles
kill hundreds of people
probably more than all other species
of crocodile combined
They hunt waterways
throughout most of Africa
Yet people have driven them
from much of the river
that shares their name
A reptile of epic proportions
the Nile crocodile can grow
to lengths of six metres
and weigh close to a ton
Its power allows it to select
from a vast menu of prey
including buffalo
antelope
and even young elephants
A fully grown Nile crocodile
has few natural enemies
Equipped with eyes on the top of its head
it studies its prey‥
and hides
A Nile croc lying in wait
can hold its breath for over 45 minutes
But with a simple flick of its tail
it catapults itself out of the water
It grabs its prey by the head or limb
and pulls the meal down
to a murky death
Another water-borne creature
also lashes out with its teeth
but this one is a herbivore‥
the hippo
Its placid demeanor belies
a volatile temperament
During the day
a water hole can offer cool refuge
from the searing African heat
Here, a hippo is in its element
Despite its substantial mass
the creature is buoyant
When a three and a half ton hippo
slips below the surface
it seals its nostrils completely
and can hold its breath
for up to 30 minutes
Hippos inhabit the watering holes
of west, east and southern Africa
as well as the upper reaches
of the Nile River
Only one predator
will hunt an adult hippo‥
a pride of lions
And even then, they're not easily taken
Hippos can run at nearly
30 kilometres per hour
The males wield 30 centimetre tusks
which they use in battle
These giant canines
can deliver devastating wounds‥
and are capable of
biting a crocodile in half
But it's the females that
pose the greatest threat to humans
They protect their calves fiercely
even from other hippos
With a newborn to guard
an adult female
won't tolerate any intruder
Every year, these leviathans
kill dozens of people
Although their range is shrinking
hippos still rule the water hole
Africa's aquatic giants
are well adapted for survival
Whether on dry land‥
in the water‥
or under it‥
these animals are equipped
to deal with all threats
and opportunities
head on
Africa is home to some of the most
awe-inspiring wildlife on the planet
venomous insects‥
toxic serpents‥
and deadly predators
But few species embody all that is Africa
like its ancient giants
This grazer weighs nearly a ton
While it feeds, it's calm
But suddenly
it can transform into one of the most
dangerous creatures on the continent
The hunter becomes the hunted
as the behemoth retaliates
The cape buffalo spends 18 hours a day
moving across the Savanna
in relative peace
But when provoked
the grass-fed giant
can prove a worthy adversary
of both fierce carnivores like lions‥
and trophy hunting humans
who target the buffalo
for its ornate rack of horns
It thunders along at the speed
of a galloping horse
It can easily disembowel a predator
with little more than
a slash of its horns
or a well-aimed hoof
100 years ago
buffalo roamed nearly
all of sub-Saharan Africa
But today, they're gone
from most of the south
Yet they're still among the most
abundant large animals on the continent
and the only thing
more dangerous than one buffalo
is a startled herd, stampeding
Another massive creature
shares the buffalo's territory‥
but this one squeezes the life
from its victims
It lies in wait
watching for its prey to approach
and prepares to attack
The African rock python
has a deadly embrace
Unlike other snakes
this constrictor doesn't strike with venom
Instead, it kills with muscle
African rock pythons
can weigh up to 135 kilograms
and grow to over six metres‥
making them among the largest snakes
in the world
They live throughout the Savannas
and forests of sub-Saharan Africa
Already powerful on land
this brawny serpent employs an even
more impressive tactic from underwater
where it glides with fluid grace
Ever adaptable
the pythons that live near water
thrive on fish
And older snakes
can find even bigger prey here
They wait underwater‥
rising every 30 minutes
to take a discreet breath
They can spend hours
in this coil of tension‥
waiting for just the right moment
to strike
Scores of teeth seize the prey‥
and muscular coils envelop the victim
Crushed, the springbok
is slowly asphyxiated
The python can swallow up to
60kg of lifeless prey - whole
After a meal like this
it can fast for more than a year
But even so
it should always
be approached with caution
This snake will defend itself
no matter what the size of the threat
So, although pythons rarely eat people
they can still kill us
Giants that are placid in appearance‥
can sometimes transform into killers
when provoked
But one of Africa's enormous animals
is unexpectedly deadly
It weighs more than a truck‥
stands twice as tall as a human‥
and can crush with a misplaced foot
It's the world's largest land animal
And if you enrage an elephant
its fury can be lethal
Humans have pushed elephants
to the brink
dividing their lands‥
culling their ranks‥
and causing disarray in their families
And now, elephants are pushing back
Once, they roamed much of Africa freely
But today
most elephants are confined
to patches of protected land
in central, east and southern Africa
Roads and farms divide them
from their traditional grounds
and impede their timeless migrations
As a result of this
they're often forced
into unnatural habitats
where they quickly exhaust food supplies
and have to compete with
domestic herds for water
While seeking out new territories
they can ravage fields and gardens
And all too often
this leads to confrontations
with unarmed rural inhabitants
In the 1990s
more than 200 people were killed
by elephants in Kenya alone
Efforts are underway
to reduce elephant overcrowding
But with ever-decreasing territory
their conflicts with us will only increase
Of Africa's trio of ancient giants
two are grazers‥
and only one is a predator
But all have earned a place
among this land's most lethal animals
A pair of predators
rules the African darkness
One is a cunning hunter‥
and the other, the ultimate survivor
But neither is exactly
what it appears to be
As they stalk in the darkness
their invisible laughter
pierces the shadows
and stirs panic in all who hear it
These creatures are legendary
hunters and scavengers
These are the eery calls
of the spotted hyena
There are three species
of hyena in Africa
the striped and the brown
which are solitary‥
and the spotted
which is a highly social animal
The spotted hyena ranges from
Senegal and Somalia in the north
to Botswana and Namibia in the south
making it the most common
large carnivore in Africa
Clans contain up to 80 individuals
But they break into smaller teams to hunt
Once dismissed as maniacal 'laughter'
their yelps, growls and whoops
act as a dinner bell‥
a call to arms‥
or a warning to their cubs
Their body language also
sends signals to the clan‥
intent to attack‥
excitement‥
or fear
When clan territory overlaps
with that of other predators
hyenas will intimidate
any carnivorous competitors
and, if given the chance
kill their cubs
They eat anything
At a kill, nothing is left to waste
The hyena's massively-muscled
head and neck
power some of the strongest jaws in nature
They can exert a bite force
stronger than that of a lion
Hyenas are efficient hunters
with the ability to crush, swallow
and digest nearly every part of their prey
including the bones
They kill their prey with their brutal jaws
But another of the night's hunters
wields a much smaller
but equally effective - weapon
The toxic punch unleashed by this predator
has earned it the name 'death stalker'
This scorpion is only 10cm long
but it's possibly
the most dangerous in the world
400 million years ago
long before the age of the dinosaurs
scorpions were perfecting
the tactics, armour and venom
that would ensure their success
There are more than
1,200 different species on the planet
and hundreds of them live only in Africa
But the death stalker thrives
in one of the most extreme
environments on Earth
The Sahara Desert
is the centre of its territory
which stretches from
Egypt southwest to Mali
Scorpions hunt the shadows
seeking out spiders
small rodents and insects
Their pincers snatch their prey
and prepare it for the kill
Then the stinger injects the lethal blow
Although a sting delivers
less venom than a snake bite
the death stalker's toxins
are nearly three times
as powerful as a cape cobra's
Fever, convulsions
and increased blood pressure
can wrack victims in
as few as five minutes
But fewer than 3 per cent
of stings are lethal
Children suffer the most fatalities
because a dose of venom is far more
potent in their smaller bodies
A pack hunter‥
and a solitary killer
Africa's nocturnal predators
have a tactic for every occasion
But among Africa's deadly dozen
one animal reigns supreme
With up to 250 kilograms of pure muscle
it's the largest carnivore
on the continent
They hunt in daylight and at night
alone‥ or in teams
There's no creature too big
or too smart
for them to tackle‥
even us
When they catch an animal
they just eat everything
After falling down
they started to bite me on the legs
The lion is perhaps the most
formidable predator in all of Africa
Once, lions roamed
nearly all of this land
unsurpassed and unstoppable
But then they met us
Over the course of the last century
humans have killed
hundreds of thousands of them
Today, the big cats may number
fewer than 23,000
Small numbers remain in
west African countries like Mali
while other populations range
from Somalia and south to Namibia
But most of them live
behind the long fences of reserves
like South Africa's Kruger National Park
sanctuary for more than 2,700 lions
In November 1998
park guard Sydney Maziya
was shutting down the neighbouring
Marloth Game Reserve for the evening
He received word that a gate
at the far end of the park was open
and was given an order to close it
The only way for Maziya
to cross the reserve was by bicycle
even though there were lions around
While I was still cycling to the gate
I heard the sound of the lions
Lions have nine different vocalizations
but it's their roar
that indicates their domain
And the roars surrounding Sydney
were coming from all directions
Females - often sisters
form the core of a pride of lions
They're joined by males who can be
nearly twice their size
Together, they're armed with enough power
to take down a buffalo
weighing nearly a ton
Their muscular back legs
launch them towards their quarry‥
while their agile front legs
pull the prey to the ground
The fatal bite
is often delivered by a male
and he's the first to feed
But while their size helps them to hunt
it comes at a price
Every hunt is crucial
because it requires precious energy
Ultimately, only about one in
every five attempts succeeds
And in rare instances, some lions
turn to a weaker form of prey
In 1898
lions terrorized the track layers
of an East African Railroad Company
Two notorious animals
killed and ate more than 120 people
They became known
as the Man-Eaters of Tsavo
After nine months of terror
the project's chief engineer
Lieutenant Colonel John Henry Patterson
finally shot the elusive cats
Today, lions kill
dozens of people every year
a statistic with which park guard
Sydney Maziya was all too familiar
When the lion jumped over me
what came in my mind was that
'oh now, I am dead.'
Before long, more lions had joined
in the attack on Maziya
The other lions that came to me
and started to eat me
Then suddenly, his luck changed
A truck appeared
and the driver had a gun
They bite me on my thigh
on my knee
After the lion left, I realized
how badly injured I was
I was losing a lot of blood
Sydney Maziya's mauled legs
are now mended
and he's back on his feet
But his encounter has left him
with a healthy respect
for the most formidable predator
in Africa
It is lucky if they don't kill you
Because I know, usually
if they grab you, they kill you
They're an elite group of 12‥
embodying all of nature's
grandeur and power
They have thrived with a vast array
of survival skills and defences
They are Africa's Deadly Dozen
www.mvgroup.org
Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org