thermodynamics
And we open a few letter bombs from our
viewers - all this and more, coming up in
this edition of Genesis Week.
And a welcome to this episode of Genesis
Week, the weekly program of creationary
commentary on news, views and events
pertaining to the origins controversy,
exclusive right here on youtube.  The Bible
does not say "Be ye transformed by the
removal of your mind" but rather we here
at Genesis Week believe God gave you a
brain for a reason, and so we use our
brains in search of the truth.
Remember if you get lost in cyberspace,
just punch in wazooloo.com or
genesisweek.com, and you will find us, or
click the ever-so-convenient subscribe
link up top. I'm your host, Ian Juby.
A December 14th "Biology Letters" paper
by Isabelle Dean and Michael T.
Siva-Jothy reported the results of an
experiment where they shaved the
armpits of men and women to see if they
could detect bed bugs better.
Ya can't make this stuff up.
Now of course, in order to get research
funding, you must give a nod to evolution,
and your results MUST support
evolution....even if the results don't
support evolution. For example, in the
abstract we read:
Talk about a stretch!  Our lack of hair is
really unexplainable by evolutionary
theory, so we must find some advantage
of the lack of human hair to offer an
evolutionary explanation!
So what did they find? Well, I like the way
Bob Yirka at physorg.com put it:
Wwwwooowwww...  This report has the
potential to affect online dating site
profile photos for men, as clearly ladies
are after the hairiest guy out there.
After all, based on this scientific report,
that's what you ladies are after - a hairy
guy which means he's bed-bug free,
right?
This is just another example of how far
people will reach to make alleged
"benefits" to be alleged "evidence for
evolution."  Even when evolution really
cannot explain the evidence - like in this
case, the lack of fur on humans.  But it
sure makes a funny story!
youtuber Potholer54 recently posted a
video "setting fire to creationist straw
men" - which really strikes me as ironic,
as he delved into trying to debunk
thermodynamics and subsequently
burned himself so bad. Potholer definitely
needs to be "filled in" on what
thermodynamics is, and in fact, I'll have a
rant coming out shortly, mostly devoted
to his video because while his discussion
of thermodynamics was SO bad and so
full of flagrant, gross error, sadly, his
response was typical of the
anti-creationary community.  But I bring
that up, along with the snowflakes that
potholer mentioned, because Nature
magazine also had an article come out on
the incredible variety snowflakes can
produce.... and just because it's winter
here in Canada.  What a better time to deal
with what we creationists refer to as "the
stupid snowflake argument."
That's right - the claim is that incredibly
complex snowflakes can form, therefore
the laws of entropy (or disorder) are
"violated," therefore we can conclude that
life can arise from non-life.
Of course, potholer first pulled the "open
systems" argument, claiming that energy
coming in from the sun can cause life to
arise - and then cites snowflakes and
sunflowers as examples.  This makes it
evident that potholer doesn't have a CLUE
what he's talking about. First of all, as I
already pointed out in a previous rant,
"closed thermodynamic systems" do not
exist!  The well established laws of
thermodynamics were formed to describe
what happens in open systems.
So why then would potholer talk about
closed systems? I can only think of two
possible reasons: Ignorance, or
obfuscation.
Snowflakes form by cooling, yet potholer
was calling upon energy from the sun to
magically defy disorder.  Energy from the
sun plays a role in evaporation of water,
yes, but energy from the sun melts
snowflakes.
Then potholer takes a quantum leap of
faith, comparing a snowflake to the
sunflower!  What???  That's like saying
that because a rock formed by natural
processes, we can therefore conclude
that the space shuttle can form by natural
processes!  And even that crude
comparison doesn't do it justice, because
the space shuttle cannot reproduce,
cannot repair itself, cannot find and
process its own energy, etc...  Do you
know what the odds are that the space
shuttle could form by natural processes?
It's quite easy to calculate actually - the
odds are ZERO that the space shuttle
could form by natural processes, and so
goes even the very proteins that the
sunflower needs in order to live.  But to be
honest, perhaps we should temper those
odds with the fact that Kim Jong ill got 11
holes in one on his first game of golf.  Ya, I
don't believe that either.
Snowflakes most certainly do follow the
laws of thermodynamics and entropy, and
snowflakes have absolutely nothing to do
with life forming from non-life.
Wahoo! Mail for me?
I wanted to give a special thank you to all
of my subscribers and viewers - thanks
for watching, and thanks for commenting.
Please know, that while I try and read
comments, I typically can't get to
responding to them, as my videos get just
waaay too many comments.  However, I
will try to highlight some of your
comments here and there, especially on
Genesis Week.
One youtube skeptic, apparently not
wanting to make his statements
publically, wrote to me privately.  He was
critical of my second pilot Genesis week
episode, criticizing me for allegedly not
knowing that dinosaurs ARE considered
to be birds.  I'm well aware of said claim,
however, apparently you missed my point,
so let me make it again:  Calling a dinosaur
a bird does not make it a bird!
Bagaack!
Citing cladistic diagrams is completely
bogus, because it's easy to show just
how flexible "cladistics" are to
accomodate the current favourite
evolutionary theory - in fact I wrote about
this on my blog where some evolutionism
thinkers were arguing over whether a
hippo was most like a whale, a pig, or a
dog!  And they get paid for this!
Oh, and by the way, there are multiple,
well-respected EVOLUTIONARY scientists
who disagree with you and claim that
dinosaurs are not birds, they believe birds
evolved separate from the dinosaurs.  So
much for cladistics.
I just released another CrEvo Rant on the
origin of life and evolution.  You can click
on the video here and go watch it right
now, or the video will be provided again at
the end of this program.
In response to that video,
Truthseeker1973 wrote in:
JMcH: A person of very skilled in saying a
lot in a very few words, put it succintly:
Evolutionists: pwnd.
Thanks for writing in folks.
The trolls were hard at work again,
flaunting their flagrant ignorance on so
many subjects that I felt like the last male
rabbit in a world of female rabbits during
mating season - wherever do I begin?
Most of the skeptical comments are really
not even worthy of a response.  However,
some of you viewers stepped in with your
comments:
In response to
Thepseudosciencefoundation's flagrantly
ignorant comments on the alleged genetic
similarities between humans and chimps,
TubeNotMe wrote:
You're right on the money. The
differences between humans and chimps
are far beyond the genetic, but even just
the genetic differences are fatal to the
evolutionary model. For example,
thepseudosciencefoundation never
mentions orfan genes, which are a 0%
match between chimps and humans - and
there's hundreds of orfan genes!  Thanks
for writing in Tubenotme, and for the rest
of you viewers, I happened to discuss this
very subject in my last newsletter, which
you can read here.  Sign up for my
newsletters here.
Well, I'm trying to keep these programs
short, so I better sign off here for now.
Don't forget, there's only a few days left
to get your video entry in to the Epic
Evolution Pwnage contest. I'm your host,
Ian Juby, hey - there's a convenient
subscribe link right there!  Don't miss a
single rant or show - subscribe to my
channel today, and if you liked this
program and want to support it, please do
me a favour: just down below is a "Share"
button, complete with easy to click on
links to share this video on plus, twitter or
facebook.  And don't forget to rate and
rant down below!  Remember the words of
Christ who said "I am the way, the
TRUTH, and THE LIFE - no man comes to
the Father but through me" - God bless
you as you pursue the TRUTH.