go!
First up today, we are talking about violence
in Afghanistan. Suicide bombings, three of
them, all of them targeting a U.S. Afghan
base in the eastern part of the country. Officials
say at least three Afghan soldiers and two
civilians were killed. The Taliban, the militant
group that used to control most of Afghanistan
says it`s responsible for these attacks. They
happened earlier Sunday morning before sunrise.
Afghan authorities say all nine of the attackers
were killed, either in the bombings or in
the firefight with U.S. and Afghan troops
that happened afterward. This isn`t the first
time that the base has been targeted by suicide
bombings. It`s located in a region that`s
home to a lot of insurgent activity.
Next up today, we`re looking at the political
unrest in Egypt. An elected assembly has drafted
a new constitution, but only after more moderate
members of that assembly left, complaining
they weren`t being heard. On Saturday, the
assembly turned over the draft to President
Mohamed Morsi. That`s him on the right, he
said there`ll be a referendum, a vote on December
15th. After that announcement protests broke
out, some from people who support President
Morsi, some from people who think he`s trying
to give himself too much power.
Egypt`s Supreme Court was planning to review
the constitution, but some of Morsi`s supporters
gathered outside the court building. The court
canceled its sessions indefinitely. It said
judges won`t go back to work until they can
do their jobs without "any psychological or
physical pressures."
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: Just the facts: Parkinson`s
disease is a disorder of the human nervous
system. Unintentional shaking may be the most
well-known sign of Parkinson`s. But it can
also cause stiffness or slower movements.
It can affect someone`s balance or speech.
Doctors don`t know what causes Parkinson`s
disease and there`s no cure for it. But medications
can help improve its symptoms.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: All right, so we don`t know what causes
Parkinson`s. we do know about 4 million people
worldwide have it, and tens of thousands of
new cases are diagnosed every year. Now, there
is a man who says he`s found a new way to
make that diagnosis. Normally when something
is wrong, you go to a doctor. In this case,
you might not even have to be in the room.
Dr. Sanjay Gupta explains what we mean.
(BEGIN VIDEOTAPE)
DR. SANJAY GUPTA, CNN CORRESPONDENT: Max Little
has a bold idea -- what if doctors could detect
Parkinson`s disease simply by the sound of
your voice?
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: A-a-a ....
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: A-a-a ...
GUPTA: Max Little is close to proving just
that. He says one simple voice test will determine
if someone has Parkinson`s. And all you need
is a telephone.
MAX LITTLE, MATHEMATICIAN: We`ve got an ultra
low-cost way of detecting the disease.
GUPTA: What makes this discovery even more
incredible, Max isn`t a doctor. He is a mathematician.
LITTLE: My name is Max Little, and for a living
I do applied mathematics.
GUPTA (on camera): So, just in terms of the
process, if someone picks up the phone and
calls, what are they told to do?
LITTLE: So, we`ve set up a study called Parkinson`s
Voice Initiative. And the idea with that study
is that we want to collect enough data that
we can test this technology outside the lab,
so we are collecting recordings from people
in all sorts of circumstances that we can`t
control.
And we want to then test our ability to be
able to, you know, accurately detect whether
they have Parkinson`s disease or not. In lab-
based studies we can get 99 percent detection
accuracy. But can we get that sort of accuracy
over the telephone when we don`t have that
sort of controlled circumstances. That`s why
we need to do the study.
GUPTA: 99 percent though?
LITTLE: Yeah. Yeah. That`s the overall accuracy.
Yeah.
In this case, what will happen is that people
will call in, they simply say whether or not
they have been diagnosed with Parkinson`s.
And then they -- we just ask them to say A--a-a
for as long as they can.
GUPTA: That`s it?
LITTLE: Yeah.
GUPTA: It sounds so remarkably simple.
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: A-a-a -a-a ...
GUPTA: So, what do you hear there?
LITTLE: Yes, that`s a classic example of vocal
tremor. You can actually hear the tremor in
the way that the vocal folds, the laringia
muscles are twitching somewhere.
And that affects the pitch.
GUPTA: So, the same soft of tremor that you
have in your hands, your arms -- you`re saying
that`s basically happening around in the muscles
around your vocal cords.
LITTLE: That`s right. Yeah.
(END VIDEOTAPE)
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: Today`s "Shoutout" goes
out to Mr. Osborn`s economics and history
classes at Creswell High School in Creswell,
Oregon.
Which of these bodies of water is the largest?
Here we go. Is it the Persian Gulf, Black
Sea, Gulf of Mexico or Lake Superior? You`ve
got three seconds, go!
The Gulf of Mexico is the biggest option here
covering an area of around 600,000 square
miles. That`s your answer and that`s your
"Shoutout."
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: Part of that massive area of the Gulf
of Mexico is now a crime scene in a real life
mystery. Authorities in Louisiana, Alabama
and Mississippi are trying to find a killer
-- but not somebody who is targeting people:
Ed Lavandera tells us what animals have become
targets and what makes it so difficult to
investigate their murders.
(BEGIN VIDEOTAPE)
ED LAVANDERA, CNN CORRESPONDENT: To reach
the crime scenes, you need to catch a ride
and take a guide.
In this island that we see (inaudible), this
is Dear Island, where you found two of them?
DR. MOBY SOLANGI, INSTITUTE FOR MARINE MAMMAL
STUDIES: That`s correct.
LAVANDERA (voice over): A Harrison County
Mississippi sheriff`s chopper and Moby Solangi,
the lead biologist from the Institute for
Marine Mammal Studies. They took us to see
the sites where most of the murdered dolphins
have mysteriously emerged along the Mississippi
Gulf Coast.
(on camera): So, Moby, get us up to date how
many dolphins have turned up here so far?
SOLANGI: We`ve been dealing with about six
or seven. We know that these three or four
of them have been found dead with bullets.
LAVANDERA (voice over): Federal investigators
say they don`t know yet if the murders are
the work of one dolphin killer or all unrelated,
but even in the wild, it`s easy for a killer
to lure in dolphins.
Katherine Burton trains dolphins at the Institute
for Marine Mammal Studies.
KATHERINE BURTON, MAMMAL TRAINER: They are
very curious, and I think by getting fed ...
LAVANDERA (on camera): Even out in the wild.
BURTON: Yes. Out in the wild, they will get
fairly close.
LAVANDERA: So they can get themselves in the
bad situation just unsuspecting.
BURTON: Right. I think sometimes they get
close without realizing they are going to
be in any kind of danger.
LAVANDERA (voice over): That`s why it`s actually
illegal to feed dolphins in the wild.
(on camera): So, this is Sheep Island where
one of the dolphins was found?
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: Right.
LAVANDERA (voice over): Rusty Pittman is an
officer with Mississippi`s Department of Marine
Resources, one of the agencies patrolling
these waters.
(on camera): It seems so much more difficult
to investigate something like this. You know,
if you have a murder of humans, you have ...
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: Evidence .
LAVANDERA: You have evidence, there is a crime
scene.
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: Right.
There`s you go.
LAVANDERA: This crime scene is huge.
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: But like you said, you`ve
got so much area through here. This is totally
different than a crime scene involving humans.
LAVANDERA (voice over): This part of the Gulf
Coast is home to the largest population of
dolphins anywhere in the United States, as
many as 5,000. The race is on to catch a dolphin
killer before he strikes again.
Ed Lavandera, CNN, Gulfport, Mississippi.
(END VIDEOTAPE)
AZUZ: The season of giving is about more than
presents. From now through the holidays, people
are finding ways to volunteer, to give back,
to make a difference for others. If you are
doing this, we want to hear about it in an
I-report, you`ve got to give it in by December
14th. And if you are wondering how do I send
in an I-report, we are glad you asked.
CHRIS LETT, CNN RESEARCHER: So, you want to
be on CNN STUDENT NEWS? Me too. I`ll show
you how by submitting an I-report video. So
let`s see what assignments are up on our CNN
STUDENT NEWS I-report page. I- report.com/cnnstudentnews.
We are going to do an I-report on how to submit
an I-report. Let`s get a camera and start
rolling.
No, I know I need to keep this short. No more
than 30 seconds, and I can`t use any music.
If I do, they won`t be able to use my I-report.
So, just me and the camera.
Hi, I`m Chris. And this is an I-Report about
I-Reports.
OK, done shooting now, it`s back to the STUDENT
NEWS, I-Report page.
Upload my story, fill out all the information
and now I`m done. No way, I`m not.
They say I need to watch out for an email
after I submit this video.
Hey, here it is.
OK, a couple of things to fill out. If I weren`t
18, I`d need to have my parents to sign this.
But I`m over 18, so I can sign it myself.
Then send this back to the STUDENT NEWS team
and they`ll let me know when my I-Report is
going to be on the show.
AZUZ: And sometimes you might notice something`s
happening behind me in the newsroom here during
our show. This meteorologist doesn`t have
to worry about what`s behind him, he`s got
something happening below him -- check out
the bottom of his screen, it`s a cat walked
right though the live broadcast, and then
hung around for a while. What`s awesome is
that the reporter doesn`t even flinch. Thankfully,
the cat didn`t come near a microphone, because
you know how we TV folks can get -- we can
be just so catty.
That`s a tail for another day, so we hope
you enjoy the rest of yours. For CNN STUDENT
NEWS, I`m Carl Azuz.