season of giving, is we attended Loshmanor.
Loshmanor is a place for assisted living and
we sat with them and sang songs, and we also
ate with them.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
CARL AZUZ, CNN ANCHOR: Fridays are awesome.
A big thanks to Moko for that "I-Report",
we are going to have more season of giving
stories later on. I`m Carl Azuz, this is our
last show of 2012, it starts right now.
Today is December 21st. It is the first official
day of winter, but the weather was not looking
at the calendar, the season`s first blizzard
hit the Midwestern U.S. Early this week, it
was headed and expected to move into New England
today. Tens of thousands of people lost power.
This storm also made driving pretty dangerous,
as you might expect in some areas. Nearly
100 accidents were reported by late Wednesday
morning, including a 30-car pileup on one
Iowa highway. An officer said the snow is
blowing around so badly, the drivers could
only see about five feet in front of their
cars. Blizzard warnings were up yesterday
in Iowa, also in parts of Nebraska, Missouri,
Minnesota, Illinois and Wisconsin. Parts of
Wisconsin had already seen up to seven inches
of snow by yesterday morning. Predictions
said another foot could be on the way.
You`ve heard us talk a lot about the fiscal
cliff, it`s a serious of automatic government
spending cuts and tax increases that`s scheduled
to take place at the beginning of the year.
Now, President Obama and Congress can avoid
this cliff by coming up with a compromise,
a plan to lower the country`s debt. The president
and Republican leaders have both offered some
proposals on how to do this, but when we made
this show Thursday evening, there wasn`t a
deal. The members of the House and Senate
said they`d stay in Washington to keep working
on it, the deadline for a deal is January
First. So make sure to check out cnn.com over
the break for all the latest details.
Today`s "Shoutout" goes out to all the students
and teachers who watch our show around the
globe. In what city will you find the world`s
busiest airport? If you think you know it,
shout it out! Is it London, New York, Tokyo
or Atlanta? You`ve got three seconds, go.
More planes take off inland at Atlanta`s Hartsfield
Jackson Airport than any other airport in
the world. That`s your answer, and that`s
your "Shoutout."
Whether it was by plane, train, automobile
or ship, 2012 was a record breaking year for
travel. According to the UNTO, the United
Nations World Tourism Organization, more than
a billion people traveled outside their countries
this year.
Richard Quest breaks down the numbers on where
these travelers from, where they`re going
to, and why that matters.
(BEGIN VIDEOTAPE)
RICHARD QUEST, HOST, `QUEST MEANS BUSINES":
Where do they come and where do they go? First
of all, where do tourists come from? 53 percent
of international tourism, cross-border tourism
is 53 percent from Europe, 22 percent Asia
Pacific, 17 - well, you can see the numbers
yourself. And those numbers obviously a lot
of it is just literally crossing borders on
short visits. It could be on business, it
could be on vacations, it could be on government
affairs, and where they go?
So, again, most of it is Europe, a large part
of it is Asia Pacific, the Americas and the
Middle East. Obviously, Europe has a disproportionate
amount. It`s because the people are going
from one country to the next. The growing
area, of course, is Asia Pacific. Now, why
tourism matters? It`s really interesting.
Nine percent of global GDP is said to be from
tourism, look at the number of jobs, it says,
look at the amount of exports, six percent
of world trade, incidentally, this is all
from the UNWTO itself. This is why they believe
it matters.
(END VIDEOTAPE)
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: Another (ph) crowd has
gathered here.
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: We want to be freedom,
we want to be free people.
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: Jumper away.
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: Joseph Kony.
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: Joseph Kony.
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: Viral on social media
sites.
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: This is a very massive
play by Facebook.
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: The largest IPO in tech
history.
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: Jerry Sandusky is sentenced
to a minimum of 30 years in prison.
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: An iconic statue honoring
the late Penn State football coach Joe Paterno
is gone.
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: Flying squirrel.
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: Fierce five ...
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: Ryan Lochti (ph).
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: Live picture from Los
Angeles from Endeavour. The shuttle rolling
down the streets of L.A.
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: The despair in Syria
has gone on for 20 months.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: During the past 12 months, CNN STUDENT
NEWS has reported on stories from almost every
continent on the planet. We`ve gone to the
deepest depths of the ocean, we`ve looked
farther into space than ever before. We just
reviewed some of the stories you heard in
2012. Now, we are going to look back through
some of the images from stories we covered
this year.
(VIDEOTAPE)
AZUZ: Every Friday we come up with ten questions
to test your knowledge of some stories we
covered that week on our show. Today, we are
looking back a little farther than one week.
It`s our end of year news quiz, with questions
about events from all throughout 2012. Can
you score a perfect ten? One way to find out.
Check out the news quiz today at cnnstudentnews.com.
Before we dash away, dash away, dash away
all, we`ve been stocking up on your "I-Reports"
over the past few weeks. The first ones came
down the chimney in yesterday`s show. So next
to your wondering eye should appear a bundle
of the gifts you are giving to help others
this year.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
JASON BROOKS, STUDENT: I plan to celebrate
the season of giving by going around my neighborhood
helping those in need. This cause is important
to me because I think it`s a good idea to
give back to my community.
GIACHINO BARCELONA, STUDENT: I plan to celebrate
the season of giving by donating all the playable
toys and outgrown clothes. I`ll just make
sure that they are clean and in good condition.
I`ll feel kind (inaudible) because I just
gave Christmas to somebody.
REGINALD FREDERICK, STUDENT: I plan to celebrate
the season of giving by donating food to the
needy. This cause is important to me because
I feel we should help the people in need.
RICHARD HANSON, STUDENT: I plan to shovel
my neighbor`s driveway so they don`t have
to do it themselves.
TREVAN WILLIAMSON, STUDENT: I have been getting
an idea that (inaudible). I will be happy
because I did a good deed. Thank you. Happy
holidays.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: One gift we left out is a blog post
to cnnstudentnews.com. You can present what
you think is the best gift to give.
We tip our hat to all of you who sent in I-Reports
and blog posts this year. And while hat`s
about all the time we have to cap off 2012`s
last show, we will return on January 2nd after
a long winter`s nap.
I hope these puns haven`t left you in holi-daze.
We wish you a Merry Christmas. Happy holidays,
happy new year. All of us here at CNN STUDENT
NEWS hope your season is something special.