The whole River Cottage gang
Is gonna join the Food Tube family.
You're gonna have your own channel.
We are, if that's alright with you Jamie?!
Mate, this is brilliant. What's the first
dish gonna be, that's the question. Well I
wanna cook you a lovely sausage and prune casserole.
And I do love that little bit of sweetness
from the prunes, it goes brilliantly with
a spicy banger. One of those big winter
warmers. The kind of dish that gives you a
hug from the inside.
So I'm gonna start browning some of these
amazing sausages.
Lovely
This is where you wanna choose your biggest,
best seasoned butchers banger. You know the
one with loads of herbs and a little bit of
spice too. This is actually gonna be a long,
slow cook and all the sausagey flavours are
gonna mingle with all the other ingredients.
So I can see in the pan there you've got onions
sweetening up and getting gorgeous.
Yes silky, sweated onions for the start. Then
we're just building up the flavours. So Jamie
I'd love some celery and I'm gonna peel a
couple of carrots. Because this is pretty close
to being a one pot wonder, it's all gonna
end up in there.
What size do you want your celery?
Exactly that size.
Thank God for that.
Everything quite chunky because it's gonna
have a long time in the pot.
That can go in, yeah.
Back in the day, rather than big chunks of
sausage, it might be a couple of pig's trotters
going in.
Right.
You know, or a bit of Ox tail. Anything that
was to hand that was gonna add a little bit
of extra flavour and body to the rest of the
dish.
Look at that! You see that colour equals flavour.
There is now a flavour that did not exist
before. That's the caramelisation of the meat
and the surface of the sausage.
Tell them about the River Cottage channel.
I'm so lucky to be surrounded by people with
such passion. You know we've got Craig in
the garden growing fabulous veg. He's absolutely
bursting with fantastic tips. John our mushroom
man and Gill, my head chef has always got
some witty new dish up his sleeve.
Pam the Jam you know, I just want to capture
a bit more of what everybody is up to.
And get it on your channel?!
Exactly right.
And you guys watching now, throw in some comments
to Huw. Tell him what you want to see. From
growing to the pickling, smoking, all the
crafts around food. Him and his network, ask
him what you want!
So let's have a look in this pan. Basically
onions, celery, carrots. In go the bangers.
Beautiful.
And in goes everything else now. Some of these
lentils you can use brown ones but you want
a lentil with a skin on it. Not like the orange
ones that turn to mush. They're gonna hold
their shape. So I reckon about maybe a third
of a pack.
Ok so about what? 40g per person?
Something like that, yeah, yeah.
So, plenty of lentils in there and then the
stock.
So chicken stock but you can use a veg stock.
Because this is gonna serve how many people?
4?
You know, 4-6. But 4 will be very generously
fed here. We want just enough stock to almost
cover. We should definitely get a couple of
Bay Leaves in there and the prunes can go
in now. This is a lovely explosion of sweetness
and fruitiness dotted through the stew.
And by the time it's done, the prune will taste
of sausage, the sausage will taste of prune,
the vegetable flavours will be everywhere
and it'll be just absolutely packed with flavour.
Mmm gorgeous.
It's just coming up to a bubble which is the
moment you want to put it in the oven, 140°C
for an hour and a quarter.
Ok so I'll put that in the oven for you Hugh.
140°C for how long?
An hour and a quarter.
You can see how it's all reduced down into
this rich stew.
And the colour! It's just gone so dark and
wintery and beautiful.
Let's just put a little bit of spinach in
the pan because a splash of lightly cooked
greens just adds a bit of zing on the edge
of the plate.
Also, I've used that sausage pan
That'll pick up some of those lovely flavours
won't it.
I'm just gonna braise it. A little bit of
salt and nutmeg?
Yeah perfect. Always a good idea.
It's like the food that you dream of when
it's cold.
That spinach looks very nearly ready Jamie,
I'm gonna get a sausage out there.
Just look at that!
How about that?! I'm just gonna put one on
this plate, bit of carrot there, bit of prune,
lots of lovely lentils. Nice big spray of
spinach. It's really kind of rustic, peasant
food isn't it. It's the kind of thing that
the Italians wouldn't think twice about knocking
together but we've done it with lovely bangers,
carrots from the garden.
Go on, get stuck in!
Oh my goodness! Isn't it just melty.
The depth of flavour is phenomenal! You have
to try that recipe. It's so good! Proper comfort
food.
Hugh, thank you very much.
Great to be here.
The River Cottage channel is now part of the
Food Tube network so guys subscribe to Food
Tube, subscribe to the River Cottage channel.
It's gonna be amazing. At the end of the day,
it's about bringing together like minded people.
We're a family.
Absolutely.
And that's why I've cooked a big hearty family
dish.
Yes! Check that out!