Rolos. Now you might not have them in your
country, you might just call them caramel
cups but here's a really cool way to make
them from home. They taste amazing, it's a
great, fun activity for you to try out using
a shot glass. Good times!
They look amazing right and trust me they
taste amazing but this is also just a little
bit of a fun activity for you guys to try
out. I made a giant one of these over on the
channel before and you guys loved that and
have asked me to scale it down so by using
shot glasses we can do just that.
So if you wanna have a go at doing this, hit
pause on the video now. Write these ingredients/tools
down and this is how you do it.
First up, grab your saucepan with a little
bit of water in there and plonk a mixing bowl
on top. So we're gonna bring that water up
to a simmer and then plonk in our bits of
chocolate letting it melt together naturally.
Now while that chocolates melting I need to
stress to you the importance of lubrication
during this video. Please don't take that
the wrong way. I'm talking about your shot
glasses. You need to make sure you've got
a little bit of butter just worked around there
or some spray oil otherwise if you just pour
the melted chocolate in, once it's set you'll
find it really hard to get out so make sure
you're nice and lubricated.
With the chocolate fully melted pour it into
your shot glasses and then it's time to start
thinking about what sort of plug you're gonna
use which is gonna form your chocolate bucket.
Now in an ideal world, and when I tested this concept
the other day, the best thing to use is the
cork from like a wine bottle wrapped in
foil, again lubricated.
Now unfortunately I didn't have any of those
corks leftover from when I experimented because
my partner, Mrs Barry, chucked them all out
so I had to use party poppers, woo!
So yeah I ended up using party poppers which
I washed out fully, wrapped in foil and then
lubricated in my spray oil. Now ideally you
wanna use the corks, or depending on the size
of your shot glasses you want something that's
slightly less of that width so that when you
push it in its gonna go up the sides and form
a chocolate bucket around it.
Once that chocolate is setting in the fridge
grab another mixing bowl over simmering water
and plonk in your favourite toffees and a
little bit of cream, stirring it together
over that heat until it all combines to make
a lovely, gorgeous filling for our chocolate
bucket.
Hello! Hello, what are your favourite sweets?
Let my daddy know down below. Hello!
And once the chocolate has set you wanna carefully
remove whatever plug device you've used to
reveal your chocolate bucket. Now add your
filling in there that we've made. Make sure
it's cooled otherwise the chocolate bucket
will melt and just fill it just under the
brim of the bucket. So once the filling has
set, it's normally about half an hour in the
fridge just to get a little skim on the top,
melt up some more chocolate and pour it all
over that and that effectively creates the
base of our bucket.
So whack it in the fridge again for a good
hour to set it all together and then all you've
gotta do is un-tap it like a little sandcastle.
That oil in there will help it slide out and
you've made it. Good times.
I'm just gonna go like this. Oh my goodness.
Mmmm! I'm a little bit addicted, I've just
had two of them and they taste amazing! They're
like three of four times the size of the ones
you get in the stores, they taste just like
it, obviously you can pimp up the filling
as you like. If you do make them, do use the
cork method. They're a little bit easier and
a bit more give in there to get out. But if
you enjoy this video don't forget to give
it a thumbs up, share, subscribe to myself
- My Virgin Kitchen and the Food Tube channel
and of course check out the giant version
of this if you haven't seen it already. And
I'll see you next time.