TERI DIMARINO: The competition
can involve everything from
the sublime to the ridiculous.
And it's fun.
It is still a grooming
competition.
This is what people forget.
It's not just a dog-decorating
competition.
There are criteria based
on the coloring of
the dog, its grooming.
There's technical
aspects of it.
How is the scissoring,
the clipper work?
Is it clean?
Here there's no holds barred.
Everything is pretty much legal
with the designs, the
creativity, and our
presentations.
It's a package.
ADRIENNE POPE: Well first
of all, you walk out
with a dog like that.
When I go to a gas station
on the way here,
people bombard me.
I mean, they're just
like, oh my gosh!
Was he born like that?
I mean, I've gotten
so many questions.
KAT OBSON: My dog's name is
Koby, and he is a puppy.
And he is designed in a
Jurassic-Park theme.
And the poodles have such great
hair for it because it
just sticks straight out.
So it's really easy to sculpt.
And I enjoy it.
It's fun.
It's good time to spend
with your dog, good
time to spend bonding.
And he gets all this attention
after he's done.
TERI DIMARINO: OK.
Our winner of the Groom Expo
2011 People's Choice Award is
Jurassic Bark.
[APPLAUSE]
[MUSIC PLAYING]