[MUSIC -- "YOU ARE
SO BEAUTIFUL"]
FEMALE SPEAKER: Hi!
FEMALE SPEAKER: Are you OK?
FEMALE SPEAKER: Sorry
I'm a bit late.
I had to pick up the tan.
The tan injections.
I have run out of
tan injections.
INTERVIEWER: Where do
you get them from?
FEMALE SPEAKER: Someone
that sells steroids.
INTERVIEWER: Are you like a
celebrity in Liverpool, then?
FEMALE SPEAKER: No, I'm not
what you call a celebrity.
[INAUDIBLE]
I do little bits.
Is it up this way?
No.
I do little bits like
TV and modeling.
And got my own website
and things like that.
When anything tends to focus
around Liverpool, they always
get me involved.
Maybe because I represent
something
about Liverpool, probably.
INTERVIEWER: What do you think
you represent about Liverpool?
FEMALE SPEAKER: I'd like to
say it was vibrancy and
enthusiasm, et cetera.
But it's probably because they
think I'm quite vain, or
something like that.
They think Liverpool is quite
a vain city, don't they?
MALE SPEAKER: This is Face
Fashion, which is an event in
aid of Liverpool Unites.
We are the official charity
of Liverpool Echo.
We were formed in the wake of
the murder of Rhys Jones.
Rhys Jones was a local
schoolboy, who was 11 at the
time, and he was murdered.
He was caught up in the
crossfire of, basically,
gang-related shooting, where
there was a bullet intended
for one gang from the other.
And he got caught in crossfire
just walking home from
football practice.
INTERVIEWER: How much hairspray
does it normally
take to keep it--
FEMALE SPEAKER: A lot.
Yeah, she used a full bottle
on the photo shoot we
did the other day.
A full bottle like that.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Like that big.
FEMALE SPEAKER: It was even
bigger, wasn't it?
The Elnett one.
RICK VAUGHN: If you want to do
this differently, you tell me.
I'll go on stage and say,
good evening, everyone.
I'm Rick Vaughn from
Radio City.
Please welcome my host for
this half of the show.
And bring you on stage.
Is that all right?
AMANDA HARRINGTON: Yeah, yeah.
RICK VAUGHN: Amanda Harrington,
is that all right?
AMANDA HARRINGTON:
That's fine.
RICK VAUGHN: I'll explain
about the charity angle.
OK, and about exactly why we're
here, how much raffle
and all that sort of stuff, the
great entertainment we got
coming up, and all that.
And listen to how loud I am and
think, fuck, I've got to
be as loud as him.
FEMALE SPEAKER: No better
work than charity work.
The kicks you get off it, it's
just worth more than
anything, isn't it?
FEMALE SPEAKER: Sometimes it's
better to give than to
receive, isn't it?
INTERVIEWER: How do you
two know each other?
FEMALE SPEAKER: We're
actually family.
We're cousins.
FEMALE SPEAKER: I make the
clothes, and she models them.
INTERVIEWER: Have you
got a label name?
FEMALE SPEAKER: Dare to Bare.
INTERVIEWER: Dirty Bird?
FEMALE SPEAKER: No, Dare to
Bare, not Dirty Mare.
It's Dare to Bare for
all the dirty mares.
FEMALE SPEAKER: He said,
Dirty Bird, then.
FEMALE SPEAKER: It's kind
of a wenchy, barn
look going on today.
INTERVIEWER: What made
you decide to do a
wenchy, barn look?
FEMALE SPEAKER: It's just
how I was feeling.
The fact that you've gotta look
like you've been dragged
out of a barn.
INTERVIEWER: Why are Liverpool
women so glamorous?
FEMALE SPEAKER: Because
we have no qualms.
Up here it's any excuse to dress
up, even if it's just to
go into to town shopping.
You gotta wear your
heels to the Asda.
No qualms in going shopping
[INAUDIBLE].
FEMALE SPEAKER: Yeah, I go to
bed in my high heels, as well,
just in case.
INTERVIEWER: What do you think
could possibly happen?
FEMALE SPEAKER: Someone might
knock me up in the
middle of the night.
Gotta be ready.
You think I'm messing!
FEMALE SPEAKER: When we went
down to London a few weeks
ago, everyone had jeans on.
We had all over-the-top dresses
like my mum's clothes.
And we went in the
Mayfair bar, and
Vanessa Feltz walks in.
She was like, oh my god,
your dress is amazing.
And was like asking us.
Everyone was staring at us
when we were down there
because nobody wears
clothes like that.
FEMALE SPEAKER: I did
another shoot last
night for my calendar.
So that's nearly done.
I'm doing a calendar to raise
money for Help For Heroes.
You know, for the soldiers.
I went to an awards with my
boyfriend once in London.
And there was a group of young
lads sitting next to us.
And they were soldiers.
And some of them had no legs, no
arms, and stuff like that.
They were only about 18, 19.
I just thought it was
just dead sad.
And I just thought, what can
I do to help them and raise
money for them, or whatever.
And I just came up with this.
It's glamorous.
It's not like topless or
anything like that.
It's classy.
And it's based on weather
scenes, really.
It's all about nature
and stuff like that.
So it's different.
It's unique.
There's one where I'm holding
a big snake in the jungle.
And then there's another one
where I'm lying on loads of
ice and stuff like that.
Another one, I'm coming
out of a lily.
So it's all based on
nature, really.
RICK VAUGHN: I'll tell
you what, superb.
[INAUDIBLE], kid.
Absolutely superb.
Right, OK.
So listen, let's get some
more entertainment on.
Make some noise!
[MUSIC]
MALE SPEAKER: Had that
for 45 years.
That's been 45 years old.
All of them have been with
me for-- there's my
mum's wedding ring.
But I think that's why they
call it the Bling Bling
Building because something
to do with me
being the king of bling.
So we'll take you through.
And on a personal note, when
I was 15, I used to
love going in lifts.
You'd work the lift yourself.
FEMALE SPEAKER: What
did you do?
MALE SPEAKER: Well, you
have gates and you'd
pull the gates across.
And I was just fascinated
with these lifts.
And those were the days where,
you know, chauffeur driven
limousines.
You could not walk up Bold
Street a lady unless you had,
maybe, a crocodile handbag
and shoes.
It was very much like
Old Bond Street.
I mean, my parents would never
walk up Bold Street.
It was too posh.
If you went to a tea room, the
ladies would be in the
pinnies, and the hair,
and all silverware.
There was the Best Dressed Man
in Bold Street at the time,
and I think it went to a
hairdresser called Antoine.
And he came from Switzerland.
And he used to walk
up and down Bold
Street with a poodle.
Because I had a nightclub called
Hollywood in the '80s
and we had the riots then.
And they were coming
down from Toxteth.
And people were rioting
for different reasons.
All for people who didn't want
to work, and for people who
did work, we were
all penalized.
So we lost the shipping because
of the dockers strikes
all the time.
So once you lost the shipping,
that was really the heart of
our Liverpool docks, really.
And that was a bad time.
But the hairdressing industry
was very, very upmarket.
You know, to be a hairdresser
in those days was marvelous
because it took you five
years as an apprentice.
These days, it's cut and
blow drying, and
monkeys can do that.
I've got my own lift.
Come on downstairs.
Botox should only be either
administered by a qualified
cosmetic surgeon or a dentist.
It's like everything else
in Liverpool, you know?
The cowboys start to
get onto the--
everyone wants to cut
price each other.
I mean, I don't know so much
about cosmetic surgery.
Although, I've had a bit.
I had it done about
10 years ago.
And then I was in pantomime
with Julie Goodyear as the
emperor in Aladdin.
And I couldn't move my face.
So when you're trying to express
yourself, acting, I
was like that.
[INAUDIBLE]
Well, I couldn't stand that
either like that.
INTERVIEWER: Would you
ever consider it?
FEMALE SPEAKER: Oh, yeah,
MALE SPEAKER: Of course.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Yeah,
definitely.
I feel like I need it quite
soon, to be honest.
INTERVIEWER: How old
are you now then?
FEMALE SPEAKER: 25.
MALE SPEAKER: I do love
this lift, you know.
Are you coming in?
Feel it going up.
[INAUDIBLE]
[MUSIC]
FEMALE SPEAKER: A lot of girls
in Liverpool will get their
lips done for any occasion.
It's like buying a
new dress now.
There's a lot of competition
in Liverpool with Botox and
dermal fillers.
And the best is to
be reasonable.
And I am probably
the cheapest.
INTERVIEWER: How much?
FEMALE SPEAKER: A full lip would
be 120, and that's a
good price.
The Botox is it's actually
a botulism.
It's a poison that goes into
just the muscle, probably the
upper face, frown lines,
forehead, eyes.
And you inject the muscle, and
it just stops it working.
INTERVIEWER: Have you ever
had this done before?
FEMALE SPEAKER: Yeah, I've had
this done about three times.
INTERVIEWER: How was it?
FEMALE SPEAKER: Yeah,
I liked it.
FEMALE SPEAKER: You can only
put so much in, I think.
OK, I'll just do a little
on this side here.
INTERVIEWER: Where does
the hair come from?
FEMALE SPEAKER: Russia,
with love.
INTERVIEWER: Is it weird to
think you're walking around
with a Russian's hair in?
FEMALE SPEAKER: No.
It's weird to think there's a
Russian walking around bald.
FEMALE SPEAKER: We sell 100%
human hair, all different
qualities, lengths, colors.
And we sell curly hair,
straight hair,
relaxed Afro hair.
And we also do synthetic, human
hair wigs, lace front
wigs, ponytails, all accessories
and stuff to go
with the hair.
This is the most popular color
of blonde because it's
different shades.
And that's 100% human hair.
So it's fitted there.
So it gets sewn in.
FEMALE SPEAKER: I would like
to go to dark because I'm
loving Katie Price's dark
hair at the minute.
But every time--
I've been wearing a wig,
haven't I, for
the last few weeks.
FEMALE SPEAKER: She ordered a
brunette wig, the Joanna wig.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Coming to work
in the morning, popping a wig
on, trying to get used to it.
But when I went home,
my husband hated it.
Joanna was my favorite.
I was going for Joanna.
I wanted to be a racy redhead.
FEMALE SPEAKER: This is the
half head wig, which
is not a full wig.
So when you've got it on, it
goes like about there.
And you have all your own
hair over the top of it.
INTERVIEWER: Do you
think the beauty
industry is getting bigger?
FEMALE SPEAKER: Yeah,
a lot bigger.
Especially in Liverpool.
INTERVIEWER: What percentage
of girls, do you think, in
Liverpool have hair
extensions?
FEMALE SPEAKER: A
hell of a lot.
FEMALE SPEAKER: I'd
say about 70%.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Yeah.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Definitely.
I can't believe that we're in
a credit crunch and how many
young girls come in and think
nothing of spending 80 pounds
on their hair extensions.
They just come in, and they
say, you know what we want
because they get it every
six, eight weeks.
And they say, I'll have two
packets of that, and they hand
the money over.
INTERVIEWER: Do you go
to tanning salons?
FEMALE SPEAKER: After the big
scare with skin cancer and
stuff like that, I have been
sticking to false tan.
As you can tell.
FEMALE SPEAKER: I feel, like,
really a lot paler now, but I
think they're trying to promote
that aren't they?
FEMALE SPEAKER: And this has
been really popular.
Most celebrities use it.
This is the one that
I actually use.
It's voted Bazaar Best
of the Best 2009.
Orange knuckles and white
fingers today.
FEMALE SPEAKER: We have been
trying to scrub her all
morning to get it off.
FEMALE SPEAKER: We'll
be scrubbing
more before I go out.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Yeah
INTERVIEWER: Why do you
feel the need to be
tanned all the time?
FEMALE SPEAKER: Because
I felt dead pale
and sick this morning.
So when I've got it on, I feel
like I've just come back from
my holiday when I look
in the mirror.
FEMALE SPEAKER: When you've
got pale, fat
skin it looks horrible.
Tan, fat skin doesn't look as
bad, on your bum and stuff.
FEMALE SPEAKER: I started using
Melanotan about a year
ago because I was fed up
with getting spray
tans all the time.
Now, I've tried every
kind of a spray tan.
Like the one I'm using at the
moment, which is the Su-do Tan
or the California Tan, they're
about the best of a bad bunch,
where they don't really
start to come off.
But no spray tan lasts
a week for a start.
So nothing's ever permanent.
You can never get a tan that's
permanent or tan that's real.
Melanotan is like a natural
source of tanning by making
you produce something
in your body.
I still get top ups and get
spray tans, of I still put on
a bit of instant tan.
You know, when I go out?
But the only reason I use the
Melanotan is because it gives
you pigments in your skin.
It's like a top up for the
sunbeds, isn't it?
It's like using a sunbed
cream inside your skin.
INTERVIEWER: Does it
have any other
effects apart from tanning?
FEMALE SPEAKER: Does it have
any other effects?
It makes you feel sick.
Well, it makes you feel
nauseous, like a sort of
travel sick.
Whenever you start using them,
you always have your 10ml
before you go to bed.
Some people only start
off with 5ml.
If you have 10ml before you go
to bed, you sleep through most
of the sickness.
But to be perfectly honest with
you, when you start off
using them, they make you
feel sick all the time.
INTERVIEWER: Some people get
it off the internet.
Where do you get yours
from again?
FEMALE SPEAKER: I get
mine from a--
well, a person.
They don't sell them on show.
But if you know a person in a
gym, they'll probably sell
them if they sell steroids.
Just because it goes hand in
hand with injecting yourself
with steroids, sort of thing,
really, isn't it?
It's also not a narcotic, it's
like putting a drug in your
body but it's not for
social purposes.
[MUSIC]
ALEX LARGE: Hi my name is Alex
Large, and today we're here at
the Mr. Liverpool contest,
here at the Plaza Cinema.
Today we're hoping for a really
good day as a show for
bodybuilders.
INTERVIEWER: So how's it changed
then over the years
from when you used to do it?
ALEX LARGE: Pretty much
the same, actually.
There's no real difference,
except, really, the standards
become higher, obviously, with
enhanced performance products.
That has contributed to a
level of very, very high
standard physique.
INTERVIEWER: Are they
the polish that are
standing out there?
ALEX LARGE: No, I'm talking
about, obviously, you've got
growth hormone involved
and things like that.
Obviously, the media,
newspapers, and coverage is
against the bodybuilding sport
because obviously it involves
anabolic steroids.
That's the killing point.
All right, fella?
COLIN MATHIESON: OK, mate?
ALEX LARGE: This is Colin
Mathieson, the owner of the
Boulevard Gym.
COLIN MATHIESON: Pleased
to meet you.
ALEX LARGE: [INAUDIBLE]
all connected for many years,
and obviously, competed for
donkey's years.
And now all the lads
are following suit.
COLIN MATHIESON: See the thing
is, with bodybuilding, there's
no age limit.
People say certain sports and
you'll go, oh, I'm too old to
do that sport.
Now, you couldn't get, like, a
40-year old starting squash,
or something like that, but if
you're 40, or you're 50, or
even you're 60, to go into
bodybuilding, you're doing the
same movements with your muscle
as a young person.
But you're doing it
at your pace.
So there's no age limit to
weightlifting or bodybuilding.
You're not straining yourself
because you're not going to
excess weights.
INTERVIEWER: Do you mind me
asking how old you are?
ALEX LARGE: I've told
him my age.
COLIN MATHIESON: I'm 59.
The proof of the pudding
is in the eating.
FEMALE SPEAKER: You
all right, pet?
Are you outside?
OK.
Do you want to just nip
down with that?
It's for Ben.
Cheers, pet.
Thanks, darling.
Yes, Lynne's coming
down for you now.
Steroids are very addictive.
On the next day--
when you've been taking
steroids, however briefly,
even just after a couple
of days, three to
five days, I'd say--
the next day, when you wake up
and say, [INAUDIBLE], you
actually get to the point in
that day when you feel like,
oh, I need to take
my steroids.
You actually have the
feeling within you.
It's hard to explain, but
it's like your body's
anticipating the rush.
Then it's the aggressive,
because they're a big man,
don't mess with me.
As soon as they start working
out regularly, even if it's
just cardiovascular stuff like
regular cycling, anything,
that's fine.
But some don't do
anything at all.
And then it just goes to
flubber and the anger--
Hello?
That was my chap.
MALE SPEAKER: Steroids
are everywhere.
Police are using them.
Everybody's using them.
I'll tell you that, everybody.
INTERVIEWER: What's
the expression?
MALE SPEAKER: Sted head.
That's what they call them Sted
heads or juice heads.
INTERVIEWER: When did
you start getting
into the steroid scene?
MALE SPEAKER: I started
going to the gym
when I was about 15.
The people behind the counter
didn't really
realize my real age.
[INAUDIBLE]
I was a young kid
with potential.
When I first did
it, I injected.
It kinda hurt, do you
know what I mean?
Because it's a thick
liquid you're
putting into your veins.
It hurt quite a lot.
So when I had been injected,
I was just on edge.
Just a bit wary, [INAUDIBLE]
do you know what I mean?
I was just a bit scared
and wary, panicky.
After I had seen it
was all right.
You have six weeks off
and six weeks on.
After I had seen that it was
OK, I felt all right.
I started to feel
a [INAUDIBLE].
When I started to take them
at the age of 16, I
had bad anger problems.
I kicked off.
There's something called
roid rage.
Have you heard of it?
I was getting in trouble
with the police.
Violence, I was having
arguments.
I was having problems
with my girlfriend.
Sometimes I was feeling like
I was getting suffocated,
because my chest was up there.
Sometimes I couldn't breathe.
I felt like I was in a circus.
I would walk around
town [INAUDIBLE]
superstar, he's this,
he's that.
But what I didn't like about it,
in the end, when I started
to come off them is the simple
fact that you're
obviously on steroids.
You're not big because
you worked hard.
You're big because you worked
half as hard as you should
work, and you took stuff
to make you like that.
It's abnormal.
I felt like a freak show.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Well, it's the
whole thing, isn't it?
Scousers.
It's to become more than
what they are.
Guys are just really interested
in their vanity,
and the way they look,
and girls, of course.
That's where the aspect is
with the younger ones.
It's to get the women.
[MUSIC]
MATT FISHER: Hi, I'm
Matt Fisher.
I'm entering for
Mr. Liverpool.
It's like a beauty contest
for male and female.
You've got to show off your
personality, as well as what
you should basically
appeal to be.
Throughout the night we'll
be modelling beachwear.
It's beachwear that
we've chosen.
And then finally it'll
be the suits.
Over the past two weeks we've
been choreographing routines.
So it's kind of like dance
routines, press-ups.
INTERVIEWER: What
are you doing?
MATT FISHER: I do press-ups.
But there's one routine where
the lads have to do press-ups
and one has to jump
over the other.
I wish I could actually
eat at KFC.
I'm going to have a tan now,
a fake tan, a spray
tan, my fake bake.
FEMALE SPEAKER: This is
an inflatable machine.
So I'm going to blow it up, and
then he'll get inside, and
I'll start spraying you.
INTERVIEWER: Is that one
of your t-shirts?
MATT FISHER: Yeah, this
is one of my t-shirts.
It's a model image and I made
it into a chicken because I
think this leg looks like
a wing, for some reason.
So I made her into a chicken.
Basically, she's had an egg.
And the human fries the egg.
I know it's pretty insane, but
that's what fashion's about.
It's about making a statement.
Sizzle, sizzle.
Yeah, I've got my own website
at the moment,
www.matt-fisher.com.
But I've been building it up
over the past five months,
because as soon as I got here,
it was my dream to build up
something like that.
My confidence has grown
so much in these past
six months, as well.
INTERVIEWER: What other beauty
treatments do you have apart
from spray tan?
MATT FISHER: I don't really
have a lot of beauty
treatments.
I mean, I used to
have facials.
I used to have one where I had
to hold a metal stick, and
they sent electrical currents
on my face.
FEMALE SPEAKER: If you come
out on a Saturday night in
Liverpool, you'll see
everyone all tidied
up, hair done perfectly.
They've got all the
nice accessories.
They look amazing.
They all look like stars.
MATT FISHER: All sequins,
isn't it?
FEMALE SPEAKER: Yeah, they
get dresses made.
So you definitely want to
go with the dark tan?
MATT FISHER: [INAUDIBLE]
FEMALE SPEAKER: Pardon?
MATT FISHER: Aren't you
dark to start with?
[MUSIC]
MALE SPEAKER: Three, two, one.
Now, with your back straight.
Head up.
Awesome, good.
One.
Good technique.
Two, control on the way down.
Three.
Easy?
MATT FISHER: Yeah.
MALE SPEAKER: Go to the
next weight up.
MATT FISHER: Liverpool is
very well known for
the football teams.
And football lifestyles
are very glamorous.
And maybe the girls look up to
the glamour models that are
already out there, and say,
I want to be like that.
INTERVIEWER: There's a glamorous
model judging
tonight, isn't there?
MATT FISHER: Yeah, Amanda
Harrington.
INTERVIEWER: Do you know her?
MATT FISHER: Yeah.
INTERVIEWER: Could you
describe Amanda?
MATT FISHER: Amanda's
fantastic.
She's a really hard-working
girl.
She's very independent.
She's gorgeous.
She's got blonde hair,
big assets.
RICK VAUGHN: Bien.
Senor Rick Vaughn, Amanda
Harrington.
AMANDA HARRINGTON: Hello.
Nice to meet you.
MALE SPEAKER: Nice
to meet you.
JADE: Oh, wait for me!
Sorry.
JADE: I was thinking, in this
lift, long enough, you could
do full make-up, couldn't you?
Hi!
Are you OK?
Hi ya.
AMANDA HARRINGTON: Are you OK?
FEMALE SPEAKER: Yeah,
I'm fine, are you?
AMANDA HARRINGTON: I'll be with
you now, I've just got to
get these pictures taken.
I know, but my fringe
is on this side.
I need to be this side.
MALE SPEAKER: A headshot.
Who's the lady in the red
dress, by the way?
AMANDA HARRINGTON: My friend.
MALE SPEAKER: Is that
your friend?
Get her in the picture.
AMANDA HARRINGTON: Jade,
do you want to get a
picture with me?
MALE SPEAKER: Get
by the window.
Get by the window.
Because it'll look
really great.
RICK VAUGHN: You've actually met
a couple of girls who are
what I call grafters.
They're actually prepared to get
out there and not wait for
somebody to rock up with a
cheque book and say, go and
get what you want.
They'll fight for every
penny they earn.
It's the old saying, isn't it?
You judge a book by the cover.
A lot of people do that.
Especially, with the
WAG culture,
the Liverpool culture.
And I dare say, there are a lot
of girls out there that
would love to be hooked up
to a footballer or two.
Wouldn't we all for
a nice life.
However, when you actually
scratch the surface of some of
the girls and realize about
their insecurities, their
frailties, they're just
normal girls.
Amanda and Jade are
real good friends.
And everyone would think, well,
isn't there a bit of,
sort of, animosity in there over
who gets what gig or who
gets what magazine.
They're from a different
era, where--
I call them young kids.
They're not young kids because
I'd like to say we're all the
same age, 20 something--
where, for them, history,
possibly, isn't a big part of
their lives.
It's all about the future.
I think kids now would rather
know about how a Selfridges
were built, rather than
how a castle is built.
That's life.
Get with the program.
Let's move it on.
Once you scratch the surface,
and all the hype around the
girls, because they're
really popular and
for the right reasons.
They do lots of stuff for
charity, which nobody even
ever talks about because you
wouldn't associate the girls
with charity stuff.
And they'll probably
not even mention
it to you guys tonight.
They're not like, they're
just normal girls,
who, like us all--
it sounds a bit corny--
just want to be loved.
AMANDA HARRINGTON: To be honest,
I've been in a couple
relationships over the years.
When I've been single, I find
it hard to meet someone
because I don't get approached
a lot, at all, really, never.
I mean, I'm not a big head.
I wouldn't like to say it's
because of the way I look
because I'm not like that.
Well, maybe that's what it is.
Maybe they are a bit
intimidated, I don't know.
I wouldn't like to say, but
that's what my friends has
said because sometimes I've
been single for ages.
And I've thought, why is that?
But obviously, maybe
it is intimidation.
I'm not sure.
My mum brought me up on my own
and didn't really have my dad
around much.
So I think that's what made me
more determined in what I do.
This is my mum.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Always
looked after herself.
Always wanted the best
of everything.
INTERVIEWER: Did she
get that from you?
AMANDA HARRINGTON: No, to
be honest, my mum's
twin sister it is.
Yeah, my twin sister.
My mum's twin is more like me.
My mum is not really
that fussed on.
You like nice clothes and stuff,
but she's not obsessed
with shopping or whatever.
Where, my mum's twin is.
I think I'm more like my mum's
twin than I am my mum.
FEMALE SPEAKER: I think some
of them should cool down a
little bit with the make-up
because most of them are
natural beauties, anyway,
aren't they?
They really are.
But I don't think she
needs all that.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Well, what's
the point of having a
personality if you
look terrible?
The whole world is based
on appearances, first
impressions.
That's not the be all and
end all of everything,
don't get me wrong.
But it's first impressions that
people have got of people
that matter.
I don't expect all of them
people to like the way I look.
But I just don't want to
look the same as them.
I look after my appearance in
my own way, not in the way
that they look after theirs.
This is Mark Hart.
He's a junior competitor, one
of our lads from the gym.
He's here today to compete.
Obviously, he'll have tan on.
MARK HART: I'll have
tan on, yeah.
INTERVIEWER: What sort of
tan will you put on?
MARK HART: Dream Tan.
We used the Dream Tan.
Last time we used Pro Tan.
INTERVIEWER: And explain
what that is.
MARK HART: Dream Tan is like
dead thick color, so when you
put it on it will be
like straight on.
Not like you've got to develop
the other tan that you've got
to put on coats and coats.
MALE SPEAKER: It reminds me
of the Fantastic Four or
something like that.
COLIN MATHIESON: Well,
I've never tried it
with a roller before.
Normally, we just put it on you
with a sponge, put on with
your fingers.
Or you could just dab it on,
just rub it in with the hands.
So I was just trying with the
sponge just to see what the
difference was like.
MALE SPEAKER: Just slap
it on like mud.
It's a bit thin, that.
COLIN MATHIESON: A friend of
mine had suggested did
I want to try it.
I had tried jiu-jitsu,
I'd tried karate.
And bodybuilding I
just got to like.
You don't do it for females.
A lot of females
don't like it.
You'll notice it will
be more like a lad
would notice your physique.
Everyone was saying to me last
night, oh, where have you
been, where have
you been, where
have you been on holiday?
I went, no, I haven't.
It gives you more confidence.
It does give you more
confidence.
And for people who are suffering
a lack of confidence
it would be a good thing.
This comes off on
your clothes.
I comes off in your bed.
When you get the tan you
sleep on old sheets.
You wear tracksuits in bed.
It's uncomfortable.
It's sticky.
It's tacky.
But it looks nice.
If was girls who always used the
sunbed shops and all that.
But now there's a lot of lads
who use sunbed shops.
I know it's not a healthy thing
and it's not a good
thing for underage or--
I can understand them putting an
age limit on using sunbeds
and sun showers.
But for other people, it's
a business, isn't it?
You can get injections.
Melanotan is what it is.
But there's reports on that.
I've got reports in the
gym on the wall.
I had a newspaper cutting saying
it's a link to cancer.
Now, whether it is a link
to cancer, I don't know.
It's supposed to help your
sexual life, as well,
apparently.
Nearly lost my finger then.
MALE SPEAKER: Liverpool has, I
have to say, and I've heard a
lot people say this, probably
the best looking girls in the
country, or not far off.
If you travel around the
country, and I travel around
the country quite a lot,
Liverpool does have some of
the best looking
girls, I think.
And they always make an effort
when they go out, probably a
lot more than other places.
It's very fashion conscious.
And so I think that
is probably one
major, major thing.
INTERVIEWER: How many
floors up is it?
JADE: Four.
Three.
Well, we're on one
so we're going to
four, so is that three?
Four.
MALE SPEAKER: They're
not celebrities.
Nobody knows them.
JADE: This is Palm Sugar.
It's the new It place
to be in Liverpool.
We just think to do the most
amazing cocktails.
They do gorgeous shots.
And I just think it's just a
fantastic place for everyone
to meet up on a night out.
MALE SPEAKER: It's very nice.
MALE SPEAKER: If you call me
on a Friday or a Saturday
night, any weekend, really,
we tend to have--
everyone looks like Jade,
well, tries to
look as good as Jade.
Certainly, Liverpool
women take pride--
JADE: How to make the
best of themselves.
MALE SPEAKER: --looking
after themselves.
It's like almost a competition,
isn't it?
Have you actually danced
on the bar yet?
JADE: No, I've had my
photo taken on there
though, didn't I?
MALE SPEAKER: In the center.
Very opulent, luxurious, very
Liverpool, lots of Swarovski
everywhere you look, three and a
half million pounds worth in
the whole place.
JADE: I just think the lights
look absolutely
amazing, don't they?
MALE SPEAKER: You've got
actually crystals on your
business cards?
JADE: No, my photograph in here
is on my business cards.
And everyone says to me every
time I that I get them out, oh
my god, how amazing
are those lights.
MALE SPEAKER: Very sparkly,
very Liverpool.
This is a traditional
gong from Thailand.
It was meal time for monks,
actually it could be heard
from miles away.
JADE: Like that?
MALE SPEAKER: This is where most
of our celebrities come,
isn't it Jade?
JADE: Yes, it is.
MALE SPEAKER: All the
footballers, the WAGS.
This is definitely your
high-end Gucci.
And downstairs is
more Topshop.
I don't think anybody
in Liverpool
takes themselves seriously.
We're all comedians,
aren't we?
I think we're all a bit real.
I think we know where we're
from and what we do.
And I suppose I'm speaking for
you here, on your behalf, you
make a lot of effort, in terms
of your appearance, and spend
an awful lot of money
on your appearance.
But you don't take
yourself serious.
You're still a real,
down-to-earth girl.
JADE: Oh god, yeah.
MALE SPEAKER: And through here
is the most popular for the
curry and chips.
This is typical of Liverpool.
This is where all the gossip--
this is where you find
out everything.
Anything you want to share with
us that's happened here?
Any gossip?
The inspiration behind this
was all Romeo and Juliet.
Obviously, where the two first
met, and it was romance.
Obviously, the Liverpool spin
on that, with the characters
and the humor would be, they
first met in the toilet.
Wasn't that loud, was it?
You know, I was born and
bred in Liverpool.
And the I went to the
States to live.
And came back, and it was
completely different.
Because when I left, it was like
shell suits, curly hair
and moustaches.
And then came back to a
little bit of style.
And I just think it's
just evolved.
I think in ten years' time,
we'll give anywhere a run for
their money.
AMANDA MOSS: The Philly
cheesesteak
sandwich looks nice.
But then I've seen half
roast chicken.
Steak.
JADE: A Reform burger.
AMANDA MOSS: Chocolate fudge
cake, followed by steak.
Chicken liver pate followed
by steak.
Oh, the burger sounds--
Burger.
MALE SPEAKER: Are you
ready to order?
AMANDA MOSS: I was going to
have a the char-grilled
asparagus and then steak.
It's got to be cooked and juicy,
but cooked all the
through to the middle,
but not rubbery.
I don't want to see blood.
I might have to send it
back if it's blood.
JADE: Can I have the duck spring
rolls please, and the
duck breast.
AMANDA MOSS: That's it.
One more drink, and then
I'm on Diet Cokes
for a couple of hours.
I'm Amanda Moss, editor of
Lifestyle Monthly magazine,
which is the biggest lifestyle
magazine for Liverpool, the
Wirral, and Southport.
Jade approached me and said,
why don't I do a fashion
column for you.
We've got loads of events
planned now.
And we're gonna just work
together loads, aren't we?
I'm having a cocktail party at
my house just for select VIPs.
We're doing champagne, cupcakes,
and jewelry.
This is where I sit when the
kids are asleep and listen to
them all synchronized snoring.
This is my little
chill out zone.
Lost my drink.
Don't know where my
drink's gone.
Well, that's Saxon's room.
Saxon and Honey tend
to sleep together.
Well, Floyd and Albany--
although Albany's with me.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Albany's
the baby?
AMANDA MOSS: No, Darling's
the baby.
Saxon!
Keep the noise down!
Why should London
be the capital
of couture and fashion?
Liverpool has got
everything here.
You get to meet lots of people
and go to glamorous parties
like this one.
Will you go downstairs
and be quiet!
I mean I'm not even from
Liverpool, and yet I've
established myself as Amanda
Moss, editor of Lifestyle
Monthly magazine.
I walk into town and
everybody knows me.
We've got more fans on Facebook
than anyone else.
INTERVIEWER: How many
have you got?
AMANDA MOSS: 1,400.
I just want everybody to just
know Lifestyle Monthly is just
the best thing since sliced
bread, really.
[MUSIC]
FEMALE SPEAKER: Liverpool
fashion, it's big hair, curls,
jewels and glitter and massive
heels, massive platforms.
I was gonna say, if you're not
in heels in Liverpool, see ya!
FEMALE SPEAKER: Little
heels, you're getting
chucked in the gutter.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Little heels
and you're out of here.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Kitten heels
make me want to kill myself a
little bit.
FEMALE SPEAKER: The whole money
that we earn from our
shitty jobs, we're going to
have amazing outfits for.
It's a babe.
It's a sexy little babe.
We love it so bad it hurts.
Liverpool is a babe.
[MUSIC]
SERENA STREGAPEDE: This is
my dress for tomorrow.
A guy called Ronnie made this.
I've had him up the
wall with it.
But it looks better
on, anyway.
It's just a nice, long fitted
dress, fishtail, as well.
Well, we have to do
a swimwear one.
And then after that, we do
the evening wear one.
These are one pair of shoes
I'm going to be wearing.
Nice, aren't they?
And we've got our pink
stools, as well.
And there's Tony when he boxed
some Russian or something.
And that's just some of
his belts, as well.
We're just waiting to get them
framed and all that and then
put up on the wall.
INTERVIEWER: How'd
you two meet?
SERENA STREGAPEDE:
In our shop.
In my work.
INTERVIEWER: What
work is that?
SERENA STREGAPEDE:
I do beauty.
INTERVIEWER: You've got
your own beauty place?
SERENA STREGAPEDE: I do beauty
and that as well.
INTERVIEWER: Do you go in there
for beauty treatments?
TONY: For some reason, I grow
more hair on my back and my
chest than I do on my head.
She gets me in there, and says,
it'll be all right, it
doesn't hurt.
So one step, bang!
Never again.
I'd rather go home and
just shave it off.
INTERVIEWER: Was it love
at first sight?
SERENA STREGAPEDE:
Yeah, definitely.
Definitely, wasn't it?
TONY: Yeah, she's lucky
to have me.
INTERVIEWER: What do you think
the outcome of the
competition's going to be?
SERENA STREGAPEDE: Well,
I'd like to win.
INTERVIEWER: Are you
hopeful or what?
SERENA STREGAPEDE: Yeah, very.
I'm positive.
I'm so positive.
INTERVIEWER: Do you know
any of the judges?
SERENA STREGAPEDE: No.
INTERVIEWER: This guy we were
with knew three judges.
SERENA STREGAPEDE: Well, Tony
boxed one of the judges, but I
don't really know him.
Because Liverpool is such a
glamorous city, everyone wants
a beauty therapist.
INTERVIEWER: Cause
some fellows get
spray tans, don't they?
SERENA STREGAPEDE: Yeah,
they do, yeah.
TONY: I know some fighters, like
Dave Coldwell, who waxes
his eyebrows.
And he's taken a little bit of a
pasting off me, from time to
time with getting them done.
It's good that he wants to look
after himself, but come
on, you don't need to
wax your eyebrows.
SERENA STREGAPEDE: Well, Tony,
a few years ago came into my
shop to see me.
And we were bored because
it was a quiet day.
So I said to him, oh what
can I do, I want to do
something, I'm bored.
Pierce my ear then.
I went, all right, then.
And I pierced his ear and he was
walking around with this
diamond earring in.
TONY: It seemed good
at the time.
SERENA STREGAPEDE: Liverpool
lads aren't
like that, are they.
I know in London and places
like that they do, but in
Liverpool lads don't
really do that.
INTERVIEWER: One thing the lads
do in the city, there's
quite a bit of steroids
going on, isn't there?
TONY: You know, if you stood
around, if you go anywhere,
you see juice heads
everywhere.
INTERVIEWER: Is that
big in Liverpool?
TONY: Certain people, doormen,
mainly doormen
do stuff like that.
I don't know.
Each to their own.
I'm not going to sit here
and say, don't do it.
If they want to do it, it's a
free world and they can do
what they want.
FEMALE SPEAKER: I think what
Marcel's achieved in the last
year is amazing because
he's natural now.
But I just know that
by the time he's--
I think up until 21, he'll train
and achieve the best he
possibly can.
But once he gets to 21, I know
because then he'll be in the
Mister classes.
And I know what it entails.
INTERVIEWER: What's that?
FEMALE SPEAKER: The Misters,
it's like up until 21 you're
like a junior.
But then, when you get past
21, you have to go in the
Misters, which is kind of like
the big men, if you like.
And to get like that, I know
he's never going to --
he won't stay natural because he
can't, because it'd just be
a waste of time.
It's an awkward subject because
they have natural
organizations, right, where
people just go and compete and
they are natural.
Everybody knows that with
bodybuilding, most of them
aren't natural.
But the thing is, they're
not drug tested.
It's kind of, like,
acceptable, if
you know what I mean.
INTERVIEWER: Why should
it be unacceptable?
FEMALE SPEAKER: Why
should it be?
INTERVIEWER: Yeah.
People talk about it like
it's a bad thing, but
why is it a bad thing?
FEMALE SPEAKER: The thing is,
within the sport, everybody
knows who is and who isn't.
In the organizations that I know
they do drug test them.
You only have to look at a
certain physique and I can
tell which is natural
and which isn't.
And so can everybody
else who's into it.
Do you know what I mean?
INTERVIEWER: It's better
to be natural, right?
FEMALE SPEAKER: The thing
is, right, it
depends what you want.
If you want to look
freaky, you're
never going to be natural.
INTERVIEWER: Why do you think
people want to look freaky?
FEMALE SPEAKER: Because it's
like the biggest and
the best, isn't it?
What with the best condition,
the best everything.
Anouska?
ANOUSKA: Yeah?
FEMALE SPEAKER: Come
here please.
ANOUSKA: No.
FEMALE SPEAKER: OK, it
doesn't matter then,
I'll close the door.
INTERVIEWER: Is she shy?
FEMALE SPEAKER: Not
at all, no.
Show them your six pack then.
INTERVIEWER: How does
that happen?
FEMALE SPEAKER: She's
just a genetically
muscular, aren't you?
But she was training
28 hours a week.
Fridays, she used to do
one to eight, all day
Saturday and then--
INTERVIEWER: One to eight?
FEMALE SPEAKER: Yeah,
training.
INTERVIEWER: As in eight
hours a day?
FEMALE SPEAKER: Seven
hours, yeah.
INTERVIEWER: Well, what do you
do for seven hours a day?
FEMALE SPEAKER: What do you
INTERVIEWER: Training?
ANOUSKA: Yeah.
FEMALE SPEAKER: What
did you do?
ANOUSKA: Conditioning.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Body
conditioning, the actual
moves, just practising
the same old routines
and things like that.
She couldn't, like, go and see
her friends after school.
She couldn't do sleepovers,
anything like that.
So now, she's still doing her
gymnastics, but she only does
six hours a week.
INTERVIEWER: It's a big thing
in Liverpool, isn't it?
FEMALE SPEAKER: Yeah,
it is, actually.
INTERVIEWER: Why is that?
MARCEL: It's a lot
bigger lately.
A lot of people want to get into
shape because they feel
like they need to keep up.
There's a lot more people seem
to be doing it now than say,
five years ago.
MALE ANNOUNCER: Right, that
completes the under 18s.
Closing round, and we'll
be moving on to
the under 21s shortly.
MALE SPEAKER: If you can psyche
your opponents out,
well, even better.
They might pose a little
bit worse than you.
You show off a bit more than
them and well, you've won it,
haven't you?
MALE SPEAKER: If the small
person looks small behind the
bigger person, let the small
person fight his way through
just to try and make them look
small again, make the big
opponent small.
MALE SPEAKER: If you're going
on that stage, you're going
out to win.
You can say you're not.
You can say whatever, but
you going out to win.
MALE SPEAKER: Yeah, just don't
put your head down.
And whatever mistakes that
you pull you can work
hard on in the gym.
I mean, whatever things that
you lack on, go back to the
gym and try and build
up on those things.
And then come back and try and
beat that better opponent.
MALE SPEAKER: Yeah, that's
what's he's done.
Well, tried to do, anyway.
Beat him last time.
Going to beat him again today.
Friendly competition,
that's all.
MALE SPEAKER: Yeah, see
what the judges say.
Just see what happens.
I don't know.
It could happen, I don't know.
See how they feel.
He can try and put me off,
but it's not happening.
MALE SPEAKER: Every
bodybuilder's watched it a
million times.
MALE SPEAKER: Jay Cutler's
my idol.
Arnie boomed off bodybuilding,
full stop.
INTERVIEWER: What's your
favorite Arnie film?
MALE SPEAKER: I was watching
Predator last night, actually,
to psyche myself up.
Because they say it's war.
That's what it's like.
MALE SPEAKER: We watched a bit
of Pumping Iron just because I
brought it down.
And then we thought, oh, we'll
watch this, just get a bit,
like, in the moment.
INTERVIEWER: Did you ever
watch Kindergarten Cop?
MALE SPEAKER: Yeah, I've
watched all his films a
million times.
Because from a young age, that's
the physique that I've
found he's brought,
for men, to have.
Do you know what I mean?
[MUSIC]
INTERVIEWER: Did you win?
MALE SPEAKER: Twice.
Both of them.
MALE SPEAKER: Do you know
what I mean, fair
enough, he won, he won.
MALE SPEAKER: More
competitive, do
you know what I mean?
It's what we do it for.
MALE SPEAKER: Give me a year.
We'll probably look up to them
as a bit of an idol.
We look up going, yeah,
we could end up
building up to that.
Fair enough, we're only young
and still growing.
Work the crowd, that's
what it's all
about, working the crowd.
[INAUDIBLE]
MALE SPEAKER: It's very
difficult to assess how
widespread Melanotan is.
It's legal to buy
and to possess.
Or rather, it's not illegal
to do that.
But it's technically
illegal to sell it.
The kits that were provided over
the internet tended to
have only a couple of syringes
in them, which isn't enough,
even remotely enough, for
a course of injections.
You know, we're hearing of
completely unusual groups of
people going into needle
exchanges.
So they weren't bodybuilders
or steroid users.
They weren't heroin
or opiate users.
They were working mums going
in with their daughters and
things like this.
It stimulates the receptors
in the skin to
produce the skin pigment.
One form of it, supposedly,
gives you a libido boost
within a very short
space of time.
We've had reports of
people's genitals
supposedly turning purple.
How do you tell them it's a
bad idea when, from their
point of view, at least, what
they're doing is taking
something which is going
to make them look
better and feel horny?
FEMALE SPEAKER: I hate it when
there's a bubble in it.
You see, you can't administer
it with a bubble in it.
That can kill you.
So what you do is you rub
the area where you're
going to put it.
And then you grab the bit
of skin like that, and
then and that's it.
You can feel it going
in your system.
To be perfectly honest with you,
I feel a bit sick off the
5ml I had before.
Bloody hell, that really
hurt, that one.
A girl has put it into
her stomach before
now and nearly died.
She's got the needle, and
she's gone that way, and
nearly died.
INTERVIEWER: Because
she injected
right into the stomach?
FEMALE SPEAKER: Yeah, you're
not meant to do that.
I mean, I don't really think
people should be administering
needles that aren't
nurses, anyway, to
be perfectly honest.
The most ones who say, it's
not meant to be about
appearance and all that are the
ones that are bitter and
resentful inside.
And they're usually
the ones that
are jealous and resentful.
And that is ugly.
That's an ugly character.
So therefore, not only are they
not nice on the outside,
but they're not nice
on the inside.
And not being nice on the inside
is a lot more tragic
than them not being nice
on the outside.
INTERVIEWER: When did
you get that done?
FEMALE SPEAKER: About five,
six years ago now, when
Liverpool won their fifth
Champion's League.
Regret it a little bit now I'm
older because think it's a bit
chavvy on a girl now.
INTERVIEWER: Have you been in
this competition before?
FEMALE SPEAKER: I haven't, no.
This is my first year.
So I'm a bit nervous.
INTERVIEWER: What time did you
start getting ready today?
FEMALE SPEAKER: I went to my
brother's girlfriend's, and
she started doing my hair and
my eyelashes and all that
about a quarter to nine this
morning when it all started.
I was in the Asda at half eight
picking my last little
bits of lacquer and everything
like that up.
I've just drove here today
in my rollers.
I had to keep on saying to the
girls, every time I was
getting out of the car
and in the car, I
kept on whacking them.
So they're all falling
out now.
Kept on forgetting to duck
my head when I was
getting out of the car.
Pain's beauty.
You've got to do it.
You've got to be humiliated.
[INAUDIBLE]
how many times you get people
laughing at you when you run
in the shop with them on .
Like I say, if you want to look
good then you've got to
do this stuff.
It's the only way your hair's
gonna stay big, really.
FEMALE SPEAKER: I said their
answers all seemed a little
regurgitated.
No, they do though,
don't they?
Because they say, why do
you want to be a model?
Oh, I really want to
help the world.
I want to help people.
No, you don't.
You just got that off fucking
a magazine or telly.
You have all the girls
waiting in here.
And then, one at a time, they're
going to walk through
and stand in front of
the judges here.
And the judges are going to be
seated on this table with all
their, like, scoring boards
and everything.
And they're going to get asked
three questions that they've
pre-prepared.
And then they're going
to walk out.
And the good judges are gonna
slag them off and write down
their marks.
Miss Photogenic, Miss Beautiful
Body, Miss Beautiful
Hair, Miss Lovely
Legs, Miss Sexy
Eyes, that one's hilarious.
And then you've got the third
runner up, second runner up
and first place.
The boys are Mr. Body Fit,
Mr. Stylish Hair, and Mr.
Photogenic and then obviously,
Third, Second, First, as well.
MALE ANNOUNCER: What would
you do if you won
Mr. Liverpool 2010?
MALE SPEAKER: Party!
MALE ANNOUNCER: Party!
Who would party with
him afterwards?
[MUSIC -- "YOU ARE
SO BEAUTIFUL"]
FEMALE ANNOUNCER: Please, make
some noise for all of our
contestants.
MALE ANNOUNCER: We're gonna
crown Mr. Liverpool 2010.
FEMALE ANNOUNCER: It's
Christian Williams!
MALE ANNOUNCER: Christian
Williams, congratulations.
Here's your Mr. Liverpool!
Give a special thanks
to the judges.
[MUSIC -- "YOU ARE
SO BEAUTIFUL"]
FEMALE ANNOUNCER:
Second place.
MALE ANNOUNCER: Runner-up
in Miss Liverpool 2010.
FEMALE ANNOUNCER: It's Serena,
Serena Stregapede!
[MUSIC -- "YOU ARE
SO BEAUTIFUL"]
SERENA STREGAPEDE: Absolutely
over the moon.
I feel like I've won because
of the way I was
and the way I felt.
I can't believe that I did come
second because my nerves
were just shot, for
some reason.
But I'm absolutely buzzing
that I've come second.
I'm gonna go and get
bladdered now.
[MUSIC -- "YOU ARE
SO BEAUTIFUL"]
MALE SPEAKER: And I think vanity
is the greatest thing
in the world.
Always have done.
And people are vain about most
things, even if they're not
vain about themselves.
You have a moral obligation
to look smart.
I took four youngsters to
the Dorchester Hotel.
It was a hairdressing
function, right?
So when I get to the top of
the stairs, watch all the
television cameras and all the
photographers come over to me.
I go to the top of the stairs
and sure enough, saw all the
lights running over to me.
And they were taking
photographs.
And I said to the youngsters,
now, tell me
why they came over.
Was it me?
Or was it the pink suit?