CHRIS ENGELSMAN: There's the
cover of Issue Number One with
Damian on there.
Kind of funny.
Hardboots, stretch OP.
A lot of people probably didn't
realize that they did
all kinds of relief cuts in
their boots and different
things like that so they could
tweak in them and do some
insane stalefishes, and
tailfishes and cross-rockets
and Lien Draculas, you know.
Tricks du jour back
in the day.
TODD RICHARDS: Damian was a
skater too, and obviously he
had the whole correctional boot
thing going, like weird
correctional shoes.
Damian's hardboot thing.
And he was one of four dudes
that wore hardboots and that,
he claimed it so hard.
But he was just like--
Damien was bananas.
DAMIAN SANDERS: Nobody rode
hardboots but our little crew,
and I really don't
even know why.
I just started riding hardboots
and they felt right,
but it really made me a
more powerful rider.
Like I could really stomp things
way more than I could--
because I went back and forth.
Everybody was trying to give
me the right softboots,
thinking I might be a better
snowboarder, and it just
wasn't the case.
I'd get back in my hardboots and
I felt like I could ride
anything and fly off jumps,
twice as big as I could go
with softboots.
When I had softboots on, the
board felt like a toy.
When I had hardboots on,
it felt like a machine.
Like it was connected to me.
When I leaned over, the board
was instantly on an edge, and
I could rest on my boots
to do half the work.
So I could really get
a good power going.
But no one ever caught
onto that.
Koflach was the only company
making the snowboard boots.
It was just Tom, Jim, myself,
Bonnie and Dana, I think, that
were riding hardboots back then,
and everybody else was
on softboots.
The entire industry.
But I'm glad I did.
I mean, they were kind of
goofy-looking, but I could get
so much air on those things.
I loved them.
JERRY DUGAN: He wore
hardboots.
I mean, that was his thing.
He was a hardboot guy.
Him and Dana were
hardboot guys.
But he could tweak his board
and tweak his body in ways
that no one in hardboots has
ever been able to do.
They were behind the whole
hardboot revolution.
Yeah, hardboots, it's the way.
Look, we can tweak everything.
That eventually caught up with
them and didn't work out so
well as things got
a little more
technical and more finessed.
But back in the days of just
big, macho grassers, and
frontsides and stalefish, melon,
backflip, whatever, it
was all pretty OK.
DAMIAN SANDERS: I think if
everybody would've followed
suit with us, snowboarding
would've--
it's hard to tell.
I mean, with these guys that are
ripping freestyle riders,
they might want that
flexibility, but I had my
boots so cut up in
different angles.
I knew exactly what I
needed to cut out
to do certain tricks.
And so I would chop out the
whole inside of the boot so I
could lean away and do Japan
Airs and Crooked Cops and all
those things and--
I mean, I had them cut up
so much they almost were
softboots, but there's just
nothing like that feeling of
the toe and edge response
that you had.
It was insane.
As soon as you thought it,
the board was doing it.
It was amazing.
And in my softboots,
I feel like I'm all
wishy-washy, swimming.
And I've gotten them clamped
down pretty damn tight, and
they're still just not
quite a hardboot.
JEREMY JONES: The thing we got
from Damien was balls and
backflips, pretty much.
The dude would just charge
everything and we always
tripped out that he could
do it on hardboots.
That was a big thing for us.
It was always kind
of mind-blowing.
How does he do that?
Because he would tweak so hard
in hardboots and we never got
in, so there was always the
Damian tweaks and it was
always in our things
we talked about.
It was, like, dude, you tweaked
that like Damien!
So it was speed, and it was size
of airs, and it was the
balls he had to do the
things he was doing.
MIKE McENTIRE: You can never
front on Damian.
There's no way anyone can
ever front on that guy.
He was the original rock star.
He was the guy, dude.
There's no one like that.
And like his lifestyle
and his whole scene.
He had everything
to back it up.
He had this Penthouse
Pet for a wife.
I don't care if he wore neon
green and orange or whatever
his thing was at
the beginning.
What he was doing was
extraordinary.
He was totally way
beyond anyone.
DAMIAN SANDERS: I was a
snowboarder when I was with
Brandy, but I was 19,
20 years old.
And I met her at a nightclub
down here, and we started
going out and the rest is
history, but that lasted for
about five years.
That was a good time.
It was perfect for my snowboard
career, because she
was a superstar, and I was a
superstar in snowboarding, so
it put us together and
it was kind of cool.
JERRY DUGAN: Damien was married
to Brandy for years
and Brandy was a--
she was Penthouse Pet of the
Year, and she for sure got way
more press than we got.
She was way more attractive and
was in bigger magazines
than any of us had been
in at that point.
I do have one great story
about Brandy, though.
So Brandy, she told us that
she spoke Japanese.
She was like, oh, I'm
fluent in Japanese.
And we all look at Damian
and we're like, OK fine.
So we're on, like, the bullet
train going to Hokkaido or
something, and Damian and
Brandy had one of the
magazines out.
And they were sitting there.
I think it was me, Tom Burt,
Damien, Brandy, and
[INAUDIBLE]
and this guy comes up to her
and he looks at her and he
starts going [INAUDIBLE]
and he asks her something
in Japanese.
And she goes, "Hai." Because
it was clear he was asking,
like, oh is that you on the
cover of the magazine?
And it's like some nude girlie
magazine and she goes, "Hai."
And then he asks another
question and she just answers,
"Hai," which means yes.
And at that point, he
just reached down
and grabbed her boob.
And we're all just like,
whoa, whoa, whoa!
We jump up, pushed the
guy off, and we're
like, hey, hey, hey!
No, no, no!
And our Japanese guide said, oh,
he asked if that was you
on the magazine and you said
yes, and then he asked if
those were your boobs, and you
said yes, and then he asked
you if he could touch them
and you said yes!
Like that Japanese is working
really good for you, Brandy.
STEVE GRAHAM: Damian and Brandy
were still an item, and
so I'm supposed to meet them at
the beach-- this is down in
Huntington-- and I see this
Mexican guy, just kind of
looking like this, looking
over, and I'm like, man,
what's that guy looking at?
And I just, huh, whatever.
And I walk up.
I'm like, hey, what's
going on?
And he says, I'm just checking
out Pocahontas down there.
And I look over and it's Damian
and Brandy and they're
both in G-strings, and
right then, I just--
oh, my God, I start laughing.
And I didn't let the guy know
that I knew them, and I'm
like, yeah, check this out.
So I started going down
there and next thing
you know, I see Damian.
He sees me and just runs around
a rock and changes.
Puts his trunks on and Brandy
just stays the same.
She's probably topless
at the time.
And so I go down there and
next thing you know, I'm
giving her a big hug, and
Damian comes around
and I slap his hand.
And homey on the hill
just, what the?
And he starts to come down.
And I'm all, beat it!
That was Pocahontas.
And sorry, Damian.
Cat's out of the bag, now.
I held it for all those years.
I didn't tell anybody.
MIKE McENTIRE: I got some really
good ones, but they're
kind of, like, x-rated, but--
[LAUGHS]
DAMIAN SANDERS: Farmer and
I were riding together.
We were filming on the
Palisades at Squaw.
We're right underneath
the chairlift.
Everybody on the chairlift
is all, go!
Go!
There's a hundred people
watching us and so, this cliff
was already pretty big,
maybe a 45, 50-footer.
Farmer goes first and he lands
and, kind of, digs this giant
hole and bounces out
and pulls it off.
And so they're ready for me.
I jump and right when I went
off the cliff, I saw that
giant divot and I think, I'm not
going to make it anywhere
but right at that hole.
So I went upside-down and
backwards down the hill and
everything caved in
on top of me.
I'm stuck with this arm behind
my back, this arm is holding
the goggles, and I'm trying to
get the snow out of my mouth,
because all of this snow
is just covering.
I was laying there, totally
compacted with just my face
showing for about four minutes,
and one-half an arm,
flipping around like this.
And I was in a full panic for
10 seconds, and I'm just
wiggling and screaming.
I can't do anything.
I can't get this arm free, and
the board's all twisted and
then I just compacted, and
so it was like cement.
So I wasn't able
to move at all.
And so, when I got just my mouth
uncovered, I'd be able
to start screaming, "help,"
and they were so far down,
they couldn't see me.
So they were all waiting for
me to get myself out.
And that's the worst part,
because I remember sitting
there for about three minutes
before they even started up
the hill, because no one knew
I was really stuck.
-What were you thinking when
you couldn't see anything?
DAMIAN SANDERS: That
I was gonna die.
I was just waiting to die.
[MUSIC]
DAMIAN SANDERS: And my good
buddies, Shawn and Dave, came
to save my life.
First guys on the scene.
Every time I moved, more snow
would fill the hole, right
into where my mouth was.
And so the goggles
are all crooked.
It's pitch dark.
I could see a little bit of
light from the cliff.
And then every time the slow
trickled off the cliff, it
went right into the hole,
right into my mouth.
It was just like clockwork.
So I just stayed there, watching
the snow trickle down
this cliff, going, "No
more, no more snow.
I'm gonna die." And I seriously
was waiting to die,
because I couldn't get
a good breath,
and I was just panting.
I was freaking.
I thought they weren't coming.
And 8 and 1/2 minutes is a long
time to spend suctioned
in there like that.
I was flipping out.
And so finally, I felt the snow
move, and I see Farmer's
head come out there.
Big woolly mammoth.
Big bear head.
And he's all, "Are you all
right?" I'm all, "Get me out
of here, I'm freaking out." He
starts digging my mouth away,
and then he got my hands,
and got me out.
So I really do owe him.
He pretty much saved my life,
there, because I was a snow
chunk away from suffocating.
And so that made me exhausted
as all hell.
But we did end up riding
the rest of the day.
And then every fricking night
I had that nightmare.
Just waking up going, I'm not
buried, I'm not buried.
It was a drag, but it was
cool for the video.
It was good drama.
So it was about seven or eight
good years of just really
power riding, and then five or
seven years of just trickling
and doing it, because I could
still get paid to do it.
DON SZABO: Damien blew out his
knee a couple times, and he
had it rebuilt one time and then
he blew it out again, and
he didn't have it fixed again.
And after that, he started
partying a lot.
DAMIAN SANDERS: I moved
into this big-ass
house on the beach.
It was literally right across
the street from the beach,
so-- just up a few streets.
And we started throwing house
parties, because we had so
many friends in the industry,
with snowboarding, and
motocross, and surfing
all being down
here in the same area.
And the house parties were
always the blast, and then I
had this idea to throw
the Pimp 'N Ho party.
This was probably about '91, I
think, was the first Pimp 'N
Ho, or '92, and everybody
dressed up like pimps and hos.
And back then, we didn't have
a clue what that even meant.
It was so funny.
All the girls we knew were
strippers from the local strip
clubs, so to have a Pimp 'N Ho
party just fit right in.
We all had these ridiculous
outfits and-- with the big
hats, and the feathers, and all
that shit, and then the
girls dressed like total hos,
and it was so much fun.
[LAUGHS]
DAMIAN SANDERS: Welcome
to Huntington Beach.
DON SZABO: Back at the house,
I mean, he had crazy parties
every week.
And ran until 2:00 or 4:00 in
the morning, and just a lot of
crazy stuff going on.
And I can say, I was kind of
worried for him, going, what's
he going to do?
He's kind of, spending his
money, and not making money
and just partying
and what-not.
And little did I know that he
was going to turn that into
his career.
And he's doing really well,
throwing parties, and doing
the whole monster stage
thing that he does.
He's a super-creative guy,
and he's always been a
really great guy.
DAMIAN SANDERS: This
is the front porch
that got so much action.
We used to have our 4th
of July parties.
Everybody would be hanging out
out here, partying all over.
This was the 'hood.
And then right there is the
beach, 100 yards away.
Can't complain.
When we first moved into this
house, the first party I ever
had, I walked outside and
Dana was riding the
oil rig, going "browrr".
You'll see later like the giant
human catapult we built
in the backyard, here, that
my buddy got launched
at the beach on.
Dana's got it on one of his
videos, and the guy flies
about 15 feet up, and then
cracks his head on the back of
the catapult.
STEVE GRAHAM: It was a
Halloween party at
Damian's, and we--
I mean, everyone was there.
We were raging.
The ladies who were strippers
ended up showing up a lot
more, like more the LA crowd all
of a sudden showed up, for
Damian's parties.
The next thing you know, there's
girls making out, and
windows being broken.
It was out of hand, and we
couldn't have enough of it.
And we were just all dressed
up in some stupid costume.
And that was, I think,
the first--
in my opinion-- the
first Club Rubber.
DAMIAN SANDERS: I
knew that night.
When that party was over, we
knew we were on to something
huge, because everybody had
the time of their lives.
TODD RICHARDS: I know
Damian used to do
that Club Rubber thing.
It was like a really big
moneymaker for him for a
while, and probably
just rakes cash.
Because people-- it's like
legendary at this point.
So he's got a good
thing going.
He's still marketing himself
as being a weirdo.
It's awesome.
I like it.
DAMIAN SANDERS: The things that
used to go down at my
house were phenomenal.
And at Rubber, Ecstasy
was huge.
Everybody was on drugs and
techno music had just come in.
So you go to that club, and it
was almost like this great
hedonism orgy.
It was just nuts.
And you go in there-- you open
a door into one of the VIP
rooms, and people were
in there having sex.
And you were like, oh, shit!
Sorry!
And you close the door and
go party somewhere else.
And it was happening
every single night.
And the cops didn't catch
on for literally
four or five years.
People were walking around with
hats that say "X Man" on
it, because that's the dealer.
The Huntington Beach team had
a great run for about six or
eight years.
There were just phenomenal.
John Huntington, I met through
nightclubs down here, because
I was doing all these
house parties.
He was also doing nightclub
production stuff.
We started going to Las Vegas,
started doing clubs out there.
And from the clubs out there,
we went into arenas.
And John was like the
booking agent.
He would go into these massive
casinos and OK, we want to
throw a Pimp 'N Ho party at
the casino, at, like, the
Mandalay Bay.
Somehow he talked him into it.
Tommy Lee was our guest host.
Minnie Me was one
of our hosts.
You know, made a fortune.
It was like one of those movies
where the drug lord is
laying on the bed, playing
in the money and shit.
It was just classic.
And then you've got 10,000
people on the dance floor and
all these huge DJs and
everybody dressed
like pimps and ho's.
Tons of fun.
It really fell into place.
From snowboarding, to doing
house parties, to doing
nightclubs, to doing production
for other people's
huge parties now.
And it's just really, I've lived
a pretty charmed life.
I've been really lucky.
-Thank you, Damian.