SUROOSH ALVI: Well, Al Aqsa is
basically Hamas television.
Who owns the channel?
Is it independently owned?
BAHAAUDDIN AL GHOUL: We belong
to the Palestinian
rights, we say so.
Just like the Israeli TVs belong
to Israel, and Al Aqsa
TV belongs to Palestine.
It's the first Palestinian
channel to produce resistance.
The Palestinians have always
said we want our land.
People have the right to defend
himself and to use
resistance against the
occupation force.
If you could give us a
well-targeted weapon that
could only kill the soldiers
of the Israeli, the
Palestinians wouldn't
use such ruckus.
SUROOSH ALVI: The last time I
came, in 2007, I met with an
organization called Palestinian
Media Watch.
They're Israeli, and they sit
and they just watch everything
that you're making here.
And they study it, and they
analyze it, and then they go
to make presentations
to the US Congress.
And they say look how radical
the people in Gaza are.
They're making Mickey
Mouse with AK-47s.
BAHAAUDDIN AL GHOUL: They also
say to their people that
killing a Palestinian is good.
So there's a different
way to see.
If you look to the same video
on an Israeli channel, they
tell their people that killing
Palestinians is a good thing.
SUROOSH ALVI: Can you tell me
about some of the risks that
are involved with working as
a reporter for Al Aqsa?
BAHAAUDDIN AL GHOUL: Our office,
which is now renewed,
has been targeted with
an F-16 bomb--
totally demolished.
Two of our cameramen's
been killed.
[INAUDIBLE]
who was murdered by
an Israeli rocket.
Two of our correspondents have
lost some of their body.
Our cameraman has lost his two
legs, and he shoot and shoot
until he lost his legs.
Made his legs cut, two legs.
So this is an occupation.
And the Palestinians
who resist are
called freedom fighters.
They would like to get
their homeland freed.
If Isreal wants to stop,
they can stop.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Hello.
FEMALE SPEAKER: The first
building was attacked at
approximately 1:30 AM, it
was a media building.
This media building had an
infrastructure of Hamas
electronics communications
on the roof.