SUROOSH ALVI: In Karachi,
politics is a contact sport,
and members of Pakistan's dozens
of political parties
have been known to
put more trust in
bullets than in ballots.
Mob violence, bombings, and
assassinations are sadly par
for the course here.
And while political leaders are
often targeted, the rank
and file suffer the
consequences, too.
We are driving into the
ANP stronghold.
It's the Awami National Party.
On this side is the ANP.
On this side is the
MQM stronghold.
And apparently, they have a
lot of beef, because they
shoot each other.
We met up with Hamza Khan,
one of the local
leaders of the ANP.
The ANP are the largest party
representing Pashtuns, the
Pashto-speaking ethnic group
concentrated in Pakistan and
Afghanistan.
He took us out onto
the main road.
This corridor often turns into
a kind of shooting gallery
between these two rival groups,
as evidenced by the
bullet holes throughout
the neighborhood.
And why aren't you worried
that people won't
shoot at us right now?
MALE SPEAKER: Maybe we
should go up, then,
as soon as we can.
Maybe we should make
our way to the top.
SUROOSH ALVI: Allah
is with us.
We'll be OK, Insha'Allah.
From the high vantage point, not
only could we see the line
that separates these two
neighborhoods, but we could
finally see what they were
so often fighting for--
land.
That is, the lack of it.
Land is the most precious
commodity in Karachi, a city
that has grown exponentially
in recent decades.
So while Pakistani politics
are often organized around
ethnic or interest groups, in
Karachi, what most of those
groups want is more land.
SUROOSH ALVI: The MQM is a
party that was founded to
represent the Urdu-speaking
Muslims whose families
migrated to Pakistan
from India.
We headed to the heavily
barricaded neighborhood that's
home to MQM headquarters.
The neighborhood was plastered
with images of the MQM's
charismatic leader,
Altaf Hussain.
This one is awesome,
by the way.
It looks like all
album covers.
That's his psychedelic era.
MALE SPEAKER: Look at him over
here, he's into iris.
SUROOSH ALVI: This one, he's
trying to go for the Che
Guevara vibe.
MALE SPEAKER: Mary J.
SUROOSH ALVI: Because he fears
assassination, Hussain
communicates with his followers
via Skype from his
home in London.
So instead, we met with the
Minister for Youth Affairs,
Faisal Sabzwari.
We were in the kind ANP
neighborhood yesterday--
Kati Pahari-- and they
don't like the MQM
too much over there.
They accuse MQM of terrorism.
FAISAL SABZWARI: The issue with
ANP in Karachi has been
that some thugs and
goons have been
running the show in Karachi.
Extortion, kidnapping for
ransom, drug money--
that's what some people
under the flag of
ANP have been doing.
SUROOSH ALVI: You can call them
thugs and goons, but I
think MQM, also, people are
intimidated by, because there
are thugs and goons on
your side as well.
FAISAL SABZWARI: No, I reject
that idea as well.
We have no such kind of
a group of people yet.
SUROOSH ALVI: There's
no military or--
FAISAL SABZWARI: No way--
yet.
Yet.
There are areas.
If you have visited Kati
Pahari, people in those
particular areas are forced
to carry out.
Why?
Because we are living amongst
those fanatics, amongst those
people who have no respect to
human life, whose politics is
only commercialized interest.
SUROOSH ALVI: So the short
version of all this is that
people are getting killed
in Karachi every day.
There's gang violence, tons of
mafia, sectarian killings, and
in more recent years,
suicide bombings.
For the political parties,
it's a massive turf war.
And while politicians and
businessmen would never admit
that they engage in
assassinating their rivals,
someone is hiring the so-called
target killers.
We wanted to interview one of
the men responsible for this
dirty work, so we arranged a
meeting with a target killer.
It was uncomfortable for
everyone involved.
We negotiated the terms
of the interview--
in a moving car and with his
motorcycle helmet on.
And not surprisingly, the guy
who kills people for money, he
wanted to get paid.
SUROOSH ALVI:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
TARGET KILLER:
SUROOSH ALVI: It's been at
my feet the whole time.
[FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
MALE SPEAKER: Yep.
SUROOSH ALVI: Thank you.
That was--
yeah.
That was really strange, sitting
next to someone who's
killed 35 people.
And you could just tell from his
demeanor and from his eyes
he was a hard dude.
And there's 600 guys like that
roaming around this city.
Anytime anyone has beef to
settle with someone else, they
want to kill them, just hire one
of these guys, don't pay
them much money, and they'll
do the work.
It's lawless, wild,
and chaotic here.
And that is some scary shit.
And on a lighter note, two
thieves got shot and killed.
They're going to go pick the
bodies up, and they've
inviting us to go along.
One thing had become clear
on this trip--
there's no shortage of murder
and mayhem in Karachi.
Between the gangs and the cops
and the politicians and the
target killers, this was
definitely one of the craziest
cities in the world.
But that's coming from me.
I asked the ambulance driver, a
native Karachiite, how he'd
describe the city.
AMBULANCE DRIVER: [SPEAKING
FOREIGN LANGUAGE[
SUROOSH ALVI: And that's when I
realized it was time to go--
[FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
SUROOSH ALVI: --that if we
didn't quit while we were
ahead, we'd just wind up on some
hamster wheel of violence
and corruption until
we, too were dead--
MALE SPEAKER:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
SUROOSH ALVI: --just another
statistic in the most
gangster-ific city
in Pakistan.
[MUSIC PLAYING]