Narrator: On this
episode of Wicked Tuna.
Kevin: There's no way
Dave's gonna beat me
on my last week out.
Either he moves or
he gets run over.
Dave: Stay the (bleep) away.
Marciano: I promised
my son I'd get him out
in the boat one
day this week.
Reel, Joe, reel!
Greg: It's not
going good today.
Kevin: Hold the hook.
This is the worst day
in my fishing career.
Dave: How's that
feel, Kevin?
Narrator: Fishing
is a hard life.
Ralph: There's gonna
be confrontation.
Narrator: And harder with
Bluefin stocks depleted.
In Gloucester,
Massachusetts,
there's a special
breed of fisherman.
For generations, they've
used rod and reel to catch
the elusive Bluefin Tuna.
Jay: Yeah, baby!
Narrator: They
depend on these fish
for their survival.
The competition is brutal.
Scott: You
miserable (bleep).
Narrator: This
is Wicked Tuna.
Dave: Go, go!
It's great to be on top,
it's great to make all the
money; but with that,
nobody likes a winner.
Marciano: For me, the money
doesn't fall out of the sky;
it comes out of the sea.
Bill: This gets harder
as you get older,
but I'm keeping up
with the young guns.
Get out of the way.
Ralph: If it's on my
mind you're gonna hear
about it and if you
did something to me,
I'm gonna do
something back to you.
Dave: Come on, man.
We better (bleep)
see fish here today.
Sandro: You look
funny doing that.
Dave: I do, I feel
funny doing this.
Week's coming to a
close here and we still
haven't caught a fish
bigger than Kevin's.
Kevin: Dave's been
on top for a while.
It's definitely
all gonna change,
there's only room for one
number one in this group.
Scott: This is a monster.
Kevin: Whoo!
Look at that, boy!
Rick: That is the
biggest fish that we've
seen all year, it's a
thousand pound fish.
Kevin: Size
matters, Davy boy.
Dave: I want the
(bleep) biggest one
in the fleet this year.
Rumor has is this is
Kevin's last week fishing
and he's heading back
to work and this is
my last week to try
and beat his fish.
Today, I have one goal,
and one goal only,
and that's to catch a
thousand pound tuna.
I know I'm never gonna hear
the end of Kevin's fish,
even if he didn't
catch another fish,
he'll find some way
to stick it to me,
'cause he got a thousand
seventy five pounder.
Paul: This is Kevin's last
week out here and he still
holds the record for
the biggest fish.
It's absolutely killing
Dave that, that he hasn't
got one to beat him yet.
Dave: I wonder how
many chunks I've cut
in my lifetime?
If I had a nickel for
each one I'd probably
be a millionaire.
Kevin: Hey, a
double rainbow.
Must be close to
Dot-Com right there.
Paul: Back the (bleep) up.
What is he doing?
Dave: (Bleep) go,
get out of here.
Kevin anchored
right on top of us.
Yeah, and it's been
the norm this year.
If Kevin's so good,
why does he need to be
following me
around, you know?
Go find your own spot.
You don't have to be
right on top of me,
he knows better.
Paul: It makes him
go out of his mind.
To him it's like
a big (bleep) you!
And (bleep) you,
and (bleep) you,
and (bleep) you!
Greg: When we see Dot-Com
with a girlfriend,
what's the, where's the
first place we look?
Kevin: The first thing we
look for is an Adam's apple.
Oh, Dave.
Nothing gets me more
excited than to anchor up
next to Dave, 'cause
it drives him nuts.
So I go out of my way to
torture him a little bit.
It's just a
little reminder,
we caught a
thousand pounder.
Biggest fish of the
season, but it's not over,
we're here to do it again.
Dave: Kevin did catch
his thousand pounder
and there's nothing more
I want right not than to
beat his ass.
Took him 27
years to get it,
took me my first
trip out to catch
a thousand-pounder
and Sandro, caught his
first fish was over
eleven hundred.
That's a big, big fish.
Kevin's was 118, very
respectable, good for him.
But Sandro's was better.
Paul: Here we
(bleep) go again.
Dave is always have to
have the upper hand,
or it'll eat him.
Alls he wants to
do is (bleep) win,
that's all he cares about.
Nancy: All right big gull,
let's move that ball.
Marciano: Hey.
All right, here we are.
I finally get an opportunity
to go to of my son,
Joe's football games.
Be great today,
see the family.
You do those little things
that I often miss out on,
'cause I spent so
much time in the boat.
Woman: Go, set it up!
Marciano: Today is gonna be
about fishing and family.
I promised Joe that I'd
get him out on the boat.
He's been catching
fish since he was eight
or nine years old.
Crowd: Yeah!
Marciano: You going to
come out tuna fishing?
We're starving to
death over here.
Joe: Yeah, I know,
I want to go.
Marciano: Joe has always
been my good luck charm.
I need all the
luck I can get.
Marciano: Eva, did you
have fun at the game?
Eva: I don't know.
Marciano: Let's
get out of here.
Ralph: Give me that
red funnel here.
All right, open
that gear oil here.
You're gonna pour it in
a little, monitor it.
We're doing some maintenance
on the boat today because I
don't want to be tied-up
with a breakdown.
You don't want to get stuck
on a rough night coming in
with a fish and you can't
get back out the next day,
so it's time to look
over all your stuff and
catch up on the
maintenance.
Get some fresh oil in,
tighten up your belts,
clean the bilge.
Pirate: I'm changing
the oil over from a,
a bigger jug to
smaller jugs.
These are reserve,
reserve jugs in case
we do need some oil.
So she burns a little
bit once in a while, so,
it's nicer to have smaller
jugs of oil on deck than
having this big pail.
Ralph: In this business you
can't be concerned about
who's catching what, and
who's getting paid what.
You got to go out there
every day and fish hard,
you know, good days,
bad days, good weather,
bad weather.
You got to focus on what's
going on in your boat,
not what's going on with
everybody else's boat.
While the
competition is there,
you got to kind of ignore it
and you got to do the best
you can with your boat every
day, day in, and day out.
Now we just
checked the oil,
tightened-up the
steering belt,
and checked all the other
vital signs for safety.
Everything appears
to be in good shape.
Ready to go out to
sea, in pursuit of the
giant bluefin today.
Basically, for me is,
I get up every day
and go fishing,
and fish hard.
And, as a result, I always
put my season together.
Evelise: Good luck,
sweetie, good luck.
Bye-bye, you be careful.
Ralph: We're going to go
inside Cape Cod Bay into the
shallow water where the
lobster fisherman have been
reporting seeing some big
tuna jumping in and around
the mackerel that are
inside there stacked up.
Hopefully we can
bend the rod today.
Here we go.
Paul: There he comes.
Dave: 90 feet, oh, wow,
that's a jumbo, boys.
That's a jumbo.
We're on the clip
Sandro right?
Sandro: Yep.
Dave: Okay.
Sandro: It's time we go out
and teach Kevin a lesson.
You don't (bleep)
with Tuna.com.
Dave: Pretty excited.
Paul: Yeah, there's a
lot of (bleep) under the
boat right now, dude.
Dave's obsessed
with beating Kevin.
He's got a great
catch, so move on.
(Bleep) it.
Sandro: 100.
Dave: How deep?
Sandro: Hundred.
Paul: I'm cutting
some bait here.
Pretty soon I'm going
to start throwing the
bait out far to get it
deep in, up high,
so they go up and down.
You don't want the fish
to swim in one pattern,
you want 'em to scatter up
and down, and all around.
Sandro: They get crazy.
Paul: Right.
Dave: Making 'em crazy.
Paul: You want
to horn 'em up.
Get 'em all frenzying.
Sandro: I got 90.
Dave: Back at 90?
Paul: Yeah, that
seems to be their
depth right now, huh?
Dave: Oh, yeah.
Sandro: All the
way up to 70.
Paul: All the way to 70.
Dave: He's right here.
Paul: Oh, he's a
big bitch, dude.
Sandro: A big bitch.
Dave: Whoa, that's
a mambo, dude.
Paul: His sole purpose was
just to get a bigger fish.
He's fit to be tied.
At this point, I just
want to catch a fish.
I just want to make
some (bleep) money.
There he comes.
Sandro: Here he is,
we're on, we're on!
Dave: Forward, forward!
Paul: Whoo!
Bury that hook
in him, bury it!
Bury that (bleep) hook!
Dave: Wait, slow down,
slow down, slow down!
Forward, forward!
Paul: Right now, we got
one on the line and we
thing it could be
bigger than Kevin's.
Reel, bitch!
Dave: Yeah.
Dave: A lot of money
on the line and
no screwing up
here, no mistakes.
Look at that (bleep)
phone ringing.
Can you (bleep) believe it?
Paul: Dr. Barry's calling,
he wants to know if
you want more Viagra.
Dave: Yeah.
Paul: Send 'em over and
(bleep) blow 'em up!
Dave: There she goes!
Paul: Yeah!
We need the
Viagra, we're old.
Dave: All right, come
on, come on, come on!
I don't want to
turn him, easy.
Hundred feet.
He's a big boy.
I want to stay right
on top of him so
we know where he's at.
Paul: I'm getting
the harpoon ready.
I got one on each
side of the boat.
The bigger size fish
you gotta have a
harpoon on each side.
You know?
You got to have them ready.
Dave: Slow it down.
I'm going to see swivel
here in a second, swivel.
Paul: Got one!
Nailed him right
in the back.
We see him,
we were psyched.
It was a big
fish, he was big.
It would be sweet
revenge to know we
got one bigger
than Kevin.
Go ahead Dave.
Dave: Pretty excited, we
know we got a big fish.
But, yeah, we don't know
if we got Kevin beat.
Paul: Keep going, keep
going, keep going.
Dave: No way.
Paul: Keep going, right
there, right there,
right there.
Dave: No way.
Paul: Yep.
Dave: That's a lo-, holy
(bleep), he's (bleep) long.
Paul: 12 feet, I told you.
Dave: No (bleep) way.
I knew, you know, when
that fish came up,
we definitely
had a big boy on.
It was definitely
a grander.
Look out, Kevin,
I'm taking you down.
Another (bleep) grander
right here, boys.
Look at the size
of that tail.
Paul: Oh, Dave
was so pumped.
They could say, oh, he
was like a little kid.
Oh, measure him.
What's his girth, and yeah.
Dave: Cha-ching,
that's all I gotta say.
That's what it's all about
right there, (bleep) boys.
That's tuna
fishing, amazing.
Paul: So (bleep)
you, Kevin.
Dave: Hey Kevin,
you there?
Yeah, you should've
been here.
It's definitely over
a thousand pounds.
You there?
Kevin: That's great,
congrats, man.
Dave: She's definitely
a contender, Kevin.
Kevin: So you
heading back?
Dave: Hell, no.
We're gonna stay out here
'til the bait's gone.
We're gonna catch
another one.
Kevin: I can't
believe Dave caught a
thousand pounder,
unfreaking real.
Marciano: I got my son
Joseph here with us today.
He's famous for getting us
the hooked baits that catch
the fish, you know?
He's done that a
bunch of times for us.
Joe: I've been fishing
since I was like
probably four years old.
Marciano: Hey, Joe.
Joe: Yeah?
Marciano: Just so you know,
you can catch my live bait
any time here, you know?
I'm ready, kinda.
Joe: Yeah, I'm
working on it.
Marciano: You're
just waiting for the
right one, right?
Joe: Right, right.
Marciano: All right.
Joe: I've thought about
following in his footsteps,
but the main thing,
I have to get, uh,
through college first.
And he's even told me that.
Marciano: It's important
that Joe go to college.
You know, I want him to have
the opportunities, you know,
that I didn't have.
Especially this day and
age, the way things are,
you really don't have
a shot if you don't
have that college diploma.
For me, that's one
mistake I don't want my
children to make.
There's a fish, fish
are ready here, folks.
Fish are ready at five.
Jason: At five?
Marciano: Joe, keep
trying right away.
Joe: Gonna try.
Marciano: See is you
can get us a live here.
Joe: Any minute now.
Marciano: There
he is again at 15.
Just keep at it, Joe, yeah.
See if we can get our
thousand pounder.
Two of 'em, two of
'em on the screen.
Three of 'em, big fish.
Jay: How high?
Marciano: They're coming
up as high as 10 and 11.
We got 'em in the chum.
They're here,
they're up in 10.
Joe, crank that
up this time.
We got 'em high.
If that
rod goes,
we're gonna get a big
fish out of the deal.
How high up do
they come, Joe?
Joe: 18.
Marciano: We haven't got
a thousand pounder yet,
but we're gonna
get one today.
Any minute now.
Pirate: Ready, Cap?
Ralph: Let her fly.
No sooner did we get tight
on the anchor that the
machine started beeping,
we started marking
giant tunas right away.
Pirate: Oh, you
better be kidding me.
Already?
Ralph: Keep the chum going.
You got one under the boat
right now at 70 feet.
Pirate: Yeah, if I
could get the birds to
stay away for
five seconds.
Ralph: Pirate expects
respect from the birds.
He expects that they keep
their distance and they
don't eat the chum that
he's throwing in the water.
Most important thing is
that Pirate doesn't get
distracted by the
birds and focus all his
attention on the birds.
He really needs to pay
attention to the bait
getting under the boat
so we can feed the tuna
and catch a fish.
Pirate: See over
there, right?
Ralph: Just over here,
it's gonna go that way.
Look at the three balloons.
Take the angle of
the three bones.
See the angle of
the three balloons?
The angle of three
balloons is actually to
the front of
the boat here.
So, if I was chumming, I
would be standing here and
go, flipping to the
front of the boat.
Pirate: Up a little
further to the bow?
Ralph: You want it,
you want it to go back
even with the balloons.
The balloons are showing
you the drift line.
So your chunk's got
to go in at that front
of the drift line.
If they go over here, the
fish are gonna be over here,
and the bait's
are over here.
Pirate: I asked the
Captain what he,
what's he want me to do?
And now and then he
tells you, say, hey,
guess what we're gonna do?
And you do what
he's gonna say, so.
Well that (bleep) got it.
Ralph: You got to constantly
get out of your chair and
watch the chum go down,
and make sure the chum
is going the way you
think it's going.
Don't take it for granted.
You got to constantly
make adjustments.
It's very important that
your chumming in the right
spot or we're jerking off.
Scott: Coming back.
Kevin: Back?
Scott: Yep.
Kevin: What depth?
Scott: 100, big boy;
that's a slammer.
Kevin: This is the spot,
there's definitely a lot of
fish here; we're
marking a lot.
Dave can catch all the
thousand-pounders he wants;
there's no way this
guy's gonna beat me on
my last week out.
Dave's just off
our port beam here,
maybe a quarter mile.
Dave: Knowing I've
caught a big fish,
and knowing that I could
possibly beat Kevin's fish,
that's a good feeling.
There's something about
having the biggest fish,
size does matter.
Kevin: You know there's a
couple weeks left in the
season, and 1,078.
That's a tough fish
to beat right there.
But, uh, there are some
cruising around here,
no doubt.
I know he's got a big
one on deck today.
I don't think it's
quite that big, but.
They're marking
another one.
It's a big one,
this is a big fish.
Scott: Yeah, we're up!
Kevin: Here we go, yep.
Just stay on it, you okay?
Scott: She's burning.
Sandro: Kevin's tight.
I think Kevin is tight.
Dave: Yeah?
Paul: Oh, he's hooked up.
Dave: Oh, man.
Paul: You know when
it's killing him,
he doesn't say anything.
Kevin: I'm gonna
kick it ahead, Scott.
Paul: If he lands another
(bleep) thousand pound fish,
it could ruin
our whole season.
Kevin: You all right?
That rod's not locked in.
I'm looking and I see
my line kind of headed
towards Dave's boat.
Scott: Heading right
for Dot Com's boat.
Kevin: You might have
to get off, Davy boy.
It's coming right at you.
Dave: We might have
to get off the, uh,
anchor here to get
out of Kevin's way.
It's gonna ruin
our day here.
Why the (bleep) does he
gotta come over here?
Stay the (bleep) away!
Look at him.
Sandro: He's reeling.
Coming in hot.
Dave: Come on Kevin,
(bleep) turn the boat.
Paul: Back the (bleep) up.
Kevin: Don't let that
rod pop out, Scott.
We hooked this big
fish and he took off.
Scott: He's still
taking line.
Kevin: He just
scrammed and he was
pulling the boat around.
Right to my buddy, Dot-Com.
Dave: Stay the
(bleep) away!
Paul: He's reeling.
Dave: Look at him.
Paul: Coming in hot.
Dave: Yeah, if he
gets much closer,
he's gonna take
out our lines.
Come on, Kevin,
(bleep) turn the boat.
Paul: Back the (bleep) up!
Dave: I can't believe this.
Kevin: If he doesn't
want to move,
I'm gonna cut
him off, period.
Dave: What's he,
right off your stern?
Is he up high, or down lee?
Kevin: Probably high.
Dave: (Bleep) right
up high, oh, yeah.
That's the only
way he can beat us,
wiping out our gear.
Kevin: Well it's
spinning ahead.
He ought to be tired, he
took a (bleep) load of line.
Scott: Die already, die!
Kevin: Oh, (bleep)!
(Bleep)!
You've gotta be (bleep)
kidding me, oh!
We saw him.
We had him about 30 feet
from the boat, and pow.
Pulled the hook,
it hurts, you know?
That was another
big fish, you know?
Eight, 900 pounder,
maybe bigger.
You're talking 20,000
dollars for this fish.
When you lose it, it hurts.
(Bleep) big bastard, too.
Scott: (Bleep) slammer.
Kevin: That thing was big.
Paul: We were laughing
our balls off.
Dave: What happened?
Kevin: Pulled the hook right
at the boat, 20 feet away.
It was worse, it was
worse losing that fish
in front of him, you know?
He's like, "Oh man, I'm
sorry that happened Kev."
Dave: Nah, nothing
you can do, Kev.
Kevin: I don't
believe him, you know?
You know, (bleep) Dave.
Dave: You know, that's
what happens when you
anchor in my spot, you
embarrass yourself and
he had it coming.
Two can play that game.
He (bleep) himself
today, too bad for him.
Ralph: Yeah, baby,
some burgers.
Living large on the Odysea.
One thing we
do, we eat good.
No sandwiches, we eat
burgers and T-bones.
Spending your life
on a 32-foot boat,
it gets to be
difficult at times.
So, depending on
the season, uh,
we always find a way to cook
good food on the Odysea.
If you want to stay out
here, you got to eat good,
wow, that's good.
Yeah, we don't really
care about lunch
when the rod bends.
It's time to get into
action and catch that tuna.
Fish on, fish on, fish on!
Get him!
Pirate lock him up,
Pirate lock him up!
Pirate: Here we go,
we're on the meat!
Ralph: How big is
he, how big is he?
Pirate: I don't know,
he must be a keeper.
He ain't bending the rod
that good, but, good karma!
Good karma, yahoo!
Right now she feels
like a good one.
Probably about
a 400 pounder.
All right, all
right, all right.
That's good, that's
good, that's good.
Hold, hold, easy, easy.
How big?
Ralph: No, it's
not that big.
I got color already.
Might be a short.
Keeper size has
been 73 inches which
is about six feet.
Let's get him up on
the surface again.
Pirate: Here we go.
Oh, that's close.
Ralph: We decided, you
know, rather than not
damage it or stress
it out anymore,
we would just release
it real easily.
Oh, yeah.
Here it goes.
That's the
sustainability factor,
releasing the small ones.
Catching the ones that
have already spawned.
Leaving the young ones
to spawn some day.
Pirate: Hoping the next one
comes up through its gonna
be big enough to stick him.
Joe: Nine, high as nine.
Marciano: See if we
can get 'em to stick.
Joe: Going down.
Marciano: Oh, I love
having him on the boat.
He's usually good luck, so
let's see what happens.
Jason: Where's he at, Joe?
Where's he at?
Marciano: Where's
he hanging, Joe?
Joe: Uh, 20 fathoms.
Marciano: 20?
How high when he comes up?
Joe: Uh, around
like 17 or 15.
Marciano: Okay.
Jason: We're on, we're on!
We're on, Joe!
Marciano: Yeah!
All right, let's get
it in the holder here.
Here we go, ready?
We're on the move.
Joe: Yep.
Marciano: We got a
good one this time.
He's taking a lot of line.
The way this
fish is running,
I'm thinking we
got another 10,000
dollar bill on the line.
Let's go, let's go!
Jason: You get
tired, you tell me.
Marciano: Watching Joe do
this like this reminds me of
when he caught
his first fish.
He was about
nine years old,
the first one he
brought in to himself.
He had caught him with me.
He pulled that fish up in
less than eight minutes.
What could I say, but a
chip off the old block.
All right, Joe,
you're doing good.
Keep that rod bent,
you're doing good,
you're doing good, Son.
Just watch that tip,
you know the drill,
you've done this a
hundred times before.
Jay: Reel, Joe, reel!
Marciano: That's good
Joe, you're doing good.
You're doing good,
keep up the good work.
Doing good, Joe.
Keep it tight,
keep it tight.
Jason: Reel, reel, reel!
There's the fish!
Jay: Reel, Joe, reel!
Marciano: That's good
Joe, you're doing good.
You're doing good,
keep up the good work.
Doing good, Joe.
Keep it tight,
keep it tight.
Jason: Reel, reel, reel!
There's the fish!
Jay: Right there,
right in the head.
Yeah baby!
Marciano: I'm not normally
a sentimental guy
and the huggy feely type;
but I can't describe
you know, the amount
of pride I feel
when I see Joe reel
in a fish like that.
You know, it show's
me I must have done
a little something
right as a parent.
Jay: Yeah Joe,
cinch it down.
Cinch it down,into
the corner, yea.
Yes.
Marciano: Tails
up, baby.
That's how we like em.
Tails up back there.
Okay here we go.
Jason: Oh he is a
big one, wow!
Marciano: Bigger
than I thought.
That's a 900 pound
fish right here.
This guy with his
shape and the color.
I'm liking what I see,
this guy's gotta be
worth $12,000, not a bad
day's pay right here.
Jason: Hey Dave, he's got
something to say to you.
Marciano: What?
Joe: This means I get to skip
school tomorrow, right?
Marciano: Yeah right.
Jason: I'd say yes too.
Come on dude, it's just
starting to get good.
Paul: Big fish right now
Dave, look at him.
Dave: Kevin lost a fish.
It's possible his luck
may have run out.
Tuna.com is back on
top, mark my word.
Going down,
going down.
Paul: Look at the
size of that mark.
Dave: Going under water.
These are no little
pencil marks.
these are big, fat, black;
like magic marker marks,
just big streaks
Sandro: Coast Guard.
Paul: Coast Guard's
here Dave, visitation.
Dave: Getting my 20th
boarding of the year again.
Coast Guard: How
you guys doing?
Dave: What's going on?
Coast Guard: We're going
to send a two person
boarding team on.
Dave: Yep.
Coast Guard: All
right, do you have any
lines port side
good here?
Dave: Nope.
He's doing a routine
boarding, that's it.
Checks survival suits, all
our permits, license,
TWIC card, that's it.
Seems like the Coast
Guard always comes at
the most unopportune time.
Whenever we're marking fish,
they come on the boat.
And because they
come on our boat,
I make sure everything is in
the best shape possible.
I make sure all my
paperwork is up to date.
Do you want all my
documentation?
Coast Guard: Yes please.
Dave: Come on in, come
on in, here you go.
Coast Guard: Thank you.
This regulation's, you
know, making sure that
everybody that's out here
fishing is fishing properly,
fishing safely.
It's still a business
and with every business
there's regulations.
You make sure everybody's
got a fair chance
and make sure the fish have
a fair chance as well.
Paul: Everyone hates them
when they board them.
And I'm like, "Wh, Why?"
"Because you aggravated
cause they're taking up
a little bit of
your fishing time?"
Big deal!
It's nota big deal.
We're lucky they're
here to help us.
So thank God,
keep coming.
Dave: It's all here.
Big boy, that ones
head and tail on.
Coast Guard: No
violations sir.
Once again, you are in
compliance and we
do appreciate that.
Dave: Alright.
Coast Guard: Make our
lives a lot easier.
Dave: And thank you
guys, thanks a lot.
Coast Guard: Thank
you very much again.
Dave: I'll see ya; I'll
see ya next year.
Coast Guard:
Yeah. [laughs]
Dave: All right,
see you guys.
Thanks for being
here again.
Coast Guard: Thanks
guys, good luck.
Dave: Appreciate it.
Paul: I'm not arrested
and we're good to go.
Kevin: We are headed for
Stellwagen Bank.
About 13 miles south
of Gloucester.
Looks good, conditions
are okay and
we'll see what happens.
I wasn't convinced that
Dave actually caught
a bigger fish.
I didn't think he had it.
Was I worried?
A little bit.
Sometimes I get this
little inner feeling when
I know we're gonna
catch a fish.
I don't know what it is.
But Scott knows what
I'm talking about
with that inner
feeling right?
Greg: Got one coming up.
Streaking right up.
Oh, that's a mark!
Kevin: We're marking a
fish and I can tell
this fish is big.
Greg: Holy moly,
there's the real deal.
Scott: It's (bleep) long!
Kevin: Dave's definitely
been taken down a peg.
Now it's, it's time to
finish him off.
Deep in the water
as fast as we can.
Greg: Streaking right up,
got em right up to,
right off the bottom.
Kevin: You know he's 20
feet under the boat.
Pull a bait down.
Then he swims up and
a big bird grabs it.
You know, sheer water.
Scott: He's got your
bait, he's got your bait.
Kevin: Does he?
Mother (bleep)!
Greg: Yeah, yeah,
get out of here!
Kevin: That pissed
me off, you know?
We get a bird
instead of a tuna.
Greg: Screw, come on fish!
Come on back,
time to eat!
Kevin: This is gonna be
my opportunity to
kick Dave's ass
once and for all.
Greg: We're on, we're
on, we're on, we're on!
Crank, crank, come on!
Kevin: Crank it, crank
hard, crank hard!
Greg: We're tight!
Kevin: Move to
the stern, go!
I just hope it
measures up.
Oh (bleep), pulled
the hook, damn it!
(bleep)!
We're on, we're on!
We're in, uh, what
I call a frenzy.
We'd hooked a fish,
we'd lose him.
We'd get back on the
anchor and that rod
would bend again.
Scott: Ah, mother (bleep)!
Kevin: The rod would pop
and the line would break.
You broke it?
It was just disappointing
Come on, what
the (bleep)?
Greg: What the
hell's going on?
Kevin: We just dropped
another one here,
pulled the hook.
He was the real deal.
I mean he was a big
one, you know?
I, I'd say he
wasn't a short.
I got gypped.
Dave: Hey Paul, Kevin just
pulled another hook.
Paul: [laughs].
How's that feel Kevin?
Kevin: That's tuna
frustration right there.
Ralph: Hooking big one,
they're getting away.
It's been a rough week.
I keep spending money
to come out here and
fish every day.
And every day I come home
poorer than when I left.
These things might have
a chance to get away
from the dogfish.
Pirate: I do this for
a living, not for fun.
Don't get me wrong, I love
fishing, and all that stuff.
But when I get, you get
into a dry spell like that,
sometimes you second guess
yourself and is it worth me
going out that way for 10,
12 hours a day, you know,
busting your hump,
you know?
In the cold weather.
Mike: I think my volt
meter is (bleep) up.
Ralph: We just got a
radio call from Mike on
the Bad Dog that he's
got a dead battery.
If you're dead in the
water with no battery,
you're really in bad shape.
You're susceptible to
getting run over or
to drift onto the rocks.
Anything bad can happen.
Mike: So I'm (bleep).
I don't know, I don't
know what to do here.
Ralph: Shut everything off.
In a case like this, the
fisherman with the dead
battery takes precedence
over the tuna fish.
So we're gonna have
to reel our lines in,
and haul our anchor,
and go take care of our
friend Mike on the Bad Dog.
Sit tight, I'll come
over and get you.
Mike: Okay.
Ralph: Reel 'em up, Pirate.
Well this is the
life that we chose,
so these are the
decisions we make when
we're out at sea.
If it was to ever
happen to me,
I hope somebody would
reel their lines in
and tow me in.
We're on a rescue
mission here.
Save Mikey Bad Dog from
the white sharks tonight.
Nobody wants to go
out there and die,
or nobody wants to
have anybody hurt,
especially as a Captain.
You know, I owned another
gill netter at one time.
I get a phone call from the
Coast Guard that the boat
sunk and there was two
people in the life raft,
when I know three left.
Fortunately we did
recover all three guys,
but that was a horrible,
horrible feeling.
Hey, do you have
shore power?
Best thing is let me
tow you to the dock.
Get ready to
haul his anchor.
A little anchor
and a lot of chain.
I got the other way around.
Go down through here.
And that's just
basically the way it is.
It's a fact
of tuna fishing,
it's just a
fact of life here.
Hey, I'm doing for him
what he would do for me.
That's the way it
works out here.
Just helping a
friendly fisherman.
Kevin: Want to get some
blood on the deck here.
We should be, uh, we should
be on our way home with
three in the boat, in early.
Greg: Not going good today.
Kevin: What happened?
You know?
I don't know,
I don't know.
Somebody put the, put the
whammy on me, I guess.
I don't know,
maybe it was Dave.
Greg: Dot-Com, Dot-Com.
I'm on, I'm on!
Kevin: Hold it, Greg.
He's towing the boat, let
him just pull us right
around, everything's good.
That's the real deal.
Scott: Pull ahead, Greg.
Kevin: So we, we
get back on the ball
for the fourth time.
(Bleep)!
And sure enough,
broke 'em off again.
You got to be
(bleep) kidding me!
Broke at the crotch.
Greg: Same (bleep).
Kevin: Same hook, too.
Gone, again.
I can't even believe
it, you know?
I'm just beside myself now.
Now I'm pissed, Greg's
pissed, Scott's pissed;
we're all, we're all upset.
It's a complete nightmare.
We mark another fish, I look
over and wham, we're on.
Number five, big fish.
Just burning rubber and
pow, we break the line.
Now we've lost five.
It's, uh, I've had it.
Scott: A loyal,
oh, we're on now!
We're on!
Kevin: He taking line?
Scott: Yeah, he's
pulling line now.
Kevin: It's marking
like it's a tuna.
Scott: Yo, there he
goes, he's taking line.
Greg: Forward!
Oh, oh, oh, don't let
that mono tungsten blow!
Let's see, we're gonna
see him right now.
It is a blue nose.
Kevin: This is the worst
day in my fishing career.
Dave: There he is.
That's a 900 pound
fish right there.
Look at him, that's
a (bleep) jumbo and
a half right there.
I look back up
again, there's two,
there's three,
there's four.
Un-(bleep) believable.
And these are just
all big slobs,
there's no little
fish there.
Sandro: We're on, we're on!
Paul: And don't pull
your, watch the rod.
Watch the rod.
Sandro: I got it.
Paul: Watch the rod.
Dave: Yeah, I don't have a
good feeling about this one.
Paul: Is it a sharky?
Dave: Looks like
a big blue dog.
Looks like a big
blue dog to me.
Sandro: A (bleep) huge blue
dog, telling me, huge.
Dave: Right now a shark is
the last thing we need.
You want to cut it?
Paul: We don't even
know what it is, yet.
You never know, dude.
Dave: (Bleep) blue dog.
I had the scissor.
I was just gonna cut it,
and move on and
get back to fishing.
And then all of a sudden.
Holy (bleep).
It's a tuna.
Sandro: Wow.
Dave: I was
definitely mistaken.
Stop the boat.
Neutral.
Forward right.
Bring him to the stern.
Kick it around.
Yeah, pull right.
There you go, nice.
Harpoon.
Keep going.
Come on.
Get on him.
Paul: Whoa!
Dave: Go, go, there he is!
Where's the harpoon?
Forward!
Pull left!
Hurry up!
Hold it!
Let go, get up!
Go, go!
Let it go!
Throw it forward!
Forward, forward!
All right, clear!
Forward, right!
Paul: I get smashed
in the (bleep) head!
I harpoon the fish, and a
safety line came up and
smashed me in the head.
(Bleep) that hit me
right in the head,
that (bleep) thing.
Dave: What, what hit you?
Paul: This, wrapped around.
Dave: Oh, really?
Paul: It (bleep) came off
the line and went smack!
Oh, that hurt, like
a bitch, whatever,
we're gonna get paid.
He's big, too, (bleep)
like 700 pounds.
Dave: I almost
cut off an 8, 000
dollar fish thinking
it was a blue dog.
Holy (bleep) are
we (bleep) lucky!
He's a cute little one.
All right here we go.
Paul: Wind him right in.
Oh that's (bleep).
Dave: Dude, that's
a nice fish.
Paul: Oh my God.
That's (bleep) sweet, too.
Look at the color
on that fin.
Dave: Holy (bleep).
Holy (bleep).
Now that's fat.
That fish is
caulked with fat.
This fish here, this is an
8,000 dollar fish, plus.
Kevin, you gave
it your best shot,
but nobody beats
Tuna.com, nobody
Paul: That's a
beautiful fish.
That shape is incredible.
Dave: Dude, we thought that
was a (bleep) blue dog.
It fooled you too.
The ironic thing is, we're
probably gonna get the most
money for this fish, right?
Paul: Out of any of 'em.
Dave: And I was getting
ready to cut 'em off.
Two slobs in 24 hours.
Now we just need to
get back to the dock and
weigh these babies in.
Look out Kevin,
we're coming for you.
Marciano: We're
on our way in,
we had a great day today.
The weather was nice, flat,
calm here and Joe came out.
We got a fish,
right off the bat.
I told you he was good luck.
He had a nice 900 pounder
laying on the deck back
here, you know?
So all in all, it
was a great day.
Joe: One more good one.
Marciano: This is getting
to be habit forming.
Nancy: Joseph, Joseph.
Joe: Mom.
Marciano: Everything went
well, we got the fish.
Nancy and Eva met
us down the boat,
so had the whole big family
thing going on down there.
Joe: Big one, huh?
Nancy: That's huge!
Marciano: That's when it
all comes together nicely.
Joe comes out with us that
one day and then, boom.
We come back with
that big, huge fish.
Are you gonna take a
ride on this one, Eva?
Eva: I guess.
Marciano: Hey he's.
Eva: It puked out!
Marciano: It's
like a horsy, Eva.
It's a fish as big as horse.
We got it early
in the morning.
First bait in the water,
20 minutes of fishing.
We had my good luck
charm on the boat,
we had Joe with us,
so we should do well
with this one.
I'm confident.
Eva, you gonna
get a ride on him?
Some kids get
to ride horses.
Eva gets to ride
giant blue fin tuna,
that's what she likes.
Say giddy up.
Eva: Giddy up.
Marciano: Tails up, just
keep getting bigger.
This is a nice one,
this a gorgeous fish,
it's got real nice quality
going for it, too.
I'm anxious to see what
these guys got to say,
but I really think we're
gonna do well with this one.
Martin: 622.
Nancy: 640.
Joe: Augh!
Martin: You didn't make it.
Marciano: What is it?
Martin: 589,
592 minus three.
Eva: What?
He was so big though.
Joe: 589.
Martin: 589.
Joe: It's a paycheck.
Nancy: Very good,
thank you Mr. Tuna.
Marciano: All righty.
Pleasure doing business
as usual, Martin.
Ralph: Tonight, I'm the
Coast Guard, tonight.
I'm the rescue tonight.
Captain Ralph to the rescue.
Do-do-do do-do do-do.
I needed a fish
pretty badly.
But sometimes, circumstances
get in the way.
Pirate: There's an
unwritten code around here.
If you're broke down or
something like that,
you know the next guy's
gonna come over and help you
out too, you know?
That's just the
thank you enough in
itself right there.
So how close we gonna be
able to drag him to is, uh.
Ralph: I'll get
him in there.
I'll float him
right to the pole.
There you go.
Mike: Yeah,
we're off Ralph.
Thanks Ralph.
Ralph: All right, Mike,
have a good night.
So there's no
tuna this week,
which is hard for
a short season.
I'm in the hole now, so
we're gonna have to work
extra hard from here on in,
in order to make ends meet.
Dave: Yeah, the fish
is, uh, definitely over
a thousand pounds.
Gotta wait till we get back
to the dock, see how much.
Hey, Sandro, you're gonna
have to help me pinch this.
Sandro: That's good.
Man: Ready?
Good.
Paul: No matter how (bleep)
nuts Dave could be,
you gotta give him credit.
Dave: That's a jumbo, huh?
That's a jumbo.
Paul: He sets out to catch a
thousand pounder, he does.
Dave: This is def, this is
definitely bigger than his.
Big one.
Paul: He's a
(bleep) monster,
nice big fat (bleep).
Dave: He's a monster.
Man: Let's see what
we've got here.
Dave: I can't, I
can barely see it.
Man: 1,015.
Paul: That mother (bleep)!
Dave: Yeah, Kevin's fish was
a little bit bigger than
ours but I said I'd get a
thousand pounder, and I did.
And that takes skill.
Yeah, Kevin may have
got the record for the
biggest fish for the
year, but I caught more
fish than everyone
this season.
He got lucky.
Sandro: Ah, there he is.
Kevin: Ah ha, look at this.
Just got in and, uh,
thought I'd pay a little
visit to my buddy Dave.
Heard he had a big fish, or
he'd killed a big fish today
and, uh, I wanted to see
what the weight was.
Dave: I'm not saying
it was bigger,
I'm not saying
it was bigger.
Kevin: Well you're out,
you're out, you're out.
Dave: You got us
beat yesterday.
What happened today?
Yeah, we saw your fish, your
fish came right up on top.
I was like, look, there's.
Scott: The whole time
he was on the top.
Kevin: Couldn't get him, we
drive on him, back on him,
he'd go down, he'd
come right back up.
He was big, that
was a big fish.
Dave: I saw it.
We saw it, we were
looking at it.
Paul: We saw the whole fish.
Dave: We saw your
boat over there.
Paul: He was like
1,300 dressed.
Kevin: That sounds
like a Dave story.
Paul: If he was a
little closer I could've
stuck him for you.
Kevin: Oh, man, we
needed like another.
Paul: Would've cut the
anchor line and back up.
Kevin: Another, what,
20 feet and we would've
got a dart in him.
Dave: That sucks.
Paul: (Bleep).
Kevin: Yep, that sucks.
Dave: It's a heartbreaker.
Kevin: The fish was nuts.
Just comes right.
Paul: (Bleep)
these tuna fish!
Kevin: I've said
it for many years.
It's, uh, greed, ego, and
jealousy in this fishery.
And they're jealous,
that's the bottom line.
You know?
It's, a, it's a trophy
fish what we have there.
We're still the
leaders here.