Rainn Wilson, creator
of SoulPancake.
It's so cool that
you stopped by.
RAINN WILSON: Thanks for
having me, Steve.
STEVE SPANGLER: So for people
that don't know what
SoulPancake is all about, tell
us about the website.
RAINN WILSON: Sure.
SoulPancake is a website where
users can explore life's big
questions--
philosophy, creativity,
spirituality, really dig into
what it is to be
a human being.
And we've also got an awesome
new YouTube channel.
Check that out.
STEVE SPANGLER: You're right.
You do want to check
out that link.
Let's--
Are you OK?
RAINN WILSON: [GROANING]
STEVE SPANGLER: So give us
an example of some of the
questions that you would have,
maybe, on the website.
Like for example, give us a
question that you would do on
the website, and then I'll
answer it using science.
RAINN WILSON: OK.
For instance, since you're
a scientist, love.
What happens when you
fall in love?
Like literally, scientifically,
in your brain,
what happens when you
fall in love?
STEVE SPANGLER: When
you fall in love.
Well, that's a little bit
deeper than I thought.
But that's-- oh!
Check this out.
You're going to love this.
Watch this.
Did you know that you can
balance a bubble on your hand
if you're wearing
a cotton glove?
RAINN WILSON: Did
not know that.
But what does that have to do
the question I just asked?
STEVE SPANGLER: Don't
worry about it.
Here.
Take this glove here.
Put this glove on.
OK?
Put it on.
Stretch it on.
So now, here, watch this.
Now, you get some
bubble solution.
It's just like glycerin
and soap.
And because of the semi-perm--
don't worry about that.
So here's what you're going
to do, is you just blow
a bubble like this.
And now watch.
See that?
It's the oil in your hands that
will typically pop it.
But because of the glove
here, it doesn't pop.
Here, hold out your hand.
I'll give to you.
Here, watch this.
Here, ready?
Hold it there like that.
Take it.
Oh!
RAINN WILSON: What was that?
STEVE SPANGLER: It just
has to be smaller.
Watch this.
And don't be afraid of it.
So here, watch this.
Hold out your hand.
Ready?
It's OK.
Just take it.
Take it.
Awesome, huh?
RAINN WILSON: It's magical.
Wow.
STEVE SPANGLER: Look, look.
It's there.
Look.
Watch.
Watch this.
Recycling.
Is that awesome?
RAINN WILSON: You know what?
That is really cool.
But again, what does this have
to do with the question?
STEVE SPANGLER: I know.
But it's fine.
I just want to show you
some other things.
Oh, you're going to love this.
Here watch.
So here.
Roll up my sleeves.
Watch.
This is called an
energy stick.
And so I put a battery here, and
there's some LEDs in here.
But when I touch this end,
nothing happens.
But when I complete
the circuit--
[BUZZING]
Look at that.
The electrons flow on my skin.
Your skin is a human conductor
of electricity.
Got it?
So here.
Watch.
I'm just going to hold
onto this end.
You just hold onto that.
It's OK.
Touch it.
So nothing happens.
So now, but watch.
If we touch our hands together
like this-- just touch.
[BUZZING]
See?
RAINN WILSON: Wow.
STEVE SPANGLER: It goes off.
RAINN WILSON: Impressive.
STEVE SPANGLER: Now,
if I touch your
shirt, it doesn't work.
See how it doesn't work?
But if I touch your nose,
here, watch this.
[BUZZING]
See?
RAINN WILSON: OK.
But you know what, Steve, I'm
beginning to think that you're
actually avoiding my question
that I posed to you.
STEVE SPANGLER: Not really.
I'll answer your question
like this.
Here, watch.
See this?
Grab onto that.
Now hold it out like this.
Here, listen to this.
Hello!
OK.
Stretch it out.
Yes.
Stretch.
Now listen to this.
Choo, choo, choo.
See, it's vibration.
[VIBRATION SOUNDS]
STEVE SPANGLER: Luke,
I am your father!
RAINN WILSON: That is actually
pretty cool.
But I think that you're not
answering my question, and so
I should probably just go.
Thank you.
STEVE SPANGLER: No, no.
It's fine.
I'll answer your question.
I'll answer it.
So here's the answer.
The science of love.
Here's what happens.
Dopamine.
So it's this stuff
that secreted.
It's like do-- and
the receptors--
OK, here.
Watch.
So here, watch this.
Pretend like this
is your brain.
See, your brain's right here.
These are my rusty
ball bearings.
And so this is like
your brain.
And this is a receptor.
And this is like dopamine.
And when you fall
in love, there's
this release of dopamine.
And when it hits those
receptors, bam!
Like that.
It's just psh!
Psh!
It's like fireworks going
off in your brain.
Psh!
I'm in love!
But there's more,
phenylethylamine.
It's a natural amphetamine
that gets
released in your body.
And here, watch.
It's kind of like this mood
that you can set the mood.
You know, like that feeling that
you get, the butterflies
in your stomach.
And it's this love feeling.
That's what it's like.
It's like love.
And that's what gets released
into your body.
And you feel it.
You know how you feel
sick when you're
in love with somebody?
Well, that's that feeling
of that PEA, as the
professionals call it.
But there's more,
noradrenalin.
Now, this is a special
thing that gets
released in your body.
This isn't really it.
It's something else.
But the idea is this, it gets
released in your body and it
gives you that emergency
state.
And by itself, psh,
nothing at all.
But when it gets mixed with the
secretions of the dopamine
and the phenylethylamine,
watch this.
It's crazy!
It's like fire everywhere.
It's like love!
And everybody's in love.
And these things get released.
And there's these other things
that are released, but it
doesn't really matter, because
when you've got
this, you've got fire.
And this lasts, and you'll be in
love for about six months.
And then it all goes away.
And you'd better hope that
football kicks in.
See, but scientists figured
out that after this lust
molecule and fire and everything
is gone, then
something else kicks in called
the cuddle hormone.
And this is what keeps couples
together over the years.
And it's there.
And it's oxytocin.
And it's found in women, and
especially in monogamous
relationships.
They had voles, and they studied
the top part of the
brain and found this high
concentration of the oxytocin.
But vasoprin was found in men.
And so that's how this
monogamous relationship can
kind of keep it going on
for years and years.
Like the marriage counselor
said, it's going to
keep going and going.
But that's kind of-- whatever.
That's the difference.
But that's kind of how you
understand this whole thing.
RAINN WILSON: Wow.
Boom.
Amazing.
Thank you so much, Steve.
That was incredible.
OK.
Now, what does this string do?
STEVE SPANGLER: No, don't
touch the string.
I'm s--
don't.
Don't!
Do not pull the string.
I'm s--
I'm begging you!
Do not--
RAINN WILSON: Sorry
about that.
STEVE SPANGLER: Thanks
for stopping by.
All right.
Somebody's going to have
to clean this up.
Higginsworth!
Higginsworth.