not yet known to us humans,
lived a tiny and complex
creature, Lil Bub.
[INSTRUMENTAL SPACE MUSIC]
One day, Bub decided to leave
her planet and venture off
into the darkness of space.
[INSTRUMENTAL SPACE MUSIC]
[EXPLOSION]
- This is her story.
[INSTRUMENTAL STACCATO MUSIC]
[INSTRUMENTAL FAST-TEMPO
MUSIC]
LARA SPENCER: All right,
here we go.
It is finally time to meet Bub,
a kitten born the runt of
the litter, who is now the
toast of the internet.
Yeah, she's toothless,
stubby-legged, extra-toed and,
perhaps, I dare say, the cutest
cat in the world.
- This is a normal
cat's pelvis.
This is Bub's pelvis.
A normal cat would have nice,
straight bones that have a
darker marrow cavity,
compared to Bub.
There's no marrow cavity, and,
of course, there's no twisting
and deformity of the bones.
[INSTRUMENTAL PASTORAL MUSIC]
- I got Bub, because I thought
she was amazing.
I took her home.
I posted pictures of her
on the internet.
And then that one photo
just, like, blew up.
[CURSOR CLICKING]
- Everything in my life was
really awful, and then it got
pretty cool.
[INSTRUMENTAL SPACE MUSIC]
- There was a lot of cute cat
videos of normal cats doing
cute things.
But, like, this is, like, an
incredibly unique cat doing
weird things.
- If we look at human life
through a cat's eyes, does so
much of what we do
seem futile?
- If there's going to be half a
decade for crazy cat people
to come out of the closet,
then let it be now.
[INSTRUMENTAL SPACE MUSIC]
[INSTRUMENTAL ETHEREAL MUSIC]