TONY VOELLM: Hello.
Good morning.
Welcome to GTAC 2013.
Focus on mobile and media.
Welcome.
I'm Tony Voellm.
I'll be your host the next
two days up here.
So feel free-- you can check me
out anywhere as I'm walking
around-- and ask questions.
I'll be taking you through some
of the fit and finish
here in the beginning about what
we need to do, and how
we're all going to
participate.
So with that, I would like to
start out with a thank you to
our sponsor.
Some of the unsung heroes are
often the people that actually
write the checks.
So here, if you see Asim hanging
around, he's pretty
awesome because he actually
has helped us fund this.
So thank you, Asim.
This conference is being
streamed live.
So welcome to all
the participants
all around the world.
We hope you're enjoying your
coffee shops, couches, beds.
For everybody here,
just a reminder.
This is being recorded.
Your pictures may show up
anywhere at any time.
I believe everybody here signed
a form on your way in.
If you did not, please
do that.
We would love to be able to
use pictures from here, so
just a reminder.
OK, agenda.
I'm going to go through the
agenda pretty fast so we can
get into our talks.
If you like to tweet or g+
about your experience
here, please do.
One note is, this area,
I think, it's
fine to take pictures.
The doors out the side, please
do not go out of those.
Please do not take pictures
through the portal.
And if you see anything that
you're not supposed to see,
please instantly forget it,
and don't take a picture.
Everything else is fair game.
You have to wear your
badges at all times.
You should have two badges.
One is your visitor
badge here.
And then you have an official
building badge.
Tomorrow, to speed things
up, please keep
your Day One badge.
That way we don't have to
recheck your ID and everything
on the way in.
So you'll have to grab a
second day badge here.
We are hosting tours.
At this point, probably
all the tickets
are gone for today.
I'm not sure about tomorrow, but
you can certainly check in
the lobby during the break times
to get a tour of the
office here.
It is a super cool office.
And I'll tell you some details
about it in a minute.
Each talk, we will be doing
a set of questions.
So we have a Dory set up.
Here is the link to
jump on the Dory.
You can vote up or vote
down questions.
Feel free to add
new questions.
We'll also try to take some live
questions as time allows.
Here's the link here.
So go ahead, and you can grab
this, and sort of jump in, and
take a look at the Moderator.
Attendees, at lunch time,
we are going to do some
roundtable discussions.
These are all of you.
Many of you have asked to host
a topic, or a topic table, or
have discussion.
We have very intentionally
offered to bring in all the
smartest people we know.
That would be all of you.
So please join in to
the topic tables.
These are sort of
participatory.
If you jump in a table, it's not
interesting to you, it's
certainly fine to get up and
go to another table.
Nobody will be upset.
It's just everybody is trying
optimize for things that
they're interested in.
Lunch.
I guess dinner is going to be
on the fifth floor today,
which is up in the
Water Tower Cafe.
It's a very cool cafe.
It actually has a water
tower that came from
New York City here.
You can actually sit in
a Water Tower, if
you've never done that.
Any time you are anywhere in
the building, even going up
and down the elevators, please
make sure you have a
Googler with you.
Somebody in one of these
brightly colored shirts, or
maybe you'll see like a
Google badge on them.
This is a workspace for Google,
and so we just need to
make sure that everybody has
a host at all times.
A little bit about the New
York City office here.
This office started in 2000.
It actually started in a coffee
shop, much like many of
the offices for Google.
So thanks to Starbucks for, I
guess, having all these great
places that we can
all go work.
This is the second largest
office internationally.
And a shout out to
my own office,
which is Seattle Kirkland.
I believe we are either the
third or the fourth.
This is a fantastic office.
It encompasses the whole Port
Authority building here.
One thing I wanted to mention
to all of you.
If you hear a giant bang
sometime today--
I highlighted this
on the slide--
there is a elevator that can fit
an 18-wheeler, literally,
in this building.
This building was designed to
drive trucks around it.
Now we just run scooters all
around this building, but
there are trucks right
behind me.
It's actually the elevator
for the 18-wheeler.
Every now and then, you'll
hear the bang.
I just didn't want you to be
surprised if you hear this.
And sometimes, it can even
vibrate the floor.
So just heads up.
It's probably nothing,
if you hear the bang
coming from this direction.
We do take up an entire
city block here.
In fact, we actually
have two parts.
We have this office.
We also have a section across
over towards the Chelsea
Market area.
As you go looking around, you
go out, you can go into the
Chelsea Market.
The whole bottom part is
actually still a market.
That's a fun place
to go visit.
There are lots of different
products here in this office.
Everything from Ads to Google
Drive to Maps and Finance.
Google Cloud is here.
Really, engineers that are
working on the products that
you know and love are all
here in this building.
We also have Marketing,
and Sales, and
Engineering, and Support.
It really takes a big team to
deliver fantastic products.
A little bit about the New
York City culture here.
We have many different
themed cafeterias.
I guess we serve like somewhere
around a million
plus meals a year here
in this office.
It just gives you an
idea of the scope.
We have these great scooters
that we can run up
and down the halls.
Sorry, unless you go on
the tour, you won't
be able to do this.
But I guess if you're on the
tour, you can grab one.
We tried this last night.
I duly impressed my friend.
I took my luggage, and my
bag, and everything.
I dropped it on a scooter, and
we raced across the building,
I think, in about 45 seconds.
The scooters really get us
around this building fast.
We have game rooms and break
rooms all over the place.
You'll see this on the
tour, which is great.
We are definitely a very
diverse company.
We support diversity in
all of its glory.
And so we have lots internal
groups to sort of communicate
and share our thoughts with
everybody, which is fantastic.
I love this a lot
about Google.
A little bit about what
we've done in the
greater New York area.
One of the things we do at
Google is we try to be great
corporate citizens.
And great citizens of the
areas in which we are.
And in this area here, just
late last year, we lit up,
literally, the Chelsea
neighborhood.
I think it's like six city
blocks that we get free Wi-Fi.
So if you're enjoying the free
Wi-Fi when you're out and
about, that's from
Google here.
It should say Google Wi-Fi,
or something like that.
Almost everybody has access.
Internal to the office
here, Google Guest.
But we've done this, and it was
really important to us to
do this around here,
to give the access.
It just wasn't quite
ubiquitous.
In terms of other interesting
things about Google, I think I
lost like 60 cholesterol points,
or something, when I
joined Google.
Previous companies didn't
take my health as
seriously as Google.
When I'm walking around the
office, I have lots of healthy
choices of things to eat.
I still have a lot more work
to do on that front.
Some fun facts about New York.
This is a fantastic city.
If you have not had a chance to
explore, hopefully you've
booked time.
Whether you've lived here your
whole life, whether you just
came in last night-- and
I heard some people
flew in this morning--
this is definitely
a great area.
New York is rich in history.
It has many different markets.
This is the Chelsea
neighborhood.
This was where a lot of the sort
of import-export into the
city happened for a long time.
That's why this building
was called the
Port Authority building.
It was attached to the port.
Some of the fun facts you'll
find around the city.
The Empire State Building,
is an amazing building.
What's interesting about this is
this is the most expensive
elevator ride I've ever
had in my life.
I did not know an elevator could
cost that much, and it
was only like 60 seconds.
But if you get to the top, and
you're brave enough to walk to
the edge, it's a very
interesting experience.
Both the Empire State Building
and the Rockefeller Center
have these spectacular views
from the top of the building.
And you can see all around
the whole city.
It's fantastic.
The Empire State Building was
the world's tallest building
for 40 years.
And then everybody started to
figure out that if you put an
antenna on your building,
you could
get the tallest building.
I don't know if that's sort
of cheating, or not.
A little known fact.
The Oreo cookie was
actually invented
here in New York City.
It was actually invented right
across the street in the
Chelsea Market.
And the ode to the Oreo cookie
is a small plaque that says
the Oreo cookie was
invented here.
So if you do get a chance to
walk across the street today
or tomorrow, you can go
find out where the
Oreo cookie was invented.
It was invented here in 1912.
And I guess they had a bunch
of cream and a bunch of
biscuits, and they were
trying to figure out
what to do with them.
So they mashed them together,
and came up with this iconic
cookie that pretty much, I
think, everybody around the
world knows.
With that, I'm going to hand
this off to Ari Shamash, who's
going to kick us off
with the keynote.
Immediately after the keynote,
we're going to go
into the next talk.
One of things I'm going to do
is between each talk, after
the speaker is finished, I'm
going to come on stage.
As time allows, we'll take the
questions from the Moderator
that you saw there,
the link earlier.
And I will sort of host
the questions.
As we run out of time, we'll
just sort of move on.
But the speakers, I believe, are
all very excited to talk
to all of you.
You can grab them at lunch.
You can grab them at breaks.
They'll generally be around.
Most of them will be around
for the two days.
Some will only be around for
the day that they're here.
So if you do want to grab them,
make sure you try to
grab them on the same
day that they speak.
With that, I'd like to kick it
off, and hand it off to Ari.
All right.
Thank you.
[APPLAUSE]
ARI SHAMASH: Thanks very much,
Tony, for the introduction.
We are four minutes
ahead of schedule.
I am going to do my
best to fix that.
I want to welcome all of
you guys to New York,
to Google New York.
I am from the New York
office here.
I'm part of the test engineering
organization,
specifically with Ads.
But before I get started, I
really want to give a shout
out to our folks from Boston.
Any of you from Boston?
Our prayers and thoughts are
with you guys as you go
through this.
As the city, and me personally,
as the city that
went through 9/11, we completely
understand the pain
that everybody is going through,
and has to endure.
We are right there with you.
Our thoughts are with you.
I'd like to start by telling
you guys a story.
I hope you'll bear with me.
There's quite a few stories
in my presentation.
My story starts in
the mid 1990s.
Just to give you some context
about the mid 1990s, here's
what they look like.
Music was distributed
on disks.
You literally had to carry
a pile of disks around.
Wi-Fi didn't exist.
If you wanted to connect
to the internet, you
had to find a cable.
If you were lucky, you found
one of those blue ones,
because they might actually
give you reasonable
connectivity.
If you were unlucky, you had one
of those beasts over there
called a modem that connected
you to the internet.
You actually had to dial
up to the internet.
You had to wait 45 seconds
before you had conductivity.
If you were even luckier,
you had a cellphone.
You might actually have to get
straps, and strap it onto your
back, because that's what
that thing looked like.
You had to carry it
around, right?
That's what a laptop
looked like.
They had tiny, little screens,
and they had these bricks.
I guess they still have
bricks today.
But they had tiny,
little screens.
If you were lucky, they might
actually be color.
Google, at the time, was just a
figment of imagination in a
couple of grad students.
Here is actually what they
looked like way back when.
For me, I was a software
developer.
I've been a software developer
my entire career.
When I graduated from
school, software
development was quite simple.
You spent a couple of months
collecting requirements from
your customer.
You write them down
in books this big.
Then you spend a couple more
months banging out software.
Then you take all that software,
you take the
requirements, you give it to
some other group, and that
group then spends a few months
validating whether the
software that you built matches
the requirements that
were written, oh,
many months ago.
The fact that something might
have actually changed in those
few months is completely
irrelevant.
You got the requirements.
You built some software.
And if it matches, it matches.
If it doesn't match,
it doesn't match.
We had a customer, financial
services, that wanted to build
a web-based application--
pretty advanced at the time--
in order to take some
data that they had.
Now, this particular company
invested about 100 years
building up their intellectual
property.
Much of it sat on 3"
by 5" index cards.
So the project was to take data
off of 3" by 5" index
cards, stick it onto a database,
and then distribute
it to the world over the web.
They were--
I don't want to say risk averse,
because they were
building an application
that was meant to be
deployed on the web--
but they didn't understand what
sort of application they
wanted to build.
We went up to them and asked
them, OK, what do
you want us to build?
We're happy to build
it for you.
Tell us your requirements.
They turned around and said,
we don't really know.
So we had a project manager at
the time who said, maybe we
should try this thing called
rapid iterations to try to
help the customer understand.
We asked him, what
you mean by that?
What are rapid iterations?
He said, well, let's build
the application.
Let's do a build, and deploy to
some sort of QA, or a user
acceptance environment,
on a weekly basis.
We'll show it to the customer
The customer will tell us
whether they think it's
reasonable or not reasonable,
and then we'll make
adjustments along the way.
This literally blew our minds.
Right?
What are you talking about?
How is it that we're going
to possibly start writing
software without volumes
of documentation?
How are we going to do
quality assurance?
How are we going to know that
we're doing the right thing?
The guy said, don't
worry about it.
Let's just try it, and we'll
see what happens.
All of us thought this was
a pretty neat idea.
So we decided to go for it.
We decided that Thursday night
would be build night.
Nobody leaves the office
until the build is
done on Thursday night.
Friday morning, QA group
comes in, validates it.
Monday, we show it
to the customer.
Customer tells us we're on
the right track, or not.
Repeat.
Sounded pretty easy, right?
So we started.
We banged some code
out for a week.
We get there on Thursday
afternoon.
4:00 or 5:00 o'clock, he
said, OK, let's just
start doing a build.
Let's see what happens.
To make a long story short,
we were there until Friday
morning trying to get the
environment working.
It was a long night.
It took us a couple hours just
to get the code to compile.
It was the first time we
actually built the thing.
Then it took us a couple more
hours to get it working in the
environment.
The environment that we wanted
to deploy into didn't match
the environment that we were
developing against.
All sorts of crazy stuff.
Finally, Friday we sleep.
Monday, we show it
to the customer.
The customer was happy.
All the application did
was log in, log out.
How much could we actually
get done in a week?
The customer was
able to log in.
The customer was able
to log out.
Thumbs up.
We're all good to go.
Right?
The second Monday morning, we,
as an engineering group, got
together and said, look, if
we're going to go through this
every single week, we're never
going to get done.
Actually, the main motivation
is that we all wanted to go
out on Thursday nights.
Like, we had lives, and this
thing was getting in the way
of our lives.
We wanted to go out
Thursday night.
What are we going to do to make
sure that this week is
not going to be a disaster?
We thought, OK, maybe we do
a trial run on Wednesday.
We did a trial run
on Wednesday.
We didn't go out on
Wednesday night.
We were there until midnight
getting the thing to run.
But Thursday night we
had a good time.
Wasn't so bad.
We only had to clean up the mess
that we made on Thursday
rather than cleaning up a
week's worth of mess.
So you can see where this
is going, right?
All of you guys understand
what software development
looks like today.
Rapid iterations, continuous
builds, all that good stuff.
But at the time, it really felt
like we were pioneers in
a brand new industry.
We ended up--
and you guys see the end story
behind all of this--
we ended up launching
the product.
Amazingly, the product is
still there are today.
Hopefully, all the code that I
wrote is long gone, four or
five times over.
That's what it's going to take
to weed the thing out.
But the product is still
there today.
The customer's extremely
happy.
But as importantly, by the end
of the project, we ended up
with an extremely high
development velocity.
From a test perspective, because
we ended up automating
the tests, we ended up
automating the builds.
We ended up automating the
environment creation that was
necessary to deploy our code.
We ended up with an extremely
high development velocity.
At the end, the only quality we
had to worry about was for
the features that we developed
in that particular cycle,
because all of our regression
made sure that we didn't break
anything in the past.
And we also ended up with a
whole bunch of artifacts.
Lots of small tests, a
collection of medium-sized
tests, a handful of manual large
tests that we had to
run, because browser automation
this early
environment virtualization
didn't exist at the time to
enable us to automate
browsers.
But we learned a couple
of things.
First of all, making testing
easy so we, as developers,
could do it was really, really,
really important.
Because then we can build a
feature, write a test for it,
and be done.
We didn't have to wait for
somebody to come along at a
later time to test it for us.
Also what we learned is if you
hold us developers accountable
for the pain associated with
building, deploying, and
testing, we would do the right
thing from the beginning
rather than waiting for somebody
else to come and
clean up our mess.
Fortunately, all the stuff that
we built for this were
skunkworks, shell scripts,
and stuff like that.
All of the artifacts
are long gone.
The artifacts that we built
were unique for that
particular environment.
There was only really
one kind of browser
available at the time.
Really, one kind of operating
system that this
was deployed onto.
So the artifacts that we
built weren't really
useful in the long term.
They were useful for that
particular project.
But the thought process that
went into my mind, something
clicked, right?
Just like it clicked with
many of you guys.
This is the right way
to develop software.
So we really felt like we were
pioneers at the time.
And it's a feeling that I think
I share with many of you
guys that are here
in the audience.
And many of you guys that are
watching this presentation.
We're at the cusp, all of us,
we're at the cusp of something
that was pretty cool.
The industry changed.
A whole new discipline within
computer science evolved.
Something that we, within
Google, call test engineering,
and it proliferated.
It really proliferated over
the last 15 years.
I wasn't the only one.
Many of you guys went through
the same exact evolution at
the same time.
Luckily for me, and for all of
us, many of you also built
artifacts that could be reused
by other projects.
Think of all the technologies
that exist today that we have
available to us to make all
of this stuff work.
Continuous build engine.
Unit test frameworks.
All sorts of desktop and
browser automation
technologies.
Virtualization, which enables
us to build really cheap
environments, and have those
environments be--
you can bring up an instantiate
environment.
You can instantiate
an environment.
You can hydrate it with data.
You can run some tests against
it, then you can destroy that
environment at a relatively
low cost.
Think about all the different
processes that are available
to us today.
Best practices.
Agile.
Dogfooding, something that we do
extensively within Google.
We have the opportunity today to
take an application, deploy
it to production, and make that
new version available to
a small subset of
our audience.
Maybe trusted users.
Maybe 1%.
Maybe only users that are
internal to your company that
can tolerate issues.
Within Google, we call
that dogfooding.
We open up our application, at
least new features in the
application, to a subset of our
audience before we turn
around and expose it to the
to the external world.
That way, if there are issues,
we know about them.
And we expose them only
to a limited audience.
There are also all sorts
of knowledge
and information sharing.
All of you guys are here at
this conference to learn.
The conferences exist about
this particular topic.
That's great.
This is not the only
conference.
There is lots of them.
Lots of mechanisms for
information sharing today.
Books, videos, all sorts
of other things.
Industry.
Many companies like Google, many
of your companies, have
dedicated organizations that
focus on test engineering, and
also focus on moving that
industry forward.
But probably something that I'm
most proud of, and we're
going to hear from some of these
folks today, there's
also an entire realm within
academia that's focused on
test engineering today.
So not only are we, as members
of the industry, focusing on
this particular topic, there's
now a fountain of information,
a fountain of research, a
fountain of students, that are
coming out of universities
having worked on test
engineering full time.
And we've invited several
members of the academia to
come and talk at GTAC this year
to help us understand the
kind of research, the kind of
groundbreaking research that's
happening in universities and
other institutions like that,
that enable the next generation,
the next wave of
information, the next wave of
test engineering to happen.
So just like I felt like a
pioneer many, many years ago,
oh, so last century, right?
We've evolved.
Many of you guys have felt
the same exact thing.
Many of you guys were
at the forefront of
this particular industry.
We've evolved as an industry.
I thank myself that all the
tools that I created for that
particular project
are long gone.
If we had to deal with only the
tools that we built for
that particular project, we'd
never be here today.
So I want to thank the many of
you that also participated in
this particular industry to take
the knowledge, to take
the learnings and
build the tools.
We've really evolved.
We've gone from pioneers to a
well-defined industry that
we're all proud to be
members of today.
So GTAC is a little bit
about sharing as well.
What I'd like to do is share
about how Google goes about
doing test engineering.
We're also going to hear--
there's several talks,
including the one immediately
after mine where you guys get
the opportunity to share about
what test engineering looks
like about your particular
companies.
I'd love to hear that,
but I'll go first.
I'll share what Google is doing
about test engineering,
some of the best practices that
we have in place today,
and some of the challenges that
we face today that I'd
love to see solved.
First, a little bit of
background about what Google
looks like as a company.
Google speed, Google scale--
we have roughly 15,000 engineers
in roughly 40
different offices around the
world at any given time, so
about 5,000 projects under
active development.
We have a single monolithic
source code tree with all
sorts of mixed language, mixed
code, mixed stuff.
100 million lines of code,
roughly 50% of which-- roughly
half of it changes on
a monthly basis.
So it's very active great.
We spent a lot of time actually
curating the source code.
We do a lot of deletes
within Google.
We don't let things rot.
Development happens
at one branch.
There's head, and
there's head.
That's it.
That's all we got.
All submissions are
done at head.
All releases are done at head.
All builds are done at head.
All tests are run at head.
Everything runs at head.
As a result, one of the benefits
is that we don't have
to support 1,000 different
versions of libraries for
different applications.
Everything runs at head.
And I'll talk about the
consequences of that in a
little while.
All the builds are
done from source.
We actually do not pull
in any binary
artifacts into our binaries.
Every single build, straight
to the source.
So even a small build-- actually
in my first day at
Google, or first week at Google,
I built a simple web
server that just responded
through to a request.
I built the thing.
I was expecting the
thing to build--
have a couple of data files, a
couple of .class files done.
Next thing I know, there's
100,000 files that go into
building this thing.
So even the smallest build, as
a result of me building that
web server--
I just want to give a little
bit of context to that.
I picked up advanced
monitoring.
instrumentation.
I picked up advancement
metrics.
A lot of infrastructure that
went into that little web
server just to respond to a
simple request, but that means
that even the smallest builds
can have roughly 100,000
artifacts associated
with them.
It's pretty complicated.
On a given day, we have about
5,500 submissions to the
source code repository,
roughly averaged out.
That's roughly 20 per second,
if we were doing at average
development across a 24-hour
period, which we're not.
So at peak, which roughly
corresponds to about three
minutes before people
go home, we have 60
plus submits per second--
per minute, roughly
one per second.
That translates to about
100 million test
cases run per day.
So that's what Google
looks like.
So I'd like to spend a couple of
minutes talking about what
test engineering at
Google looks like.
There's really two
parts to that.
There are the tools and the
people, but first a little bit
of context.
Google's focus is really
about engineering
productivity as a whole.
The test engineering group or
the discipline is part of this
greater discipline.
So as part of engineering
productivity, we focus on
three things--
developer infrastructure, which
is really about building
tools that every single
developer within Google uses.
It's about test engineering,
which primarily focuses on
test automation, but also is
involved in lots of different
areas, and I'll show you
examples along the way--
and also release engineering,
which focuses on building
tools and optimized
processes--
repeatable processes--
for getting information
out the door.
But our mission is
pretty simple.
We want to develop it, build it,
test it, release it, and
measure it--
better, faster, stronger.
Throw in all your favorites
superlatives there.
So first let me start with
the build system itself.
The longer, the better--
that's kind of a bad thing if
you look at things from a
developer productivity.
We want to avoid
this scenario.
So Google's build system is
really optimized for a whole
bunch of different things, but
primarily performance.
So what we do for performance
is parallelize as much as we
can all the builds.
First thing we do when somebody
does a build is
analyze all the dependencies,
what can run in parallel.
Then we send those requests off
to our cloud, which has
not thousands and thousands and
thousands of machines just
standing by waiting to receive
orders to build information--
massive performance.
We can get to roughly 60 files,
we average about 57
actions every second
on a 24-hour
basis through our cloud.
We also optimize for
correctness.
Make clean is a bug.
You should never have
to make clean.
If you have to make clean,
there's a bug
in the build system.
There's something that's
not defined.
not declared.
There's something that's
incorrect.
Our build system imposes that
correctness on on everything
that we do.
Incrementality also fits in.
We want to do the least
amount of work.
That has two consequences.
First, we want to figure out the
least amount of work that
needs to be done for that
particular developer.
That's pretty well understood,
and all the build systems
around the industry do that.
But we also want to make sure
that across Google as an
enterprise, we do the least
amount of work.
That means if my colleagues over
in the other side of the
world-- let's say
Mountain View--
have done a built at a
particular revision.
And I then do a build of that
same revision, and the same
file, same target here
in New York.
I should not have to repeat
the compilation.
They built it.
I should be able to reuse it.
So our cloud actually caches the
output of all the builds,
and I benefit from somebody
else's build of the same
target at that same revision.
We also want to simplify use
by developers, so our build
system is multi-functional.
I can build a file.
I can run that particular
target.
I can test that target.
I can run source code coverage
for that particular target.
And then I can do a dependency
analysis on that particular
target, all using the same
commands, just by changing
arguments-- the same
basic command.
I don't have to go and
do crazy things.
The same applies for
multi-language.
I, as a builder, don't have to
know whether it's a Java
target, a Python target, a shell
target, a C++ target, a
JavaScript target.
I want to just run the test
against it, I run that target
and I run the tests
against it--
pretty simple, pretty
powerful.
There's lots of talks, and I've
provided these URLs that
go into a lot more detail
about our build system.
Feel free to go check
them out.
Some performance numbers about
our build system--
this talks about
incrementality.
About 90% of our builds run
less than 20 seconds.
It's only when you get in the
90th percentile and higher do
our builds take a lot longer
than that, because the caching
doesn't kick in.
You're building something
from scratch
that nobody else built.
Our cache--
anywhere from 89% to 98%
effective, depending on what
you want to do.
There are actually two levels
of caches, one on my local
workstation--
so if I run two builds in a row,
my second build leverages
the first build.
I don't have to go back to the
cloud to download all that
information.
But let's say the first time
around, I run my build.
89% of the time, I will be
leveraging off of somebody
else's build.
The great part-- and I'll talk
about the continuous build
engine-- our continuous engine
is sitting there building
stuff at every single change.
I as an individual developer
can take advantage of the
cache that's been primed by our
continuous build system.
Build performance over time
has also decreased, even
though the amount of code we've
typically have to build
has increased.
This is a direct result
of test engineering--
or just straight up
engineering--
against the build system to make
it more efficient, better
analysis of dependencies,
better analysis of
parallelization, but also just
plain old faster computers
that we can run our
builds against.
We talk a little bit about
test execution.
Just like builds, tests also
happen in extreme parallel.
So if a particular test suite
has four test cases-- as this
one does, this example does--
we'll run all four of
them in parallel.
More so, we'll actually start
the execution of tests as soon
as the build for that particular
test is done.
So if test one, test two, test
three, and test four need to
be built, if test four--
the build for test four gets
done first, the execution for
test four will start first.
If test four fails, we don't
even bother waiting for the
other three to report in.
Test four fails, therefore the
entire test suite fails.
We report that right away
so the developer can
start taking action.
And this might actually happen
before test one, test two, and
test three even finish
building.
Our continuous build system ties
these two tools together.
Widely adopted within Google,
there's one continuous build
system that accounts for the
vast majority of all the
builds that we have
within Google.
This is what its user interface
looks like.
There's two key components of
this continuous build system
that I'd like to talk about.
First is the before and after
submit test abilities, and the
second one is about flaky
tests and the
consequences thereof.
The first one is actually
really key.
Like I learned in my first
project, if you make it really
easy for developers to run
tests, and hold them
accountable to that, they will
run tests and check code
that's actually correct
into the repository.
You don't have to find
out about after.
So our continuous
build system has
what's known as a presubmit.
I can take some code that I'm
sitting and editing on my
workstation, hand it over
to the continuous build
environment and say, take this,
merge it in with the
last known green, and tell me
whether I'm going to break the
build or not.
That's great.
I don't have to set up my
workstation in any special way
to make test running possible.
It's just a generic
workstation.
It's going to be running my
code, and changes are going to
be running in the same exact
environment that the
continuous build engine uses to
determine whether tests are
correct or not correct.
So that's fantastic.
We actually take that to an
even more extreme level.
As soon as code is submitted
for a code review within
Google, the code review process
not only sends it to a
human being-- another human
being to go take a look at,
but it also sends it
to the continuous
built system to evaluate.
We don't wait for the
developer to ask the
continuous build system
whether the code's OK.
We just do it proactively.
So roughly the same amount of
time, likely maybe even
faster, they'll hear
from their peer in
terms of a code review.
Your code looks good.
Your code is horrible, throw
it out, start from scratch.
Or anywhere in between.
You'd also hear back from the
continuous build system--
your tests pass, your tests
fail, anywhere in between.
What tests fail, what
the logs are--
they'll get notification.
They'll also get a great email,
and this was a tool
that was built by my colleagues
over in Zurich.
They'll get an email that says,
your incremental code
that you just added only
has 23% test coverage.
For example, I picked
23% out of a hat.
So we do incremental
test coverage--
source code coverage right there
dynamically on behalf of
the user in an attempt--
and I'll be nice-- in an
attempt to notify the
developer about what level
of coverage their
incremental code has.
OK, I'll stop being nice.
It's really about shaming them
into believing that they
should be writing more
tests for stuff
that they're writing.
But they get this stuff
all proactively.
It's right there.
And the code reviewer
also sees it.
So here's an incentive for the
developers, right off the bat,
to do the right thing.
Our continuous build system
also handles fine grade
dependencies.
That's one way of lowering
compute costs for us.
Like I said, 100 million
tests a day.
That's pretty expensive
to run all of them.
We only run the tests that
are actually necessary.
We know all the dependencies
through the build system.
We know what test is impacted
by what particular change.
We'll only run the tests that
are appropriate for that
particular change.
Flaky tests--
endless pain for us,
flaky tests.
Flaky test is defined
as a test that is
non-deterministic.
Given a fixed environment,
particular revision of code,
particular set of changes, you
run the test numerous times,
and the test gives you
different results.
There are lots of possibilities
for what causes
flaky tests--
environmental issues, code
issues, test code issues
itself, et cetera.
You can imagine if there's a
routine that returns a random
number, and the unit test that
tests it tries to check that
the number is below a particular
threshold.
Well, maybe if it's testing a
50-50, it will pass half the
time and fail half the time.
So, non-deterministic flaky
tests are shown in this
particular display by the
scattering of reds.
By the way, the solid line of
red, that's a failure that was
submitted by a particular
user.
That's the second to last
row from the bottom.
But the miscellaneous reds that
you see there are all
flaky tests.
They're tests that are
non-deterministic.
Why is this a problem?
Well, first of all, if the
developer's making a change,
and they submit their change
into the presubmit queue and
the presubmit queue fails, the
developer does not know
whether it was the change that
they introduced, or if it was
a flaky test that caused that
particular failure.
Worst case, they go and they
start trying to find out
what's going on within their
code that caused this
particular problem.
We would love to be 100% correct
around tests passing
and failing, because that would
enable us to go to the
next level of automation.
If we detect a failure,
we reject.
We roll back the submit.
That would be fantastic.
But we can't do that, because
of flaky tests.
So we do three things.
Our build system keeps track
of flaky information.
And that particular tool was
built by my colleagues over in
London to measure, understand,
and present back to the
developers the level of
flakiness associated with a
particular test.
It's pretty easy to see the
different patterns with flaky
tests as opposed to
real failures.
So we do statistical analysis
and try to come up with some
particular numbers.
We try to get the developers
to fix them.
So by letting them know their
tests are flaky, by shaming
them into letting them know that
they're tests are flaky,
we get the developers
to fix them.
If we can't, we do the least
popular thing, and we just
retry tests over and over and
over again until we determine
that the test is flaky,
or we determined
that the test is OK.
We look for a pass.
As you can imagine, as I showed
before, our submits
into the source code repository
are not uniform
over a 24-hour period.
So we can take advantage of
the overnight hours to do
incremental source
code computation
for all of our projects.
We also do extra analysis of
flaky tests overnight.
So that's our continuous
build system.
Some statistics about it--
number of submits per day.
A CL within Google is
called a changelist.
It corresponds to a particular
change that was committed into
our repository.
Linear growth over time--
that's fantastic.
We hire more developers.
More developers write
more code.
We have more submits
over time.
The good news is that those
developers are not only
writing code.
They're writing tests.
So the number of seconds that we
need to use to compute code
test runs for every single
submit is also
going up over time.
That's fantastic.
Developers are writing
more tests.
For any given change,
we run more tests.
We're happy to do that.
But I have kids that are going
through geometry today, so I
understand this.
When you take a straight line,
multiply it by a straight
line, you end up with
a quadratic.
Quadratics are bad.
There is no way-- even with
all the data centers that
Google has, there is no way that
we at Google can keep up
quadratic growth across
all of our test cases.
I remember we actually
had a conversation.
Our developer tools group had
a conversation with our data
center people.
They went up to them and
they said, we need more
machines to run tests.
The data center people,
being data center
people, were quite blunt.
They said, you have
a choice to make.
You can run your tests.
We have enough computers
to run your tests.
We'll have to shut down all the
production applications.
You guys OK with that?
Tests or production?
What do you guys want to do?
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
ARI SHAMASH: Yeah.
So that's where we are today.
We are heavily applying
engineering to solve a brute
force problem.
This is a theme that comes up
over and over and over again,
and I've seen this over the
last 15 or 20 years.
When you can apply brute force,
the easiest thing to do
is apply brute force.
But brute force times
out after a
certain amount of time.
You just can't scale.
You have to start thinking about
better ways of doing
things, and that's what
we're doing today.
So maybe we don't run the tests
at every single change.
We run them periodically, and
then we'll run all sorts of
interesting culprit finding to
try to figure out where in
between that the breakage was.
There's actually a talk tomorrow
about culprit finding
within Google.
So let me talk a little bit
about the people, the people
that make this all happen
within Google.
There are two roles--
SETs and TEs--
within the test engineering
group at Google.
We within testing engineering
do a handful of things.
We create processes and plans
that would help test a
particular product.
We think of best ways to
maximize coverage.
But we also are highly involved
in building a lot of
the tools that I talked about.
In fact, many of the tools that
I demonstrated were built
by the test engineering
folks here at Google.
I'll show you guys
some examples.
There are some links that
you can go to to
read more about this.
First one, probably making up
roughly 50% of what we do, is
really focused on flaky tests.
I described earlier the problems
with flaky tests.
They're a huge cost, and they're
a huge time sink.
How do you eliminate
flaky tests?
You build hermetic environments
you can
run your tests in.
Hermetic environments are
self-isolated environments.
Instantiated tests
are run against
them, and then deleted.
The more hermetic they are, the
less external dependencies
they are, the better.
The cheaper it is to create that
environment, the faster
the tests will run.
So a lot of the engineering that
we do is about building
consistent, reproducible,
hermetic environments, so we
can run multiple of those
environments and run tests at
the same time.
For a typical application, we
might be running 5, 10, 15, 20
instances of that application at
any given time in parallel
with different revisions of
source code being tested
against that application.
That's pretty common.
We need separate environments
that don't interact with one
another and don't interfere
with all the testing
that goes on there.
So that's roughly 50% of the
time what we do, and there's a
link over there that has
more information.
Another one is metrics.
If you can't measure it, you
can't really understand it or
control it.
So we try to measure lots
of interesting things.
We're Google.
We love data.
We collect lots of interesting
data and present it to
developers as a way, again, to
get the engineering groups to
the right thing.
And when I talk about
developers, I actually mean
us, because we're developers
as well.
So we collect metrics for test
engineering, in addition to
collecting metrics on the
developer engineers--
or the product engineers, the
developers on products.
First one-- and I'll kind of go
around the slide, starting
with the upper left
hand corner.
This is positive reinforcement
about
incremental source code coverage.
This was built by my colleagues
in London.
They had this idea that for
every single submit, we'd
measure the incremental
source code coverage.
And if it's good source good
coverage, we'd give credit to
the person who submitted it.
So here it is.
We have these lookout
displays scattered
all around the offices.
If any of you guys are going
on tours, look around.
There's a whole a handful
of them around the
fourth floor here.
They're constantly being
refreshed with update metrics.
So that's an example
of econometrics
that we put up there.
These lookout displays scroll
through lots of different
information.
If a person does a great job
with incremental source code
coverage and they submit a
change that's got high
coverage, they get their
picture up there.
It's right there in the middle,
nice and big with lots
of green around it.
The group that this was deployed
into started a
friendly competition of who
can get the highest green,
most number of greens, get their
face up there as often
as possible.
Fantastic.
Loving it.
This utility alone raised
source code coverage for
applications by a significant
amount.
Bottom left hand corner
is latency metrics.
So we measure constant
performance of application,
make that information
available.
We don't wait until the
application is in production
to find out that significant
performance problems
are about to hit.
We measure.
We show it.
We move on.
We also show build status, and
that's that green Project X
status that passed today,
last timestamp, whatnot.
There are some groups, who shall
remain nameless, that
don't adhere to the--
or don't respond to the positive
reinforcement that's
on the top left hand corner.
We had a problem with a
particular group where non
high priority bugs, like the
P3s and P4s were piling up.
And the group was just not
motivated to go and fix them.
So we brainstormed about this.
We tried all the positive
reinforcement--
giving them kudos for fixing
bugs, rewarding them,
recognizing them, doing
all the good things.
Didn't make a difference.
So we went the other way--
public shame, humiliation.
We put this utility together.
We need it black on purpose--
black is ugly--
with lots of red around
it-- accusatory, put
up the worst offender.
We were sitting there
in the morning.
A bunch of us were
sitting there.
It was nice and quiet.
We were sitting there
typing away.
The next thing we know,
somebody comes in.
And I'll give you the G rated
version, because GTAC is a
family-friendly sort
of of conference.
Why is my picture up there?
Comes up to us-- why is
my picture up there?
It was a lot more colorful.
You had a lot of bugs.
What do I do to get my picture
out from there?
Go fix your bugs.
The entire day, we hear furious
typing, lots of
banging, lots of other
choice words.
Picture disappears by
late afternoon.
Next thing we know, why is my
picture up there, from the
second person who's up.
You have lot of bugs.
Go fix them.
Needless to say, a few weeks
after that, problem solved.
So in the summary, for test
engineering, we really look
for creative ways to introduce
cultural change so things are
done correctly right up front
with our developing groups.
So the impact of test
engineering--
and you know we're not
in with every single
product within Google.
There's only about 800, 900 of
us or so against a population
of 15,000 engineers.
So we're not engaged with
every single group.
But the groups that we do engage
with, first of all, are
really happy to have test
engineering support.
But we also have demonstrable
impact.
For example, Google+--
100 new features released
in the first 90 days.
That's roughly, on average,
more than a release a day.
Search, we can go from an idea
to production in 48 hours--
less than 48 hours.
And Chrome-- the browser--
six weeks, regular schedule,
[INAUDIBLE].
That's the impact of
test engineering.
I also want to pause
at this point.
I know Tony addressed this.
But really, it's test
engineering, the discipline of
test engineering within Google,
that sponsors this
conference year in
and year out.
There's lots of volunteers
from the test engineering
discipline that help put
it together this year.
And the test engineering
discipline funds
it year over year.
So I want to say thank you to
the various members that
organized this conference, and
the various individuals and
executives that form test
engineering, but also made
this particular conference
happen.
So now it's your turn.
Over the next couple of days,
we're going to hear many of
your presentations about what
test engineering at your
particular companies
looks like.
Maybe you call it something
different.
Love to hear the names.
We'd love to hear your
best practices.
We'd love to hear
your challenges.
What can we learn from
each other to
improve all of our practices?
So I have a question.
Are we done?
Are we done with test
engineering?
Here we were 15, 20 years ago.
We clearly had a lot
of work to do.
We were all pioneers in
a brand new space.
Are we done?
We kind of have awesome tools.
All this stuff works.
We're able to develop
software.
So the question that I have--
are we about coffee?
Do we need to hunker down and
drink more coffee, and
continue engineering
[INAUDIBLE]
test engineering?
Or is it about beer?
Do we pick up some beer now?
Samuel Adams-- again,
a shout out to my
friends over in Boston.
Fantastic beer.
Should we grab some beer and
go celebrate, be done?
Are we done with this particular
discipline?
I think the answer is no.
As much as I would love to get
together and drink some
beers-- it's only about 10
o'clock in the morning.
It's a little early.
We're not in Ireland.
Coffee is still good.
But we have a lot of work to
do, because the world is
changing underneath us.
And that's really why many
of us are here today.
Let's take some statistics
from YouTube.
72 hours of video are
uploaded every
single minute to YouTube.
Four billion hours of
videos are watched
every single month.
While developers are sitting
there watching videos while
they're waiting for their
build systems.
2011--
more than one trillion views--
140 views for every single
person on the earth.
That's even assuming that every
single person on the
earth has internet access.
Most interestingly, 70% of the
traffic comes from outside the
United States.
That's on the media side.
On the mobile side, 25% of
traffic to YouTube comes from
mobile devices.
So I started thinking about
this and said, is this is
really a problem?
That's great.
That's great that YouTube has
all these fantastic statistics
showing the change.
Is this a problem?
So I looked at various different
sources on the web.
The source for this particular
graph is up there.
Mobile versus desktop
traffic--
desktop is that 85%.
Mobile is at 15%.
We all apply the 80-20 rule.
I don't know.
This looks to me like
we're kind of done.
We figured out the desktop.
We figured out how all of its
issues with the desktop.
We know how to mock out
all of its inputs.
all of its output.
We know how to analyze
the output.
We have image comparison.
We have great tools for
understanding of applications
that are working well.
It looks like we're done.
Then Eric Schmidt--
former CEO, current chairman
of Google--
and his buddy Jared Cohen wrote
a book-- it was actually
just published today.
I got my copy yesterday.
Fortunately I got a chance to
read through some of it--
called "The New Digital Age,"
that talks about some of the
changes that are under foot.
And I'd like to tell you
a little bit about it.
And the first thing he says is
that there's only about two
billion people that are
on the internet today.
But he predicts that in the next
few years, five billion
more-- the incremental--
will come online.
And he's seeing some early
indicators that this is true.
First, he visited
Iraq in 2009.
The first thing he noticed in
this war ravaged country,
trash wasn't picked up.
Reliable water was not evenly
available across the country.
The first thing that they got
up and running, one of the
highest priority items in Iraq,
was getting a mobile
network so they can exchange
information from one another.
One of the first things that
they got up and running.
Like to tell you about another
story in Africa, again, as he
was traveling the world.
In the Congo fishermen--
actually, fisherwomen--
fish.
They used to take their
fish to the market.
If they were lucky,
they sold them.
If they were unlucky, the fish
went bad, they threw them out.
Using mobile devices,
they actually leave
the fist in the river.
They catch the fish, but they
leave them in the river until
they have a customer ready
to pick them up.
They receive notification
on their mobile device.
They take a fish out
of the water.
They give it straight
to the customer.
No loss in inventory, maximize
their opportunity.
And this actually created
a semi-economy there, if
somebody has fish that another
fisher person wants, they can
now exchange it among themselves
using mobile
technology.
Lots of interesting stories.
So are we done?
Again, is Eric right?
So I started looking to more
data, and this one, again, the
source is on the bottom.
74% of the developed world is
already using the net, but
only 26% of the developing
world is using the net.
And if you average it out
relative to population, the
average is 35%.
Much closer to the developing
world line than the developed
world because there's a lot more
people in the developing
world that still have
to get connected.
So let's revisit these graphs
again looking at them from
different geographical
perspectives.
Let's take South Korea.
South Korea is highly advanced,
but the story there,
desktop versus mobile, tells
a very different story.
Much closer to 60-40 than
it is worldwide.
Let's take another step
and look at India.
The story in India is
radically different.
There's a lot more mobile stuff
going on than there is
desktop stuff, and this
trend is only
going to continue growing.
So mobile's already
here today.
It's something that we have
to address today.
There's lots of challenges with
media and mobile, and
I'll run through them.
Platforms.
Tremendous amount of variability
in platforms.
Lots of hardware, lots of
different operating systems.
The operating systems themselves
may not be as
stable as you would
love them to be.
And unlike on the web where I
as an application developer
had complete control of the
stack, top to bottom, in my
production environment,
that's no longer true
on the mobile side.
If I'm an app developer, I now
have to deal with other
applications that are on the
device-- my application, the
operating system, all sorts of
different combinations and
permutations that
are going on.
The hardware is different, the
platforms are different.
Input.
There's no longer just
a keyboard and mouse.
There's tremendous amount of
variability in input these
days across all the
different devices.
There are cameras.
There are GPS receivers.
There's touchscreen.
There's gestures.
There's physical buttons.
There's voice recognition.
You can tell the device
what to do.
On the output side, there's
all sorts of devices.
Resolutions, languages, all
sorts of issues around that.
Also the network is no
longer consistent.
The same application that's
running on the web, at least
you can assume that if the
application is running, you
can talk back home.
It managed to get downloaded
somehow.
Offline is getting better and
better every single day.
But really, how many desktops
are offline?
Mobile is no longer true.
The same application that's
running can experience, within
minutes, lots of network, no
network, medium network,
network bandwidth, network
latency, all sorts of the
variability on the network side
that have to be dealt
with in some sort of
interesting way.
On the media side, the
variability in
quality is as high.
Codex, will this media work
on this particular device?
Will it work well?
Will it stream?
Will it be real time?
How do I understand
video quality?
Any of you have taken compressed
videos and looked
at them image by image, you'll
see that the images are
radically not good.
But that's OK, because our
brain does a great job of
taking a sequence of them and
putting them together.
Sound.
Our ears are not as forgiving.
If there's a pop in the noise,
instantly our brains will
determine that this is bad.
Software delivery mechanisms
have changed.
We now have to, again, go back
to the world where we're
downloading software.
We're allowing the user to
download software, and if we
want to release a new version,
we no longer can do it
instantaneously and give
access to all of our
developers.
We have to wait for the
developer to download it.
So again, we have to deal with
multiple, different versions
at the same time.
Worse, there's now an
intermediary between
our users and us.
The app stores are there.
Security, privacy.
We have to go back to a world
where malware, and viruses,
and all these other things
are at play.
Also device sharing
is at play.
So these are all
the challenges.
And again, I feel like we're
pioneers again, coming back to
be same feeling that I had
when I started my little
adventure in the 1990s.
I feel like we're
about to begin
on a brand new adventure.
We're all pioneers in this brand
new industry, having to
solve roughly similar problems
that we solved many, many,
many moons ago.
All of us collectively have
to solve them, but
in a brand new space.
And if we think mobile and media
are it today, the next
generation of devices
is upon us.
You got one of these guys.
We have to worry, how
do you test this?
It's a whole new challenge.
The number of inputs that are
available to this particular
device are enormous.
Cars.
How do you test cars with all
their inputs and outputs and
all the decisions that
they get to make?
And all the other devices?
So I'd like to close by saying
all of us are pioneers.
All of us are in this
adventure together.
Let's put on our
thinking caps.
Let's share, let's
collaborate.
Coffee.
Beer later, but coffee now, and
figure out what the next
wave of test engineering is
going to look like for these
new devices, both for the
media and for the mobile
devices today, and for the next
generation devices tomorrow.
Same sort of adventure that many
of us have gone through
starting on the desktop.
Let's take all of our thinking
for the desktop and apply it
for all this new world.
Thank you very much.
I hope you enjoy this
conference.
[APPLAUSE]
TONY VOELLM: Wow.
That was a fantastic, Ari.
Thank you for that.
I learned some really important
things in this talk.
One is Ari is going around
taking pictures of people
sleeping at their desk.
You're see that.
So watch out.
If you're sleeping, he may
take your picture.
ARI SHAMASH: But not me.
I never sleep at my desk.
TONY VOELLM: And the other thing
I noticed in his graphs
is there's a quadratic decrease
in productivity at
Google right around January.
2 Who would figure this?
End of December, January.
So hopefully, all you've got
some really good notes.
I joke around about these
things, but there are a lot of
great thoughts in here, and a
lot about the challenges that
are going to be there going
forward and all the problems
that we need to solve.
That's what all of
you are here.
If you're not spending time
during the breaks talking to
each other, you're not getting
the most out of this
opportunity.
So we really want everybody
here to be talking to
everybody else, so
please do that.
Two quick things.
We have transcribers that
are over in this corner.
Everybody's done a great job not
standing between where I
am and over there.
Just be cognizant, please
don't do that.
Otherwise they can't get the
transcription correct.
And we also have somebody
signing over
here, which is great.
So thank you.
Hopefully I just didn't
have some bad word or
something like that.
I think that's thank you.
I grew up near Gallaudet
College, so I
picked up a few things.
And with that, we're going to
move on into our next speaker.
So we have James Waldrop
here from Twitter.
He tells me that he is
an avid kayaker.
He likes to kayak at night
mostly because his kids are
sleeping then, which I can
very much appreciate.
I get to walk the dog somewhere
around midnight, so
that's something that we
definitely share in common.
And even though I'm not going to
explain to you why, if you
want to go out to moderator, you
should put this question
in there about why is his
product labeled "Lago?"
Because he loves this question,
that's what I heard.
So with that, James, come on up,
and we're excited to hear
about your talk, Testing
Systems At Scale.
JAMES WALDROP: Thank you.
[APPLAUSE]
JAMES WALDROP: Thanks, Tony.
Let's see, yes, the product.
It's really an open
source library.
I try not to basically say too
much about it, except clearly
at presentations like this.
It's actually called Iago, with
an I. The font used for
these presentations is sans
serif, so please keep that in
mind as you look at the name
of it, because I constantly
get questions about Lago, and
people who are clearly using
sans serif fonts are looking at
this going, OK, that's an
L. It's not an
L. It's an I. Anyway.
So, I joined Twitter about two
years ago, a little more.
And when I joined Twitter, my
first week we had an outage
where the site was not
available to users.
And the experience for
the users was this.
And this is not a great
experience for your user if
you care about actually keeping
your service up,
although it's an amusing
picture.
People love to make fun of it.
Clearly, if you're an engineer
who works at Twitter, this is
a very sad face image.
You do not want to have this
showing up, and your mother
calling you and saying, hey,
your system's down.
So how do we get rid
of the Fail Whale?
In the last couple years, we've
gone a long way towards
getting rid of it, and I'm
basically going to talk about
how we do that at Twitter.
Specifically, if anybody really
wants to know the
meaning of it, Fail Whale is
a 502 HTTP response code.
If it takes more than five
seconds to render your request
or to respond to your request,
then we will serve you a Fail
Whale instead.
And so that gives you an idea
of exactly what's going on
behind the scenes when
you see that.
It's not a great story.
So why the Fail Whale?
I'm sure there are quite a lot
of Ruby advocates in the world
and in this room, and a lot
of the systems at Twitter
famously were built on
top of Ruby on Rails.
I'm not going to say anything
bad about Ruby.
I will say, though, that when
you have a monolithic
architecture that has all been
written in one big blob of
code, effectively, then it
becomes very hard to
effectively manage that code,
both in terms of its
performance and in terms
of its ability to
make changes to it.
So the Ruby world has a lot of
interesting ways to achieve
performance these days at the
scale that we care about, and
unfortunately, we really
couldn't do any of them
because of our monolithic body
of code that wasn't able to be
iterated on in a
reasonable way.
The answer to that, of course,
was to decompose it.
And so at this point, I think
we have something along the
order of about 120 services
in production.
So we've taken this monolithic
body of code over the course
of the last two years and turned
it into a lot of little
services which are written in
many different languages,
including many on the Java
Virtual Machine, Java Scala,
Closure, and then also some
written in things like Python,
C++, and still Ruby.
But now that it's decomposed,
we can make
changes to it more quickly.
Our engineering organization
of, hey, I'm going to build
this particular area of the
product, and you're going to
build this area over here,
actually is able to work that
way because they have their
own services that they can
deploy, and this guy over here
has his own services that he
can deploy.
And so they can work relatively
independently of
each other.
The problem with this, as
anybody who's maybe gone
through this or if you think
really fast, you might realize
that there's an issue here,
which is that as you move from
this monolithic world to a
service-oriented world,
testing becomes a
huge problem.
Because in order to test any
given piece of software to
find out if it can handle
production load, you need to
be able to stand up that
whole environment.
And in the case of Twitter and
in the case of, for instance,
the previous Talk Google, that's
probably close to if
not impossible.
And so how do we test
in this new world?
How do you test systems at scale
when any one service
might depend on 20 downstream
services, and they in turn
depend on another 20 downstream
services.
In told, if you want to stand up
any front end environment,
you're probably going to have to
stand up 80 of those 120 or
whatever number of services
we have in production.
The rest of this talk
will be about
synthetic, artificial load.
Clearly, I wanted to give kind
of a front page shout out to
all the other ways that we have
to test performance, but
I will say that all of them
are in production.
And I don't know about people in
this room, but personally,
I feel like if I'm testing it
in production, and my users
can experience pain or I can
take the system down, let's
say, in production, then that's
probably too late to be
testing it.
And I really want to test it
before any of that can happen.
But the techniques that we have
to test in production, as
far as performance goes,
are canaries.
Canary, if you're not familiar
with the concept, you have a
cluster of systems that
are handling requests,
maybe 1,000 of them.
You deploy your new version of
software to one of them, and
now it's taking 1% of the
traffic, and you get to see,
hey, is it getting better
or worse as
compared to the old system?
Clearly, though, it's taking
production traffic.
There's dark traffic.
This is a little safer.
It is basically a system--
and we use
this heavily at Twitter--
we have a front end
called TFE.
Funny name, right?
TFE will take traffic, and then
if it's configured in
such a way as to do this, it
will send all of the traffic
to the normal production
systems, and it will copy,
send a second request, to a
system that's not stood up yet
and whose response it's
going to throw away.
But now users aren't affected
unless, for instance-- this
has happened, sadly--
the system that it's sending the
traffic to doesn't respond
in a reasonable amount of
time, and TFE isn't
necessarily configured
correctly in
order to handle that.
Let's say, pretend that this
might not have happened six
months ago.
And lo and behold, you have an
outage caused by dark traffic.
And then the final one is more
interesting to people who are
doing functional testing.
Tap compare is the ability to
do a dark traffic read or a
dark traffic write, like I just
described, but compare
the results and make sure that
the software you're about to
stand up actually sends the same
content as the software
that you have in production
today.
And with that said, I'm not
going to talk anymore about
testing in production.
Well, I will, but only in
a scary, inappropriate
way, but it's fun.
So what did I do?
I joined, like I said,
two years ago.
I was in the Performance
Engineering Group at
Salesforce.
I came to Twitter specifically
to try to solve this problem
as far as performance goes, and
I wrote a load generator.
A load generator internally
is called Parrot.
It turns out, though, that
there are any number of
trademarks associated with
Parrot, including most
unfortunately the Parrot
VM that Perl
6 will run on someday.
When we open sourced it, I
couldn't call it Parrot, so
it's called Iago.
I actually had no idea that Iago
was this bird that you
see up here.
I'm too old to have
seen "Aladdin." I
crowd sourced the name.
I said I can't call
it Parrot, guys.
What should I call it?
A bunch of people wrote back,
and the one that got the most
votes was Iago.
I'm like, Shakespeare?
I don't get it, but OK.
Sure, it got a lot of votes,
and then I found out it was
"Aladdin."
So why did I need to write
a load generator?
There are a lot of load
generators out here.
I've used most of--
I'm not going to say all of
them, but I've used a lot of
load generators in
my lifetime.
I've used JMeter.
I've used LoadRunner.
I've used ab.
I've used Flood.
I'm not going to go through the
full list, but I've used a
lot of them.
So why did I feel
like I needed to
write a new load generator?
First of all, a lot of coded
Twitter is written in Scala.
I wanted learn Scala.
I had written some toy
projects in it.
And so I was like, hey, wait.
What's the best way to
learn a language?
You write some piece of code
that you already know how to
write in this new language.
That'll be great.
Sure, that's an awesome reason
to invent a new load
generator, right?
Another reason is that, you
know, do you ever get this
sort of thing like if I'm not
actually doing engineering
that the other engineers
won't respect me.
So it's like if I just bring
in JMeter or I bring in
LoadRunner, and I start running
load against their
system, I'm not going to get
nearly as much credit or
respect in the organization as
if I wrote my own, right?
[LAUGHTER]
JAMES WALDROP: So, yeah.
Another reason.
Hey, all those other
load generators,
sorry, guys, you suck.
There's really no reason
to use any of them.
They're all bad, clearly.
I hope the answer is obvious.
None of the above.
But when it comes to load
generators, I have done this
three times before
I got to Twitter,
and then did a fourth.
And I open sourced it,
so hopefully I never
have to do it again.
But I really want load
generation to be simple, and I
have a lot of experience
when it's not
simple of what happens.
And what happens is that you
end up with very large
performance engineering teams,
and they're very
hard to hire onto.
It's a very specialized skill.
And so you're sitting there
constantly trying to scramble
and figure out is it
going to scale?
Is it going to scale?
And you don't have people
to answer the question
why or if it will.
And you don't have enough people
to answer the question
why won't it when it doesn't.
So if you're an engineer, as
I've been, and you want to
answer this question, will my
new service, new whatever,
feature, gizmo that I'm about
to ship to production, is it
going to scale?
Can it handle a million QPS?
How do you go out and do that?
You sit down in front
of your computer.
You're an engineer,
and guess what?
You write a for loop.
Right?
So a for loop-- if anybody's not
ever written one, I really
hope that all of you have--
sits there.
You write a for loop.
Let's see, I think I
have a piece of it.
Yep, there we go.
So that's a for loop.
We're going to start up 100
threads, and we're going to
make requests as fast as we can
against whatever service
it is that we have stood up.
And apologies, this was not code
reviewed, so it may not
be actually compiling, but it's
my sort of theoretical,
abstract for loop.
And any load generator that
you're going to use had
probably better be able to
be better than this.
If it's not better than this,
then the engineer is just
going to sit down, and they're
going to do it themselves,
because this takes five minutes
to write, if that.
So that is if you're writing a
load generator or you're in
that business, you had better
outperform the for loop.
Unfortunately, though, at least
if you're an engineer,
the for loop is really
appealing.
And if you're, say, JMeter, and
all of your configuration
is either via XML if you want to
do it that way, which most
people don't, or it's a GUI that
looks like it beamed in
from the late '80s, and if your
load runner is a GUI that
happens to be really unstable
and can't do automated testing
at all, or if you're ab, it's
something that's completely
not configurable at all.
I'm sorry to bash
on Jamie here.
I'm sure a lot of people
here have used it.
It takes forever to actually
write a load test in JMeter.
And if you want to do anything
interesting at all, you're
going to be writing a plug-in.
And I have done that, and let me
tell you, I do not wish it
on anybody.
And so it would be really nice
if whatever this load
generator was was really easy to
write new things in, it has
to be extensible.
A for loop actually satisfies
all of those constraints.
But the for loop
has a problem.
It turns out that it's actually
quite wrong as far as
testing performance
of your code.
It will give you nice, warm,
fuzzy answers of I can handle
40,000 QPS.
Woo hoo, look at me and my
product and my service.
It scales really well.
But it turns out that that has
nothing to do with what's
actually going to happen to it
when you get into production.
Why is that?
So let me talk about some
systems theory.
Sorry to be academic
for a second.
Does anybody here know
Little's Law?
Raise your hand if you
know Little's Law.
Awesome.
Nobody here knows
Little's Law.
I'm glad I put this slide in.
Little's Law is a really awesome
mathematical result in
queuing theory that says that
if you have a service and
requests are arriving at a
particular rate, the number of
concurrent users or concurrent
requests that that service
will be able to handle can be
found by saying what is the
request rate, and what is the
latency or what is the time it
takes to service that
particular request?
And that it might sound
intuitive, and it is if you
think about it.
Like, hey, if I have 100
requests a second, and it
takes a second to satisfy that
request, then I will have 100
requests concurrently, right?
It's simple math.
But it turns out that the math
behind that is actually pretty
hard to derive, and it's awesome
that it's such a
simple result.
But really, it's just math,
so why do we care?
What does Little's Law have
to with a for loop?
Well, if you are a performance
engineer, you very much want
to change one thing at a time
about your system so that you
can know for sure that the
performance impact that you
are experiencing is because
of that change.
Flaky tests were mentioned
earlier.
Flaky tests are the bane of
performance engineers because
you never get one answer.
You always get a range
of answers whenever
you run these tests.
And so it's really important
that you be able to change
something, try it again, change
something, try it
again, and get results
you can count on.
But Little's Law actually makes
that very hard to do
that on a system which is
specified in terms of
concurrent users.
So open versus closed systems.
Basically, an open system--
and again, I'm not talking about
open source, like APIs
or anything like, that this
is systems theory--
an open system is a system
where requests and arrive
independent of your ability
to service them.
So in other words, an open
systems is what you get when
you put your service on the
internet where your users, as
much as you wish they would, do
not care that you're slow
right now, or that there's a
big spike, or the Michael
Jackson just died.
They're going to send you
requests, whether that's
tweets or trying to retweet,
regardless of your ability to
actually handled them.
A closed system is much
nicer to model.
If you can imagine, probably the
best example I can think
of is a call center where you
sit there on the phone with
the poor person who's sitting
in front of the computer.
There are only 500 agents, so
that's the concurrency right
there, 500.
And they sit there and say,
I'm sorry, the system
is slow right now.
I'm waiting for your
data the load.
That's a closed system.
It's awesome because you can
just say, all right, I need to
be able to send 500 threads.
JMeter can model that
quite well.
But in a in the real world,
we model things with
requests per second.
And that concurrency is equal to
latency times request rate.
We need to model request
rate, not concurrency.
One more thing.
JMeter and almost every other
load generator I've used by
default will speak HTTP,
which is fine if
you have a web service.
Clearly, Twitter is a web
service, so why isn't that
sufficient?
Well, it turns out that
when you build a big
service-oriented architecture,
you're probably not speaking
HTTP on the back end.
At Twitter, we're
talking thrift.
Thrift is a wire format that
is similar protobuf, which
many of you are probably
familiar with if you're not
familiar with thrift.
And you have to be able to talk
thrift if you're going to
be able to test systems in
isolation, because like I
said, you can't stand up the
whole service of Twitter, all
120 of them, and then send some
HTTP requests in order to
make something happen way down
10 systems deep so that you
can find out whether or not
you can handle the load.
So you need to really be able
to test components, not just
the whole system.
Supporting thrift is really,
really tricky.
It turns out that in thrift, you
codegen your protocol, and
you typically do that
at compile time.
So when you're building your
system, you have bound it to a
particular RPC by the
act of building it.
And that means, then, that all
of your data objects are there
at compile time, and if your
imagining a world like JMeter,
then it means that my load
generator is suddenly going to
have to know not only your
protocol, which is tricky in
and of itself, but also going
to have to have all of your
codegen stuff.
Which means that if you think
about it, there's 120 systems
at Twitter, so that means that
now my load generator code is
dependent on all 120 thrift
interfaces that they expose.
And I've open sourced it, so now
it's dependent on anything
anybody can ever do, which
is clearly impossible.
So I had to change the mental
model of how this works in
order to satisfy that need
to support thrift.
HTTP, you don't have any
of those problems.
HTTP is a very well-defined
protocol--
cookies, headers, post,
different kinds of requests--
but very well-specified, and
other than HTTP 2.0, nobody's
going to invent a new kind of
HTTP that you need to support
in order to make your
load generator work.
But thrift is a lot harder.
So I had to flip the model in
terms of the load generator.
So in the JMeter and any other
system-- you might use world--
the dependency is
on the system.
Instead, I flipped that, and the
dependency now goes from
the system to the load
generation library.
And so when I got up here, I
talked about the fact that
Iago is a library.
It's not a product per se.
It is a load generating
library.
You depend on it just like you
depend on any artifact, and
what it gives you is enough
stuff that allows you to write
to an interface, which allows
you to implement your
particular load test.
And I'll show you some examples
here in a minute.
And you write to
that interface.
And then you launch
it, and it ships.
With that dependency
comes enough--
like, jar, blah, blah, blah--
comes along and then allows
you to launch it.
It comes with, effectively,
an execution
environment along with it.
Secondly, so not only is Iago
different in that it flips the
dependency model on its head,
it also uses Finagle.
If anybody has used Finagle,
then you're probably like yay,
cool, Finagle's awesome.
I'm assuming that's
not most of you.
Finagle is a Scala
library that we
use heavily at Twitter.
It's open sourced.
We wrote it.
And a lot of people
are using it.
And it allows us to do
asynchronous RPCs
over Thrift or HTTP.
Really, name your protocol.
MySQL was recently added.
And we have a Google Summer of
Code-- shout out to the folks
who organized that--
Google Summer of Code project
this year for adding Zookeeper
support, for instance.
So chances are that if it
doesn't support what you need
to do it, it probably will be
there or is easy to write.
Finagle, because it's
asynchronous, solves our open
system versus closed
system conundrum
that I described earlier.
It's based on Netty, which in
turn is based on Java NIO.
So if you have an asynch world
like that, you can basically
say hey, I needed a request to
arrive every millisecond.
Let's say that my arrival
rate is 1,000 RPS.
So I need a request to arrive
roughly, if I had a uniform
distribution, every
millisecond.
OK, great.
I'm going to send a request
every millisecond.
I'm not going to have a
thread per request.
I'm not going to care how slow
or fast your system is.
A request will be sent and will
arrive every millisecond.
If your system is down,
then I'm going to get
a connection refused.
If your system is up but slow,
then there's going to be a
socket held open for certain
amount of time.
But the resource constraints
on my test system are not
going to interact with the
resource constraints or the
problems that you might
have on your service.
That kind of coupling is death
to a performance test.
If you get your system under
test coupled with your Load
Generator, then you've created a
closed system, and you're no
longer modeling reality, at
least modeling reality for
most of us here.
Clearly, I described a case
where somebody could create a
closed system.
But for the most part, I
believe everybody here
probably works at
internet scale.
And therefore you are all
needing a model open systems.
And so you need something where
it's going to generate
those requests regardless of how
slow or fast the service
is at this particular build.
So that's all cool.
But what's it mean?
So I mentioned that I'm going
to get some code.
I'm actually moving faster
than I expected.
Maybe I should slow down.
So we'll have a lot of time
to look at the code.
But there are some implications
about this model
of hey, here's a library,
you depend on it.
You write your load test
using this library.
And then you just launch
it, and it runs,
and it's all good.
For me, the most important
thing--
I came from a team at my last
company where, when I left, I
think there were 15 performance
engineers.
And now I've heard over the last
two years and change, the
team is now something like
50 performance engineers.
And their job is to write
performance tests.
And that's what they do.
And as the engineering team
grows there, they have to hire
more performance engineers
in order to performance
test all the stuff.
I think that that model is very
hard to make successful.
Especially when I started at
Twitter, the company was quite
a bit smaller.
I think there were roughly
200 engineers at
Twitter when I started.
I wasn't going to be able to go
and performance test every
single person's thing.
They were all moving
really fast.
Way faster than I could
move just by myself.
And I wasn't going to go
out and hire another 19
performance engineers really
quick and say, OK, great, now
we're going to be able
to test your stuff.
And oh by the way, today we're
something like 900 engineers,
which is the size of actually
just Google's testing, but
never mind.
So now I would need 90
performance engineers, or
whatever the ratio is.
Let's say it's 5%, and
I'd need 45 or so.
And you can project out to
infinity and realize that, in
fact, this is probably not going
to scale, because there
aren't that many performance
engineers on the planet.
And so it's really important
to me that if you're an
engineer and you're building a
service, that you be able to
write your own performance
test.
Not that you can go and learn
JMeter or not that to force
you to go and, God forbid,
and use LoadRunner.
But that you actually can just
write some code, like you
would write your for loop,
and write your
own performance test.
So that's a clear implication
of this dependency model
switch is that you're no longer
working in a world
where most of the domain
expertise is something that's
unfamiliar to you.
You're working in a world
where it's your service.
You probably already wrote a
sample client when you wrote
your service, and you just
use that same code to
generate the load test.
It's very simple.
Similar to how the for
loop is very simple.
Like I've said, I've been at
Twitter for two years.
I've written two load tests
the entire time
that I was at Twitter.
I spent the first six months
writing the Load Generator.
I wrote a couple sample
load tests that were
actually never run.
People looked at it and said,
oh, this is easy, I'll just do
this myself.
And I never actually
ran those.
And there were two instances
where I had to do a load test,
because they were testing some
aspect of the system where
either in one case, no team
existed that was maintaining
that system, and yet we were
expecting to get a large burst
in traffic.
And in another case, it
was crossing so many
organizational groups--
this was the most
recent example.
I had to test for
New Year's Eve.
And so I wrote that test of
what happens when 30,000
Japanese people all tweet
at midnight exactly.
It's the best distributed
denial of service attack
you've ever seen.
[LAUGHTER]
And so those are the two load
tests that I had to write.
I'm going to show
you one of them.
I don't think I have time
to show you both.
But I'll show you the most
complicated one, so you get
some sense of exactly how
hairy can it get.
And I'll talk about
that in a second.
There are some unintentional
things that happened as a
result of doing it
in this way.
I mentioned that you have sample
code already written.
It turns out that you actually
have to write a lot less code.
When I write a JMeter plug-in,
there is a ton of boilerplate
that I have to implement.
In other systems, I have to
write a whole bunch of stuff
just to get it to
do what I want.
Iago, the code you're writing is
the code you already have.
So you probably are just copying
and pasting it, in the
worst case, or pulling
it in as a
dependency, in a better case.
And so you just don't have
to write as much code.
It really takes people,
literally--
you might think I'm
exaggerating--
but it typically takes an
engineer at Twitter who has
never been exposed to the Load
Generator before and everybody
now at this point, I believe--
well, except the 50 or so we
hire every month--
will have been exposed to it.
But it takes them about 30
minutes typically from I don't
have anything, my manager just
told me I should probably find
out if this is going to scale to
all right, here I've got a
load test and I've run it, and
I found out that, in fact, it
doesn't scale at all.
Oh shoot.
I have to go back to
the drawing board.
Or better case, it's awesome.
It also has another really
fascinating application that
I'm going to get to here in
more detail in a second.
But Finagle makes it really easy
for you to think in terms
of asynchronous operations.
It has this concept
of the future.
Hopefully many of you are
familiar with that from the
Java world.
The future signature in Scala
is a little nicer and easier
to work with than
it is in Java.
And it allows you to compose
RPCs in a way that let's you
say things like, first, I need
to authenticate this user.
Then I need to check and see if
they have the right access.
Then I need to run this
request against
this backend service.
And I'm going to
scatter gather.
I'm going to run this request
out to 100 different services.
And I'm going to compile
the results.
And I'm going to throw away the
ones that didn't come back
in a certain amount of time.
And then I'm going to collate
that into a response that I
send to the user.
I can do all of that in about
three lines of code.
So Finagle makes it really
easy to compose really
complicated RPCs.
Using that in the Load
Generator, in turn, means that
you can write really
complicated load
tests really easily.
And I didn't expect that at all,
because I had never been
exposed to Finagle.
And that was a really
nice result.
The thing that that means is
that, as you're going to see,
it means that you can write very
complicated functional
test scenarios.
Before I had a tool like this,
the way that I would do
performance testing and make
sure that the service is
behaving correctly at the same
time, let me describe a
scenario where this
isn't done.
Let's say that you have a load
test and you're running it and
your service is performing
really well.
And then later, somebody has the
bright idea to go and look
and see what's actually
happening.
And what's happening is
hey, it's amazing.
The performance is awesome.
It's really, really good.
It's serving a 404.
Or it's really, really good.
It's serving a 500, because
there's an exception.
And it turns out that an HTTP
200 with a nice graphic, like
a fail whale, might,
to your Load
Generator, look like success.
But in fact, the right thing
isn't happening at all.
Well, how do you solve
that problem.
Well, of course, then your
Load Generator needs to
hopefully pay attention to more
than just the response
code, but also you might
think that--
this is the way I solved
it in my last gig.
You run your load and
you're running a
functional test beside it.
And you're like, OK, under this
amount of load, these
scenarios still operate
correctly.
And so here I've got JMeter,
let's say, running against the
service, and I've got a Selenium
test or a web driver
test running simultaneously.
And that's fine as
far as it goes.
But wouldn't it be nice if you
could actually say 100,000
users can all do this
at the same time.
Where they can do these
50 different things
all at the same time.
Honestly, I don't know of any
way to do that other than this
Load Generator Iago.
I didn't have to load test 100
services, so I had lot of time
to dedicate to making
Iago great.
It's still not as great
as it could be.
We are in the process of syncing
out a bunch of stuff
to the open source repo--
bug fixes and such.
But if people are inspired by
this talk, feel free to come
and make contributions.
Unintentionally, the idea of
having a service which is
really solid became the model
for how we do all of what I
call developer productivity.
Or probably a lot of you.
It's not a realization
I had alone.
But we basically are focused--
I manage a team now focused
on developer productivity.
And our build system
works this way.
The test frameworks that we
support works this way.
Our test infrastructure
set up works this way.
Our deployment tool
works this way.
And so it became a model for how
things should work is that
give engineers great tools that
are really easy to use,
where the default, it's
almost easier to use
than to not use them.
And they will do the
right thing.
And so that's how we're doing
things at Twitter, which
hopefully is no surprise
to anybody.
All right, now we get
into the meat.
Hopefully you can
all read that.
I actually don't care if you
can't read that too much,
because it turns out that this
is just an example of how to
write an echo service in
Finagle using Thrift.
So you can imagine that you
would have a service like.
It takes a method.
Or it has an RPC
that says echo.
And then it's going to reply
back with what you wrote.
I'm trying to be relatively
open kimono here.
There's no hidden dependencies,
other than on
Finagle and things like that.
But there's no hidden
code here.
That's really how the
service is written.
I cut it off at the end, because
below that is all the
Zookeeper discovery business.
And I figured people
don't care.
Here's a client.
I hope anybody who's writing
a service is probably also
written a client for it.
If you haven't, then you should
probably think about
doing that.
Because you learn a lot of
interesting things when you
behave like your customer,
whoever that is.
But here is a client
that is going to
send the message hello.
And when it gets the response
back, it's going to print
something out and say, all
right, I got a hello back.
And that's how you write that
code using Finagle talking to
my echo service.
And it's not a lot of code.
There's a lot of noise
in there about types.
But other than that, it's
pretty self explanatory.
And by the way, if anybody here
doesn't know Scala and
you're totally confused,
my apologies.
Here is a load test.
Take a look at that
for a second.
Notice that it's calling
client.echo.
I'm going to go back,
So if you see that, it's
actually the same code.
And in fact, it turns
out it's less code.
How's that possible?
How could it be less code?
Well, it turns out that Iago
takes care of some of the
boilerplate as far as connecting
to a service goes.
So this load test actually does
a little more than the
sample client.
If it gets a hello back,
then it sends another
message and logs it.
So that's a really
simple example.
I'm going to get into
a more complicated
example here in a second.
It turns out that if I wanted to
write a for loop that just
sent echo requests
asynchronously, as long as I
knew enough about Java NIO or
Netty or some other library
like that, it would be really
simple for me to do that
without too much effort.
So great, what have I gotten?
How can I do better?
So we have more complicated
problems than that, it turns
out, at Twitter and hopefully
most of you as well.
So load testing direct
messages.
Direct messages are a feature in
Twitter where you can send
a private message from one user
to another as long as
there's a following relationship
between them,
with some exceptions that I'm
not going to go into related
to brands where you can direct
message them without them
following you.
I didn't put any of this in
the slides, because I was
worried that comms would
come after me.
So I will talk about
this rather than--
I have to get slides approved.
So nothing I'm going to tell you
is confidential, per se.
But at any rate, we had a TV
show, one of these reality
game shows similar to, say,
"American Idol" where people
are singing.
They get up on stage.
They sing.
You vote.
And then America picks
the winner.
They go home with hopefully a
nice recording contract that
doesn't take too much
of their money.
And one of these such shows
wanted to use Twitter to do
the voting.
And this show had a $5 million
prize at the end.
And they were going to do the
voting every single live show
over Twitter and include
those votes along
with everything else.
But voting online has to be
private, at least, without
some major exceptions.
And so they were going
to use DMs.
And at the time--
in order to not get myself in
trouble, I'm not talking about
when this was--
but at the time, we were getting
roughly 400 DMs a
second over our system.
So 400 messages a second
back and forth that
were of this type.
And when you figure out that
most of the TV showing happens
in the East Coast and Central
together, which is most of the
population of the United States,
and that all of this
voting would be happening at
the same time, because the
polls open, as it were, at
the end of the show.
And so everybody immediately
goes and they do their voting.
So you get a flood of traffic.
We figured out that we were
going to have roughly on the
order of 2,000 to 3,000
DMs per second.
And as I said, the production
traffic at the time was 400.
And so clearly, we were going to
have a large increase over
what we could handle.
So we needed to be able
to test that.
This is a Direct Message.
Again, I'm going to
show some code.
And actually, I'm going to go
a little quickly, because I
have about four minutes.
But I'm not going to
go super quickly.
That's just an underlying
type that would
hold the Direct Message.
Here is my processor.
You might actually be able to
figure out from the code what
the TV show is.
So we're actually going
to show five, I think,
slides of code here.
So don't get too attached
to any one piece of it.
This is happening up
in the constructor.
There is an eval.
And then we pull in a config.
And then there's
a couple URLs.
This is using our API 1.0
endpoint instead of our API
1.1 endpoint.
This code was written long
enough ago that there wasn't a
1.1 endpoint.
And by the way, none of it
has been code reviewed.
So please, my apologies.
I know it's not the highest
quality code.
I wrote it in, literally,
like a day.
So there you go.
Here's some stuff.
It turns out that if you're
going to have $5 million
riding on the votes, that you
had better get them right.
You better not drop any
votes on the floor.
You better not have
votes show up for
people you didn't expect.
And so the voting, like in my
load test, when I talk about
being able to test correctness
and load at the same time,
turns out to be critical
in this case.
Because I need to be able to
make sure that of those 3,000
DMs per second or whatever the
number is that I'm going to
test at, that all of them show
up for the right guy or girl
or whoever it is.
And that like I said, none of
them get dropped on the floor
or arrive--
well, out of order is
fine in this case.
So I need to track
a bunch of stuff.
It also turns out that I don't
have another system like
Twitter that's not Twitter.
I don't have a copy of Twitter
in my back pocket that I can
just stand up and run a bunch of
tests against, because that
would be expensive.
And it probably wouldn't fit.
So I need to use Twitter in
order to run this test, which
means I run the risk of knocking
over production, as
it turns out.
But anyway, that was
a known risk.
But it also turns out that I
don't have millions of users
in my back pocket.
And I can't go create millions
of users, because it with
throw off our analytics and
our growth team would get
really excited.
And I would have to break
the news to them that
that was just me.
[LAUGHTER]
And so I don't have a million
users in my back pocket.
So I decided, you know what?
It doesn't matter.
I did a lot of talking
to other engineers.
This is pretty shortly after
I arrived at Twitter.
I didn't know much of the
system at that point.
So I talked to a lot of people,
and they said, no, it
probably doesn't matter.
You can probably send all these
DMs from one account.
So I sent all the DMs from
myself, literally.
I used my own account.
But it turns out that we have
rate limiting at Twitter.
And so if I need to send 3,000
DMs a second, if any of you
want to do this, you're going
to get stopped almost
immediately.
But it turns out that my Load
Generator is running in
production.
And so it has access to
memcache, which means it has
access to the rate limit.
It has access to my
rate limit token.
And I can go and reset it
as part of my load test.
So the load test is sitting
there DMing.
And meanwhile, it's also
talking to memcache
saying, that guy?
No, we're going to zero
out his rate limit
again all the time.
Over and over and over
again quite rapidly.
And I mentioned that I want to
make sure we don't drop these
on the floor.
Our customer was using our
streaming API, which
internally we call Hosebird.
And so I wanted to make sure
that I was getting the same
data that they would be.
So I make a connection
to Hosebird.
So there's my connection
to memcache.
There's my connection
to Hosebird.
I highlighted the connect to
Hosebird code, because it's
not that interesting.
And then here's my load test.
So I need to pick a particular
host to hit.
I need to decide what I'm going
to send, so I have a
vote randomizer function
that I'm going to call.
I need to set up the request.
I'm going to make a
URI out of that.
I'm going to set the OAuth
header with all the right
correct authentication codes.
And I'm going to make a Iago
slash Parrot request with all
of those parameters.
And then I'm going to map that
onto my request, call my
service, which is that
second line up there.
And when the response comes
back, I'm going to decode it
and check to make sure that I
haven't exceeded my DM limits.
And if so, reset them.
And then I'm going to look and
see if I got a decent response
back, meaning it's some HTTP
response as opposed to an
exception that I got
on the wire.
Then I'm going to read that DM,
and I'm going to do some
check for missing
DMs at the end.
It's very simple logic.
It turns out that this logic
actually had a bug.
It's kind of funny,
I think, anyway.
You'll see.
So the way I wrote it originally
was all right, I'm
going to send a message.
And when you send a DM or
anything on Twitter and when
you create something,
you get back an ID.
So I'm going to get back the
ID in the response, and I'm
going to be waiting over here
for the stream to give me a DM
with that ID.
And I found out that we were
dropping tons and tons of DMs
on the floor.
This is horrible.
It's not working at all.
What's the problem?
It turns out that Hosebird was
delivering the DM before I
actually got the
response back.
So our streaming API is fast
enough that it will send the
DM down before you even
know what the ID was.
And so I had to create DMs that
have unique text in them
just so that I could
match them up.
Because I was going to get them
on the streaming side
before I got the response.
It's an awesome bug.
So that's all the code.
That's it.
That's how you test DMs.
So what do I want you to
take away from this?
So clearly, most of
you, some of you--
I don't know how many people
from Google are here.
Google clearly deals in more
scale than we do, as does
Facebook and a number
of other sites.
But in general, most of the
world doesn't handle the
amount of test load that
we have at Twitter.
Just to give you an example,
when I went into this, one of
the things that I wanted to be
able to do was to be able to
generate a lot of load.
I had run into scalability
problems with JMeter and
systems like where they have
very simple request response
patterns, meaning give
me a counter.
Great.
I got a counter back.
And you can be very
fast at that.
And 40,000 QPS was a lot
for JMeter to handle.
And I knew that Twitter handled
more than that when I
came to the company.
So I wanted something that
could scale really well.
And I had in my head that oh,
100,000 RPS would be cool.
That would be awesome.
And one day, somebody needed
that much, and we were able to
do it, and it was no big deal.
And then somebody else
came along and they
wanted 500,000 QPS.
And I was like, ooh, wow,
that's a large number.
OK, let's see.
I had to tune a couple things.
And then we did that.
And then I haven't
touched the code,
honestly, in like six months.
And a month ago, I was idly
sitting lunchtime
conversation, and I
hear behind me two
million QPS we tested.
And I turn around.
I'm like what?
Two million?
Who?
What?
Really?
I was like, you didn't do
that with our stuff.
So how did you generate
two million QPS?
That's awesome.
I want to know what did that.
Turns out you can generate
two million QPS.
That is almost an afterthought
versus everything else that
you get to do with this.
So pretty interesting as far
as Twitter's problems go.
It turns out that you probably
all should want your engineers
to be writing their
own load tests
instead of doing it yourself.
And you should also clearly
want your load test to be
accurate and model
the real world.
There you go.
I have all of one minute
for questions.
And I'll be available
for lunch.
[APPLAUSE]
TONY VOELLM: Great.
Thank you, James.
I got my takeaways
again this time.
One is I learned you are a
optimism and not a pessimist.
All your for loops had
starts but no ends.
JAMES WALDROP: Yep.
Thanks.
[LAUGHTER]
TONY VOELLM: And I
also learned I
have to go learn Scala.
And somehow, somebody slipped in
like a next generation list
somewhere in the world.
And so Scala is it.
I also know Foursquare
does Scala.
So it's growing in popularity.
We're going to take a break
here in a minute.
I think we have time for
one question if we want
to go to the mic's.
So if you have a question,
go to the mic.
Otherwise, we'll take one
off the Moderator.
Then we're going to
take a break.
Then we're going come back
here exactly at 11:30.
And we're going to go into the
next set of presentations that
will be done by Mozilla.
And right before this question,
two things.
Some people have been asking if
the slides will be posted.
Yes, they will be posted.
And so will the video and the
content and all these
questions and everything
after the talks.
So they will definitely
be out there.
And number two, there's a lot
of people standing up in the
back of the room, just some
to stretch your legs.
But there's also people that
would like a seat.
So when you come back from the
break, kind of squish into the
middle as much as you can.
So with that, we'll
go to a question.
JAMES WALDROP: I like
the top one.
TONY VOELLM: All right, so
here's the first question.
It says, does Iago allow clients
in languages other
than Scala?
In other words, can developers
port their clients in other
languages to write performance
tests?
JAMES WALDROP: Yeah.
Sorry.
Can you hear me?
So Scala is a JVM language,
which means that those
libraries are available to any
other JVM language, which
means that as long as you have
code written for the JVM--
and that can include things
like Jython or
JRuby for that matter.
So really, anything that you
write on the Java stack for,
you can use Iago.
Cool.
Thanks.
TONY VOELLM: All right, with
that, let's go ahead
and take our break.
And we will be back at 11:30.
[APPLAUSE]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
TONY VOELLM: Hello.
Hello, welcome back.
True to word, here, we're
going to start.
As a reminder, please do squish
in as you can to make
room for others.
So if you can sort of move to
the center to leave that
space, that'll be great.
If you are interested in the
topic tables, we're going to
be selecting the topic
tables for lunch
here in a few minutes.
You can go to g.co/gtac2013 and
you can find a link to the
moderator to go and figure out
what topics you want to vote
up or vote down, or even
suggest a new topic.
So pleased go do that right
now if you can.
And up next here we have
David Burns and Malini
from Mozilla here.
They're going to talk about how
do you test a Mobile OS?
And a little fact about Malini
here, she told me that her dog
is named after a test
subject in Portal.
So you can always go ask her
about this from that.
So with that, I'll let
them kick it off.
Thank you.
MALINI DAS: Thank you.
[APPLAUSE]
MALINI DAS: So can you
all hear me OK?
Yeah?
Awesome.
So I'm Malini Das and
this is David Burns.
And we work on automation
frameworks over at Mozilla.
And we're here today to give
you a rundown of the recent
challenges that Mozilla has been
facing while automating a
new Mobile OS.
So how do you test
a Mobile OS?
That's the question that first
came into our heads when we
were tasked with supporting
this new platform.
And we knew that answering this
question wasn't going to
be as easy as just googling for
an answer or just winging
it as we went along.
There's a depth of problems
that need solving.
And solving them in a good and
long lasting way would save us
lots of pain in the future.
So today David and I are going
to talk to you about how we
solved this complex problem and
share with you the pain
points and the victories
we had along the way.
So let's see here-- great.
So what Mobile OS am
I talking about?
As some of you might know,
Mozilla has been working on
something called Firefox OS.
And this is an open web
accessible device that's built
on top of what we know best
which is the browser.
So we're using Gecko, which is
our web rendering engine, to
drive the phone itself, allowing
all the applications
running on our phone to
be written in CSS,
JavaScript, and HTML5.
So now you might be wondering
why would we
want that in a phone.
Well, we've seen a recent trend
towards web technologies
in the mobile environment.
So around 60% of the apps right
now in Google Play and
the app store have at least
one part of the app
that's a web view.
So what this means is that on
top of your operating system
that needs to run your native
applications, you also need to
have a web rendering engine just
to show this web view.
And this trend towards web views
isn't going to go away
any time soon.
We're seeing a prevalence of
frameworks like PhoneGap which
allow you to write an
application once using web
technologies and deploy to
multiple mobile platforms
instantaneously.
So what's the problem here?
The problem is that these
operating systems are doing
extra work.
So not only are they running
the applications, but they
also need to run a web rendering
engine just to show
you parts of this application.
So is there a way to remove
this extra work?
That's the goal of Firefox OS.
What we want to do is unite the
concerns of the OS and the
browser so your phone
is doing less work.
And what we want to do is
optimize it so well that we
can run on low end devices.
So we get this benefit that, by
optimizing our browser, we
get to optimize our phone.
And by targeting low end
devices, we get to put this
phone out to emerging markets
and put it in hands of people
who may not have a smartphone
before or may not have had
access to the internet before.
So what this means is
we now have to make
our browser a phone.
And what do we need
to do for that?
That means that our browser
has to do things like send
SMSes and make phone calls.
And on top of that, it has
to act like a browser.
So it has to render web pages.
And that gave us, the automation
and tools team, the
task of figuring out how we can
instrument and test all
these new features
in this platform.
So what exactly should
we test?
Since Firefox OS is essentially
a flavor of
Firefox but on the phone,
we want to test
all the same parts.
So this means that we want to
test things like rendering.
Now, rendering essentially means
how the web page looks
like once it's loaded.
And the way that we test it is
that we let the web page load,
and we compare the data with
either a reference image or
reference data to make
sure that they match.
If they don't match, then we're
not giving new mobile
users an experience of the
mobile web that they deserve.
We don't want to regress in
any way in rendering.
Another shared concern that we
have with browsers is that we
want to make sure that we
have a performant phone.
So we need to check
performance.
If our phone takes too long to
execute anything, then no
one's going to want
to use this phone.
So this means that we need to
test performance for simple
things like loading
applications.
But we also want to do stress
tests, so that we can make
sure that we don't provide a
degraded experience over time
or that we can catch memory
leaks and all that fun stuff.
But now on top of these concerns
that we have with our
browser, we have new concerns
since we're a smartphone.
We now have to worry about
application, unit and
integration tests.
So smartphones have a number of
base applications, like the
calendar or the dialer.
And you want to make sure that
these applications work before
you send out this
phone to people.
So to do that, you want to
answer questions like, does my
application work?
Do the functional parts of
this application work?
Does this application work
with the system app.
Does it work while other
applications are running in
the background?
Now this is important for us
so that we can test our own
base applications.
But we also want to give this
test for a framework to third
party developers so that when
they write their apps, they
can have the confidence that
it'll work in this new
environment.
So Firefox OS is not just going
to run on any desktop.
It's going to run on phones.
So now we have to worry
about testing the
phone environment itself.
This means things like gathering
hardware metrics.
So one of the hardware metrics
that we want to gather is
things like boot time.
So how long it takes the phone
from an off state to go into a
usable state.
I'm sure we'll had phones at
some point where you could
press the button to turn it
on, and it's just not
responding.
So you go and you
make a coffee.
And you come back, and you
still see a boot screen.
That behavior is not acceptable
for new users.
It might be OK for early
adopters types.
But we're going to be giving
the phone to people who may
never have had a phone before.
And we want to give them a good
optimized experience.
So as we develop this phone, we
want to make sure that we
can gather data like boot
time and make sure
that we don't regress.
Another important thing that
we need to worry about now
that we're running on a phone
is hardware metrics as the
phone is running.
So things like battery life.
Back when we all had feature
phones, you could turn our
phone, on it would run for
a week without having to
recharge it.
But now with our energy guzzling
smartphones, we're
lucky to get two days
off a single charge.
So we want to be able to make
sure that as we progress with
our phone and as we build it
out, we maintain a good
battery life and other hardware
metrics like this.
Now one of our most important
and interesting new test
concerns is telephony.
So the smartphone has to be able
to do things like send a
text message and check your
network provider and make an
actual phone call.
And if you can't do this
reliably, then it's nothing
more than a frustrating
portable computer.
So we're going have to figure
out how we can actually solve
for testing telephony.
So now that we know what we want
to test in general, how
do we go about doing that?
Do we have any tech lying around
that can help us run
tests with these concerns?
Well, since Firefox OS is
similar to Firefox, then we
can use the tests that we run
against Firefox against it.
We have many existing frameworks
for Firefox.
But none of them tackle all of
the issues that we need to
tackle here.
We have things for rendering the
performance, but we don't
have things for telephony.
We don't have a way of
communicating to multiple
instances at the same time,
because we never had to deal
with cross-device
communication.
So what all this pointed
out to was that we
needed a new framework.
And us being good engineers,
we were wondering, wait.
We shouldn't just let this
be a band-aid solution.
We have the opportunity to build
a framework that can
answer questions not only
for now, but can
build for the future.
So that any future framework
that we build can leverage the
work that we're doing now.
So now that we figured out, OK,
we need a new framework,
what exactly should it solve?
So this framework has to support
our existing test
frameworks.
So Mozilla has hundreds of
thousands of tests running
against Firefox.
And we want to be able to
seamlessly run them against
Firefox OS.
It makes no sense to go off and
make your own framework
and then rewrite
all the tests.
That's just madness and
unnecessary work.
So the ideal framework will be
able to uplift all these
frameworks into Firefox OS.
The next requirement is that
it should be the foundation
for future frameworks.
What this means is that to run
any tests on the phone, we
need to be able to communicate
with their own.
So the test runner has to
talk to the test device.
And this is the core driving
mechanism behind all of our
frameworks.
And any future framework will
need to solve for this
communication.
So our framework should be
able to provide this core
pipework that's reusable across
frameworks today and tomorrow.
And the last requirement is that
it should be reusable for
any Gecko environment.
So what that means is that
whatever we create today
should work on Firefox for
Android, Firefox for desktop,
and Firefox OS and any Gecko
product in the future.
This'll help us write one test
framework once and then run
them in any other environment
later.
So let's get to the gritty
details of these requirements.
So in order to uplift some of
our existing frameworks, what
do we need to do?
Well, our existing frameworks
currently rely on Firefox
add-ons to run.
They use add-ons so that they
have access to the privileged
space of your test
environment.
So they execute code against the
Chrome of the environment.
And this is fine for a desktop,
because it has the
ability to run Firefox
add-ons.
But in the beginning days of
Firefox OS, we didn't have the
ability to run add-ons.
we.
First started thinking about
test solutions about four
months after the project
was announced.
So we had very little
to work with.
We didn't know what direction
the product will
eventually go in.
But all we knew is that we're
going to be building this on
top of Gecko.
So while we didn't have the
ability to easily uplift these
frameworks using add-ons, that
means that we have to somehow
integrate our framework
with Gecko itself.
This was actually an
opportunity, because instead
of running as an add-on, we now
get to integrate directly
into the engine, and we would
get a performance boost.
So whatever we select as our
framework, we had to make sure
that we integrate the key parts
for every framework so
that they'll be uplifted easily
without any problems.
Another consideration that we
needed to take into account is
that we're running on phones.
And we don't want to assume that
the phone will always be
connected to computer
via a USB.
We want to stick them in data
centers and somehow talk to
them over the network.
So whatever framework we have,
we want it to be able to work
in a networked environment
so that we can remotely
communicate with
other devices.
And the last but extremely
important consideration is
what can we actually open
up on the phone?
So we don't want to just
test web views.
We want to be able to test
things like setting the
battery and check if the web
view has actually received
this new information.
We want to be able to get as
much control of the of device
as possible from the get go.
So what can we actually
control.
So what this all boils down to
is we need a reusable and easy
way to control different phones
and to control multiple
devices at the same time.
And all of this should be done
in an easy and reusable manner
across frameworks.
We want to drive the phone
at all layers.
And we want to have privileges
across the device.
So what that means is that I
want to be able to change file
permissions, but I also want to
be able to do things like
change app permissions.
So the solution that we came up
with is a framework that we
called Marionette, which is
essentially WebDriver meets
Firefox OS.
So why WebDriver?
Well, the phone itself
is a web device.
So WebDriver was written so that
you can manipulate user
views from a user perspective.
So you can test web pages in an
easy and supported matter.
The great thing about WebDriver
is that it's the
protocol behind Selenium.
So by implementing WebDriver, we
get to uplift our existing
Selenium tests for free.
And it's something that's
already familiar to testers.
On top of that, WebDriver is
being proposed as the W3C
standard for browser
automation.
So by implementing WebDriver, we
essentially get to kill two
birds with one stone.
Because we can implement open
web standards and also solve
our testing needs.
Another great thing about
WebDriver is that it solves
our remote access problem
for free.
It's already built in with the
idea of local and remote ends.
So you can communicate and
create a session, a WebDriver
session with one device, and
then also have another session
with another device within
the same test.
So this will allow us
to do things like
cross-device telephony.
And the other consideration is
how will this help us with our
uplifting frameworks problem?
Well, WebDriver has this
extremely helpful method
called Execute Script.
And what Execute Script does
is that-- yeah, you
know what it does.
It's totally hacky.
But it's awesome, because
it works exactly
what we need to do.
What it does is that it lets
you execute any arbitrary
JavaScript that you want in the
current application space.
And that's exactly what
Firefox add-ons
were trying to do.
We use them only to execute
code on the device itself.
But as I mentioned before, we
needed to execute code in
privileged space.
That is the Chrome.
And WebDriver only cares
about content, so
what the user sees.
So what we ended up doing is
we didn't end up making
WebDriver itself.
We ended up doing WebDriver
plus plus.
So we added a few extra
things to it.
So we needed to access
privileged space.
So we added a new method
called Set Context.
And what Set Context does is
that it allows you to set the
current executing context of
your Selenium commands.
So you can do things like,
I'm going to set
the context to content.
I'm going to navigate
to a web page.
I'm going to check what
privileges this web page has.
Then I'm going to set the
context to Chrome, change the
application permissions, and
then go back into the content
and check if my application has
actually respected these
permission changes.
So this helps us write extremely
robust tests.
But it also helps us uplift
these frameworks for free,
because now they can easily
execute whatever JavaScript
they want against the Chrome.
Another key difference that our
WebDriver implementation
has is that the current
doesn't have a full specked
out area on gestures.
And we're a phone.
And we have touch screens.
So that means that we want to
automate user input, which is
multi-finger gestures.
So just to get our own work
off the ground, we started
working on the WebDriver
specification for gestures.
And what this means is that we
added a bunch of gesture
commands into our
implementation.
But the general way that we
solved it is that we added the
ability for you to create any
gesture you want by using
chains of action primitives.
That is, I can change one finger
to do press, move and
release, but the other finger
can just press and release.
And then you can change these
things together to create any
gesture you need.
And the third difference that
this implementation of
WebDriver has to other ones in
Firefox is that it's built
directly into Gecko.
And that gave us a huge
performance boost, because
you're no longer running as
some secondary concern.
You're a primary concern.
So to explain the gritty details
of its implementation
is David Burns.
Here you go.
DAVID BURNS: So how
does it all work?
As Malini said, Marionette gets
kicked off every time
Gecko starts up.
And so Gecko starts up every
time the browser starts up.
And we have this really nice
server sitting there waiting
for us to now accept commands
and execute them.
And because it's essentially
just executing JavaScript, and
large portions of Firefox is
written in JavaScript, we can
now call pretty much anything.
We can go all the way, as Malini
said, from the browser
Chrome, which is where all the
nice security areas are, down
to the very insecure parts
which is a web page.
And we can execute anything
in between.
So now we're essentially
starting to drive a phone, an
operating system,
with WebDriver.
A standards-based automation
API just driving
an operating system.
It pretty much doesn't get
any cooler than that.
So I'm going to now split
out into kind
of how we did things.
We've done a number of things
slightly different to the way
the WebDriver project
does things.
And it's mainly because it's
what fits better with us.
So we essentially have a dummy
clients, which just kind of
sends arbitrary commands
over to the device.
The WebDriver project kind
of does things with HTTP.
Its protocol is kind
of RESTish.
It's not proper REST, but
it's close enough.
And it delivers a nice JSON
payload into a browser.
The browser then knows
what to do with it.
And because we're doing things
with JSON packets and we're
doing wall sockets into the
device, we only allow one
connection.
And the reason why we're doing
it with pure TCP is because
we're trying to utilize some of
the other technologies that
are going into Gecko
at the moment,
like the remote debugger.
We're using a similar
technology.
But I'll get back to that
in the server parts.
So I'll kind of show you how,
from a simple point of view,
I'm just going to use
the terminal.
We can easily just kind of
Telnet into the device.
I don't know if anyone
can see that.
I'll leave it on the
screen for a while.
So we can easily Telnet in.
It shows kind of a nice echo
response from a Telnet server.
Can we have the computer.
Ah, there we are.
So we get a nice echo response
from a device.
The echo's just coming
from the phone.
So we can see what it's doing.
We can go back to the slides.
So now we've got a nice
mechanism into the phone.
The server's kind of the
really nice part.
It's the nuts and bolts that
kind of drives Marionette and
kind of gives us all the in's
into the device and into the
browser to be able
to control it.
The mechanism we're using
is what we've called the
JavaScript transport layer.
It's just kind of raw TCP
into the browser.
But we now can send JSON
payloads through it.
I just got a few little extra
bits and pieces added to it,
which aren't too important
at the moment.
But it gives us this
mechanism.
It's being used at the moment by
the remote debugger, which
is part of Firefox.
So like if you have an Android
device with Firefox for
Android, you can kind of connect
your phone to a host
computer and then debug
from Firefox
straight on to the device.
It's the same technology
as that.
We just kind of now are using
it for automation.
We've created our own actor,
because it's a actor
relationship in it.
And the actor then receives
all the commands that are
coming through.
It kind of breaks down what's
in the JSON payload and then
kind of decides where
it needs to go.
Normally it goes through
to a listener.
And a listener attaches itself
to all the content that's
happening on the page.
So like if you have multiple
frames, a listener gets
attached to each frame so that
when we switch from frame to
frame, we just can carry
on executing.
So where are we using it?
We're currently using it
on devices, emulators.
We've got a special build
of Firefox for
desktop called B2G desktop.
It's kind of got a number of
all the things that we need
for B2G, minus hardware
things.
And we're using it on Firefox.
Marionette is now a tier
one testing frameworks.
So that kind of means that
withing Mozilla, if you push
something into our repository
and it breaks a Marionette
test, it will be backed
out, and you kind
of need to fix it.
This is kind of how we
view our test things.
I know it's probably not going
to be to viewable.
But kind of on the left is
commits grouped by pushes into
a repository.
On the right, I've limited
the UI to only show
the Marionette tests.
That shows all the
Marionette tests.
So Marionette, and then
hopefully by proxy, Selenium
is now part of the Mozilla
kind of waterfall.
So every push that goes into
Gecko now tests Marionette.
It tests like the core
parts of Marionette.
And then goes off and tests all
the different parts that
it needs to.
And then in the sense of what's
to the left of the
Marionette part kind of shows
all the different platforms
that we're running on.
So we've got Linux.
We got Windows.
We got mobile devices.
So we always know that
Marionette's going to be there.
And it's become so core to
the way we do things.
So how's it used?
It's being retrofitted into a
number of our test feeds.
As Malini said, we've
got hundreds of
thousands of tests.
And we need to test that
things are working.
Because, essentially, Firefox
OS is a browser on a device,
we need to make sure that how
people manipulate the dom is
still working properly.
How people are rendering CSS
is still working properly.
Our reference tests are
kind of important.
And we need to make sure that
JavaScript and all these other
little bits and pieces that are
core to the way Firefox
works still works
on the device.
Except we can't use the testing
frameworks before.
We just need to kind of make
sure the tests work.
And we are also starting
to go into
[INAUDIBLE], so telephony.
It's kind of important for a
mobile operating system to be
able to make telephone calls.
Internet is all great and all
that, but people like to use
phones to make phone calls
for some silly reason.
And then we've got this
interesting part.
A mobile device has got multiple
parts to it that we
need to make sure that
we can access.
So the browser needs
to access these.
And then from an automation and
testing point of view, we
need to be able to instrument
them and test them.
So there's different parts.
There's GPS.
There's Bluetooth.
There's USB.
There's all these different
parts of the system-- cameras,
things like that.
And browsers needs to be able
to speak to the hardware.
The hardware goes, well,
here's all the
inputs that you want.
And then we go from there.
And we need to test
all of this.
So I'm going to show you a quick
test on the computer.
So it's going to run
an emulator.
Emulators, just by nature,
are kind of slow.
What this is going to do is
this is going to run a
geolocation test.
It's starts with the emulator.
It's going to set a number of
different bits of information
in the background to the
emulator, then check it.
Make sure your emulator style--
it's very slow.
Runs everything.
Hooray, and all our
tests pass.
But you can see it sets
information, and then it's
retrieved information, checked
everything's working.
Back to slides please.
And then we also need to make
sure that the UI is working.
People need to make sure that
they've got a functioning
device that if they go to make
a phone call, if they go to
set an alarm, they go to do all
these things, those key
parts of the system are working
as they expect.
They're working in
a certain manner.
But it's not just making sure
that Mozilla can make sure
that the UI's working
properly.
OEMs who make the devices and
are going to be flashing them,
they're kind of stripped on
making sure that things work.
Because it's kind of their name
that's on the hardware
when it goes out to people.
So they want it to be of
a certain quality.
And for those who've worked with
iOS and with Android and
have tried to automate the UI
and then kind of gone gray or
gone bald, because you pulled
your hair out, we need to make
sure that we give third party
developers who want to make
apps a nice way to automate
the UI, if they need to.
Or if they just need to execute
different bits of code
as they see fit, we
give them that.
Because if you give them a nice
testing infrastructure,
you have a nice ecosystem
that third party
people want to come.
People want to build apps
because they can prove that
there app is of a
high quality.
So I'm going to kind
of show you a test
running on a device.
If we can put it on
this, please.
This is where I hope it works.
If it works, that'll be fine.
The demigods have struck.
MALINI DAS: There we go.
DAVID BURNS: No, that's me.
Let me show you how quickly
the phone resets.
[LAUGHTER]
DAVID BURNS: While that loads,
I'll get everything ready.
Sorry for the technical delay.
All right, take two.
Uh oh.
Come on.
OK.
Oh, that's why.
That look like it?
Maybe not.
Oh, yes.
All right.
So we try and reset the phone
between tests where possible,
because some parts we can't
kind of clear out.
So what it's doing is it's just
going to set an alarm a
few times and then make sure
everything's working.
And I've broken it?
Yeah, this was working earlier.
Oh well.
[LAUGHTER]
MALINI DAS: I swear it totally
was working earlier, right
before the talk.
DAVID BURNS: Yeah, OK, we'll
just kind of skip the
technical difficulties, and
we'll go back to slides.
So where we've been.
A lot of our testing
infrastructure we kind of had
to be building on
the fly as well.
Because as Malini said, we kind
of were late to the game.
We were invited late
to the game.
But we've had to play catch
up very quickly.
So we had done Jenkins just
running in the cloud, running
our unit tests, our
web API tests.
So kind of this hardware
part tests.
And then we were running
then against emulators.
Luckily, when were at this
stage, we didn't have hundreds
of engineers working
on Firefox OS.
But then things changed.
And we started getting more
engineers than we needed.
And more of the system
started being built.
And we needed to start running
our unit tests, our web API
tests and UI tests.
Because we need to make
sure that all the
functionality is working.
[INAUDIBLE], which is the code
name for the UI needs to be
working at a certain level.
And we're running these on
emulators and we're running
them on PandaBoards.
For those that don't know, a
PandaBoard is just a Android
development board.
It allows us to do
some neat things.
It's essentially just a Nexus
S without a screen, and kind
of looks like a [INAUDIBLE]
or raspberry pie.
And then we went from there and
we started actually also
testing on real devices.
So we've got some devices that
our OEM said was going to be
over some ilk, and we started
testing against those.
And soon we're going to be
testing against the devices
that we're gonna also be sending
out to the public.
This is what a rack of
PandaBoards looks like.
There's a number in there--
this is a unit that was
designed by our IT
department--
and it's a number
of PandaBoards.
They've all got ethernet,
they've all got power.
And what happens is, whenever
a test is ready,
we flash the device.
It's got an SD card on it that
we can change, because SD
cards only have a certain
lifespan.
We can swap out.
It flashes the SD card, then
we run our tests and we go
from there.
One of the things mentioned
earlier is that we also suffer
greatly from flaky tests.
Mobile is one of those places
where you're going to get a
lot of flaky tests.
And a lot of it also comes
down to hardware.
So one of the nice things about
the Panda set up is
we've got a framework called
Mozpool and in our pool we've
got lifeguards who check
how things are going.
If they notice that a certain
board has an increase in
failures, it starts taking that
board out of commission,
kind of let someone know.
And then we can just hot-swap
the device.
Because this is just in a data
center, so our IT department
can go there, swap it
out and carry on.
The other part of our test
infrastructure is making sure
that we can do stress tests
against the device.
Just running and running and
running and running tests,
because people don't
really switch off
their phones nowadays.
They go to bed with
them on, wake up
and it's still running.
And that's the major use case
that people are going to be
using and we need to make sure
that the device doesn't become
sluggish over time, it
doesn't crash all the
time, things like that.
We need to do all these
really weird and
wonderful stress tests.
We started doing fuzzing over
it with a tool called
Orangutan--
which was written by Will
who's in our team--
which just does gestures on the
device at a very low level
and then sees what survives.
And we've started doing
performance
test against devices.
One of the important things that
people wanted to be able
to do is play games.
Most people play games on
smart phones these days.
So we want to make sure that if
you're playing a game, that
you're getting a high
enough frame rate.
We want to aim for that 60
frames a second so we can make
sure that it is not jerky, it's
not anything like that.
There's no jank, which is where
you try scrolling, it
stops for a bit and carries
on scrolling.
We want to make sure that those
things aren't there.
And these types of tests mean
that we can make sure that
when we deliver this device to
people, to OEMs, and when
third party people want to
start using it, they have
their confidence in
what we've done.
And that's it really.
It's been a huge learning
experience for our team.
We've learned some number of
weird and wonderful things
along the way, and we've tried
to solve a number of problems.
And hopefully we've shared
it up with you all.
Thanks.
TONY VOELLM: Great.
Great, thank you David
and Malini.
[APPLAUSE]
TONY VOELLM: That
was fantastic.
Actually I really loved
that last picture
there with the racks.
I also learned the danger of
calling APIs rest APIs,
because sometimes your devices
just take a rest.
[LAUGHTER]
TONY VOELLM: So with that, if
you would like to ask a
question, there's a mic
in the back there
and a mic over there.
Feel free to grab the mic if
you want to ask a question.
And in the meantime, we'll
grab one off of
the moderator here.
So first question up.
How do you automate recovery for
devices that fall off USB
or get wedged outright
during testing?
MALINI DAS: Do you
want to take it?
OK, well it depends
on the device.
So we have the PandaBoards which
you can power cycle.
And we don't use USB
for them, we
communicate over the network.
Wedge outright during testing?
I don't really understand
what that means,
but perhaps you do.
[LAUGHS]
But for other devices, we have
to power cycle them.
We have some tests run directly
against our phones,
and we have to currently
manually reboot them.
But we have someone working on a
solution for that right now,
because manually rebooting
them is just not
sustainable at all.
DAVID BURNS: Yeah, we ask our
manager to go-- because we've
got a big Faraday cage in our
Mountain View office-- and
every so often we just ask our
manager to go work in there
for the day and just power cycle
whenever we need them.
MALINI DAS: Yeah, so
that'll be solved.
TONY VOELLM: You've found
a use for your manager.
Perfect.
All right.
Looks like we had
some questions.
I think you were up first,
so ask away.
AUDIENCE: Sure.
You touched on UI performance
testing at the end there.
But what tools do you use to
actually validate the UI
performance?
Do you have some kind of video
recording or people who are
watching it?
MALINI DAS: Yeah.
So we have this tool called
Eideticker, and what that does
is that it's just a camera
that's focused on the screen.
And it captures it and checks
that the data is moving
actually at 60 frames
per second.
So we have two ways of capturing
that video data.
One is to plug it in a video
out cable directly to the
phone and send it directly to
our computer and analyze HTMI
output directly.
And the other way-- which is
what we're experimenting with
right now-- is with high
speed cameras.
And we're just making sure that
each of the frames are
changing at the rate
at which we expect.
AUDIENCE: Cool, thanks.
TONY VOELLM: So following to
that, so as you're sort of
swiping or moving, one thing is
the frame rate, but how do
you actually know the animation
is happening?
DAVID BURNS: I don't know
about the animation.
But when it comes to swiping,
one of the key things that
brought us to doing this type of
testing was when we rewrote
a lot of the Firefox for
Android stuff, when you
scrolled, we were getting
a lot of checkerboarding
happening, because the drawing
wasn't happening fast enough.
So we created a framework.
Well, I say we.
Will Lachance, he's on our team,
he created a framework
called Eideticker, and that
just watches for these
checkerboarding and then
works through that.
He created Orangutan, which
instruments Android and tells
it how to scroll and
things like that.
So it's allowed us to test
against other browsers so we
could see how well we
checkerboarded.
Well, we don't want to
checkerboard, but how other
browsers were handling
the same website.
TONY VOELLM: Great.
Second up?
I think you were up.
And if you want, you can say
your name and where you're
from and then ask
your question.
If you just want to ask,
that's fine too.
AUDIENCE: Hi, I'm Daniel from
SNAP Interactive, and my
question goes to security.
Obviously, Marionette is a
really great thing that allows
you to drive everything
about the phone.
But what if someone were able
to get access to that and do
those kinds of things to your
phone that you don't
want them to do?
How do you prevent something
like that from happening?
DAVID BURNS: At the moment,
Marionette is only available
in engineering builds.
So you have to build
it into Firefox OS.
We're working with our security
team to work out a
nice way for developers to be
able to have Marionette.
So you just go in, buy a phone
from your local phone company,
and then start working
with it.
Because yes, security is one
of our biggest concerns.
Privacy as well, because people
might be doing internet
banking on things like this, and
we want to make sure that
they feel secure that they
can do all these things.
But also that if a developer
goes and buys it, they can
start working with it.
So we've got a number of ideas,
especially for desktop,
how to sort the desktop
problem.
The mobile problem at the
moment, it's just don't put
Marionette on there.
And then, as and when we can
solve that problem, it'll
start slowly being
put back in.
AUDIENCE: Thank you.
TONY VOELLM: Great, thank you.
And another question
over here please.
AUDIENCE: Yeah, hi.
I'm Jonathan from Salsa Labs.
And if I recall correctly, you
guys said that you in your
WebDriver Plus protocol,
you speak JSON over
TCP, rather than HTTP.
So I'm wondering whether I, as
a potential Firefox OS app
developer, can use standard
Selenium client libraries that
already exist to speak to
Marionette or whether I have
to base it off of something
you guys have written?
DAVID BURNS: So our Marionette
client library is 90% the same
as the Selenium library.
Ideally when we get to a certain
place, what's going to
happen is WebDriver's got an
idea of the commands that it's
got and then it's got
a command executor.
And what we want to try to do is
just switch in the command
executor for Firefox only and
then it just knows to speak
through that and then works.
AUDIENCE: Thanks.
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
HTTP and JSON [INAUDIBLE]?
DAVID BURNS: And the spec also
says that we have to do HTTP.
We've already got a shim that
people can use, but my gut
feeling is that the Selenium
project is probably going to
be using straight into it, and
then if you're not one of the
languages that the Selenium
project manages itself, you'll
probably go through the shim.
So we're still going to have
that and it just essentially
takes the HTTP, maps it down to
a RTCP connection and goes
from there.
TONY VOELLM: So let me take a
question from the moderator so
those that are watching live and
remotely also get to ask
some questions here.
I can throw this one over
to Malini, I guess.
Do you prefer to run your
automated tests on real
devices or emulators?
MALINI DAS: Well ideally,
we'd like to run
devices all the time.
But we haven't solved the
infrastructure problem of how
do we power cycle
these devices?
And devices are very finicky.
Emulators have been incredibly
reliable as a way of testing.
So we've been running
all of our tests.
Any time you commit code to
Mozilla, we run our tests
against emulators just because
they're easy to put up in VMs.
It's a very easy platform
for us to use.
And it's actually fairly
representative of the
environment that you're
running in.
So for most cases, emulators do
just fine, but we do want
to build out more
device testing.
TONY VOELLM: OK, and
last question.
And then I'll do some
announcements
right after this question.
So please, from the
audience again.
AUDIENCE: This is Quam.
I'm from Android Test
Engineering.
So from a mobile OS testing
perspective, I think there's a
lot of stack between what you're
offering to the app
developer down to maybe the
kernel or the driver level.
How do you solve the problem of
poking layers in between?
Because from the presentation,
a lot of the cases I've seen
are mostly integration level
or functional testing.
How do you poke levels
in between?
And also, in related to the
question you just answered,
there are device specific
characteristics or [INAUDIBLE]
or problems.
When you test mostly
on emulator, how do
you solve the problem?
MALINI DAS: For the first
question, would you
like to take that?
I'll take the emulator one.
DAVID BURNS: OK.
So for the first one, one of
things Malini mentioned during
the talk was that we can set
context and we can switch
between different contexts
within the browser.
So 90% of the time, what
app developers
are going to be using--
well, actually probably
app developers are
going to use it 99.9%.
They're going to be running
everything in the content
layer, which is just your
average web page.
For what we're doing, we have
frameworks like what we call
[INAUDIBLE]
Test and things like that.
And what that does is that will
speak through JavaScript
into the Chrome layer and then
the best use case I can think
of as to how we test the dom.
A lot of the dom stuff will be
happening and that will be
happening in privileged space,
kind of then pushes out to the
content space.
And we need to make sure that
when it manipulates it in a
certain way, that we can then
instrument it that way.
So we can sit in the dom like
in the Chrome space, the
browser Chrome, and then just
see what it's doing, ask it
questions, and then get
information back.
We have--
TONY VOELLM: And with that,
Malini, you have 10 seconds,
and then you two can
chat at lunch.
DAVID BURNS: Yeah.
TONY VOELLM: So you
get 10 seonds.
MALINI DAS: Sure.
So for device specific
flakiness, on the emulator we
are able to distribute to other
people in our community
so that they can use it and
test and make sure that it
works in this environment.
If it fails, then it's
really up to them to
fix those flaky problems.
But when it comes to device
specific problems, you have to
have the device on
hand to fix, to
resolve these flaky issues.
And that's another problem.
But that's why we rely on
emulators so heavily as well.
TONY VOELLM: All right,
thank you.
So we're going to break
for lunch here.
I have two quick
announcements.
If you wanted to do the topic
tables, they're going to be
out in the lobby.
We have these conference rooms,
by the way, the whole
conference.
There's four of them
out there.
If during any of the other
sessions you need to take a
break, you need to get some work
done, you're free to sit
in the four conference rooms
that are out there.
Right now though, they have some
signs posted outside as
to what the topics are
for each room.
So you can grab food and then
figure out the topic.
If you have any dietary
restrictions, you need a
kosher meal, something without
dairy, or something like that,
the people from our great food
service are here in the back.
And you can just ask one of
them to help you out and
they'll get you a
special meal.
And with that, we're going
to break until 1:15.
Lunch is from 12:15 to 1:00.
And then we're going to come
back right at 1:15, so please
in your seat by that time to
hear the next talk from
Expedia on mobile automation in
continuous delivery pipelines.
With that, thank you and
have a great break.
[APPLAUSE]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
TONY VOELLM: Hello.
Welcome back.
This is always one of the
toughest talks of the day.
It's right after lunch.
You're going to be
a little sleepy.
We could try some things.
We could maybe have this
elevator go up or down.
Maybe you'll wake up.
Truck could drive out here.
If everybody could squish to the
middle again just to leave
these easy access seats for
people to go and sit down.
And then if you need the
caffeine, it's still in the
back there so coffee, juice,
soda, you can also just run
laps back there if
you need to.
With that, I'm going to
go ahead and kick
off the next talk.
We're going to do a couple
things in the afternoon here.
So we have two full
length talks here.
Actually we have three full
length talks, and we're going
to have a series of
lightning talks.
And the lightning
talks are really
going to be like lightning.
They're going to be very fast.
And there's going to
be five in a row.
So with that, I'm going to
go ahead and kick off
the next talk here.
It is going to be Igor
Dorovskikh and Kaustubh
Gawande are going to go and talk
to us from Expedia about
mobile automation and the
continuous delivery pipeline.
And so with that, Welcome
up, guys.
IGOR DOROVSKIKH: Thank you.
KAUSTUBH GAWANDE: Just to
introduce ourselves, I'm Igor
and he's Kaustubh.
Oh, sorry I got that
messed up.
I'm just checking if you guys
are awake or already asleep
after lunch.
OK.
Good.
So let's jump right into it.
Before we get started, I
joined Expedia in 2004.
And how many of you have been
in a situation where the
number of automated
tasks is zero?
How many of you have had your
business or the product team
say you engineering team, you
just cannot ship fast enough.
You just cannot go
quickly enough.
How many?
OK, not bad.
OK, all right.
So what I'm here to talk about
is I heard the same thing for
many, many years.
And we're going to talk about
some of the things we have
done the last couple of videos
to try and address both of
those situations.
So if you're in that situation,
stay awake.
It will help.
let's get right into it.
Here's a graph of what
Expedia has done over
the last few years.
So the blue bar is the number
of hot fixes we
used to ship 2005.
And the green bar
is the number of
releases we used to ship.
And the number of the red is the
number of what we called
business AB tests, where a
business can try different
functionality on the site and
let the customers decide
what's right for them.
So in the web world, that's
where everything is going.
You ship fast, you try different
things, you let the
customers decide.
Don't assume you know what they
want or what they like.
And the last is my favorite.
The part where Expedia
stock rises up twice.
I wish the stock rises up 20
times versus the releases were
up only two times but
unfortunately that's going to
have to wait for awhile.
So this is the best [INAUDIBLE]
work on continuous
delivery can do for you.
it can help you ship faster,
more releases, and ultimately
make you rich.
So what does that tend
to look like?
I'm going to talk about test
automation some basics.
because we have a wide variety
of audience here and online
and so I want to make sure
we talk of the basics.
We'll show you what the
continuous delivery pipeline
of tests looks like for Expedia
specifically for our team.
We work on the Expedia front end
site so everything you see
on expedia.com or one of the
Expedia sites, it's our team
that's shipping that,
including mobile.
We do mobile web, mobile apps.
And so we'll talk about little
bit of the test methodology
and some of the unique things
we have done in
the last few years.
and then Igor's going
to talk about the
specific tools we use.
Almost everything we
use is open source,
so it's very cheap.
Free.
And then we'll talk about the
key benefits that we have
gotten as a test organization.
So specifics on what
benefits I have
constantly seen and measured.
So there's a lot of talk in
the industry about agile.
Continuous integration.
Continuous delivery.
Mostly [INAUDIBLE]
are falling.
There's a lot of talk DevOps.
There's a whole DevOps
movement going on.
So this is the best slide I've
found to explain what
continuous delivery
really means.
In 2006, Expedia was agile, but
we didn't really have a
continuous integration
system in place.
Well, then we fixed that.
2006 to 2009, we had continuous
integration in
place, didn't really have
continuous delivery in place.
So it's been a progression.
The last few years, we've been
focused on the continuous
delivery piece.
And my talk is going to
be focused on the--
and Igor's going to cover the
automation tools we're using--
the test automation piece
of continuous delivery.
So basics.
Most people know what a test
automation pyramid is.
What I'm here to tell you is
just one simple thing.
If you are serious about
continuous delivery, get your
test automation pyramid right.
It's super critical to getting
to continuous delivery.
Which means lots and lots,
thousands, hundreds of
thousands of unit tests.
A small number of integration
tests, and a very small number
of UI or end to end tests
as we call them.
It's super important.
I'll show you a good graph.
So just over the last year,
the green is obviously the
number of unit tests
that we evaluated.
Orange the medium or the
integration tests and the red
are the large tests.
For a long, long time,
Expedia's pyramid was inverted.
We were lot of [INAUDIBLE]
tests.
Some integration tests and
very few unit tests.
Man, it was so difficult for
a tester to catch bugs.
Only they like our
new automation.
It was crazy.
So this has been a huge part
of helping us get to
continuous delivery is get your
test pyramid correct.
Measured it and drive
it insanely.
Let's talk about the continuous
delivery pipeline itself.
What does the pipeline
look like?
Before a developer checks in any
piece of code, there are a
series of pre-commit tests that
they need to run and Ari
in the first talk referred
to this.
Most of these are unit tests.
They run in milliseconds and
you can run hundreds of
thousands of them very,
very quickly.
Once it's checked in, you have a
single branch, called trunk.
Again, the Google talk referred
to this as well--
single branch, all developers
are checking
in code in one place.
We run a couple of tests,
sets of tests.
for the mobile team, we use
JavaScript unit tests.
So there's open source
tool called Jasmine.
We use that.
There are plenty
of other tools.
You guys can pick
what you want.
And then we run a series
of trunk small tests.
What are these small tests?
These are basic happy path
functionality that a typical
Expedia user would do.
Search for a flight,
book a flight.
Search for a hotel, book
a hotel and so forth.
So we make sure the basic
functionality is working even
before the build gets promoted
to our live servers.
Assuming the previous tests
pass, it gets promoted to the
next stage where we run
a much broader set
of acceptance tests.
These are a little bit
more involved.
Search for a hotel, change the
dates, click on a few things,
make sure I like all the try
one, try two scenarios are
working, great.
Those are green, then deploy
to an environment
that is very special.
this test environment does not
have any live dependencies.
No live services downstream.
No live connections
to third parties.
one of the most interesting
problems Expedia has to solve
is we have live connections
to hundreds of airlines.
Global distribution systems
which is where the airline
fares get filed.
And you have to talk to them in
real time because airline
availability and prices can
change between seconds.
I'm sure lots of people here
have seen price changes all
the time, right?
And so we are dependent on third
party data in real time.
And imagine trying
to automate that.
One of the hardest
problems I think.
So what we do is we mask all
those dependencies and say we
want to focus on the UI only.
We are going to stub out, or
mark out all the dependencies,
so that whatever we are testing
only covers the UI and
we can find things fast.
The things that our devs
might have broken.
So we run those on the iPhone,
Android, and then we use
Chrome as basically
a base device.
It covers all the other devices
that are out there
that are slightly older, but
they're still in use in Asia
Pacific countries, and some of
the European countries and
things like that.
So we try to cover as many of
customer base as possible.
Keep in mind, none of the test
run unless the previous thing
has passed and is green.
All right.
Some simple rules around
the pipeline.
it has to be green
at all times.
There are hundreds of
check-ins coming in.
Not to the scale of Google,
but at least we have 400
developers checking in
every single day.
The changes conflict
with each other.
Things break.
So it's important that there's a
certain amount of discipline
keeping the pipeline
green at all times.
Otherwise, you cannot get
to continuous delivery.
If a build breaks, which can
happen, it auto-locks the
branch so no more check-ins
can get in.
Let's not pollute the code base
so that we can figure out
which seal has broken
the branch.
And then what we do
is we say, OK.
If the build is broken, we have
to be able to fix forward
in 10 minutes or less,
or else the CL is
going to get reverted.
It's a very, very low tolerance
for people keeping
the build broken, right?
And the reason we come back in
10 minutes is we flirted with
the idea of five minutes, 15
minutes and all that good
stuff and what we realized is
the simplest reason for a
build break is when devs
miss checking in a file
accidentally.
And it takes no more than five
or 10 minutes to get the file
back in and call it green.
There's the build control
where we rotate the
responsibility amongst different
team members,
Developers, testers, we actually
even have PMs do this
so that they understand
why it's important.
If a build is broken, their job
is to get it green in the
10 minute time frame.
And what we have found is
initially, it used to take us
five, six hours to actually get
builds where they need to
be, but now we're down to 10
minutes, 15 minutes intervals.
So we have seen some
good success there.
Let's talk about the oral
methodology that we use in
testing, and then Igor's going
to talk about the specific
tools we used to cover
each of these.
So Expedia's a very agile
company and customer the most
important thing to us.
I think there is no test better
than simulating exactly
what the user is doing.
And these VDD tools--
and Igor's going to talk about
a very specific tool that we
use- like to simulate exactly
the user actions.
And the best part about it is,
you can have PMs, product
managers, business teams
write them because
it's written in English.
You don't need any technical
degrees, you're don't need to
be a superstar SAT to write
the Cucumber scenarios.
Your test engineers, your PMs
can write them as well.
We use really the most for UI
and integration level of
testing because that's
more users scenarios.
At the code level, we really
strongly encourage our
developers to take
a [INAUDIBLE]
approach.
Write the test first, then write
your code, and your code
is not good until
the test passes.
We have had mixed success with
this, so we're still working
on getting it better.
Alright, you have all these
great tests in place now.
Fantastic.
What's next?
Let's take them, put them in
Jenkins which is the build
system that we use.
When you include them in Jenkins
you have to make two
key decisions.
What is the speed of the test
you are running, and how often
do you want to run them?
If they are really, really fast,
you can run them very
often, and ask for them every
single build, so you've got
lots of regression coverage.
If they are really slow like the
large test, or the UI or
the end to end test,
well guess what?
You are going to have to figure
out whether you want to
run them a few times a day, or
once a week or whatever.
And so again going back to Ari's
talk this morning, he
talked about the [INAUDIBLE]
of the problem.
This is why we choose to run
the large test only twelve
times a day. every two hours.
So they do not run as part
of every single build.
Just to go back, what that means
is what you see here are
all the regression test cases
that run except the large
tests that can take
hours to run.
Some of our tests take three,
four hours to run.
You can't put them
in the build.
You got to run them at
a certain frequency.
So we run them every
two hours.
All right, so you have
these tests.
They are in Jenkins.
But, again, what do you
with live decencies?
That's when you use mocking,
stubbing, remove them so that
you can focus on testing
your code, the stuff
that your dev changed.
Once you have this, you need
to have visibility.
People need to know what's going
on with your builds,
with your tests, so we use
some Jenkins plug-ins.
These are called built-in
test radiators.
We're going to show
you some examples.
And we also have a video of how
the process works in real
time a little bit later.
I have been in this situation
way too many times.
You have tests, they run, they
fail, and people ignore them.
They just don't care.
Or they just go whatever, I
mean, it's the tester's job to
go take a look at them, or the
automation engineer's job.
So again, discipline, in terms
of how quickly we react with
to failure, and how quickly
can we fix it.
Again, the video will highlight
how we have done it.
And hopefully, that will be
helpful for some of you guys.
So over to Igor.
He's going to going to talk
about specifically frameworks
we are using for mobile and how
it's integrated into the
whole Jenkins system.
IGOR DOROVSKIKH: Thank
you, Kaustubh.
I enjoyed the speech a lot.
I hope you continue
until the end.
But anyway, my name is Igor.
I'm test lead engineer at
Expedia for the past year.
So I was in mobile department,
like, the
second QA when I started.
And I had to basically solve
what kind of tools we have to
use, and how we can map the test
pyramid to fulfill all
the problems and solve all the
problems we had at that time.
So I'll try to go as fast
as we can because
we're limited on time.
There are other the talks in
this conference about the
specifics of some
of these tools.
But what I tried to focus
on how it fits into the
continuous delivery process.
So I'll start it with Jasmine.
So Jasmine is a J-Unit
task framework.
We use it to, basically, put it
in the top of the pyramid,
which is the functional
BDD kind of--
even though it says unit test,
I still think it's BDD
approach for testing
the JavaScript.
So in order to run the
JavaScript test in the
Jenkins, we use the Jasmine Gem,
which is a Ruby library,
with the CI reporter to generate
J-Unit XML reports
that helps us to draw graphs in
the Jenkins to see how we
progress over the time.
And the good thing about
Jasmine, it complements the
other UI functional test,
which our Selenium.
And in order to write the
Selenium test, we're using
Ruby as the main language and
Cucumber on top of it to write
our test in English.
Kastubh was mentioning that it's
important that the test
has to be written in a language
that everybody
understands, including project
managers, developers, and also
QAs, obviously, right?
Even product team is looking at
the test to see what kind
of coverage do we have.
Later, I will show you an
example of all Cucumber
scenarios, so you have a better
idea for those who have
never have we've seen
that before.
We also use Cucumber with
a Ruby to write our
integration-level test, which
is the API test for mobile
departments, specifically.
And we use a just regular HTTP
library with a JSON parser,
and it works very well for us.
Again, it's all written in
Cucumber in English.
But it fits in the middle
layer of the pyramid.
That's our kind of
integration test.
And for the lower level of
pyramid, we use the TestNG.
Before, we had the J-unit, but
the problem was, J-unit, it
was kind of hard to parallelize
all the tests.
And TestNG solved that
problem for us.
So we use TestNG as our,
primarily, unit test framework
to test our platform, which is
a back end platform for the
whole Expedia.
And as to Kastubh mentioned
earlier, it's important that
the test executes fast, so
we're not going to be
dependent on the live
environments.
And that's when EasyMock, we
use, it's a mocking solution
for our unit test.
And for the UI test, and as well
as the integration test,
we use our custom stubbing
solution.
So that helps to speed our
test execution in the
continuous integration
environment.
OK, so the previous slide was
actually mostly focusing on
the mobile web and mobile
web tools we use.
Here, you can see, we also do
the mobile apps as a part of
our team that we have to test
both on iOS clients and
Android clients.
So specifically for the
iOS, we use the Frank.
It was the first framework that
we started looking at
last year that was supporting
Cucumber.
Like I mentioned earlier, for
us, the BDD tool Cucumber was
the main focus, plus we can use
Ruby, that means we can
reuse a lot of our
test methodology.
That we established before,
even for native clients.
And that's why Frank felt, that
that category, at that
time, and we'll start
using that.
The only part that it I
cannot test with Frank
is the hybrid apps.
It doesn't support the web
views in your native
applications.
So for the Android, we using
Robotium currently.
But we're looking to Kalibash
because Kalibash is very
similar to Frank.
They're pretty much identical.
The Kalibash is basically,
that's what we're looking for
to transfer our test--
in the future migrate
all of them
from Robotium to Kalibash.
And we're start doing that by
already converting end to end
tests, functional tests
for Android.
And because we also have a
pipeline for the native apps
as well, just like for the
mobile web, we tried our
stubbing solution was
a tool called VCR.
And it's not a joke because,
like regular VCR, it records
live responses into the
cassettes, which you can
replay later, and this is
our stubbing solution.
It's open source.
You can find it easily, Google
it, it's a great tool for the
testing native apps if you
need stubbing solution.
OK, so you already probably know
this, guys, that we are
big fans of open source tools
at Expedia because they're
simply free, and a lot of people
contributing to them.
But unfortunately, all of
them has an issues.
So some of you using the
Selenium web driver, either on
iPhone, or desktop browser
like Chrome, Firefox, and
maybe on the Android.
But because we're mobile,
obviously, we're dealing with
the mobile clients.
So specifically, for the Android
Selenium web driver,
we've found an interesting
issue.
Whenever try to test HTTPS
pages, and there's an invalid
certificate on the alive test
environment, your driver will
basically get stuck.
You're going to get blank
page and that's it.
It's a failure.
So the work around was,
basically, generate the
certificate on the regular
Chrome browser and then import
it to the real device.
And it worked very well.
Another problem with the Android
Selenium web driver we
encountered was the drop down
boxes, or drop down options,
they call them.
So we couldn't solve the problem
because the Selenium
driver couldn't handle that.
So we use the Jquery as
the hacky solution.
And it works up to date.
So we use a SIM launcher, it's
a Ruby lightweight server, to
start our iOS simulator
before we start
executing Selenium tests.
And the problem was that that
particular framework didn't
have the flexibility to
rotate a simulator
while you do test execution.
So one of our engineers in
London actually wrote
AppleScript to add that
functionality.
So whenever we run our Selenium
test, we can rotate
simulator and see how our
responsive design will render
our mobile web application
in the web view.
So basically, those problems are
related, obviously, to the
Selenium web driver, both
on the AS and Android.
Now, on the Frank, which we use
to test our native app on
iOS client, we just couldn't
figure out how we're going to
collect the logs if the
application crashes.
So what we used is a third party
framework, Crashlytics,
which is not free,
but it's great.
It gives you a lot
of information.
It's probably the only framework
that's not free that
were using.
But it gives you great
information and logs.
AUDIENCE: It's free now.
IGOR DOROVSKIKH:
It's free now?
There we go.
Awesome.
So Crashlytics enables
us to get the logs--
crash logs--
as well as networking
data to analyze if
the application crashes.
And we also use the
[INAUDIBLE]
I put here.
It's basically, besides
debugging, we try to collect
analytic data.
We use [INAUDIBLE]
to change the configuration
application in the run time.
It helps also to do more like,
I would say, analytic logging
and testing in that matter.
And finally, I've
been mentioning
cucumber many times.
For those who haven't
seen that before.
This is the scenario, written in
[INAUDIBLE] language in the
Cucumber format, which is, if
you guys look at the screen,
it's very English-oriented,
readable.
It supports multiple
languages.
English is not the
only language.
The power of this is that you
write your test in the
business logic as your
acceptance criteria.
And then, all the
parameterization, all the
parameters you have to hard code
into your code like we
used to do with the unit
test frameworks.
Everything is here.
This is the text file, right?
And if you can look at this
specific scenario, where we
tried to test the hotel search
against multiple countries in
the Seattle area and make
sure the image is there.
If you want to just expand
the number of
countries you want to test--
I mean localization--
if you want to change the
Seattle to New York, that can
be done here.
It gives us a flexibility and
scalability, meaning that we
are flexible in terms of
changing tests on the fly
without looking at the code.
It can be done by nontechnical
people like project managers,
QAs, developers, at any time.
They call us Three
Amigos, right?
And another thing, it's
a live document.
It replaces the old test cases
and all tests widths.
So we do not, in Expedia mobile,
we do not have any
test cases.
We do not have test widths.
Cucumber, they call them
feature files,
are replacing those.
Can you guys start the video?
So right now this is the live
demo of how we execute our
mobile web test in parallel.
It's important run tests in
parallel for the speed of the
pipeline, right?
You want to get coverage
as fast as you can.
And this is a UI test,
which are slow.
They are the largest test.
They go end to end around.
And you want to execute
them on as
many clients as possible.
Here in the demo, you can see
there's both the iOS, iPhone
simulator and Android simulator
running exactly the
same test, but what you don't
see on this demo that it would
do in real lab, running
against real
devices on mobile web.
So this is a great example that
parallelization saves you
tons of time, which you will
need if you want to implement
the continuous integration into
your department, into
your company.
This is the sweetest part
of automation, when
you see this working.
I think it's a two
minute video.
AUDIENCE: How many times
have you [INAUDIBLE]?
IGOR DOROVSKIKH: Once.
Which is basically keep
the both tasks.
They are not starting all the
time at the same time.
The Jenkins control that.
So for the purpose of the demo,
we recorded both back to
back simulator started
at the same time.
But they could be, like,
delayed by-- depends
on the check in.
They are triggered
automatically.
OK, so let's go to
the next one.
OK, web build radiator is a
Jenkins plug-in that we're
using at Expedia to monitor the
health of the pipeline and
the real time.
This is the tool that helps
us, basically, to spot the
failure right away and to jump
on it and make sure the
developers fix it as
soon as possible.
Kastubh mentioned 10
minutes period.
It's very fast.
That's why visual
representation is very important.
I'm sure that probably most of
you have been in a situation
where you were running your
tests, and there's a fail
error, and nobody look at it
for a day, at least, right?
So these radiators are running
on big screen TVs around the
office, and you'll see the video
in a few minutes, where
you're going to see that how
it helps to visualize the
health of your pipeline.
It's really important.
And red call is basically a
representation of fail error,
which, you know, attract
attention right away if
there's one.
So this is the, we call
it web test radiator.
This is not a plug in.
It's just confluence page
where we are basically
representing the graphs from
different Jenkins jobs to see
overall picture of a product.
So this is the mobile website
that we are using currently
for the mobile hotels.
And you can see, on the left
side, the graph is much
greener than on the right side
it's because it runs against
stub data and mock data.
On the right side, the test is
running against the live
services, which is the
test environment.
This is live services, which
undergo the a lot of changes
during the day, and that's why
it's much more redder.
So when you are building a
pipeline, it's important to
have both and see what's
going on with live
services and stub data.
OK, let's play the
second video.
It's self-explanatory.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
IGOR DOROVKIKH: It helps after
lunch, right, to wake you up?
So, yes, this is exactly
what we do--
we're responsive to the failures
during execution.
You see what happened?
Developer checking stale code,
broke the test, QA look at it,
and it's not necessarily QA.
Sometimes the project manager,
even the director of the whole
team comes, say Igor, why
is the radiator is red.
So it's very important that
actually the whole team
participates in the process.
And if they spot the failure,
they react to it, fix it, and
it's green again.
And before I give my term back
to Kaustubh, I just want to
make two keynotes.
What I learned for the past
year, what's important in
order to be successful in
terms of embedded test
automation and continuous
delivery, is you always have
to plan ahead.
Always plan your testing,
either it's BDG tests,
functional test, or integration
test, at least a
week or two weeks before
you start a sprint.
Especially, if you are an agile
company, it's very important.
Besides that, it's very
important to understand what
kind of test you will put
into the pipeline.
Not all the tests go there.
Be very selective.
It cannot be large.
For those tests that you think
are the one that is a good
candidate for the automation for
the pipeline, always make
sure you consult with
developers.
Ask a second opinion.
Talk to the project managers if
it's good for the product.
And for those tests that will
be like for more like an
integration environment, or any
other live environments,
that will take longer time--
like large tests for two hours
or three hours of execution,
put them there.
Make sure you segregate,
right?
That's very important.
And now Kaustubh will
wrap it up.
KAUSTUBH GAWANDE: So just a
quick recap of some of the
benefits we have seen
from doing this.
This is just the last
couple of years.
We've increased our
Java release.
Content releases can
go out every day.
But Java releases is the hard
core changes that can break a
lot of things.
We've increased that
almost four times.
The typical regression, like I
said, you're checking a bug,
oftentimes, it takes a day to
find the bug, are day like fix
it on verify it--
well, with this new system, you
just saw, in a matter of
minutes, the code got checked
in, something broke, we
noticed it, we fixed it,
moved on, right?
So worst case scenario, when we
have massive breaks, maybe
four hours to fix the whole
thing end to end, but a lot of
the time it's been minutes that
we can get issues fixed.
We run 100s and 100s of stubbed
regression runs every
day that find all
kinds of issues.
And when you combine them with
regression you run with how
quickly did they get fixed, it
really enables you to do
continuous delivery.
Just from my team's standpoint,
the testing time
we have saved by doing this is
in the order magnitude of 40%.
So something that used to take
us five, six, seven days to
test and ship, we're doing
it like two days or less.
And that's helping us move
faster, get more agile, and,
obviously, the obvious one
is, the moment you have
automation, you can run it on
multiple devices in parallel.
So we have four times the device
coverage we have today
than what we had a year ago.
And as the number of devices in
the industry are scaling,
you really need a solution like
that that you can just
keeps scaling more
and more devices.
That's it, guys.
Questions?
[APPLAUSE]
TONY VOELLM: Great, Thank
you, thank you.
Yeah, I learn a lot.
All I need to do mobile testing
at Expedia is a
cucumber, a radiator, and
some Velcro to stick
my phones on a wall.
So thank you.
In all seriousness, if you have
questions, please do line
up at the mics.
I'll take some questions
off the moderator here.
And let's see, first
question up.
Did you find automated test in a
different language Ruby than
your application--
oh wow, this one is
hard to parse.
It says, did you find automated
tests in a different
language, Ruby, than your
application, limits
developers' collaboration
on tests.
KAUSTUBH GAWANDE:
I'll take that.
So we made a very a conscious
decision here.
Last year, when we were picking
Selenium, we knew we
could run it with either
Ruby or Java.
And we said we'll go with Ruby
although all our devs are
really good at Java.
In fact, it was the developers
who came and told us.
You know, Ruby's as a scripting
language works much,
much better for automated tests
as compared to Java,
which can be a lot heavier.
So it was in collaboration with
devs where we said, OK,
what is the right tool to use,
and we agreed on using Ruby.
Has it limited the
collaboration?
Absolutely not.
We have our devs writing Ruby
tests all the time.
I just got an email yesterday
saying a new dev that joined
checked in 75 new tests
that are now
running in the pipeline.
So I think the devs are actually
really part of the
solution here.
Collaborate with them and find
what tool is right for you.
TONY VOELLM: Thank you.
All right, so we have
two live questions.
So I think you got here first.
You can say your name,
your company, if you
want, and your question.
Any piece that you'd like.
AUDIENCE: Hi, I'm Chris McMann
with Wikipedia, the Wikimedia
Foundation.
I'd like to ask you about
enthusiasm for creating
feature files in Cucumber.
How do you build enthusiasm.
Do you have enthusiastic
contributors for your scenarios?
And how big of a backlog of
scenarios and feature files do
you keep at any given time?
IGOR DOROVSKIKH: So I'll
answer that question.
When I started, I was
the only enthusiast.
But I had full support
from developers.
And I think about that
as a living organism.
You have to infect everybody on
the team, like a parasite,
and make sure the people
all get the disease
of Cucumber, right?
And then what happened is,
a year later, right now,
everybody writing this, let me
give you a good example.
Project managers write an
acceptance criteria in the
Spring in the Cucumber format.
Then developers and QA pick this
up, massage it out, make
it look clean and nice, and
put Ruby logic into a page
object model, and all
tests become live.
So in my opinion, it's only
successful tool when everybody
is using it.
Everybody means everyone
on the team.
If it's only the QAs,
you will fail.
Does it answer your question?
AUDIENCE: Yeah, we can talk
about this some more.
I'm doing the same thing.
IGOR DOROVSKIKH: We will.
TONY VOELLM: The thing was--
let's take this offline
later--
IGOR DOROVSKIKH: Absolutely.
TONY VOELLM: Just so
it's on the mic.
There's one more like, OK the
live question sat down.
I guess they got their
questions answered.
We'll go to the moderator
here.
Does testing mobile web apps on
real devices find more bugs
in testing on a desktop browser
re-sized with fake
user agents?
IGOR DOROVSKIKH: Actually,
it's a good question.
Sometimes we have to test
in real browsers.
And a good example is
a Facebook connect.
So Facebook login feature for
Expedia, because of the
limitation of Android Selenium
web driver and iOS Selenium
web driver, we couldn't launched
the new window to
test that functionality.
So we used the Chrome with the
iPhone user agent where we
actually did some resizing to
test the responsive design and
also were able to launch
the new login
page for the Facebook.
So yes, actually, we tried to
use a lot of open source
tools, lately, just to solve
problems around the driver.
So wait for the APM talk.
KAUSTUBH GAWANDE: I think just
to quickly add, yes, I think
there's a place for both.
You want to use Chrome with
user agent strings.
But you also want to
use simulators
and also real devices.
There's no one size fits all.
You have to do all three because
they find different
types of bugs.
IGOR DOROVSKIKH: I agree.
TONY VOELLM: Great, thanks.
Yeah, so here's a hot question
that's been popping up further
and further on the
interest list.
It says, does testing mobile
apps, sorry, actually, it just
got itself to go down.
Was the UI demo run
with mocked data?
Is your deployment to prod
automatic, or is it gated with
manual intervention?
So how much automation
do you have?
And are you mocking
out your data.
KAUSTUBH GAWANDE: So the reason
why we focused the talk
on the test automation piece
is because we haven't fully
fleshed out of the continuous
deployment piece.
What I do know is that, you
know it used take us seven
days to do a manual test run all
the different languages.
Now it takes one day.
So there is manual intervention,
but it's like
significantly lower.
And one of the things that we
did was, we take screen shots
as the app runs, and we pushed
them automatically to our
localization team who are
the experts in the UI.
They look at that.
And we get feedback in
less than 24 hours.
So we are also using automation
to speed up those
local verification process.
TONY VOELLM: Nice.
OK, I think we have time for
one more question, so we'll
take the live question
over here.
AUDIENCE: Hi, my name
is [INAUDIBLE].
I work for ITA software
by Google.
Thank you for being such
a great customer.
I see that, in Cucumber, you
have project manager writing
the test definition--
well, the test objective
in free form at the
beginning of the test.
And then you have a test
engineer come and write the
test itself.
Over time, with such a large
body of tests, how do you
manage to see tests drifting
from the definition?
So we have an integration
plan.
And we keep that up to date.
Whenever a feature changes, part
of the job of the job of
the QA engineers is to go and
update the existing test out
of there, and also
deprecate tests.
We do internally go in there in
there and deprecate tests
that are no longer,
like, valid.
So the good thing is, you don't
to go to a document and
update the test plan now.
You're actually updating your
alive automation, right?
So which means that it's
going to get run.
If it sits there, you
have a choice.
Either it has to pass, or you
have to remove it so that you
know it's no longer applicable
to the feature.
So it's part of the spring
development process to going
and update that.
IGOR DOROVSKIKH: And we
use tagging for that.
It helps a lot.
We create different profiles.
KAUSTUBH GAWANDE: Yeah,
we have tags.
TONY VOELLM: Very nice.
So thank you, Kaustubh.
Thank you, Igor.
And if you guys want to
suggest a topic table
tomorrow, it's sounds
like Cucumber is
going to be a hot topic.
So thank you, thank
you, thank you.
So now we're going to go ahead
and enter into our series of
lightning talks.
Each one of these is going to be
15 minutes, including Q&A.
And so we're going to keep
these pretty fast paced.
First one up here is David
Rothlisberger.
And I'm going to start a rumor
that, like, he's related to
someone on the Pittsburgh
Steelers so he says he can get
everybody free tickets.
So with that, he is
from YouTube.
And he's going to talk about
automated set top box testing,
which will be fascinating.
DAVID ROTHLISBERGER:
Don't need that.
TONY VOELLM: OK.
DAVID ROTHLISBERGER: So it's
YouView, not YouTube.
TONY VOELLM: Oh, sorry,
oh, YouView.
[LAUGHTER]
DAVID ROTHLISBERGER: So if we
could have my laptop up on the
screens, please?
OK, so at YouView, in the UK,
we make set-top boxes.
And to test our set-top box we
have scripts running on a PC
sending infrared signals--
pretending to be human
user pressing
buttons are my control.
And we check the video output
from the set-top box using
video capture hardware and image
processing to ensure
that it's done the
right thing.
We have other many other types
of test as well, but this is
the most interesting
one to talk at a
conference like this.
So today, what I'm going to show
you is how you might go
about implementing
such a system.
The command line we're looking
at here runs GST Launch, which
is provided by GStreamer.
GStreamer is a set of libraries
and utilities for
handling audiovisual media.
If use Linux on your desktop,
your media player is likely to
be Totem, which is build on
GStreamer, just to give you
one example.
So let's run this.
GST takes as its command line
argument GStreamer pipeline.
So these exclamation marks here,
a GStreamer equivalent
to the shell's pipes.
So this pipeline has a video
test source element generating
a video streaming with
this test pattern.
And its output is piped to this
color space converter
element, which converts each
frame to a format understood
by the next element in the
pipeline, which is ximagesink.
A sink is an element that
consumes video.
And this particular one renders
out to an x11 display.
GStreamer ships with a ton
of different elements,
such as this one.
V4L stands for Video
for Linux.
It's an API for drivers.
And V4L 2 source supports any
device with Video Linux
drivers, such as my laptop's
webcam here.
Or it could also be a external
video capture device.
We can customize the behavior
of individual elements by
setting their properties.
So if I go back to video test
source, I can set its pattern
property here to something
different.
And we can see it's generating
a different video pattern.
Now here's where it
gets interesting.
I'm going to add this template
match element.
Template match is a thin wrapper
around an open source
image processing library
called Open CV.
The CV stands for
Computer Vision.
Open CV is originally
by Intel.
And Template Match takes
a path to an image.
And I'll show you what
image looks like.
It's this white circle on
a black background.
And when I run this, we can see
that template matche is
drawing a red border wherever
it finds a match
in the video stream.
Now the CPU overhead of the
image processing is
introducing a little bit of
jitter into the video stream,
which causes some time stamping
problems for the sink.
So just tell the sink to ignore
timing information in
the stream itself and just
display frames as soon as they
arrive, and it's a little
bit smoother.
Each element can post messages
to the GStreamer bus.
So I'll ask GST launch to
print those messages.
And here we can see that
template match has posted a
message for every frame that
it's processed showing us
whether or not it found a
match and the X and Y
coordinates of that match.
So I hope that you can see how
all these pieces fit together,
and how easy it is to develop
a better capture image
matching system of this type.
All these components are open
source, so we can really take
control of our test
infrastructure.
We're no longer beholden
to proprietary systems.
Now, I consult to a company
in the UK called YouView.
YouView is a joint venture by
the BBC and other major UK
broadcasters and ISPs.
And YouView makes
a set-top box.
To test the set-top box, we've
developed Stb-tester, and
we've open sourced.
So it's built from
these components
that I've just demoed.
So it supports any video capture
hardware with Video
Linux drivers, or, indeed, any
GStreamer source element.
And it uses GStreamer
python bindings.
It allows you to write your
test scripts in Python.
And they look like this.
Set-top box tester.press sends
an infrared signal.
Wait for match, searches for
the specified image, and
raises an exception if
it doesn't find it.
So this script navigates to
our network and internet
settings menu and we've
encapsulated that into a
separate Python functions
so it can be
reused across scripts.
Then we press down until
we find this image.
And I'll just ask my editor to
display those images online.
So I'll remind you, this
is just Python.
And those were just
string literals.
It's my editor that knows how to
display the images inline.
It's [INAUDIBLE]
before anyone asks.
So you press down until the
sub menu is selected.
We press OK.
Then we press right until this
automatic option is selected.
There we press down and we
assert that next button has
been highlighted.
We press OK, and within 30
seconds, we expect to find
this image.
So as you can see,
it's very simple.
It's very readable.
It's entirely procedural, and
it reads much like a manual
test script written
in English.
So non-programmers on the test
team have no trouble
understanding this, and relating
it to their own
requirements, test coverage,
matrices, and so forth.
But at the same time, it is
Python, so it's very powerful,
and you can do anything you
can imagine, really.
So I'll just show you a couple
of quick examples of other
stuff we've done.
This is a video I recorded
earlier of an Stb-tester
script that knows how to
navigate through this double
carousel of pairs.
So I've told it to
find BBC iPlayer.
And now that it's found it,
I've told it to find 4oD.
So again, the red rectangle is
showing us where Stb-tester
you test has found a match for
what it's looking for.
And now it's found 40D.
I've asked it find Demand 5.
So it's looking for this long
thin blue rectangle to
identify the current
selection.
It looks for an image of
unselected player to find
where it needs to go.
And it figures out what buttons
it needs to press to
accomplish that.
And I'll just play that again,
while I'll show you the source
code implementing that logic.
I won't go through it, but it's
just to show you that
it's fairly simple.
It's barely two pages of code.
And most of that is docstrings
and doctests.
Although I have removed
error handling.
But if you're interested in
seeing the full code, I've
posted it on stb-tester.com
as an example.
So essentially, your script
would just call Find Player,
pass in an image of the
unselected player to know what
it needs to find and an image of
the selected player to know
when it's got there.
Here's another example.
This State Machine is YouView's
setup wizard.
So each image in this diagram,
each node, represents a
possible state that
the UI can be in.
And each edge represents an
action that the user can do
from that given state.
This diagram's generated
entirely automatically from
some Python code we've written
to describe the Setup Wizard.
Each image you see is exactly
the same image that Stb-tester
tester uses to identify
that the UI is in
that particular state.
And each edge, each user action,
is a Python function
that carries out that action.
And you can click
on one of them.
And it shows you the source
code implementing that.
And that is all fully
hyperlinked.
So you can draw down as
deep as you like.
Non-programmers can still follow
the flow of each of
these functions here.
So you could write a test script
where you explicitly
call each of these actions in
the order you want them.
Or you could do something
smarter.
We do, after all, have
this representation
of the state machine.
She's it can randomly generate
random walk through it.
Or you could have a test script
that takes a given path
and just tries cutting the power
to set-top box at every
possible state, just to
see what happens.
You know, all this kind of
stuff that's incredibly
tedious to do manually,
especially for
each software release.
I'll show you the full
state machine there.
All done.
So if you look at this in a
certain light, it almost looks
like a wire-framey kind
of UX design document.
And really what we're aiming for
is fully machine-checkable
specifications.
And this is generated from
plain text files.
So it's version controllable,
all that good stuff that we're
used to for our code as
developers we can now have for
our specifications as well.
It's very exciting.
Before I quickly take some
questions, I'll just point out
that stb-tester.com has loads
of documentation.
We've got introductory material,
some videos, to help
you get started.
There's mailing lists, if you
have any questions, and we try
to do the development of it
as openly as possible.
So thank you for your time.
[APPLAUSE]
TONY VOELLM: Great,
thank you, David.
All right, we can go ahead and
pull up the moderator.
If you have questions, you
go to either side here.
In terms of asking questions--
that was very fascinating the
way you did the sort of image
matching and so forth.
I'll start off with a
question of my own--
how complicated does the image
logic have to be, or is it
just very pixel perfect in terms
of matching and looking
for elements.
DAVID ROTHLISBERGER: So as we
capture video directly from
the set-top box, we're not
going through cameras or
anything like that, we have
fairly high fidelity images,
but we do have video capture
hardware that does H364
encoding in the hardware,
so we do get some
artifacts from that.
So our image processing
algorithm does handle that.
And it's got a few knobs that
you can tune either globally
or for a specific image,
if you'd like.
TONY VOELLM: Very cool.
He also reinstalled my faith
in Emacs as being cool, the
fact that it will embed
the images for me.
OK, I'll take a question right
here off of the moderator.
It says, does having images and
test scripts cause flaky
tests when styles change.
DAVID ROTHLISBERGER: So I
wouldn't call it flaky tests.
I'd say that the tests start
failing predictably if the
style changes.
So yes is the answer
to that question.
As you've hopefully gathered
from some of my examples, most
of the actual image matching we
actually pull into library
functions which the test scripts
call themselves.
So very few test scripts
actually read like the one
full of images that I showed
at the beginning.
So it's just a matter of
changing the common functions,
or your scripts not working.
And you can do things like match
any of these images so
that your tests continue to work
across different software
releases if you need to still be
testing a version that's in
production that's got different
images than a
development version.
TONY VOELLM: Nice, clearly this
next question was written
by somebody who's done this.
It says, how do you manage the
image repository without
sucking the soul of some
poor test engineer?
[LAUGHTER]
DAVID ROTHLISBERGER: Well,
again, everyone seems to be
fixating on these images.
To be honest, the main problem
we've had is not with the
image repository.
It's with flaky video
capture hardware.
So I guess the answer to this
question would be much like
the previous one, where the
image repository is fairly
small compared to the number
of tests that use it.
And we also have a lot of
unit tests of our tests.
We've captured a lot
of screenshots.
And any time we want to make a
change to the image processing
algorithm, we run all those
unit tests against our
collection of previously
captured images to make sure
that everything continues
running properly.
TONY VOELLM: Great, is
this a live question?
AUDIENCE: Yeah.
TONY VOELLM: OK,
sure, go ahead.
We have time for
just one more.
AUDIENCE: So I was just
wondering if you used your
framework to measure
performance, let's say, such
as latency, if you click on
something, how long does it
take to go to the other view,
things like that.
DAVID ROTHLISBERGER: So when
we're doing the image
processing on a full sized,
720p, or whatever, full size
video stream, even with a fairly
powerful computer, we
do the image processing
in real time.
So what we do, generally, is
we just drop frames if we
can't process them.
But for testing performance,
we flick a
switch in the test script--
we use Python Context Manager
to have this apply just a
portion of the script--
where we cue up every single
frame, and then we can measure
things like that, like,
smoothness of
animations or latencies.
Latency is a bit difficult
because we've got to take into
account all the various
latencies in the system, the
video capture device, the
encoder, the infrared emitter,
and so on, and so on.
So we're working on it.
We're getting there.
TONY VOELLM: Great, and with
that, thank you, David.
DAVID ROTHLISBERGER:
Thank you, Danny.
TONY VOELLM: That was
very insightful.
DAVID ROTHLISBERGER: Cheers.
[APPLAUSE]
TONY VOELLM: So our next speaker
up is Ken Kania.
He is from Google.
And he's going to talk about
web driver for Chrome.
And so with that, have fun.
KEN KANIA: Thank you.
All right, so thanks Tony.
So to start off,
my name is Ken.
Just a little bit
of background--
I work on the Google Chrome
Testing team, particularly on
the browser side.
So a little bit of
background of how
Chrome testing is broken.
Just real quick, there's
the browser team.
Then there is kind of the
mobile team, then
there's the OS Team.
So I'm primarily on
the browser side.
OK, so basically, I'm going to
be talking today about a tool
that we have supported within
the Chrome team which is
called Chrome Driver, or also
called Web Driver for Chrome.
So you can see up here, it's
very simple problem.
Many of you are probably
familiar with it.
You may be even familiar
with the tool.
So we have, in Chrome, just
Chrome, over 300 million
active users.
This is pretty old data, but
at least that still holds
true, hopefully.
But so we have ever expanding
amount of platforms.
So of course, we just started
with Chrome, with Chrome for
Beta on Windows 2008, expanded
into other desktops, now Mac,
Linux, and then, more recently,
Chrome OS branched
out into Chrome OS, and then
now mobile, Chrome for
Android, and Chrome for iOS.
So the question, the basic
question, is, as a web app
developer, how can I go about
automatically verifying that
the critical functionality of my
app works across all these
different platforms?
So this is a pretty broad
question that you could look
at just in browsers
in general.
But today, this talk, I'm just
going to focus just on Chrome.
So within Chrome, how can I
verify my functionality, the
critical functionality that map
provides across all these
platforms automatically.
And so hopefully, during your
development process, you've
engaged in good unit testing.
Maybe if you're a really
diligent tester, you've also
done some sort of isolated
component testing.
But at the very end of the day,
you want to be able to
have some guarantee that what
the end user sees and what you
go through as an end user
is actually correct.
And basically, the solution to
this problem is Chrome Driver
so a little bit of background.
Chrome Driver follows the W3C
web driver working draft that
some of the Mozilla guys talked
about a little bit
earlier on this morning.
So because of that, it's
interoperable with all the
open source web driver client
libraries, whether its Java,
or Python, or Ruby, or whatever
fits your boat.
It is open source.
Chrome Driver is open source and
maintained by the members
of the Chromium project.
And Chromium, for those of you
who aren't familiar, is just
the project that supports Google
Chrome and another
Chromium-based browsers.
So for the rest of this talk,
I'm just going to describe a
couple things.
Number one, how can you
use Chrome Driver?
What does it actually do?
And number two, what kind of
work we've done to enable
chrome driver Torque, not just
on desktop, but also the other
Chrome platforms, specifically
Android, in this talk.
And then, hopefully, I'll give
you a little bit of a deeper
dive about how exactly Chrome
Driver works, just for you
guys who are curious and maybe
who want to adopt kind of
similar technologies underneath,
depending on what
frameworks you are using.
So to start, web driver, so that
previous slide doesn't
really make whole lot of
sense if you don't
know web driver is.
So web driver is a cross-browser
automation API,
which is primarily for
website testing.
That's what it, historically,
was for.
Now there's become more use
cases, wider audiences using
web driver.
But that was, at least, one of
the main, original, and still
is, the main intention for web
driver, the web driver API.
So it's cross browser.
So this API covers, I listed
couple of things there.
We have browser control, being
able to simulate the user
input, whether it's mouse, or
typing, keyboard, et cetera.
And also, another category I
just put together is, web
stuff, random web kind of stuff,
like being able to find
elements on a page, evaluate
script, evaluate JavaScript,
manipulate local storage
cookies.
So that's basically
web driver.
So web driver is a cross
browser automation API.
And Chrome Driver is essentially
the implementation
of that protocol for Chrome.
Not a very difficult concept.
But so, just to get you a little
bit familiar with those
of you who perhaps haven't seen
a lot of web driver stuff
before, here's a sample test
written in Python using the
open source Python web
driver library.
That first statement, we're just
creating an instance of
Chrome Driver.
We're passing in the path to
our Chrome Driver binary
executable.
We'll talk about that
little bit later.
The second statement is simply
navigating to our test page,
in this case, which is Google.
Then we're finding an element on
that page with the name q.
We're saving a reference to
that element inside this
variable search box.
We send some keys,
which is just
typing, type Chrome Driver.
We submit that form.
And at this time, web driver
will then wait, if there's any
navigation that's occurring
because of that typing, or
because of the form
submission.
And then we actually do the one
actual test part of our
test, which is, we assert that
Chrome Driver is in the title
of the page that we
have navigated to.
And lastly, of course,
we just quit.
That's a simple, really simple
test that hopefully gives you
a feel for what you can
do with the API.
So now, how can we go about
using Chrome Driver?
So an important thing here is
that Chrome Driver, actually,
for desktop, for Windows, Mac,
and Linux, has been around for
quite some time, over a year.
You can easily find that on our
public Chrome Driver site,
code.google.com/p/chromedriver.
Of course, you can just
search for it.
But recently, in the past couple
of months, several
members of the Chromium team
from Android, also from the
browser side, have been working
on a new version of
Chrome Driver, which we just
call Chrome Driver 2.
Pretty creative.
So basically, this is a
re-architecture of Chrome
Driver to be able to span, like
I was talking about at
the beginning, multiple and
more Chrome platforms.
Because we want our testers to
be able to run these tests
against as many Chrome platforms
as possible.
So with this re-architecture,
we were able to support, not
only desktop, as I have listed
at the top, but also Android.
And so I'm happy to announce
that we do have alpha support
for Chrome on Android, Chrome
Driver on Android testing,
with Chrome on Android.
And you can kind of get hold
of that on our website.
I posted a couple of links here
that you can look at.
A couple caveats with
be Android alpha.
Currently, you do need a
special configuration.
You do need a Mac or Linux host
connected via USB to your
actually Android device.
And there's also a couple of
things, like you need Chrome
27, a couple more details that
you can see on the site.
And basically, though, really,
what you need to do is specify
the Android package capability
when you start your session.
And for Chrome OS and for iOS,
unfortunately, if you want to
use that, you just need to
be patient or I want to
contribute.
So you have to wait for that.
So how does it work?
A little bit of background
on how it works.
So there's mainly three
components.
On the left here, I have the web
driver client, which is,
essentially, your test.
It doesn't have to be a test.
Maybe you're writing something
else which uses the web driver
library, which is available in
all those different flavors,
different languages that I was
talking about earlier.
And that communicates, these
are all processes, at least
for Chrome.
So that's one process, your
web driver client process.
And that talks to Chrome Driver,
which is the tool that
we're talking about in this
talk, which functions as the
web driver server.
And that, of course,
communicates over the standard
web driver protocol that we've
been talking about today.
And Chrome Driver talks to
Chrome, controls Chrome, via,
right now, two main ways---
dev tools and extensions.
And so this is Chrome
Driver two.
The old Chrome Driver used a
different Chrome automation
API, which was desktop only.
But so now we're just going to
talk about Chrome Driver 2.
So a little bit about dev tools
and extensions for those
guys who, perhaps, haven't heard
a whole lot about it.
So dev tools is the
same thing.
You can see it easily in Chrome
by just Right clicking
the page, going Left clicking,
Inspect Element.
You'll see that kind of debugger
view that comes up
usually at the bottom
of the page.
And you'll see as
the DOM tree.
You'll be able to see
performance metrics.
You can trace and see the
network activity, what's
taking so, what resources are
taking how long to load and
kind of that break down.
So that's essentially, that
debugger interfaces is using,
basically, dev tools
underneath.
Dev tools, of course, is short
for developer tools.
So we're using that.
And the main benefit behind
using that is, number one,
it's pretty low level.
It used to be mostly implemented
in web kit, which
is now Blink, or has been
split into Blink.
But it's supported on all the
platforms that Chrome runs on,
except for iOS, currently.
You can do, on iOS 6-plus, you
can do dev tools, but it's
only officially supported
through Safari on OSX.
So we can't actually access
that right now with Chrome
Driver on iOS.
The second main tool that we
use, or API that we used to
automate Chrome is the
extensions API that Chrome
comes supported with.
So of course, many of your
guys are familiar with
extensions, the concept
of extensions.
But extensions were meant
to modify or enhance the
functionality of the browser.
And we've taken that, and we've
just of course, plugged
in our own custom extension to
be able to control the browser
through some of the APIs that
are provided there.
But however, since extensions
are desktop only, we've relied
mostly on developer tools
for most of the stuff
that we care about.
So here's just a nice diagram
for you guys who are
interested in kind of what the
overall implementation really
looks like.
So there's three pieces here.
There's the Chrome
Driver Server.
And there's the browser,
Chrome's
multi process browser.
So you have that browser
processing.
You have those two rendered
processes.
You can see, commands will come
into through the HTTP
server from our web
driver client.
It'll be delegated to a
particular session.
So perhaps you might have
multiple web driver clients
talking to this one Chrome
Driver server.
So you might have multiple
sessions.
And these sessions usually
control their own instance of
the browser in this case,
it might be a little bit
misleading, but you can see
each session has a line to
this dev tools server.
Usually, those are separate
browsers.
But the session we will talk to
the dev tools server, which
then delegates down to
particular renderers through
the dev tools agent.
And hopefully, your web app that
you're trying to test is
running in one of
those renderers.
And another one of those
renderers hopefully, we have
the Chrome Driver extension
running to be able to do some
of the extra stuff we need
to do to automate
the browser on desktop.
So what's kind of some of the
future stuff that we're
considering for this tool,
some plans that we
hope to start on?
So, in general, since we have
switched to developer tools
for the basis of controlling
Chrome, that gives us a lot of
more, since it's a little bit
lower level than our old API,
it gives us a lot of really cool
features like being able
to profile what, in JavaScript,
or on your page is
taking up so much memory, what
kind of memory leaks,
possibly, do you have.
Some interesting performance
measurement stuff, access to
the logs of the JavaScript
console.
Talking more specifically
about Android, we're
considering supporting
the upcoming
Chrome-backed web view.
So right now, web view
is, of course, kind
of an Android concept.
We are considering, though,
supporting, when Chrome
supports or powers that web
view, to be able to integrate
with that and actually
test that.
We are considering also running
the driver on the
device, instead of requiring
that host configuration I was
talking about earlier.
For iOS, it's a little bit
tricky, as I mentioned,
Because of the limitations just
in the UI web view, how
we're using the UI web view
in Chrome for iOS.
And we're still in pretty early
stages of development,
kind of planning, so not a
whole lot to say there,
unfortunately.
So that's basically the end of
what I wanted to talk about.
So if you're interested in using
ChromeDriver as a tool,
we have ways that you
can file bugs.
I have that link up there.
Also, there's a user forum,
a public user forum.
And of course, since it's all
open source, we love to have
third party patches,
contributions, you name it.
That concludes my talk.
Thank you.
[APPLAUSE]
TONY VOELLM: Great.
Thank you, Ken.
You've come a long way since
writing games based on the
Power Puff Girls.
That's what happens when they
tell me these little tidbits.
It looks like we may have
time for one question.
If there's not a
live question--
OK.
Let's go ahead and take one live
question, and then we're
probably going to just move
on to the next talk.
So please.
AUDIENCE: For some time, Firefox
has been able to
control the profile.
I think Chrome's handling
of profile now
has parity with Firefox's.
And I don't think it's part of
WebDriver specification.
Is that something that you're
talking to Mozilla about, and
will it continue to support,
manipulating profiles in Chrome?
KEN KANIA: Right.
To start off, we are not
currently talking with Mozilla
about that.
But we are interested in maybe
not supporting profiles per
se, but there's a distinction
in Chrome--
I'm not sure about the
other browsers--
between your user
data directory
and also your profile.
So for ChromeDriver, we do, in
the tool, allow you to specify
a custom user data directory,
which maybe has several
profiles already set up.
Be able to do stuff like that.
But we don't have any way now
to dynamically, through that
WebDriver API, create new
profiles, or edit profiles, or
anything like that.
TONY VOELLM: Great.
Thank you, Ken.
KEN KANIA: OK.
Thanks.
[APPLAUSE]
TONY VOELLM: Our next speaker
up is Vojta Jina.
He likes funky jazz, and he has
a very action-packed talk.
He's probably going to
run right to the
middle, or to the end.
So you probably won't have
questions, and we'll just go
right on into the next talk
right after he's done.
Here you go.
Great.
Thank you.
VOJTA JINA: Thanks.
This conference is about
automation in testing.
So I assume you guys are one of
those crazy people who try
to automate everything.
Even if it takes more time than
to do it manually, we
write a script for it because
that's what we believe in.
And that's cool.
I mean, Angler team,
we are the same.
Like we basically try to
automate everything.
So from simple things like
automatic deployment, to
website, to things like--
we have CI server, and whenever
I push some code to
GitHub, it automatically builds
Angler, runs all the
tests on different browsers,
and screams at
me and if it fails.
Or every release has
a change log.
That's basically a list of
changes, like list of new
features, back fixes,
breaking changes.
And you know what?
We generate even that.
We have a convention for Git
messages, and then there's a
script that basically generates
the change log based
on the Git history.
My favorite example
is Angler docs.
So let me actually show
you the docs.
If you go to docs.angler.js.org,
there is
Angler documentation.
This is, for instance, API docs
for ngClick, which is a
directive in Angler.
And down here, here's
an example.
Here is a source code for that
example, and then there's a
live preview, like demo, where
you can actually play with it,
and see how it works.
Cool.
Of course, the whole
documentation is generated
automatically.
But the thing I want to show you
is the second tab, which
says, "End to end test." That
is basically an example for
you how you could possibly
test such a code.
Right?
Like end to end test for that.
But what do we do with that?
We extract all these tests, and
then we round them as a
part of the build.
Let me show you that.
So it looks like something
like this.
Now you can see it's basically
going through the whole
documentation, and checking
whether these
examples still work.
This is really awesome, because
before we did this, it
would be like-- all the time, it
would happen-- like someone
would email me.
Like, hey, man.
Your docs example for
HTDP doesn't work.
Like, ah.
Cool
I even didn't know there was
an example for that.
But now with this, you don't
have to think about it.
And if you break it, it
will scream at you.
We basically tried to
automate everything.
Let me kill this guy.
And we do testing a lot.
We rely on testing a lot.
And, therefore, we want to make
sure that our testing
story is a really efficient.
That's pretty much why we did
Karma, which is, I would say,
a test run that fits
our needs.
Because we did we made
it for ourselves.
And that's what I want
to show you now.
I want to show you this test
run that we use to test
Angler, and pretty much to
test any JavaScript.
So let's do a demo.
So Karma is an MPM package.
So assuming you have no JS, you
get install it through and
MPM Install Karma.
And then, the first thing you
need in order to start, you
need a configuration file, which
is basically for Karma
to know about your project.
Basically what are the
files of the project?
What browsers you want to use,
which testing framework you're
using, and stuff like that.
To make it simple, you can
generate this config file by
Karma in it.
And it would ask you a couple
of questions, like what
testing framework you want
to use, which browsers,
and stuff like that.
And it will generate the
config file for you.
Or if you are using Grunt--
Do you know, guys, Grunt JS?
It's a really awesome task
runner for JavaScript.
So if you are using Grunt,
there's a Grunt plug-in for
Karma that allows you to
configure Karma through Grunt,
and you don't need this
configuration file at all.
All right.
For This demo, I'm going to be
using Angler codebase, which
already has this config file.
So we can start it.
I can do karma start.
What's happening in the
background, it starts a
browser that I told it in
the config file that
I want to be using.
You know, we can forget about
the browser for now.
But the important thing is that
there is a real browser
in the background that
karma will use to
actually executive a task.
That's something I want to
actually talk about, because
you can execute--
you can test [INAUDIBLE]
browsers.
You could do like
OJS and Rhino.
But for us, it was really
crucial to use real browsers,
because if you know Angler,
there's tons of like
components, and custom
directives, and stuff.
And that's tons of
DOM manipulation.
And we need to DOM API.
We need to test these things.
So we need a real browser
for that.
Plus, there are so many
inconsistencies between
different browsers.
And honestly, JavaScript itself,
as a language, it's
not that bad.
It's pretty consistent.
But the DOM API, that's what's
most of the issues.
So again for us, we need
a real browsers.
Plus, the third thing, there
is a good advantage once
you're using real browsers.
It basically communicates
through HTDP in [INAUDIBLE]
circuit, so it means you
can use any browser.
You can test your phone, your
tablet, TV, Playstation,
whatever you want.
OK.
Let's go to source code.
Another thing that's happening
in the background is that
Karma is now watching all the
source files of my project.
And whatever I hear is like
cache factories and service in
Angler, it's not important
what it is.
But I'm going to save the file,
just press Command-S.
And you can see that Karma
immediately sees that, and
starts executing
all the tests.
You can see it executed over
1,800 of unit tests in, like,
three seconds on the
real browser.
I mean, three seconds is not
bad, but if you have a huge
project, it can be more.
And our goal is to get this
instant feedback so I can run
these tests all the time.
Because what I really do during
development is, like, I
want to run these tests
on every Save.
That's why we have
this feature.
We call it d-describe
and [INAUDIBLE].
On the right side,
that's my test.
I'm not sure if you realize
the syntax.
It's a Jasmine testing
framework.
I should mention that Karma
is agnostic of testing
frameworks.
You can use it with any testing
framework you like,
pretty much.
There is an adapter for
[INAUDIBLE], Mocha, Jasmine,
and Nodeunit, and stuff.
We at Angler are
using Jasmine.
That's why this example
is in Jasmine.
But you can use anything else.
Describe in Jasmine basically
means, like, defining a test
suite, a list of suites.
And it means defining
a single test.
And what I can do, I can
focus these things.
I can put d-describe.
And now when I say, if you can
see, it immediately executes
just this suit.
So it's even faster.
Now, it executed only 24 of
these 1,800 unit tests, and it
was like, I don't know,
a few more seconds.
And so the goal is--
The thing about this that's
important is it gives you like
new workflow.
It's basically like using test
as a development workflow,
where you basically can stay in
your text editor, and you
don't have to move back and
forth between the browser and
your text editor to see
how things work.
Because what I can do--
let's say in this
test, I can do--
I don't know--
console.log(cache1.) Whatever it is.
Maybe give me size.
It gives me error, undefined,
whatever.
OK, so there's no size.
So that gives us info.
The thing is that I just saved
the file, and I immediately
see in the console the results
from the real browser.
So I don't have to go to the
browser to do these things.
This is really important for the
workflow, because you can
stay in the browser.
Sorry, in the text editor.
One more thing that I want to
mention is that there's no
support from the text editor.
I'm using Sublime.
You can use Emacs, Vim,
whatever you want.
Because the only thing that
the text editor in this
workflow does is saving files.
I got one more thing that
I want to show you.
And that's debugging.
Because what I can do, I can,
inside this code, if I want to
actually use a real debugger, I
can do this, and guess what.
I can go to the browser that I
had somewhere in background,
and I have debugger.
I can watch variables.
I can see call stack.
I can step into functions.
And this is something that is
not a feature of Karma.
It's just the browser.
Like most of the modern
browsers, they have debuggers.
So it only allows
you to use that.
And again, you don't need any
support from the text editor
to do that.
If you happen to be using
something like WebStorm, or
some better IDEs, you can even
configure it to do this do
debugging directly
from WebStorm.
So you can put break
points and stuff.
You even don't have to leave
your IDE for debugging.
All right.
There is tons of
other features.
Like, it can do code coverage.
It can [INAUDIBLE] a file
so you can develop.
You can use CoffeeScript and it
will compile CoffeeScript
on the fly.
There's a Dart plug-in
for testing Dart.
All kinds of other plug-ins.
But I think the most important
feature is the workflow, that
you can run tests, and instantly
get the feedback.
That's the main thing,
so that's what I
wanted to show you.
If you like it, you can go
to GitHub check it out.
It's open source, so [INAUDIBLE]
pull request.
And as I said, we're probably
running time pretty soon, so
I'm not sure if we are going
to have questions.
But I'm going to be here today,
and whole tomorrow.
So find me, and I'm more than
happy to talk to you guys
about pretty much anything.
TONY VOELLM: Thank you, Vojta.
Actually I think we may have
time for one question.
I have to say I was really
happy that you only typed
karma start.
And you never typed karma end.
I was a little worried if that
was going to happen, because--
VOJTA JINA: Oh.
I did Control-C.
TONY VOELLM: I tried to
make everyone up here.
OK.
OK, with that, we can take a
live question, if someone has
a live question.
Or we can go to the Dory.
Or we can move ahead.
OK.
I got a question here.
The number one question.
You probably saw this, actually,
in the UI, too.
It says, "Why was Karma renamed
from Testacular?"
VOJTA JINA: OK.
I didn't expect that
question at all.
I don't think I want to answer
this question on the stage.
But the good thing is that now
typing Karma is way faster
than Testacular.
Because especially, if you are
using a regular layout,
keyboard layout, it's
like really--
it's really easy to type.
TONY VOELLM: Great.
All right.
Thank you, Vojta.
Than you very much.
VOJTA JINA: I think I would
like to close this with a
quick story.
I think we have two minutes,
so I can do that.
TONY VOELLM: 30 seconds.
VOJTA JINA: 30 seconds?
I will do it quickly.
Because I'm really happy
about that thing.
There is a project called
YouTube on TV.
It's basically if you have
Playstation 3, there's a
YouTube app, and it's
written in Angler.
And a few months ago, we were
helping the team to debug some
performance issues, and I
noticed that they have like 90
or 100 unit tests.
I was like, well,
that's not many.
So I asked them, like,
guys, why don't
you write more tests?
And when they showed me like how
painful it was to, like,
add a new test in their
[INAUDIBLE], and how slow it
was to run these tests,
I was like, OK.
I understand that.
And so the next week, I helped
them to set up their
environment with Karma.
And we actually set it up
to even run it on real
Playstation.
And it was really cool, because
in a few days, maybe a
week, I got an email from Tyler,
one guy on the team.
And he was like, Vojta!
This shit is awesome!
Like it completely
changed our life.
We test drive everything now.
Believe me or not, but after a
week or something, they had
over 400 unit tests.
So it basically took them about
a year to write 100
tests, and then they wrote
like 300 tests
in just a few days.
The point is that you should
spend time figuring out your
workflow and your environment.
Find the right tools for you.
It doesn't have to be Karma.
I don't care.
Use whatever works
for you guys.
But it's so much worth
it to spend the time.
Because once you do it, it will
save you tons of time.
TONY VOELLM: Cool.
Thank you.
[APPLAUSE]
TONY VOELLM: Next up here we
have Patrik Hoglund, who is an
avid drummer, which probably
comes in quite handy when he's
banging his head against this
automated video quality
measurement system.
So with that, Patrik.
PATRIK HOGLUND: Thank you.
Thank you.
Right.
So I'm going to talk about
automated video quality tests.
That is a problem we run into
with the WebRTC project.
First, has anyone heard
about WebRTC before?
There's a couple.
OK.
Well, for the rest of you, no.
WebRTC is a web standard that
is being developed right now
for video and voice chat
built into the browser.
We are implementing this
right now in Chrome.
And also, Firefox and Opera
are implementing this web
style in here.
WebRTC gives you the possibility
to, in a web page
with JavaScript, acquire users'
webcam and microphone,
with their consent, of course,
and send it over the net
directly between the
participants.
So it uses peer-to-peer
technology.
And all the stuff is built into
the standard, so it's
really easy to write a video
chat application that works,
regardless of LIT, and
firewalls, and other things
that can be in the way.
OK?
So the Chrome implementation of
this is done in Stockholm,
and Mountain View,
and in Kirkland.
And I work in the Stockholm
office with this project.
So we wanted to test this.
But to explain what we need to
test, I'm going to explain
briefly how a WebRTC
call works.
This diagram here, as you can
see, is a very simplified
description.
So what happens here is that
we can imagine we have two
browsers on two different
machines somewhere.
And then it is up to the web
page to implement that
application part there,
as you can see.
And implement a signaling
solution.
The point of the signaling
solution is to first figure
out like, who would
you like to call
with WebRTC, for instance?
And [INAUDIBLE]
implement like a contact list,
or random, or whatever.
And also the signal resolution
exchanges the information that
is needed to set up the call.
For instance, what code
[INAUDIBLE] support and so on.
We're going to gloss over that
part completely, and start
focusing on number two.
You can see it on there,
which is media.
When media starts flowing.
OK?
Given that we set up a call,
how do we test it?
So one of the goals we set out
to do here was to set up a
call and measure the
video degradation.
Because obviously, when we send
video over the internet,
we're going to have
to compress it.
Also in WebRTC, there's a ton
of built-in algorithms for
bandwidth estimation, and like
adapting the encoding
parameters to how much bandwidth
you have, or how
loose you connection is.
Or, as I like to see it as a
test engineer, a lot of things
that can go wrong.
A lot of things that
can break.
So we wanted to measure the
video quality to the console
at the other end of the call.
We wanted those measurements
to correspond to user
perception as much
as possible.
What do I mean by that?
Well, basically if a user would
think it looks bad, it
should get a low score.
And if it's artifacts that a
user doesn't really notice
that much, it shouldn't affect
the score too much.
We wanted this thing to
run continuously.
We wanted it to be a reusable
toolchain with small tools
that have well-defined
tasks as much as
possible to make it reusable.
And we wanted the implementation
work to be a
self-contained unit
so we could hand
it off to an intern.
And that is precisely
what we did.
We handed it off to our
intern, [INAUDIBLE]
from Bulgaria.
And she implemented it,
and it worked great.
So that's why I'm here to share
with you an overview off
what goes into making
a tool like this.
We're going to obviously gloss
over a lot of details, but
hopefully we'll give you an idea
of what we need to do.
OK.
When we started this thing, we
already had the tests, which
could launch a browser, open two
tabs, launch a small C++
binary, which is a signaling
solution, and have the two
tabs set up a WebRTC call.
Set up a video, it gets fed
into a regular video tag.
HTML5  tag.
We had some fake webcam drivers
on all major platforms
so that we could basically feed
known input video into
the webcam and have it look
like the webcam to WebRTC.
We also have implementations
of the peak signal to noise
ratio and structural similarity
algorithms.
I'm not going to go into detail
what those are, but
supposedly together to give a
pretty good picture off the
video quality.
Then the first problem to solve
was, how do we record
what is coming out of the video
tag on the other side?
First, we considered screen
scraping solutions where we
scraped the pixels on
the screen, and
that kind of thing.
But fortunately, we were able
to avoid that because you
would have had to make
a platform-specific
implementation of that.
Instead, it turns out you can
take a canvas tag, and tell
the canvas tag, hey,
canvas tag.
Capture the pixels that
I'm displaying in that
video tag right now.
We hooked up to a JavaScript
timer that tries to capture at
30 FPS, or as fast as
it can, really.
And then we ran into some other
problems, like we can't
write the frames to disk from
the JavaScript environment, so
our intern wrote a Python server
that we've talked to
using web circuits.
And then the Python server
writes them to disk.
It's a bit more [INAUDIBLE].
So after running this, you end
up basically with a couple of
hundred of image
files on disk.
And then we run a small tool
to consolidate those
into one YUV video.
That is raw video.
All right.
But there's still some problems,
like we have no idea
where the video starts.
Like when we run the tests, we
don't know where we'll start
and end the video because the
driver is just going to loop
it over and over.
Since the algorithms I talked
about, they're only going to
compare frame to frame,
and give you a score.
You need to compare the right
frame in the output video with
the right time in
the input video.
Otherwise, you're going to
get the wrong score.
Even if you solved that
synchronization problem with
the camera driver, what if we
dropped the first two frames?
Then we would compare frame
and the output video with
frame and minus two in
the input video.
The score would be very much
punished for something the
user wouldn't have noticed.
So that's not good.
If the JavaScript happens to
not capture all the frames,
because I sure don't know
hard to predict how fast
JavaScript will run.
The trick is to encode barcodes
into the input video.
So you can see a bar strip
at the top there.
It is going to move along
with the video.
You see three examples of the
video here because this is
what our test looks like.
What's going in, what's coming
out from the other side, and
the camera is keeping up
capturing the stuff there.
How will that help us?
Well, it will make it able for
us to encode a unique ID in
each frame in the input video,
and then later find out which
frame we actually capture
on the other side.
The encoder user uses--
I'm going to go quickly through
these details-- so the
encoder uses a library called
Zebra Crossing.
It can generate barcode
for us.
So we generate a bunch of
barcodes in rising numbers,
like one to whatever.
Then it uses an ffmpeg to
convert those to YUV.
Then combine the YUVs
to a barcode movie.
So that's going to be a very
narrow movie with a moving
barcode in it.
And then we can stitch that
together with an input file of
our choosing and create
a video such as the
one we saw over here.
Our setup of the feed that
we do into a fake webcam.
Have WebRTC acquire
that webcam.
Then we also test that our
device acquisition code, and
all that stuff, works for
the operating systems.
We capture what we get on the
receiving side with the video
camera thing I talked about.
Decode the barcodes, and
then we analyze it.
The analysis step is the
next slide that I'm
going to talk about.
First, the barcode decoder.
What does the barcode
decoder do?
It takes the YUV movie we
produced in the capturing
step, splits that into a bunch
of PNG files, because that is
all Zebra Crossing
understands.
Again, using ffmeg, run it
through Zebra Crossing and,
then we've got a bunch
of numbers.
So our tools is going
to produce
a file called Stats.txt.
That is a mapping for each frame
in the output video,
what is the corresponding frame
in the input video?
That is used in the final
analysis step here.
So now we have this thing that
takes the original video, the
captured video, and
that mapping.
And then it's just going to
run PSNR and SSIM on each
frame, using the map [INAUDIBLE]
that's .txt.
What we end up with is
something like this.
It is a bit hard to see here in
the graph, but what you can
see in a graph is that first
those lines that you see in
there, that is the distribution
of scores.
So each frame is scored
individually.
And then the big thick line
in the middle, that is the
average for that
particular run.
What you can also see, or maybe
not, is that we are
around four to six decibel peak
signal to noise ratio,
which I would say is reasonable
for internet
transmitted video.
The big dip on the right there,
by the way, is our
regression, it looks like.
And when it goes back up again,
that is where the
regression was rolled back.
For the structural similarity,
similarly, we get consistent,
I think, about 0.926 out
of one in the score.
When we put the whole thing
together, we end up with that.
As you see, it's a fair amount
of stuff in there.
The parts I mentioned earlier,
like you have your input video
that you just need to prepare
and encode once.
And then when you run your test
continuously, you feed
the same video into the webcam,
and you run the tests,
as in our case.
And then you do the necessary
conversions so that you get
the YUV file.
And you decode the barcodes.
And you end up with something
you can analyze, and produce a
score from that.
So that concludes my talk.
Thank you for you time.
[APPLAUSE]
TONY VOELLM: Thank
you, Patrik.
So if you have a live
question, you
can go to the mic's.
I see somebody up there.
And then we can also
pull from the Dory.
So why don't we go live
first, please.
AUDIENCE: Hi.
So a question about
the output frames.
Does it ever happen that you
lose output frames because you
couldn't decode the bar coding
where the video quality is so
low you can't decode it?
PATRIK HOGLUND: Yeah, so
it hasn't happened
very much for us.
When it has happened, it is
because WebRTC is completely
broken and the CSS rendering
black or garbage or whatever.
So if the image gets so
distorted that even the
barcode library can decode the
barcodes, then the image is
probably completely broken.
So that is the conclusion you
can draw from that, really.
TONY VOELLM: Let's pull one
from the Moderator here.
Do you test AV sync issues?
If yes, how do you do it?
PATRIK HOGLUND: No, we don't.
So I guess that answers
that question.
No, but I mean that is almost
maybe something you can extend
the test to.
And by the way, there is a tape
for all of you here that
all this code that we have
written for this is open
source and check in through
the Chrome repository.
So if you want to use it,
know yourself out.
So if you want to write
something like that, you can
probably do it.
TONY VOELLM: Very cool.
Let's take another one here.
Are you able to measure the
video quality while streaming
at various network conditions?
PATRIK HOGLUND: No, but
we would love to
be able to do that.
Presumably when you have a lot
of packet loss or a burst of
packet loss or a lot of delay or
whatever, you would expect
the bandwidth estimation
algorithms to adjust
accordingly.
And then you should
see probably that,
OK, 2% packet loss.
Well then we got maybe 34
in PSNR or whatever.
And nothing can keep your stuff
working for all the customers.
And I think this is something
people don't do enough of.
Verifying that, OK, it looks
great on Google's office
network, but it will not
work in an ADSL line
in India, for instance.
So we have plans for that.
TONY VOELLM: Interesting.
We have time for one
more live question.
I think you got up here
first, or did you?
Toss up.
OK, left.
Please, what's your
name, where do you
work, and your question.
AUDIENCE: I'm [INAUDIBLE].
I'm from Amazon.
So the question I had
was why barcodes?
You might as well have written
numbers in there.
PATRIK HOGLUND: Yeah,
absolutely.
Well, we had a library for it,
like I said, Zebra Crossing.
And I think barcodes are
relatively resistant to normal
artifacts when you encode
and decode a video.
I mean, we don't want
that to be flaky.
And it has turned out
to work very well.
TONY VOELLM: If they had used
numbers, then they would have
had a Cookie Monster
instead of zebra.
OK, thank you, Patrik.
Thank you.
Thank you, Patrik.
PATRIK HOGLUND: Thank you.
[APPLAUSE]
TONY VOELLM: Got ahead
of myself.
Actually next up is going to be
Minal Mishra from Netflix.
And he's going to talk about
when bad things happen to good
applications.
MINAL MISHRA: Thank you.
Good afternoon, everyone.
I hope you can hear
me all right.
I'm Minal, and I've managed
a few of the key
platforms in Netflix.
To start off, did everybody
know that
yesterday was Earth Day?
So happy Earth Day
to everyone.
I'm going to use Earth science
to kind of introduce my topic.
So let's start with
what makes Earth a
successful life system?
One of the most widely accepted
theories of plate tectonics.
Plate tectonics, for the
uninitiated, is basically
large scale movements in the
Earth's lithosphere.
It is not limited to just the
formation of mountain ranges
and ocean trenches, but it also
postulates that it is
very essential for life
to succeed on Earth.
Some of the tasks that are
accomplished by tectonics are
replenishment of depleted
nutrients, generation of
magnetic field, which prevent
the violent solar wind from
affecting Earth, and stabilizing
the temperature of
the planet by recycling
carbon dioxide.
So what is the similarity
between a successful life
system and a successful
software application?
A successful software
application needs to adapt and
constantly innovate, depending
on market demand.
This means that there is
constant change in every layer
of the stack.
And haven't we all seen that?
With the success of the mobile
platforms, we know that these
platforms need to constantly
and rapidly innovate.
But every coin has
a flip side.
So does this churn.
In the case of life supporting
plate tectonics, we have seen
catastrophic side effects, like
volcanoes, landslides,
earthquakes.
And while we have come to accept
these side effects, we
have also made tremendous
progress in the technologies
that are used to determine and
drive these events with high
rate of accuracy.
Thankfully, we in the software
industry don't have to deal
with anything of
that magnitude.
But software development, the
dynamics, go hand in hand with
its own side effects that
we refer to as bugs.
And we have gone and developed
a lot of systems that help
catch these bugs sooner
than later.
I'm going to talk about one said
system that, at Netflix,
has helped us catch these
bugs, which is
our endurance systems.
And I will basically also
explain, discuss some case
studies which will help me
illustrate how bad things that
are out of your control can
affect a good application.
So let's start with what is
the motivation behind
endurance test for a consumer
application?
The user expectation, right?
We all, as users, have began
to use mobile applications
rather than website, because
of the magical experience
offered by it with greater
performance.
The performance of application,
again, varies
from platform to platform and
also on the application
architecture.
We also face unpredictable
user behavior where user
behavior might invoke code path
that might affect the
performance of the
application.
And finally, for a media
applications like Netflix
where users spend at
least 30 minutes--
we don't have TV shows which
are shorter than that--
a simple memory leak can lead
to suboptimal experience for
our consumers.
So like every other automation
team, we went ahead and built
a functional automation
system.
The architecture that you see
here is very similar to a lot
of the client automation
architecture that are
available today.
However, we built a custom
in-house solution basically,
which could scale to multiple
different platforms that our
application is available on, and
also build reusable parts.
So certain platforms
use certain parts.
But overall, this is the
architecture of one such
platform using those
reusable parts.
And of course, with the
continuous integration mantra,
we put our functional test
behind the continuous
integration system on Jenkins.
The thing with the custom
solution was that it was
modular enough that we could
basically develop endurance
tests on top of the system
with minimal effort.
And then with the power of
Google Spreadsheet, we were
able to build a reliable
endurance reporting system.
Obviously, we are a client
automation team.
We don't want to deal too
much with databases,
server, and the cloud.
So why not use Google
Spreadsheet?
So what do we measure?
We basically split performance
counters into three parts.
Platform specific, which is
memory utilization of the
platform itself, CPU utilization
metrics that is
provided by platform.
The second being video playback
statistics where we
measure things like the playing
video bit rate and
audio bit rate, which is again
dependent on network
conditions and the hardware
itself that you're
playing back on.
The frames rendered dropped.
The buffer size, which
is important.
And rebuffer count, which is
really important from a
consumer perspective, since it
determines the quality of
experience.
The third piece is, of course,
the application metrics where
we measure start up time
for the application.
In order to give a good consumer
experience, you need
to have faster start up times.
And we also measure certain
transition times between pages
as the users navigate
through them.
So CI for endurance.
You can see the image right
there, which is pulled from
the performance metrics
that you normally
receive from a car.
Like a lot of people in the Bay
Area where I live, I also
drive a hybrid car.
And what I've realized is the
continuous feedback on my
driving performance has helped
me become a better driver.
So we took this idea, and we put
it for our application to
continuously measure the
performance of our
application.
This also ensured that
performance is treated as a
feature and not as
an afterthought.
And for the test team's benefit,
we can then ensure
that our endurance tests
are current.
But you know what they
say about old habits.
They die hard.
I realized that when I came back
from a long vacation and
I began driving my car, I easily
slipped back into the
old bad habits.
And I felt that having looked at
my performance train over a
period of time, I could easily
correlate the mistakes that I
was making with the trends
and be easily
able to remember them.
So we decided to build trend
shots on top of our continuous
integration for the endurance
tests where we use simple
statistical functions to kind
of track progression over
build for the different
performance counters.
And we looked out for the
statistical outliers.
Using this system, we were able
to find several bugs that
were introduced by
our developers.
But to justify the title of this
talk, I'm going to talk
about two such case studies
where we found issues using
this system that were not
introduced by our developers.
The first one, last year,
Netflix realized that the API
service that delivers data to
hundreds of different devices
needed to be rearchitected.
The main reason behind that
was the fact that one size
fits all model could not work
with low power devices.
So the direction that we moved
to was giving the controls to
the devices to be able to tweet
the response so that you
get just enough response
data to render a
rich UI for your platform.
As I mentioned before, we were
tracking the start up times on
our platform over different
builds.
And this chart over here
basically shows you the
different start up times to the
different experience that
you might launch into.
One is the regular experience
and the other is the kids
experience.
What we realized is, after a
point, once we switched to the
new version of the API, the
start up time to the kids
browse screen increase
by about 25%.
And we were able to look at
this build and immediately
notify our partner team.
And over a period of time, we
were able to fix it before it
actually affected our
end consumers.
The next example is
even more scary.
Because we got notified of this
issue three days before
our release.
This was a release that was
scheduled in December when we
were releasing a ton of
promotional features for our
new original series, "House of
Cards." It's a great show, if
you haven't seen it.
So the other thing that we also
do is, like I showed in
the application stack itself,
like we are dealing with
bleeding edge services.
We also deal with the bleeding
edge ADK from our partners.
So like a good consumer of the
platform ADK, we were the
first one to take
the ADK version.
The top graph basically shows
you the application memory
that is provided by the counters
in our application.
And it kind of remained
consistent over
the last six months.
You can see it's kind of
remained flat in terms of how
much memory it is utilizing.
The bottom chart shows you the
available native memory, which
is the counter provided by the
system, which tells us how
much memory is remaining.
And you can see, as we switch to
the new version of the ADK,
you can see the mountain ranges
are there where there
were times when memory
hit rock bottom.
And there were times when
it remained constant.
But while testing this, we found
a functional bug, which
was more worrisome where the
playback would crash every
time you changed the audio
stream, which is a big deal
for our customers.
And we realized we were
able to track this
bug back to the ADK.
So we reverted back to the
previous version of the ADK,
notified our partner, and went
ahead with our business.
Three days before the release,
the partner comes back to us
and tells us that the bug has
been fixed and you can
go and adopt it.
So we said, OK, we'll
test it out.
Everything worked fine.
Functionality, the application
looked really good.
But what you see out here is
that the native memory
consistently hit rock bottom.
So these are tests.
Endurance tests are tests which
run for two hours over
our platform.
And most of our functional
tests gets
done within 30 minutes.
So the memory leak over here
manifest itself after one hour
of video playback.
And as a Netflix consumer, you
know there are no movies which
are less than one hour long.
So we were able to track
this down to an ADK.
Again, we reverted back and
shipped the version in time.
The key takeaway that we have
over here is basically any
form of test that you're
developing, whether it be
functional integration or
performance test, make sure
you're consistently running it
and analyze the result that
you get out of these tests.
With these thoughts, I would
like to end the talk with the
quote from Robert Allen, which
has a bigger meaning in life,
but I think it's still
appropriate
for the test community.
Thank you.
[APPLAUSE]
TONY VOELLM: Great.
Thank you, Minal.
That's an old adage.
If nothing's running, it
doesn't use any memory.
So that's a good learning.
I think we have time
for one question.
I don't see any live
questions just yet.
We'll wait for the Dory.
If there's a good Dory question,
I'll pick it.
Otherwise, we're going to go
into a break right after this
until 3:45.
And then we have two very
interesting talks-- one from
academia and one talk that
has influenced many
of the others here.
So let me see this Moderator
question here.
It says, do you include any
testing parts into your
product delivered
to end users?
What statistics do you get from
the apps on end users'
devices, and how do you deal
with that huge, I suppose,
amount of it?
And if the lawyers are
not here, it's OK.
Don't answer that.
MINAL MISHRA: Yeah,
basically we do a
lot of end user testing.
We do instrument our client
applications with a lot of
information that gets logged
into our service.
We have a huge cloud-based
system, which basically
collects all this data.
And we basically process this
data in a distributed cloud
platform to kind of get an
analysis of what our users are
going through.
Because it's very hard for you
to test all the cases.
And the best way to test it is
by testing it in production.
TONY VOELLM: Great.
And with that, thank you.
We'll be back in seat at 3:45.
So I will see you then.
Thank you.
[APPLAUSE]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
TONY VOELLM: Hello.
Hello and welcome back.
We have two more talks today,
very fascinating talks that
are coming up.
This first talk is
from academia.
And we have a couple of talks
from academia, here.
This next speaker is Tao Xie.
And he is from North Carolina
State University and will be
talking about testing for
educational gaming and
educational gaming
for testing.
And one nice little fact is he
is actually a UW alumnus, so
he is a dawg, D-A-W-G. So
with that, thank you.
TAO XIE: Thank you, Tony.
Good afternoon.
Next, I'm going to talk to you
about some recent work in
collaboration with Microsoft
Research, including Nikolai
Tillman, Jonathan De Halleux,
along with Judith Bishop.
That theme would be about the
synergy of testing and
educational gaming.
On the testing side, I will talk
to you about the dynamic
symbolic executions incorporated
in the tool
called Pex, from Microsoft
Research, along with
parameters unit testing as a
way for you to incorporate
behavior checking for
your testing.
And then, with this foundation
of technology, we have these
games, Pex For Fun, as a way for
you to teach students or
teach yourself about different
kinds of skills, including
software testing skills.
In the rest of the talk, I will
basically give you the
background, first,
on the testing.
And then we'll move on to
educational gaming.
Particularly, I will give
the background.
And then I will give you a
little bit brief introduction
of writing code, in the browser,
in your favorite
browser, of your choice.
And then I will talk about a
gaming type of coding do's, in
the Pex For Fun website, and
further discuss how we could
leverage such gaming types
in educational settings,
including teaching and
learning, and then
conclude the talk.
Here's a screen snapshot of
the tool, Pex, released by
Microsoft Research.
It's a publicly available
tool.
The URL is near the bottom
of the slides.
Basically, it's a plugin
for Visual Studio.
Currently it supports different
kinds of Dot Net
language, including C Sharp,
Visual Basic, and F Sharp.
Like here, basically, it's very
easy to for you to use.
Install the plugin, and then you
could, just several mouse
clicks for you to generate
a set of test inputs, as
displayed near the bottom on
the Visual Studio window.
Let me give you a little brief
overview of the key
technology, called dynamic
symbolic execution, in Pex,
how we could generate test data
automatically to achieve
high code coverage.
On the side, I have this very
simple piece of code.
That's a code in the test.
As you can see, the inputs would
be an integer array.
And then inside, we have
three conditionals.
The first one, checking whether
the array is a null
pointer, and then the second
one, checking whether the
length is greater than 0.
And then the third one is
checking whether the first
element is equal to that
very big number.
In that case, we will throw
an exception to indicate a
potential bug in that particular
code location.
Dynamic symbolic execution was
proposed back in 2005 and,
these days, have been
incorporated in different
kinds of testing tools,
including security testing
tools, along with Pex.
Dynamic symbolic execution
will start with a default
input for the argument
or [INAUDIBLE]
selected or randomly selected
input value.
For this case, we could just use
a default value as a null
pointer for the integer array.
We execute the program, being
instrumented with additional
code, to collect runtime
information, particularly
which path this test execution
would tranverse.
And what constraints on the
inputs do we need to satisfy
in order to tranverse that
particular path.
As we could see, if execute
a null pointer, we would
tranverse the true branch of
the first conditional.
At the same time, we collect the
constraints, record as a
past condition, as a equal to
null pointer, after we finish
the execution.
Next, we want to generate
new test data, right?
Because we want to
excise different
behaviors of the code.
How to do that?
We picked an already collected
past condition and
negate part of it.
In this case, it's simple,
because we have only one
constraint.
We negate it.
We have a not equal
to null pointer.
We fit these new constraints
to a constraint solver or a
[INAUDIBLE] improver.
The constraint solver would give
us a concrete input value
that would satisfy this
particular constraint.
For this case, it's easy.
We could see, we just need an
empty array to satisfy the
constraint, that array
is not null.
Then we further execute
the program with
this new input data.
Further, we can see now, we
reach the second conditional.
And we take the fourth branch,
because a.length now is equal
to 0, not greater than 0.
Similarly, in the next
iteration, we negate part of
the constraint, in this case,
a.length greater than 0.
We fit the new constraint
to a constraint solver.
We get the new concrete
inputs as one array
with only one element.
That element is equal to 0.
With this new input, we
further go through
the process we have.
In this particular case,
we now reach the last
conditional.
But the first element
of the array is not
equal to a big number.
It's equal to 0.
So we next would
negate the last
constraints of the path condition.
Finally, we fit the constraint
to the constraint solver.
We get this big number in order
to trigger the exception
throwing statement.
For this particular simple
example, we are done, because
we actually explored all the
paths in this simple program.
In reality, many real world
applications of software and
their tests wouldn't
be that simple.
We may have an infinite number
of the paths or, at least, a
huge number of the paths
in the code.
We need to have some advanced
technologies, including those
incorporated into Pex, to deal
with those complicated
situations.
In this talk, I'm not going to
go into the details about
these technologies.
But the basic idea of dynamic
symbolic execution is,
actually, what I described.
So far, we focused on crashing
or exception throwing
situations, in the
previous example.
We know, if you want to assure
high quality assurance, in
terms of a functional
correctness, only catching
this crashing or robustness
issues may not be enough.
We need to go one step further
to write down some strong
enough assertions in order to
catch these, like a functional
correctness box.
To do that, we could leverage
parameterized unit testing,
which is a methodology to help
you to engage developers and
test generation tools to work
together, in order to exploit
the best out of this
test automation.
In conscious conventional unit
tests, which do not have
parameters, right?
When you write unit tests, you
don't have parameters.
You just write some test
methods, and then you execute
the body of the test methods.
But in parameter unit testing,
a unit test has parameters
like the one I put
on the slide.
As you can see on here, we have
two parameters, list and
an integer item.
The body of this unit test is
testing adding an element into
a list to see whether the count
of the list has been
increased by one.
Very simple behavior.
How do we do that?
How do we check the behavior?
Next, we would put several lines
of code, very similar to
what you have been doing in
traditional unit tests.
Basically, you write down the
method call that you want to
test, and then you write all the
assertions that you want
to check the behavior.
Keep in mind here, the
assertions that you are
putting here need to be general
enough to deal with
all different kinds of argument
variables coming in.
Not just hard-coded like 10 or
20, or push one element to an
empty list, that kind of
specific situations.
To allow you to write these
kinds of general properties as
assertions, we have a specific
kind of construct called
assumptions, which
may not exist in
conventional unit tests.
Basically, you could
[INAUDIBLE]
in this case lists not equal
to a null pointer.
Otherwise, as you can see, we
will throw exceptions in the
body of the unit test.
As you can see, for this kind
of parameter unit test, we
basically separate two
constraints, two concerns,
more precisely.
First, we want developers to
write down what you really
want to check, the behavior
checking of the sequence of
the method calls along
with the assertions.
Then we allow test generation
tools like tests to generate
high quality test data, to
excise different portions of
the code, if possible, violating
the assertions that
you put down there.
So it's a nice way of separating
the concerns of
these two parts, one being
done by humans, the other
being done by test automation.
Actually, parameter unit testing
or parameter unit
tests have been supported by
quite different testing
frameworks, like including
different kinds of .NET
testing frameworks along with
JUnit 4 or beyond for the Java
unit testing.
The parameter unit testing would
be fully exploited in
terms of the power in practice
when you are using parameter
unit testing in combination
with test
generation tools like Pex.
For the .NET programs, we have
Pex that I mentioned already.
For the Java unit testing, we
have some tools such as
Agitar, AgitarOne, for allowing
you to use test
generation for parameter unit
tests written by developers.
So far, so good.
Today, we already listened to
quite some talks engage in so
many different kinds of testing
tools, including the
one that I just described,
Pex.
But after the talks, or like in
our typical scenario, when
we get tutorials at industry
contexts or academic settings,
then quite some audience may
not have the exact tools
installed on their laptop.
After the talk, after the
tutorials, they may not
actually expend the effort
to install the tool
and try out the tool.
So that's an issue we
have been observing.
So without actually seeing how
things are, what kind of
benefit you would get, they
may not bother to install
different kinds of tools
in their environment.
So that's an issue that we
commonly observed in terms of
tool adoption.
My collaborators at Microsoft
Research have a similar
observation to how to
deal with that.
They basically put the tool
online, not just putting the
tool online or downloading,
actually making the tool
useable within a browser.
So that's how the Pex for fun
website would come into place.
Actually, if you had a mobile
device or laptop or your
desktop, you could actually
enter the URL pex4fun.com and
try things out to get the sense
of what benefits you
could get with the
power of test
generation underlying Pex.
Here's the website,
a screen snapshot.
As you can see, in the middle,
you can enter the source code
that you want to test and a
particular name, like puzzle,
with certain parameters.
You can view that piece of code
as a parameter unit test.
Then you just click the button
near the middle left hand
side, Ask Pex.
Then Pex will generate test data
and send back the test
data to the browser being
displayed to you near the
button of the web page.
So that's a basic functionality
of this website.
It can allow you to quickly get
a sense of what this tool
could do for you.
I think that kind of an
experience could be borrowed
by many other tool vendors or
other tools in terms of giving
people a quick overview
of what their tools
could do for them.
But indeed, there has to be some
limitation on the browser
version of the tool.
For example, the total length of
the code in the test might
not be too long.
You only have one file being
copy-pasted in that browser
text box for the code
in the test.
Single-threaded.
No environment interaction, such
as you cannot use FiiO
network communication, that
kind of thing, in
the code in the test.
No non-deterministic behavior.
It will try to avoid
floating-point computations,
which cannot be handled well
by existing [INAUDIBLE].
We also impose this 20-second
expiration time for test
generation when you click
the button, Ask Pex.
But some of these issues are
just specific to the browser
version, not to the--
like we're use still
the plugin version.
In summary, so far I've
discussed the dynamic symbolic
execution, how it works, and how
Pex could be used, and how
Pex could be migrated to a
browser version so that many
people just open up their
browser and then get a sense
of what it could do for you.
In order to make this browser
version really usable, to have
similar user experiences as they
were doing within their
typical IDE, for example,
VideoStudio, my collaborators
in Microsoft Research put a
lot of effort in creating
these nice features, such as
auto code completion, when you
just type in, for example,
console.w, it would pop up
some suggestions for the method
that you want to put
in, along with a description
of these API methods.
Very nice features, it just
allows you to feel the similar
experiences as in the
normal, typical IDE.
So basically, for this kind of a
browser version of the tool,
you could leverage the cloud to
do the computation, do the
test generation.
And you use the browser as the
front end for the user to
enter the code they would like
to test and then also use the
browser to display the
test data being
generated back to the users.
So far so, good.
We have Pex, and we have the
dynamic symbolic execution
incorporated in Pex.
My collaborator at Microsoft
Research put this Pex for fun
website so that you could
play with it.
But think about it.
Unless you are really like a
geek, otherwise you wouldn't
come back to this website.
Like, oh, every now and then,
you just type in some code and
click the button and say,
oh, how fun it is.
Or you generate strong forward
detection capability, like in
terms of test data, and then you
play it again and again.
I mean, I think few people
would do that.
Then we think about how we could
leverage this websites
and the test generation to do
something more fun and more
useful in our world and life.
That's how the coding duels
come into the picture.
It's a major game type for
Pex for fun website.
So far, for the coding duel game
type, particularly for
the Ask Pex button, basically
you click one time of Ask Pex
button that will indicate one
iteration of gameplay.
About one month ago, we had more
than 1.1 million of the
clicking the button.
So many people around the world
are using this website
to do a different kind of thing,
like particularly for
learning while having
some fun.
Or it's being used in
a classroom setting.
Let me give you some idea
on what a coding
duel would be like.
And the ideas are very simple.
For a game creator like myself
or actually anyone around the
world, you could create a secret
implementation on the
right hand side.
Basically, you write a very
simple piece of code.
And then you also release
[INAUDIBLE]
of the secret implementation.
Then the players would need to
complete or finish the player
implementation so that the
player implementation would
have the exact same behavior as
the secret implementation.
And you would say, I cannot see
How could I type in the code to
make the behavior the same
as the underlying secret
implementation?
It's mission impossible.
That's how aspects of Pex
come into the picture.
Pex would give you feedback to
tell you under what inputs you
have the same behavior between
these two versions, under what
inputs you have different
behaviors.
In addition, Pex would be the
judge to determine whether
these two implementations
have the same behavior.
Let me use an example
to walk you through.
On the left hand side, I already
created a secret
implementation, a very simple
one, recursion function.
On the right hand side, I
release to the player with the
player implementation basically
the anti-one.
You just return x.
Then when the user, the player,
tries to play this
game, first, the player would
click the button Ask Pex.
Because without any hints, the
player has no clues on what
directions the player needs
to modify the code.
Then after the player clicks the
button Ask Pex, behind the
scenes, we actually have this
test driver being synthesized.
It's more like a parameter
unit test.
You have the input argument the
same as the signature of
the two implementations.
But we construct a new branch
there saying that if the
return value of the secret
implementation is not equal to
the value of the player
implementation, we throw an exception.
As you can see, dynamic symbolic
execution will try to
cover all feasible paths, of
course, all feasible branches.
And if possible, Pex, or dynamic
symbolic execution,
will fire test input to
cover that branch.
What does that mean?
If you can cover that branch,
it means that you have at
least one test input to cause
the behaviors of the two
implementations to be different
so that you have a
failing test.
So in reality, if you click
the button for these two
implementations, you will see
the table displaying two
passing tests and one
failing test.
Basically, we are saying that
if your argument value is 1,
the written value is 1 for
both implementations.
2, similar thing.
The return value will be 2
for both implementations.
But if you have input value as
3, the secret implementation
will return 6 in cell 3 which
would be returned by the
player implementation.
So as you can see, as a player,
when you see this kind
of feedback, you try to modify,
you try to do some
generalization, objection,
reflect on how would you
modify the code implementation
so that you could satisfy the
constraint of the three
test inputs.
Basically making the passing
tests still pass, but making
the failing test also pass.
We use this kind of gaming with
middle school students.
We see very interesting
behavior there.
They may just say focus their
energy on the failing test
without thinking about making
the passing first two parts of
the test also pass.
More like overthinking
the [INAUDIBLE]
solving in their mind.
So to summarize these coding
duels, basically we provide
these kind of fun and engaging
experiences by allowing the
user, the player to have this
iterative gameplay over time
by clicking, asking Pex over
time when they change the
player implementations based
on the feedback.
The feedback is adapted
and personalized.
Like you play the same again.
You may write down different a
player implementation, make
different revisions.
Then the feedback you are
getting would be different
because dynamic symbol
execution, or Pex, would
leverage both the player
implementation and the secret
implementation to generate
specific tests to show the
differences or the commonalities
of the behavior.
It's very difficult
to do cheating.
You may say, oh, because
earlier, I mentioned that
floating-point computation
would not be good for
[INAUDIBLE], so let's just put
a bunch of floating-point
computations there to fool Pex
or fool dynamic symbolic
execution, that would
not work well.
It's very difficult
to defeat that.
In theory, you could.
But in practice, it's very
difficult to cheat.
We have very clear winning
criterion.
Basically, as long as Pex cannot
generate a failing
test, then you win the game.
We have quite some users posting
their feedback and
their experience online.
I'll just read you some of
the interesting ones.
"I used to love the first-person
shooters and the
satisfaction of blowing away a
whole team of noobies playing
'Rainbow Six,' but this is far
more fun." The user was
referring to playing
Pex for fun.
The second one, apparently, as
you could guess, the second
one is a professional, rather
than a student.
"I'm afraid I'll have to
constrain myself to spend just
an hour or so a day on this
really exciting stuff, as I'm
really stuffed with work." We
don't want to impact your
normal workload there.
But on the side, it's good
to have some kind of
entertainment while
learning yourself.
The third one is talking
about the learning
and teaching aspect.
"It really got me excited.
The part that got me most is
about spreading interest in
teaching computer science.
I do think that it's really
great for teaching and
learning." We have many, many
more different, very positive
feedback from the users.
And recently, like two years
ago, we had this coding duel
competition at our major
software engineering
conference, International
Conference on Software
Engineering 2011.
And we provided these 30
coding duels for the
conference attendees including
students and researchers.
As you can see, I zoomed in
there with one of the coding
duels, number 10.
Basically, the green entries
would indicate that user
actually solves the coding duel,
wins the coding duel.
For the red ones, that would
indicate the user makes an
attempt but fails.
The number there indicated how
many attempts the user made,
basically how many times the
user clicked Ask Pex before
they actually finally got
it for the green one.
Or the red ones, in the
end, they still
couldn't win the game.
It's very interesting to see
for this particular coding
duel is not that trivial.
As you can see, we have
one user solving
the game four times.
That's very good, four times
actually got it.
But we can see the other had 147
times and finally got it.
You could reflect that user's
really patient or determined.
It's up to you to judge whether
you want to hire this
person to be you tester
or not, right?
So you could have different
interpretations on that.
But as later I will describe
more, another very interesting
thing for you to see is that as
a teacher who would create
this kind of a game for a
student to try, a teacher
could actually see every
single step the
user actually tried.
For this particular case, we
should actually go inside to
see for that user with 147, what
on earth did this user
finally got it right?
Like, what's the turning point,
or why do you need so
many times?
Or for the fourth one, what is
actually the magic happened?
Four times you got it.
It's very interesting to see
the process besides just
seeing the end result.
So to summarize what we talk
about coding duels, basically
it's given a particular secret
implementation and an empty or
incomplete player
implementation, we ask users
to try to improve the player
implementation so that the
behavior would match the secret
implementation one.
The students need to infer the
intended behavior of the
secret implementation that they
couldn't see, and then
they would iteratively try to
generalize that behavior to
the code implementation that
they are working on.
We also have this kind of a
social experience to make it
more fun and engaging.
We had this live feed.
Then on the website, you could
see at this particular moment
who are solving what.
Are they successful, or
are they failing and
still trying very hard?
It would be fun to watch if
you don't have many useful
tasks at hand.
Especially when you create some
coding duels, to just
see, oh, who are solving
my duels.
That's an interesting
live feed there.
We also had these rank lists
for different users.
A user could gain some points
by creating coding duels for
other people to play.
Also gain some points by
successfully solving certain
coding duels.
We have these kind of rank lists
of people around the
world on this website.
We had a leaderboard along with
other nice features for
social experiences.
We would like to take advantage
of these platforms
so that we could really get much
in terms of the teaching
and learning, rather than just
say I will put it there so
that anyone who would like to
try it out, just try it out.
To do that, basically
we provide
different kinds of features.
For example, as a teacher, we
could create a course by
assembling different
web pages.
Like the course page, we
already have different
materials on different topics,
testing, along with different
programming topics.
Here is a screen snapshot
there, basically for the
teacher, This is like
a sample course.
We can see that on the right
hand side, we have this kind
of dashboard of showing the
students' progress on solving
some exercises in the form
of coding duels.
And in real time, the teachers
could look into what kind of
problem they are facing.
Are they struggling on
a particular thing?
Or maybe the exercises are not
that clear in terms of giving
students a requirement.
We used coding duels
in a graduate
software engineering course.
Typically, you would think, oh,
this kind of a nice game
could be used in intro
programming courses.
Indeed, that would
be the case.
For example, if you are teaching
LOOP, you could just
take a certain piece of the loop
head out and then ask the
student to fill in that
particular, for example, the
upper bound of the loop,
this kind of thing.
But at same time, we actually
tried it out at a graduate
software engineering course
in terms of teaching them
specification writing
requirements, testing design
patterns, many different
kinds of topics.
Here's just a screen snapshot of
a particular exercise that
we prepared for training
students in
specification writing.
As you know, in testing, in
order to right very strong
test articles, you need to
write strong properties.
For the topic of parameter unit
testing, to write that
unit test with parameters, you
need to have strong assertions
of properties to really check
the behavior that you would
want to check.
So this exercise actually has
some natural language
descriptions of some
properties of a
particular API method.
And then we ask students to
actually translate these
natural language discussions
into some formally checkable
properties.
So in this particular exercise,
as you can see,
students may not have much space
for guessing because
it's actually solving
the given exercise.
But the nice thing about it
is that you actually get
automatic grading.
Both the instructors and
the TAs are very happy.
Because in the end, you just
look at, oh, how many failing,
how many passing into the green
entries and the red entries.
And you just calculate the
scores, rather than really go
inside to grade them
with tiny details.
And here is just one example of
how we use coding duels for
teaching testing.
The code in the test actually
is a stack,
is a boundless stack.
We create this coding duel by
passing in some parameters
like the elements, array element
capacity, this upper
bound for the stack, and the
element which could be the
element you want to push
into the stick.
Or you want to check whether
the stack has this element.
But we don't know.
We don't tell you exactly how
we are going to use that.
But earlier, the first two lines
are basically talking
about assumptions we put in.
And then we have the next four
lines describing the setup of
that stack.
Basically we just put this array
element into the stack
so that you could allow the test
generation to generate a
particular state for you in
this particular setting.
And then in the end, we put down
the assertions we really
want the code in the
test to be checked.
But we keep the middle empty.
As you can imagine, the middle
part, the empty part, that
needs to be filled would be
about what method on the tag
you want to invoke
on the stack.
In addition, you may also need
to add some assumptions to
really make sure that the
assertion will be passed.
So if you have interest, you
could go to the URL to try it
out yourself to see the
different kind of exercises.
How do you use Pex for fun?
I already demonstrated
some scenarios.
As we all know, MOOC has been
very popular, Massive Open
Online Course.
There are at least two major
challenges there to make
things work in MOOCs.
First, grading.
If you have thousands or even
millions of students, you
cannot afford hiring TAs to
grade these students'
submissions because typically,
they are free in
terms of the course.
Then here, if you Pex for fun,
you could create exercises and
get this automatic grading
for free as a nice
feature on the side.
But indeed, it's an open
challenge in terms of like
addressing cheating.
If one student just copy-pastes
another student's
solution, they're working on the
same duel, we really don't
have certain controls
in terms of that.
It's an open challenge for many
different technologies.
It can be a useful course
assignment in regular course
situation, both academic
settings or industry setting
for training.
We have done that in terms of
the topics from intro to
programming or software
engineering,
including testing topics.
We actually could have these
competitions, including
student competitions and
professional competitions.
We had this experience
at ICSE 2011.
And finally, as I hinted on
earlier, it would be very
interesting for you to
actually observe one
particular player or user's
problem-solving process.
As a recruiter or a company's
employees, you want to hire
some potential employees.
You want to see how
they are doing.
But basically, you could create
some well-designed
coding duels for
them to solve.
Not only seeing how many
attempts they are making, you
see the problem-solving
process.
They're kind of similar to what
you typically would do
using the whiteboard to see how
a particular person would
do on solving some problem.
So it could be used in that way
for you to really assess
people and improve people.
Like for example, your children,
you want to see how
they are doing on programming on
particular problem solving.
To summarize what we discussed
in teaching and learning,
basically, if you want to become
a teacher, to really
create a course for students
or employees or friends to
play with and see their
problem-solving process, you
could sign in with a Microsoft
account, like a Hotmail
account [INAUDIBLE].
And then you pick a nickname and
send us the nickname, and
then we could enable you
with a teacher role.
And as a teacher, you could
create courses.
You could monitor the progress
of students'
problem-solving processes.
You could interact with them
in different ways.
So in the future, there's a lot
of exciting things ahead
like how to provide tutoring
support for students if they
are facing some difficulties.
You see the 147 user
trying 147 times.
Typically, a student would get
frustrated after they try a
number of times.
For this case, we shouldn't just
say, oh, you keep trying
or you fail.
You may have some hints
on the side like in
the real-world setting.
And how to detect plagiarism,
I mentioned already it's an
open problem.
For the ranking, so far we use
passing or not, right, whether
you have behavioral differences
or not.
But we really want to have
other criteria like code
quality and other kinds of
criteria for us to take into
account in terms of providing
better grading.
Support other languages,
[INAUDIBLE].
More detail in this
upcoming paper.
It's available from
my homepage.
And in conclusion, I talk about
two different kinds of
technologies, but they are
correlated to each other,
supporting each other.
Dynamic symbolic execution,
along with Pex and parameter
unit testing, and Pex for fur as
an application or platform.
To conclude that, my email
address is there.
We welcome collaborations
on this exciting period.
I would say in 40 or 50
years, you may retire.
Right?
Educating the next generation to
do a better job than us or
at least as good as us
is very important.
I think that besides just doing
tests with automation,
it's a good opportunity for us
to think about how to make
education and learning more fun
and more valuable for the
next generation.
Thank you.
[APPLAUSE]
TONY VOELLM: Great
Thank you, Tao.
Very fascinating.
So I had forgotten earlier, I
had a few things up here.
So for some live questions, I
was going to throw this out to
a live question.
We'll determine the
best one here.
So this is a little Androidy.
So we have the Dory up.
Let me go to the Dory, or
to the moderator here.
It's not a door.
So first question up, how does
a tool like Pex fit into the
software life cycle?
TAO XIE: OK, so Pex could be
used like the other test
generating tools.
You finish your code
implementation, and then you
apply Pex to generate test
data to excise different
portions of the code.
In addition, it actually could
fit in TTD, Test-Driven
Development.
But in this situation, you write
parameter unit tests
first without actually having
your code implementation.
But in this setting, keeping
my parameter unit test
[INAUDIBLE] would be very
powerful to force you to write
quite a lot of functionality
when you try pass the test.
It's debatable whether that's a
good thing or a bad thing in
terms of philosophy of TTD.
But it could allow you to spend
more time on writing the
code implementation rather
than with very minor
increments of adding
new features.
TONY VOELLM: Interesting.
There's one live question
here, so we'll go ahead.
Tell us who you are, where
you're from, and then your
question please.
AUDIENCE: I'm Jessica Nickel.
I live in New York City, and
I work at Targetspot.
I was in education for 10 years
before transitioning to
QA testing.
And I find this really
exciting.
And I'm just wondering if there
are plans to develop a
curriculum around this so that
way teachers can be guided who
may not be so technical but
who are interested in
incorporating this into
their classrooms.
TAO XIE: Yes.
Yes, actually, there are quite
some materials already on the
website for you to customize use
in your setting, including
like intro programming along
with parameter unit testing.
We are still putting in quite
substantial efforts in getting
more materials to cover
different topics and customize
for different levels.
We also welcome collaboration
in terms of these particular
aspects, like developing more
course materials so that more
people could benefit
form this course.
TONY VOELLM: Great question,
by the way.
That was a good question and the
first one up, so I'll set
that there for you.
OK.
I think we have one more
live question.
So please go ahead, who you are,
where you're from, and
your question please.
AUDIENCE: Hi, my name is Mark,
University of Malta.
So I can see how symbolic
execution is really good for
generating a bunch of
test cases, which
maximize your coverage.
How does Pex handle the
[INAUDIBLE] side of things?
So once you've generated the
test, how can you be sure that
the system is behaving
properly for
that particular test?
TAO XIE: Right.
So that would fit in what
I describe as a
parameter unit tests.
Of course, you could just apply
Pex like any other test
generation tool.
You don't write anything.
You just rely on crashing
or not, or throwing and
exception or not.
That's already there.
If you want to have higher
confidence in terms of
behavior that you are checking,
you write this kind
of a parameter unit test with
strong enough assertions so
that it's not hard-coded for
some constant input value, but
more general.
So you would get the benefit
by additionally doing
parameter unit testing.
OK, Thank you.
TONY VOELLM: Yeah, thanks
for the question.
So up here on the moderator, it
says, "Pex only identifies
unit testing parameters,
right?
It will not handle functional
or integration testing."
TAO XIE: OK.
So basically, as you can see,
Pex basically, with the nicely
specified interface, that's the
test data that Pex would
generate tests.
You could encode your
integration test or functional
test inside this parameter
unit test.
But the next question is that,
could it scale well?
That's another question.
We need to see what kind of
code we are dealing with,
whether the code we are testing
would have dependency
with the environment.
Maybe you need to do environment
isolation,
[INAUDIBLE]
like do mocking, this
kind of thing.
So you may have to do a lot of
these additional techniques
typically you would do in your
traditional unit testing, yes.
TONY VOELLM: Very interesting.
And we have time for
one more question.
So is this a live question?
We'll take it, please.
AUDIENCE: Hi, I'm Daniel
[INAUDIBLE].
I'm a Googler.
The parameterized testing
assumptions and assertions
reminded me quite a bit of code
contracts but also felt
kind of like the opposite.
Like rather than specifying
within your code parameters,
you're writing the test which
is meant to be kind of
auto-verified.
I was wondering if you could
kind of contrast those
approaches a bit.
TAO XIE: OK, very
good question.
So in a code contract, like
pre-, post-conditional design
by contract, you write the pre-,
post-conditions in the
production code.
So typically, people would write
mostly preconditions.
And very few people would
write post-conditions.
Why?
Because it's very difficult to
write post-conditions because
it's very complicated to capture
the behavior of that
particular piece of code.
If you write parameter unit
tests, yeah, you also have
assumptions and assertions.
Notice here, the assertion there
would be specific to the
scenario that you constrain,
with the method sequences in
the middle and assumptions
that you put in.
So that you have a much
easier time for you
to specify the behavior.
But indeed, code contract would
have more applicable
scope or testing different
situations only [INAUDIBLE]
the piece of code.
Parameter unit test would be
just applicable on the
scenario that you specify
there with whatever
test data coming in.
So I think that's a tradeoff
that we are making.
I mean, the design by contract
has been going
on for quite a while.
But we haven't seen enough
practitioners take up
substantially.
Hopefully, parameter unit test
would allow people to actually
get some benefits of these
formal methods.
But at the same time, they
are still following their
traditional practice of
doing unit testing,
writing unit tests.
OK, thank you.
TONY VOELLM: OK, great.
Thank you, Tao.
TAO XIE: Great Thank you.
TONY VOELLM: Thank you.
[APPLAUSE]
TONY VOELLM: So this next
speaker up I believe has
spoken at more GTACs
than anybody else.
He probably does not need
an introduction,
but I will do one.
This is Simon Stewart from
Facebook, and he is going to
talk to us about how Facebook
tests Facebook on Android.
And so with that, I'll
hand it off to you.
Thank you.
SIMON STEWART: Brilliant.
[APPLAUSE]
SIMON STEWART: Thank you very
much for that introduction.
Yes, i think I have
spoken at more of
these than anyone else.
This is the one where
I snatch the
crown from James Whittaker.
[LAUGHTER]
SIMON STEWART: Sorry, James,
if you're watching.
Before I begin, I've been having
a fantastic day today.
The quality of the talks
has been amazing.
And the thing that I've really
noticed has been just the
awesome work the stenographers
have been doing.
Like when I haven't been
paying attention.
[APPLAUSE]
SIMON STEWART: And the signing
down here is phenomenal.
Just blown away by how well
organized this is.
So well done, Google.
Keep up the good work.
Yeah, so how Facebook tests
Facebook on Android.
If I'd been thinking carefully
when I named this
presentation, what I would
have done is I would have
called it "How Facebook Bakes
Quality Into Facebook on
Android." Because we don't
just test for the sake of
testing, right?
It isn't something that we sit
there and go, you know what?
I really fancy doing some
pointless testing today.
There's nothing I'd rather do.
Actually, sometimes I
do feel like that.
But it's only when it's
a really slow day.
Why are we doing this testing?
We're doing it to bake quality
into our apps.
We can't bolt quality onto an
application at the very, very
last minute.
We can't bake security in at the
very last minute, either.
We can't bake performance
in at the last minute.
These are things that we need to
be thinking of all the way
through the life cycle
of the application.
So yes, how Facebook tests
Facebook on Android.
So let me take you
back to 2012.
It was a long, long time ago
in a galaxy right here.
The Facebook app on Android,
it worked.
It was kind of fun.
And it also had really, really,
really lousy user
experience.
Here's a quote from Mark here
going, "We were never able to
get the quality we wanted.
Looking back, that's probably
one of the biggest, if not the
biggest, mistake we made."
And why was the performance of
the application so appalling?
Well, actually, it
wasn't that bad.
But what we were doing is a
pattern that's fairly common
in the world of mobile
applications.
And that's to use the WebViews
extensively.
Facebook was a web company.
We like to be able to
release software.
We do it twice a day now.
We push to our live website
twice a day.
That allows us to iterate on
things really quickly.
It allows us to make a series
of chronic and awful and
terrible mistakes, realize that
we've done something, and
fix it in the next day.
Problem is that you can't
do that on a mobile app.
Someone downloads the app, and
then they're stuck with it.
If you've got a bug in that
application, they may never
update again, which is a
horrific place to be in.
So we'd like to retain
some flexibility.
And the way we did that
is we used WebView.
And the WebViews on Android
and iOS are sub-optimal, I
think is a way to
describe them.
There's a number of problems
with them, not least of which
is they're like no other
browser out there.
The Android one is based on
the stock Android browser,
which is not Chrome, unless
you're on Jelly Bean.
And if you're on Jelly Bean,
actually, the browser is
Chrome, and the WebView is
something completely different.
The JavaScript engines tend
to behave appallingly.
They're very slow.
They're tedious.
And so what we were doing is we
were making each of these
WebViews to allow us to
iterate more quickly.
And it was just leading
to a really poor
experience for our users.
So we had to stop.
We reassessed.
What we did is we decided we
were going to make mobile a
first-class experience.
That went the wrong way.
I could do the entire talk
in reverse, by the way.
Start on the final slide, begin
with your questions, and
then just make it
up from there.
Hands up if you'd like
me to do that.
There's one hand.
Two hands, brilliant.
Next year.
I'll be invited back for
sure after this.
So what we did is we decided
we were going to take our
engineers, and we were going
to train them up on mobile.
And this graph here has the
numbers removed, but there's a
total of about 1,400 engineers
at Facebook.
Not all of them contribute
to our mobile codebase.
But what happened is
it was all going
along fairly regularly.
And then we went, what we
need to do, we need
to put mobile first.
We took our PHP developers.
We ran them through
training courses.
We educated them.
We hired people in who were
skilled at Android and mobile
development.
And that's the result.
We had this massive uptick in
the number of engineers
committing code to our
mobile codebases.
That's a fantastic thing.
We're now moving a lot faster.
The important thing, though,
is that it's engineers
contributing to our
mobile codebase.
There are no Android team.
What I mean to say is, there is
no longer an Android team.
We tried to do that.
We tried to have a group of
people who were responsible.
We called them the Core
Android Team.
And they were going to be
awesome, and they were going
to somehow keep up with the
flood of new features coming
into the web.
And that didn't work.
So what we did is we
took a step back.
We reassessed again.
And now what happens is each
of the teams producing a
feature own that feature on
every platform it's on.
So if you own pictures, you own
it on the web, the mobile
web, iOS, Android.
So that's far easier for people
to keep things in sync.
There's probably people
on those teams who are
specialized on Android or iOS.
But there isn't a group of
people who are responsible for
desperately trying to ape
features from the web in a
mobile client.
And that allows us to keep
parity in place.
And that means that users get
a far better experience.
If something appears on the web,
chances are it will also
appear on the mobile client
relatively soon after that.
We do have spoons.
So there is no Android team.
So what's a developer's
day like?
Let's say you're on one of
these feature teams, and
you're going to do something.
How do we bake quality
into the application?
It's done all the way
through the process.
So let's begin with
how we build.
That seems to be quite
an important
thing to do with software.
We need to build it.
So we use Git at the moment
for source control.
It's a DVCS.
And so what we do is we
have a central repo.
And that seemed like
a good idea.
Everyone works on their
local machine.
There are two branches that
we care about day to day.
Google I know only have one.
And that's because none of
their tests fail because
they've got the presubmit,
and it's awesome.
We haven't got the presubmit,
so people check in.
So there are two branches
that people care about.
The first one is master.
That represents not a villain
from "Doctor Who," but the
most recent version.
You can see who enjoys
Britsh sci-fi here.
It's the latest version
of the code.
So master has everything in it
that has been committed to the
code base so far.
It's a linear history.
What we also have is a moving
tag called stable that
represents the last time that
we were sure that our unit
tests were passing.
So there's master, and
there's stable.
That's kind fun.
And all this code is checked
out, for Android at least, in
a single tree with effectively
three or four directories up
at the top.
Java, Java tests, because you
never mix tests and Java code.
It's just not the thing
that you do.
Third-party libraries, we keep
those out of the tree.
And resources used
for Android.
OK, I've got my drink
of water here.
Yes, so it's all one tree.
That's kind of fun because we've
got more than one mobile
app that we make for Android.
And there's Instagram
in there.
There's a Facebook app.
There's a messenger app.
There's a camera app.
If you download an app for
Android from Facebook, it's
all been built from that tree.
I'll throw that all over
my laptop later.
So--
yes, people know
Murphy as well.
So what does it look
like when you begin
working on a feature?
Well, what you do is you're
probably on the stable branch.
You create a new branch for
your fancy feature.
Hackity hack, hackity hack,
hackity hack, you get commit.
And you create a new feature.
But while you've been working,
there have been N other
developers also checking
in code.
So periodically, you want to
grab the work they're doing
and rebase.
So you're always working
on the top of the tree.
You go hackity hack, hackity
hack, hackity hack.
When you're ready, you commit.
And then you do a rebase.
So what we like to do is while
you're developing locally on a
branch of your own, you
can have as many
branches as you want.
You can have your commital
organized any way you want.
But when we push it into master,
we want a logical
change to go into
our codebase.
We don't want the individual
steps you did.
Now there's a number of reasons
for doing that.
The first one, a logical change
is a lot easier for
other people to comprehend.
If you want people to understand
what you're doing,
what you need to is explain
why you're doing it.
That helps increase the quality
of the code when
someone comes and has
a look at things.
And second of all, if we need
to yank your changes, it's a
lot easier for us to do that if
we can see the one logical
change that went in, rather than
the intermediate steps,
particularly if you're like me
and you work on two or three
things at the same time.
So we always just squash our
commit before we run this
command, arc diff.
So how do we write
all this code?
We use IntelliJ.
Its Java, right, so there's two
choices of IDE, IntelliJ
or Eclipse.
Both of them are perfectly
reasonable choices.
But the way that we've
structured our codebase means
that IntelliJ is actually a
really good fit for us.
And from a massively biased
point of view, I prefer it.
And Facebook is small enough
that, actually, an individual
choice and someone advocating
can really make
a difference there.
So you're using IntelliJ.
You want to make sure
the code is good.
You want to make sure the
code is testable.
How do you make sure the
code is testable?
You use what?
You use dependency injection.
So when you're doing
object-oriented software, OO
software, you've got
collaborators.
The class that you're working
on collaborates
with a bunch of things.
And there are two ways that
it can get hold of its
collaborators.
The first way was popularized by
J2EE back in the late '90s,
early 2000s, and was
service location.
You had this big thing, and you
went into it in the middle
of your method.
And you went, thing, give me
a database connection.
And thing would look at you
and go, here's a database
connection.
And that would be fine.
And then 2003, 2002, early
2000s, this dependency
injection phrase started
becoming more popular.
And the major difference with
that is that rather than
having the method go, thing,
give me one of these, the
method signature or the class
under test somehow accepted
its collaborators from the
thing that created it.
So there's constructor-based
dependency injection, where
all your collaborators
are passed in at
construction time.
And there's also setter-based
dependency injection.
Also some magic-based dependency
injection, where
you annotate things and then
Guava or Spring or whatever it
is that you like suddenly
populates fields that you have
no idea how it did it.
But it's done it
somehow, right?
Now the advantage with
dependency injection over
service location is it makes
your collaborators really,
really obvious.
It encourages you to think
about who your class is
collaborating with.
I remember I was on one project,
not at Facebook, and
they were using service
location, and I ripped out all
the singletons, and I added
every single thing they
depended on till they construct
a signature.
And 14 arguments later, somebody
went, that's a really
big signature.
Yes, yes it is.
Do you think we've got
too many roles and
responsibilities?
I went, I don't know.
We should probably slim that
signature down somehow.
So yes, how are we
going to do that?
Thinking what we'll do is we'll
split the class up and
have fewer responsibilities.
And what they said to
me is they went, ah,
we'll pass in a map.
[LAUGHTER]
SIMON STEWART: So yes,
dependency injection, a
really, really useful
way of ensuring that
your code is testable.
It makes it really easy to swap
out collaborators at test
time, and that's vital.
So you've written your
code in IntelliJ.
That's nice.
You've used dependency
injection like a good
developer should.
You probably want to
build your code.
Now we use a tool called
Buck at Facebook for
building our code.
Why do we use a tool
that nobody else in
the world yet uses?
There's a number of
reasons for it.
What we want is we wanted a tool
that had minimal overhead
when we added a new library
or module to the project.
Our original [INAUDIBLE]
solution had a lot of
boilerplate code.
It had lots of submodules.
If you've used Maven, the way
that you would do a new module
is probably you'd have a
top-level library, and then
you'd have some sort of
POM that would point
to it and who knows.
It's ugh.
We want to keep boilerplate
out of our codebase.
Boilerplate is things that
machines should do for us.
But we also wanted the
build tool to be
friendly to the IDs.
We'd structured our code in a
way that actually plays really
nicely with IntelliJ, and we
don't want to lose that.
We want really, really
fast, clean builds.
But we want our incremental
builds to be even faster
because as Ari said right at
the beginning of the day,
doing a clean is a bug
in your build system.
You should never, ever
need to do that.
So yes, we want faster
incremental builds.
And what we need to do is we
ahead of time don't know all
the things that people are
going to try and build.
So we want to support adding
ad hoc build steps.
So Buck, our build system, has
three really important
concepts in the middle of it.
The first is a build rule.
Now that's a procedure
for-- oh, you can
all read, can't you?
Yeah, OK.
It's a procedure for producing
output files from input files.
So you list a series of sources
and dependencies.
And the build rule runs.
And you get the outputs.
You get one output.
That's the invariant
of the system.
You can have at most one output
from a build rule.
A build file contains a
series of these rules.
And typically, it's called BUCK
in all capitals, which is
great unless you're on a
case-insensitive file system.
So we declare all the
rules in that.
And if we want to have a
dependency between two rules,
we use a label to get to the
build rule, and call that a
build target.
OK?
So it's a string identifier
for a build rule.
This is what a target
looks like.
I like to read the slash slash
as "from the root of the
repository." So from the top
level, there is a directory
called java, com,
Facebook, share.
Excellent, colon.
In which there is BUCK
file, UI, with a
build rule called UI.
So this gives us a completely
declarative path to the thing
that we're attempting to
build, which is nice.
By the way, if you've ever
used the Selenium build
system, it uses exactly the
same syntax as that.
It's called crazy-fun.
If you work for Twitter, pants
uses, I think, exactly the
same syntax.
Is that right?
Yes, it is.
Brilliant.
Good.
I think it's because there
is a sort of diaspora of
ex-Googlers who pine for the
amazing build system that Ari
talked about.
[APPLAUSE]
SIMON STEWART: So yeah, what
does a build file look like?
[LAUGHTER]
SIMON STEWART: It
looks like that.
This is how we build our
library for Android.
They're called UI, so the
one that we had before.
We do a recursive glob over
the directory structure
underneath, where this
rule is declared.
So it's not over the
entire tree.
It's just over the subtree
beneath this.
We have a series of
dependencies, which are
declared there.
And visibility.
So by default, no one else can
see a build rule outside of
the build file you're
declared in.
So you can have dependencies
within a build file.
But if you step outside, you
need to make it visible.
You can either make it public,
anyone can use this thing, or
you can limit the visibility to
certain subsets of rules.
In order to make it nice and
easy to have a library that
you can depend on in the rest
of your code without needing
to be aware of how that library
is structured, with
the Java library, you can also
export your dependencies.
So you can say, look, if
you depend on me, then
transitively, you get all
my dependencies as well.
Which is a nice way of
composing everything.
Who knows Python?
What language does
that look like?
It's a leading question.
It's Ruby.
No, hang on, it's Python.
Our build file is Python.
We interpret the build file
using the Python interpreter.
We're moving to Jython because,
you know, it would be
nice not to have to rely on
Python being installed on the
local system.
But yes, so it's Python.
And that allows us to do some
really, really nice things.
Like if we're missing the
ability to build a certain
type of target, if a build rule
should exist to build iOS
library, for example, we could
add it to the system using a
glob of rather unpleasant Python
and then just use an
iOS library in the rest
of our build rules.
And then when we modify
Buck, we can fix it.
And we can bake that
into the platform.
And that's kind of nice.
So we've got this ability to
modify the build system on the
fly in a Turing-complete
language in a completely
declarative build system.
I'm not sure how I feel about
that, but it is awfully
convenient.
So what we do, you
run your builds.
We build a directed
acyclic graph.
I was really pleased when I
started working on Buck
because it allowed me to use
some of the computer science
that I struggled through all the
way through university and
use terms like directed
acyclic graph
with a straight face.
And what we do is we analyze
that graph, and we build
sub-parts of the tree
in parallel.
So we try and build everything
as massively
parallel as we can.
And that enables our builds to
be significantly faster.
And then because we know that
if the inputs to one of the
previous steps haven't changed,
the output won't have
changed, we can skip
building that step.
We can just use the
cached output.
And that allows our
incremental builds
to be nice and fast.
How does IntelliJ feel about us
monkeying around on a file
system like this?
Apparently, it likes it.
We run a command called
Buck project.
And what that will do is it will
scan through the entire
file system for BUCK files.
And it will generate the
IntelliJ configs.
So what you do is you go,
aaah, I haven't got an
IntelliJ config.
Buck projects points
IntelliJ at it.
And suddenly, everything
works out quite nicely.
That will also set up some
exports for build rules-- for
test runners and things
like that.
So that's nice.
And it's fast, guys.
This thing is quick.
Because if you want people to
write tests, if you want them
to be using dependency
injection, if you want them to
be doing all these things that
we want to encourage people to
do, being slow doesn't help.
Again, [INAUDIBLE]
the developer who was sleeping,
going longer is better.
Longer isn't better,
shorter is better.
Instant is best.
Actually, if it could somehow
leap forward in time and give
you the results before you
finish writing the code, that
would be better still.
But assuming we're constrained
by the laws of physics,
instant is best.
So Buck, by default, spins up
as many threads as it can,
1.25 times the number of calls
in your machine, as reported
by Java Safe.
You've got hyper threading
enabled.
On the modern laptop, that means
you've got 10 parallel
builders running, four physical
cores, H with hyper
threading, times 1.25, 10.
And we found that by
doing this, we can
slash our build times.
Our build time, when we were
running in single threaded,
used to take about 20 minutes.
And we ran things in parallel,
and we dropped that down to
four minutes.
That's quite nice.
It's an incremental system.
So we only rebuild
what's necessary.
There are going to be some
changes that we're going to
make in the future, like at the
moment, we need to scan
the file system every time we
do a build to figure out
what's changed.
If we demonized something that
watched the file system, as in
turned it into a demon rather
than just told it it was bad
all the time, we could
go faster.
And the other thing as well is
it would be nice to be able to
do a distributed build, and if
someone's built the thing you
need with the same signature of
the inputs, you should be
able to get the same outputs.
You shouldn't need
to do a build.
So in 2012, what happened was we
flipped everyone from using
Ant to using Buck.
And I'm just going to
hide that, pull
that up to the front.
Can we flip to the
Mac, please?
Excellent.
So there are two interesting
things here.
I've checked out the source
code for Buck.
And we build Buck with Ant,
because we're insane.
You can see the activity
monitor from OS
10 just down here.
CPU usage is a thing to look.
So what I'm going to do
is I'm going to do--
let's do a clean.
I'm going to just time a clean
build of Buck and then running
all its tests.
So it's doing the compilation,
excellent.
Now it's running
the test cases.
It's still running
And it continues to run
the test cases.
And I'm not going to wait,
because it takes about a
minute and a bit to
do everything
that it needs to do.
So now what I'll do is I'll use
Buck to run every single
test in the file system, and to
make it a fair comparison,
I'll do a Buck clean.
Because I'm actually in the
directory that Buck is
installed from, we may see
a bit of Ant output as it
bootstraps itself.
We should be fine.
But look at the CPU
usage over here.
What it's doing now is it's
parsing everything.
It's testing all the tests.
It doesn't do a meme.
And bam, in the time it took me
to describe what was going
on, it's run every single test
in the Buck system, and that
took significantly less than the
minute it would've taken
if we were using Ant.
So that's pretty cool, right?
Can we go back to the
slides, please?
So at the time we did the
switchover, it was quicker to
pop up a warning on the Ant
build saying, why don't you go
and download it?
You could download Buck, install
it on the system, and
do a complete build far more
quickly than if you finished
your Any build, which
is crazy.
And the good news is Buck
is open source.
You can go and download it.
You can go and have a play with
the build system that we
use at Facebook.
We accept Pull Requests.
Please send Pull Requests.
They'd be lovely.
It's pretty nice.
If you want to see the
documentation, just head over
to the Facebook.gethub.com, and
take a look at that URL.
It's under the Apache 2 license,
so if you're working
in a bank, you're worried about
having to suddenly make
all your source code available,
because you use a
new build tool, relax.
It's OK.
It is written in JAVA.
I know it's not trendy, but it
is a perfectly working like
language, and a small amount
of Python, which makes the
Pythonistas happy.
And it works in OS
10 and Linux.
Now the reason it doesn't work
on Windows is because nobody
builds on Windows.
AUDIENCE: We wish.
SIMON STEWART: Well
none of our team
currently build on Windows.
I'm sure at some point, there'll
be a need for it.
So I mean, that's a
flippant comment.
And it was fine.
And of course, we build
Buck with Ant.
So, yes, we've got this amazing
fast build time, right?
And that allows us to test.
Testing's good, right.
We get on developers
to write the tests.
At Facebook, there is no SET,
no SDET, no TE, no QAE, no
test department, and
QA department.
We just have engineers.
Now some of the engineers have
a passion for testing in the
same way that some engineers
have a passion for databases,
some of them have a passion for
security, and some of them
have a passion for finding
pictures of kittens on the
internet and posting it
to their timeline.
But we get developers
to write test.
Everyone who writes a line of
code is expected to also be
writing test for that line
of code, which is nice.
Seems to be working out all
right for us so far, and I
quite like it.
I always find that companies
that have a test team, the
test team tends to be looked
down on and not treated with
the love and respect that
they ought to be.
I love you guys, it's OK.
Yeah, I remember sort of getting
interviews from people
going, he wasn't good enough to
be a coder, but he might be
OK as a tester.
And it's like no, no,
no, no, no, no,
you've got it all wrong.
They're not good enough
to be a tester.
They might be all right
as a coder.
And it wasn't appreciated in the
way I thought it would be.
Funny, that really.
So what kind of test do we
ask people to write?
We start with unit tests.
Unit tests run using JUnit.
Kent Beck works at Facebook.
We're not using TestNG.
Cedric doesn't work there.
Kent does.
For those of you who don't know,
Kent Beck wrote JUnit.
Cedric wrote TestNG.
And we encourage people to
write unit tests to run
locally on the JVM, because
we appreciate fast.
Fast is really important,
new fast break tests.
That isn't the Facebook mantra,
but it almost is.
In order to enable people to
move quickly, their using
dependency injection.
We can replace collaborators at
test time using EasyMock.
That's one of the libraries
that we use.
Mockito is another choice if
you're looking to do things.
But EasyMock is what we settled
on at Facebook.
But we're building
an Android app.
And if you include the Android
jar from the Android
development kit, and you run a
test using it, what tends to
happen is any time you touch
anything, included in that
jar,, you get an exception
with Stub!
being the only message
in that exception.
And that's because what they've
done is they've
provided an ABI compatible jar
with no implementations,
because the implementation runs
a Dalvik on the device.
That makes writing tests
incredibly difficult.
That's a bad thing.
We don't like that.
So what we do is we use a
library called Roboletric.
Again, it's open source.
And what that does is
it provides Stub!
Implementations or fake
implementations of each of the
Android methods.
So what we can do is we can
compile, and test and run in
the IDE on your desktop
for a really fast
developer feedback cycle.
And that's nice, because there's
no compilation to
Dalvik, no pushing apps in the
machine, the device, or the
emulator, and you can get that
nice fast cycle time.
We appreciate fast.
But unit tests don't cut
the mustard, right?
You will occasionally want to
make sure that all the unit
tests function correctly, and
the software when you plug
everything together
doesn't fall over.
I was on a project once which
have slightly over 2 and 1/2
thousand tests.
It was a dot net project.
The test ran in about
two seconds.
It was amazing.
And the app would consistently
not start up.
And it's because they had
forgotten to write integration
tests and larger tests, and
they were just using mock
objects and going yeah, it'll
return null here and throw an
exception here for exact
same method.
No, guys, you need
larger tests.
Larger tests, there are a
handful of frameworks
that you can us.
UI Automator, which came
in API level 16--
so basically Jelly
Bean and above.
I think it's there in ICS, but
Jelly Bean and above it,
starts becoming useful.
We use that quite a lot.
We're writing our own test
framework to allow you to
write tests out of
process and off
device, using UI Automator.
We call it Bully, because
it pushes things around.
I may have to come up with a
better name before we open
source it, or maybe
not, who knows.
We also use Robolectric for the
older devices, and there
are some tests using that.
We use MonkeyRunner.
We use a whole series of tools
that come with the Android
development kit.
And they're all quite nice,
but Robolectric, UI
Automator--
those are two of the key
ones that we use.
By the way, we also run things
like power tests, and on
device tests, and things
like that.
But these are tests of the
standard normal developers,
rather than crazy ones who
really enjoy testing.
You've got the code.
You've tested the code.
You kind of think it works,
so you're ready.
You're going to push
it into master.
So you remember way back
in the black slide,
there was arc diff.
What does arc diff
actually do?
Kicks off the code
review process.
You write a description
of what you do, you
write a test plan.
And if the test plan goes well
I don't know or the written
equivalent, you tend to be told
off and told to improve
your test plan.
And we send it up to a tool
called Phabricator, which is
like a Swiss Army chainsaw
of project management.
So it does tasks.
It does code reviews.
It does browsing of
repositories.
It allows you to do all sorts
of clever wonderful things,
and we like Phabricator
at Facebook.
And this is what a code
review looks like.
You can see here that the chap
has submitted a reasonable
test pilot.
It has been greyed out,
but it's in purple.
The reviewer has come
back and asked him
to make some changes.
The developer has made
some changes.
That's what the little icon
second from the bottom does,
and then the reviewer's
gone, this is good.
You can check it in.
Now Phabricator has a killer
feature, and I don't know if
you can tell what it is.
It's image macros.
In the middle of your code
review, you can just type a
little line, and it will
insert an image
into the code review.
This is American Obama, which is
President Obama playing an
electric guitar shaped like a
bald eagle while wearing an
American hat.
I quite like that one.
I stare at it endlessly.
It's fascinating.
And ship it.
It's like, it's all done.
Just ship it, land the code.
Do something interesting.
To land it, we use the
command line tool,
Arc, short for Arcanist.
It's the command line
counterpart to Phabricator.
And landing does two things.
It runs lint, which can
be run separately.
And we use the Android linter
with additional lint rules
that we've added to check for
things like null pointer
exceptions.
So we use at nullible quite a
lot from Guava, optional as
well, like Guava library--
fantastic.
If you're not using it, just
download it now and use it.
It's one of the best things
to come out of Google for
developers for a long,
long time.
It's awesome.
We also make sure that all the
APIs for the versions of
Android that we support are all
present and other bits and
pieces, and we do an Arc land.
What Arc land does is it takes
your changes in your local
branch, rebases them onto master
and pushes your version
of master into the
central one.
So if you take a look at the
history of the project and get
a master, it's a single
linear history.
We don't have weird branching.
It's just a straight
down linear
history of logical changes.
So you've landed your code,
you've tested it.
It's all wonderful, right?
No, hang on.
We also have a continuous
build system.
If you haven't got a continuous
build system yet,
just use one.
I don't care what you use--
CruiseControl, Go--
we use Buildbot.
And you can see here that
most of the time,
things are pretty good.
One developer has caused the
test to fail, and so we're not
going to move the
stable branch.
But when these tests all go
green, then we go, excellent.
And these are sort of longer
running tests, so these are
integration tests, end to end
tests, that we don't want a
developer to run on their local
work station, because
there just isn't time
in the day.
And if you're not breaking the
continuous build server
periodically, you're probably
not working hard enough.
It's what one of my friends
used to say.
I think he's right, actually.
I think it's OK to break the
build periodically, as long as
you fix it immediately
afterwards, possibly by
yanking your change out,
reworking it and
resubmitting it.
So Buildbot runs all these
longer running tests, these
paratests, make sure there are
no regressions in performance
or anything like that.
Now we're done, right?
Oh crap.
Sorry, [INAUDIBLE],
you win the bet.
He betted that I wouldn't
profane.
Does that count as profanity?
I don't know.
Shit, there we go, done
it properly now.
So, yes, it's built.
We need to Dogfood this thing.
As I said before, when you get
this application on your
phone, if it falls over,
[INAUDIBLE] need
to download it again.
That would be an awful, awful
thing to happen, so we Dogfood
extensively.
And one of the platforms that
we make sure that we Dogfood
on is Gingerbread.
Problem is, at Facebook many
of our developers are paid
well enough to be able
to afford an ICS
or Jelly Bean device.
And we can ask for a Galaxy
Nexus for testing
and things like that.
But Gingerbread is still
incredibly popular.
They're still churning
out devices with
Gingerbread on it.
And these are the latest numbers
from the dashboard
that Android has on
their website.
And you can see Gingerbread is
about 40, 45% of the market.
And so what we do is we make
sure that people are
voluntarily using Gingerbread
as their primary device and
they're Dogfooding
our applications.
So they installed the beta
builds on their device, and
they keep on using that.
One of the key people using
Gingerbread as their day to
day device is a release
manager for Android.
He is not always the happiest
person, but he often flags up
pretty nasty regressions that
no one else has caught yet,
because they only show up
as sort of outer memory
exceptions on Gingerbread,
where the devices are
constrained.
So this is the PHP hammer,
by the way.
I don't know if you've
seen it.
It has nothing to do
with the talk.
I just love the picture.
So you've downloaded the beta
version of the app, you've
side loaded it.
What it does is it
periodically--
at Facebook at least--
contacts the build services
and goes, is there a new
version of the application?
And if there is, it nags
people to update it.
So it downloads it in the
background, and then goes,
would you like to install it?
Would you, would
you, would you?
And you go, yeah, all right.
And so once you're on the
testing track at Facebook, and
you always using the beta build,
you're always using the
most recent beta build, which
prevents sort of old bugs
being filed by people.
And finding bugs is incredibly
easy, because what people do
is they take their device,
and they shake it.
Now, we call that a reg shake,
because you normally only
shake your device when you're
going, it's not working.
Oh, hello, I can file
a bug, excellent.
And that's kind of a really
nice feature.
So to get good instant bug
reports from people, as
they're experiencing it, using
the latest version of the
application, which allows
us to do our releases.
Our releases--
never thought I'd get
there, did you?
So you could pick two, when
you're doing a release.
You can have features, quality,
or regular schedule.
Wow, that's a kind
of tough choice.
If there any project managers
in the audience, features,
quality, schedule is not
two, that's three.
So we decided that we were
going to do time based
releases which are
high quality.
That means that occasionally, we
ship without features that
we've been working on.
Now the advantage of a
time based release--
and our releases are about four
weeks long, so what we do
is we cut a branch, we do
stability work for about three
weeks, we have a release
candidate for about a week,
where we push it out to the
beta testers and anyone in
Facebook who volunteers for it,
and then we ship to the
Play Store.
So once a month, there's an
update to the Facebook
application.
And it's really nice having that
regularity, because it
means if you're working on a
feature and you missed this
release, you know that you're
not going to have to wait
forever before the
next release.
it means that you can get the
stuff as quickly as possible.
And it means you've got that
consistency, that regularity.
You also know that your feature
isn't going to be
blocked as somebody else
frantically tries to finish
their thing.
That's nice.
So time based releases are
hugely, hugely valuable to us.
And done isn't just hey, it
compiles, and the tests pass,
and nobody's filed a bug with
it yet on the release
candidates.
Done is things like, isn't the
design work all finished?
We've see changes going into the
release branch around the
design of a feature, that we
know that the piece hasn't
been finished.
If the feature hasn't
been finished, we
yank it from the release.
We either hide it behind a flag
and strip it out using
Dex, ProGuard even, or we just
remove the particular feature,
and we ask people to keep
on working on it.
And logging--
how do we know when we release
a feature that it isn't
causing a million crashes?
We get metrics, and feedback
and information from the
versions of Facebook that you're
running on your phone.
If something goes wrong, we
get told about it somehow.
Sometimes it depends.
And we can look at that data,
and we can go oh, crikey,
there's being a sudden spike in
crashes on this particular
kind of device.
Let's fix that.
So we get information
from the world.
If you haven't put logging in,
we can't get that information.
Sometimes there are certain
side changes
that need to be made.
We still use WebViews
in a few places.
So if you're pushing a new
feature, we need to make sure
it works for the old and the
new vision of the app.
And obviously, privacy and
legal review are really,
really important.
Facebook cares about privacy.
We're a social network.
If people don't trust
us with their data,
we're dead in the water.
So we need to really, really be
concerned with privacy, and
we are, and legal review,
just in case.
So they're just as important as
a code review, and that's
what done means.
So that's basically how we bake
quality into the Facebook
application.
We go all the way through.
We run tests consistently.
We encourage people to use
design patterns for
testability.
We have defense in depth.
So there are unit tests,
integration tests, the
continuous integration server.
We have people Dogfooding
all the time.
We encourage people to use
devices that aren't commonly
used by people who have got well
paid jobs, but are used
widely in the real world,
particularly in the small
markets, the emerging markets.
Great, so thank you very
much for your time.
We've got time for
some questions.
Thank you.
TONY VOELLM: Thank you,
thank you, Simon.
That was fantastic.
I really liked seeing
the end to end.
We have a couple
live questions.
So how about we go to
the left first.
Go ahead and state your name,
where you're from.
AUDIENCE: Hi, my name's
Christian from Google.
I actually work on
the Guava team.
SIMON STEWART: Awesome work.
AUDIENCE: Yeah, well, that's
more my other teammates.
SIMON STEWART: The
JDK5 backport--
fantastic.
AUDIENCE: Working
on that today.
SIMON STEWART: Ship it.
AUDIENCE: So I want to thank you
for some really innovative
work on build systems, and
putting that out to the
community is a really
awesome thing.
So I'm glad to see it.
I had a question about Buck,
particularly because not all
companies have access to
all the source code
they will ever build.
So how do you handle binary
dependencies of things that
are third party libraries.
SIMON STEWART: Yep, there's a
rule called pre-built jar,
where you can just check in.
So we've got third party
dependencies.
We don't build Guava from
source, for example.
We just checking in the jars.
AUDIENCE: OK, you
check in jars.
SIMON STEWART: Yeah we
check in the jars.
We have pre-built binary
rules, and you
can depend on those.
The binary rules allow you to
also attach source jars and
javadoc jars.
And if you do that when you
run Buck Project, it will
actually hook in the sources,
so that you can browse into
the source code while you're
working on your project.
AUDIENCE: Very sweet, and
obviously you have an Eclipse
plug-in coming soon, right?
SIMON STEWART: We accept
pull requests.
AUDIENCE: All right,
there you go.
TONY VOELLM: OK, it looks like
we have time for one more
question, so we'll
go over here.
AUDIENCE: I'm Dave.
I'm from Family Search.
So you mentioned that the
codes in a single tree--
is that like all of the code at
Facebook, or is it just the
code for Android?
And the other question the kind
of goes along with it is
does that mean it's all
in one get repo?
And how does that perform?
SIMON STEWART: So at the
moment, the Android
code is in one repo.
The IOS code is in another, and
dub, dub, dub, the website
is in the third repo.
I think Google have
demonstrated, you can smoosh
everything together, and that
works pretty well for Google.
I mean, we saw all the stats
earlier, which were amazing,
just totally mind blowing.
So we could do it that way.
But at the moment, we
have separate repos
for the various things.
But all the Android code
lives in one tree.
Cool.
TONY VOELLM: OK, actually maybe
we'll just grab one
more, and then I have some
announcements about dinner and
things like that right after
this, so go ahead, last
question, please.
AUDIENCE: Noah Sussman, I'm an
independent consultant, but
formerly of Etsy, where I
designed the CI system with
pre commit, because it
worked so awesomely
for Google and Mozilla.
So why not?
Why no pre commit?
I'm fascinated.
SIMON STEWART: Just because we
haven't had the need for it.
The other thing, as well, is
sort of we're a relatively
small company.
I know 1400 engineers sounds
like an awful lot, but That's
1400 engineers spread over the
web, the IOS app. the Android
app, working on our internal
tooling, working on stuff for
our data centers,
just everything.
Facebook does more than
just the news feed.
We've got messaging
infrastructure.
We've got groups.
We've got all sorts
of fun things.
So 1400 engineers isn't
actually that many.
The team working on Buck--
there's about three consistent
contributors, and then there
are other people who join the
team for a month or two, and
then they roll back out again.
So there just isn't a huge
amount of manpower.
And it turns out that if you run
all the unit tests before
you check in, that catches
most of the problems.
So that hasn't been this sort of
pressing need to have a pre
submit thing.
When there is a neat, then
I think we'll do it.
But YAGNE is a really
good mantra.
If you've not heard
of YAGNE, it comes
from the Agile community.
You Ain't Gonna Need It.
So don't write it, don't use it,
until you actually have a
need for it.
And then put it in.
So that's why we don't do it.
TONY VOELLM: With that,
thank you, Simon.
Hopefully you'll join
us for dinner.
SIMON STEWART: Thanks
very much, guys.
TONY VOELLM: Wow, that
was a incredible day.
There's a lot to digest, a lot
of really fascinating things
we learned about, everything
from how to verify set-top
boxes from YouView, not
You-- the other one.
We learned from academia about
how to use gaining and gaining
type systems to engage and
create the next generation of
computer scientists, and even do
some very interesting work.
There's just a lot to think
about, so hopefully you'll
think about it.
And hopefully you'll share it
on the stream and everything
that we have on G+
and Twitter.
We'd love to hear what
you thought was
interesting as well.
For dinner, what we're going to
do is everybody is invited
to dinner if you're up in the
water tower, but because we're
going to go through behind
closed doors areas, we're
going to have people meet
us in the lobby.
And then we'll take shifts of
moving everybody up to the
water tower cafeteria.
Please, no photos once you walk
through the secure doors.
That would not be happy
for you to do that.
So please don't take any photos,
but definitely come
and enjoy dinner.
And I hope all the speakers
are going to join us.
And you can go ask them
further questions.
So with that, start meeting us
out in the lobby, and then
we'll walk you up So thank
you, thank you.
[APPLAUSE]
[MUSIC PLAYING]