[MUSIC__-_REGGIE_WATTS]
JASON SCHWARTZMAN:
Ladies and gentlemen,
welcome to the first-ever
YouTube Music Awards.
[CHEERING]
[MUSIC - ARCADE
FIRE, "AFTERLIFE"]
WIN BUTLER: We love you, Lou.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: All right.
That was awesome!
Hi.
How are you?
I mean, I want to hug you.
REGGIE WATTS: That's incredible.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: I want to
hug you, but there's so many.
I mean, how do we do it quickly?
Can we just do it
like this real quick?
OK.
REGGIE WATTS: It's a group hug.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: All right.
OK, great.
Well, that was a good--
FEMALE SPEAKER: That was good.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: That
was our first live music
video of the evening,
from Arcade Fire, directed
by Spike Jonze.
WIN BUTLER: This is live.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: This is live?
WIN BUTLER: It's actually live.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: Right now?
WIN BUTLER: Don't be nervous.
REGGIE WATTS: That's weird.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN:
All right, well--
REGGIE WATTS: I guess it's live.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: It is live.
REGGIE WATTS: OK.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN:
I didn't think
they meant it when they said it.
REGGIE WATTS: OK, well--
JASON SCHWARTZMAN:
Where's everybody going?
REGGIE WATTS: Hold on.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN:
Everyone's leaving.
REGGIE WATTS: Why
is everyone-- OK.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: No, we want
to say-- that was Greta Gerwig,
by the way, dancing--
REGGIE WATTS: That was amazing.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: --with
those wonderful children.
Thank you, Greta.
Thank you, children.
I don't know all of your
names, but for the evening I'm
just going to call you Diana
as a collective, I guess.
REGGIE WATTS: Yeah,
Diana as a collective
for a group of
children is great.
I think that's a good idea.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: So
I'm Jason Schwartzman.
REGGIE WATTS: Hi,
I'm Reggie Watts.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: And we're
hosting the first-ever YouTube
Music Awards, presented by Kia.
REGGIE WATTS: Yes.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: So
for the last two weeks,
millions of people
have been voting.
In fact, I think the
number was 16 billion.
REGGIE WATTS: 16 billion.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: People have
voted, which is unbelievable.
I don't really believe it.
And so it's-- yeah.
Hey.
REGGIE WATTS: Hi.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: Hi, guys.
REGGIE WATTS: What?
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: Hi.
REGGIE WATTS: There's
so many people up here.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN:
So 16 million people.
And you guys tonight, we
find out who you voted for,
who the winner is.
This is the big night.
So get excited.
REGGIE WATTS: There's
a theme tonight.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: And
the theme of the night
is creativity because that's
what this is all about,
making things.
And we're celebrating the
people who made things,
and people who made things
on YouTube with music.
So if you look behind me,
all these people here,
these are all the musical
acts and directors
and creative people and
collaborators that have--
REGGIE WATTS: Every
single person.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: We've
all joined together
to put on a one of a kind
hopefully live show for you
tonight.
REGGIE WATTS: This guy too.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: We're going
to be making live music videos.
Do you want to
introduce some people?
REGGIE WATTS: Yeah,
let's introduce them.
OK, so here we have
Tyler, the Creator.
[CHEERING]
REGGIE WATTS: Yes, right here.
Avicii.
[CHEERING]
REGGIE WATTS: Yes.
We have Arcade Fire.
Yes, M.I.A.
[CHEERING]
REGGIE WATTS: Where is she?
Get it?
OK.
Lindsey Stirling.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN:
Earl Sweatshirt.
REGGIE WATTS: Earl Sweatshirt.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN:
Lindsey Stirling.
REGGIE WATTS: Who else?
Eminem and Lady Gaga are
backstage getting ready.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN:
They're getting ready?
Yeah.
I like your shirt.
REGGIE WATTS: This is
everybody-- everybody.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: And we have
amazing directors tonight.
James Larese, Ray Tintori,
Fafi-- my sweet baby Fafi.
Hi, Fafi.
OK Go, Joe Sabia,
Wolf Haley, one
of my favorite
directors in the world.
REGGIE WATTS: Yep.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: Where is he?
REGGIE WATTS: I don't know.
There's our creative
director too,
Spike Jonze, and Chris Milk.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN:
Listen, I want
to just let you know something.
I've never hosted
anything in my life.
One Christmas party,
and it was terrible.
I didn't introduce
anybody to anybody.
And I want to say that-- huh?
Listen, guys.
We were invited to come
here and host, Reggie and I.
REGGIE WATTS: That's
right, we were.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN:
And it was decided
early on that we
shouldn't have a script.
We have some note cards
with bullet points on them.
I already ruined mine.
But there is nothing
scripted tonight.
This is all about
anything happening.
It's all about that.
REGGIE WATTS: We're basically
the same as one of you guys,
but we're here to kind of be
a surrogate to the experience.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: So
listen, anything can happen.
There's no script.
And it was decided upon--
all right, we're going to go.
REGGIE WATTS: We're
going to go now.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: But I
want to tell you one thing.
Anything can happen,
and there are
going to be a
series of obstacles
that Reggie and I have to
attempt to overcome tonight.
Please bear with us if
you're watching this,
and you're someone--
what is that?
Ugh, it's a Sharpie.
All right, I'm OK.
REGGIE WATTS: You
just got sharped.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: It's OK.
I didn't know what it was.
REGGIE WATTS: By the director.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN:
It came at me fast.
I got bad peripheral
vision in my left eye.
All right, please welcome
CDZA with the history
of music on YouTube.
Go!
Have fun!
Enjoy yourselves!
REGGIE WATTS: CDZA!
MICHAEL THURBER: A
one, two, three, four.
Good evening, ladies
and gentlemen.
We are CDZA, and we
are going to give you
an abridged history of some of
the greatest music on YouTube.
Go!
[MUSIC - CDZA, "ABRIDGED
HISTORY OF YOUTUBE MUSIC"]
MICHAEL THURBER: But
what kind of history
would it be without
the amazing Tay Zonday?
[MUSIC - TAY ZONDAY,
"CHOCOLATE RAIN"]
[MUSIC - CDZA, "ABRIDGED
HISTORY OF YOUTUBE MUSIC"]
MICHAEL THURBER: Ladies and
gentlemen, put your hands
together for the
one and only T-Pain!
[MUSIC - T-PAIN,
"I'M ON A BOAT"]
MICHAEL THURBER: And now put
your hands together for Walk
Off the Earth!
[MUSIC_-_WALK_OFF_THE_EARTH]
[MUSIC - CDZA, "ABRIDGED
HISTORY OF YOUTUBE MUSIC"]
MICHAEL THURBER: Ladies
and gentlemen, we like you
guys so much.
Let's have an amazing night
at the YouTube Music Awards!
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: All right.
REGGIE WATTS: All right!
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: I feel good.
It feels good.
It feels good, Reggie.
REGGIE WATTS: That
felt really good.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN:
How do you feel?
REGGIE WATTS: And it
was very professional.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: I feel good.
How do you guys feel?
REGGIE WATTS: You
guys feel all right?
FEMALE SPEAKER: Amazing.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: Yeah?
FEMALE SPEAKER: Awesome.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Amazing night.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN:
It was awesome.
I have a hair in
my mouth somehow.
It's odd.
REGGIE WATTS: Yeah,
but leave it in there.
It'll have a drying effect.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: Really?
I should put it back?
I have to find it.
I threw it on the floor.
REGGIE WATTS: Put it
between cheek and gum.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN:
So as a reminder,
we're about to give out our
first award of the night,
and it's chosen by you.
So we're going to go to
the VIP section, which is--
REGGIE WATTS: Where is that?
JASON SCHWARTZMAN:
How do we get there?
All right, this way.
REGGIE WATTS: That's
a long ways away.
MIKE: We've got to run there.
REGGIE WATTS: OK.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN:
We have to run there.
Oh, wait.
Before we go, can I
introduce you really quickly?
This is Mike.
Mike, say hi.
MIKE: Hi, guys.
How are you?
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: All right.
Mike's going to take
care of us tonight.
We're going to run?
How fast?
Go.
REGGIE WATTS: OK, let's go.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: All
right, I'm running.
OK, it's fine.
I'm going right around you.
Where are you, Reggie?
Aah!
Obstacles!
People!
Reggie, you go first.
I'll help you.
REGGIE WATTS: OK.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: Never climb
up the other side of a ladder.
All right, Daddy's going up.
REGGIE WATTS: OK, there we go.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: Thank you.
REGGIE WATTS: By the way--
RASHIDA JONES: Hey, how are you?
REGGIE WATTS: Hi.
RASHIDA JONES: Hi.
Hi.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN:
Rashida Jones, hi.
RASHIDA JONES: Hi.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: How are you?
Nice to see you.
RASHIDA JONES: Hi.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN:
Who are these people?
REGGIE WATTS: Who are these?
RASHIDA JONES:
You guys are cool.
Just check them out for a while.
I'm going to go, but
thank you so much.
Thank you.
Thanks.
REGGIE WATTS: Rashida!
Rashida, no.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: OK.
Rashida?
Rashida, when were these
babies last fed, though?
REGGIE WATTS: All right.
Hi.
So-- oh, hi.
OK, announce the next thing.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: OK.
I'm going to hold up this card.
REGGIE WATTS: OK, now--
JASON SCHWARTZMAN:
All right, listen.
The YouTube Breakthrough
recognizes the biggest breakout
acts on YouTube, the artists
with the highest growth.
Speaking of growth,
you're a baby.
Shh, it's OK.
Speaking of growth and
views and subscribers
over the past years,
roll to the package.
[MUSIC - KENDRICK LAMAR,
"BITCH, DON'T KILL MY VIBE"]
[MUSIC, NAUGHTY BOY, "LA LA LA"]
[MUSIC - MACKLEMORE &
RYAN LEWIS, "THRIFT SHOP"]
[MUSIC - RUDIMENTAL,
"WAITING ALL NIGHT"]
[MUSIC - PASSENGER,
"LET HER GO"]
JASON SCHWARTZMAN:
And your award
goes to Macklemore
and Ryan Lewis.
REGGIE WATTS: Macklemore
and Ryan Lewis!
JASON SCHWARTZMAN:
Congratulations.
On everything, congratulations.
REGGIE WATTS: Hello.
MACKLEMORE: Do we get
to keep the babies now?
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: I don't know.
I don't think--
REGGIE WATTS: You want
to keep the babies?
MACKLEMORE: This video
was one that we shot.
We spent about $5,000
on this music video.
And we did it with our friends.
And we went to different
thrift shops in Seattle
and just had fun
making a music video.
That was it.
And we didn't have babies.
If we would have had
babies, it probably
wouldn't have been as
successful, because babies cry.
But they're amazing.
And I can't believe that
we won these kids, man.
I've always wanted a kid without
having to actually have sex,
so this is perfect.
REGGIE WATTS: Here's the award.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: Here's
your award, technically.
REGGIE WATTS: There you go.
I almost forgot.
That's the award.
But hold it the right way.
Otherwise, time will reverse.
MACKLEMORE: Can I say
something real quick?
REGGIE WATTS: Yeah.
MACKLEMORE: I just want to
thank my elementary school, Tops
in Seattle.
I want to thank--
REGGIE WATTS: Seattle!
JASON SCHWARTZMAN:
All right, listen.
MACKLEMORE: I want to thank
my parents and my fiancee
and the person that used to sell
me sh-- when I was a teenager.
I love you all.
[CHEERING]
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: All
right, listen, you guys.
REGGIE WATTS: Pacific Northwest.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: It's time
for our next live music video.
And I'd like to welcome
the world to Lady Gaga.
[CHEERING]
LADY GAGA: This is for my dad.
I'm sorry, Dad.
And I'm sorry, Mom and Natali.
And this is for my fans.
I'm sorry too.
And this is for my lover.
And I love you too.
AUDIENCE: I love you, Gaga.
AUDIENCE: We love you!
LADY GAGA: And
this is for anybody
who has that pain inside.
They don't know why.
But--
[SIGH]
LADY GAGA: This
is for you, Spike.
[MUSIC_-_LADY_GAGA,_"DOPE"]
[CHEERING]
AUDIENCE: Gaga!
Gaga!
[CHEERING]
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: This is a
message from our sponsor, Kia,
who made this video at a
party they threw last night.
TARYN SOUTHERN:
Whew, loud out there.
Hey, guys, I'm Taryn
Southern, and I'm here
at Kia Soul Live, which
is the official pre-party
for the YouTube Music Awards.
And we're celebrating with
artists and their fans.
Not only is Kia super proud to
present the first-ever YouTube
Music Awards, but also
the Response of the Year
Award, which honors the best
of song covers and parodies
and remixes on
YouTube this year.
Let's see who the fans
are voting for, shall we?
FEMALE SPEAKER: We
voted for Boyce Avenue
with Fifth Harmony, "Mirrors."
MALE SPEAKER: Boyce Avenue
featuring Fifth Harmony.
I love their videos.
I'm a big fan.
FEMALE SPEAKER: I voted
for Lindsey Stirling
because I love her.
MALE SPEAKER: I loved KRNFX.
That guy was awesome.
KAREN SOUTHERN: So
there you guys have it.
I don't know about you,
but I'm ready to find out
who won Response of the Year.
So back to the
YouTube Music Awards!
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: The award
for Response of the Year,
presented by Kia,
recognizes the best remixes,
covers, and parodies on
YouTube based on your views,
likes, shares, and comments.
I'm going to throw
to the package.
[MUSIC - LINDSEY STIRLING AND
PENTATONIX, "RADIOACTIVE"]
[MUSIC - BOYCE AVENUE FEATURING
FIFTH HARMONY, "MIRRORS"]
[MUSIC - WALK OFF THE
EARTH FEATURING KRNFX,
"I KNEW YOU WERE TROUBLE"]
[MUSIC - JAYESSLEE,
"GANGNAM STYLE"]
[MUSIC - THE PIANO
GUYS, "TITANIUM/PAVANE"]
REGGIE WATTS: All
right, the winner is--
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: The
winner's name is in the cake.
REGGIE WATTS: It's in the cake?
What cake?
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: The
winner's name is in the cake.
REGGIE WATTS: Winner's
name is in the cake.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: Oh.
REGGIE WATTS: Jason,
the winner's name is--
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: So, OK.
It says the winner's
name is in the cake.
Reggie?
REGGIE WATTS: Yeah?
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: Divide and
conquer, or how do we want to--
REGGIE WATTS: Let's
divide and conquer.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN:
So I'll take--
REGGIE WATTS: Yeah, you want to
take it from this portion over?
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: Yeah.
Are you going to work far right?
How are you going to do it?
REGGIE WATTS: I'll
go left to middle.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: Likewise.
REGGIE WATTS: OK.
All right.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN:
Aw, man, I hate
to have this cake go to
waste, so I'd like to cut it.
Should we cut it?
Is there a knife?
Yeah, cut it.
I don't want to waste this cake.
REGGIE WATTS: This cake
could feed a lot of people.
OK, there's nothing in that one.
OK.
Why don't we do middle first?
Doesn't that make more sense?
Oh, wait.
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
What's this?
This isn't it.
OK, it looks like white
card is the winner.
Nope.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: The
winner is Lindsey Stirling
and Pentatonix, "Radioactive."
[CHEERING]
REGGIE WATTS: Finding Lindsey.
Finding Lindsey.
LINDSEY STIRLING: Over here.
REGGIE WATTS: Finding Lindsey.
LINDSEY STIRLING: Hello.
REGGIE WATTS: Oh my god!
LINDSEY STIRLING: Oh!
REGGIE WATTS: Jason,
quick, I found a Lindsey.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: I'm coming!
LINDSEY STIRLING:
Oh, I'm so excited.
REGGIE WATTS: How are you?
LINDSEY STIRLING: I'm good.
REGGIE WATTS: Good.
This is my cake hand, so.
LINDSEY STIRLING: Oh, nice.
REGGIE WATTS: Oh, yeah.
LINDSEY STIRLING: Oh, hey there.
REGGIE WATTS: Yep, he does that.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: Hi, darling.
LINDSEY STIRLING: Hi.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: How are you?
Congratulations.
I'm so sorry.
LINDSEY STIRLING:
Oh, cake hands.
REGGIE WATTS: Oh, thank you.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN:
Congratulations.
LINDSEY STIRLING: Here we go.
REGGIE WATTS: We want
to present this to you.
This is the award for
the award that you won.
LINDSEY STIRLING:
Oh my goodness!
REGGIE WATTS: It's a
representation of the award
that you won.
LINDSEY STIRLING:
It's beautiful.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN:
Yeah, congrats.
It's amazing, all that
you've accomplished.
Truly it is.
It's great.
LINDSEY STIRLING:
Well, thank you.
And a big shout
out to Pentatonix,
who won this award with me.
Love you guys.
REGGIE WATTS: Yeah, yeah!
LINDSEY STIRLING: Awesome.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: How
long have you been playing?
LINDSEY STIRLING:
I've been playing
since I was six years old.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: Wow.
REGGIE WATTS: I knew you
were going to say that.
LINDSEY STIRLING: You knew it?
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: Really?
REGGIE WATTS: Suzuki method?
LINDSEY STIRLING:
Suzuki all the way.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: Really?
LINDSEY STIRLING: Yeah, you too?
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: No, only
the first couple albums.
REGGIE WATTS: Where'd
you learn to dance?
LINDSEY STIRLING:
Actually, I was
self-taught through watching
YouTube tutorials, no joke.
REGGIE WATTS: What?
You're pure YouTube.
LINDSEY STIRLING: Exactly.
You know what?
I owe everything of my success
and this award to YouTube.
I was the artist that
everybody wanted to change.
And YouTube allowed me to be
true to my passion, allowed
me to be true to my
values, and true to myself.
So thank you, YouTube.
Thanks for all the fans.
And thanks to Pentatonix!
[CHEERING]
LINDSEY STIRLING: Yay!
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: All right.
Our next live music video is
performed by Earl Sweatshirt,
and it features
Tyler, the Creator.
And it's directed by Wolf Haley.
Now, I love these
guys very much.
We want to put them
in a big, pink box.
It's for their song "Sasquatch."
Look, a shark!
REGGIE WATTS: Where?
[MUSIC - EARL SWEATSHIRT
AND TYLER, THE CREATOR,
"SASQUATCH"]
[CHEERING]
EARL SWEATSHIRT:
[INAUDIBLE] in this bitch.
Thanks, guys.
Hey, back up.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN:
That was great.
That was great, you guys.
Well, innovation
means many things.
Reggie, what's
innovative to you?
REGGIE WATTS: Well, I think
innovation is the spirit
to do whatever you want to do
without thinking about it too
hard, but implementing the
forces of chaos and darkness
to transform it into something
even darker, or perhaps
even a little bit lighter.
Force of chaos.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN:
What do you guys think?
This is OK Go, by the way.
[CHEERING]
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: Damian,
what is innovation to you?
DAMIAN KULASH: Force of chaos
is pretty dead-on right there,
yeah.
Force of chaos
harnessed for good.
DAN KONOPKA: Yeah.
Yeah.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: Force--
DAN KONOPKA: Spirit of darkness.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN:
Spirit of darkness, OK.
Well, in the spirit of
chaos and innovation,
OK Go are going to do a little
bit of innovation on my face
right now.
Go, guys.
Hit it.
DAMIAN KULASH: OK, go.
[MUSIC_-_REGGIE_WATTS]
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: Innovation.
That cream feels
good on my face.
DAMIAN KULASH: It feels
good putting cream
on your face, man.
It feels real good putting
cream on your face.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: You
know, it's innovative.
Children-- I want to thank those
two little beautiful children
who were out earlier.
I'm sorry if they were scared.
But I love them.
Before we give out this next
award, it's technically mine.
So I'm going to dedicate
this award to my daughter.
DAMIAN KULASH: For my
last color, guys, I want--
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: This
award is for you, baby.
I love you, sweetie.
[MUSIC_-_REGGIE_WATTS]
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: Shh.
All right.
And now a little bit of magic.
MALE SPEAKER: Head back, Jason.
Head back.
There you go.
[MUSIC_-_REGGIE_WATTS]
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: The
award for innovation
recognizes some of the most
unique concepts and creators
in music videos on
YouTube this year.
Roll it, daddy.
[MUSIC - BAT FOR
LASHES, "LILIES"]
[MUSIC - ANAMANAGUCHI,
"ENDLESS FANTASY"]
[MUSIC - ATOMS FOR
PEACE, "INGENUE"]
[MUSIC - TORO Y MOI, "SAY THAT"]
[MUSIC - DESTORM,
"SEE ME STANDING"]
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: All
right, ready, Reggie?
REGGIE WATTS: Yeah, I'm here.
So here.
Oh.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN:
Unlock the envelope.
REGGIE WATTS: Let's see, towel.
Oh, OK.
And that.
OK.
I'm going to give
you this towel.
This is for you and all of
your camouflagic troubles.
And we're going to announce this
Innovation of the Year Award
together.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN:
All right, go ahead.
REGGIE WATTS: OK.
I'm going to open the envelope.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN:
OK, I'm with you.
REGGIE WATTS: Because I know
you can't see right now.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN:
I can see, but--
REGGIE WATTS: OK.
I want you to read it because
you went through so much.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN:
DeStorm, "See Me Standing."
Get up here.
The winner is DeStorm.
Come up.
Where are you?
REGGIE WATTS: DeStorm,
"See Me Standing,"
ladies and gentlemen.
May I give this and
present this to you?
DESTORM POWER: Yeah.
Damn.
REGGIE WATTS: Sir.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN:
Congratulations.
DESTORM POWER: Thank you.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN:
Hi, I'm Jason.
DESTORM POWER: Hey, what's up?
JASON SCHWARTZMAN:
Pleasure to meet you.
REGGIE WATTS: Hi, I'm Reggie.
DESTORM POWER: Yo.
REGGIE WATTS: Good to meet you.
DESTORM POWER: I just received
the dopest paperweight ever!
That's what's up, YouTube!
Yo, I just want to
say that YouTube,
they started something
amazing six years ago.
I've been on there
for, like, ever.
And this award means more than
any other award I ever got,
because YouTube
was my beginning.
So I just want to
thank God, Matei
Dima for producing
an amazing video.
And to all the fans who put
up with me for seven years,
I thank y'all for that.
And man, that's some crazy sh--
going on on your face, man.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: Thank you.
It's makeup paint.
Like it's not real paint,
but it's not real makeup.
It's somewhere where they meet.
It's like brackish water.
DESTORM POWER: It's dope.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN:
Yeah, thank you.
Thank you.
DESTORM POWER: Well,
thank y'all, man.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: Thank you.
REGGIE WATTS: DeStorm!
OK.
REGGIE WATTS: All right.
Like many of you,
our next performer
made her own video
for her original song
and uploaded it onto YouTube.
Almost 500 million
views later, she's
with us here tonight
to perform that song,
"Crystallize," in a live music
video directed by Ray Tintori.
Please welcome Lindsey Stirling!
[CHEERING]
[MUSIC - LINDSEY
STIRLING, "CRYSTALLIZE"]
[CHEERING]
[MUSIC - REGGIE WATTS
AND JASON SCHWARTZMAN]
[MUSIC_-_PSY,_"GANGNAM_STYLE"]
[MUSIC - BAAUER, "HARLEM SHAKE"]
[MUSIC - TAYLOR SWIFT, "I
KNEW YOU WERE TROUBLE"]
[MUSIC_-_RIHANNA,_"DIAMONDS"]
[MUSIC - MACKLEMORE AND
RYAN LEWIS, "THRIFT SHOP"]
JASON SCHWARTZMAN:
Listen, I'm going
to go ahead and
open this envelope.
And your winner's-- the winner's
name is somewhere on the stage.
REGGIE WATTS: OK.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN:
Wait a second.
REGGIE WATTS: What about
this obvious thing here?
Should we--
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: Wait.
REGGIE WATTS: I'm
really afraid, though.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: I am too.
Hold on.
Before we do this--
REGGIE WATTS: What if this is--
JASON SCHWARTZMAN:
Are you allergic
to anything I should know about?
REGGIE WATTS: I'm allergic
to nuts and gluten,
so this better be not a--
JASON SCHWARTZMAN:
I hope there's not
like a nut cake in there.
REGGIE WATTS: Yeah.
Yeah, with extra gluten.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: Reggie, stop.
REGGIE WATTS: OK.
All right.
Should we?
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: Yes.
All right, let's make this bed.
Let's unmake this bed together.
One, two, three.
FEMALE SPEAKER: "I
Knew You Were Trouble!"
REGGIE WATTS: Taylor Swift,
"I Knew You Were Trouble."
Hi.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN:
Well then, who
is going to accept this award?
REGGIE WATTS: Oh,
there they are.
You guys, come on.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN:
Hi, how are you?
I'm Jason.
REGGIE WATTS: Whose
little sister is this?
JASON SCHWARTZMAN:
Nice to meet you.
REGGIE WATTS: Is this
your little sister?
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: Hey, you
brought your own microphone.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Yeah, I
don't know if it works.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: That's good.
Hey, I'm Jason.
Hi, how are you?
REGGIE WATTS: Hi, guys.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN:
Hi, guys, how are--
REGGIE WATTS: Thank
you very much.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: Thank you.
Well, it got painted.
Hi, how are you?
REGGIE WATTS: Hi, how are you?
FEMALE SPEAKER: Hi.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: How are you?
Congratulations.
FEMALE SPEAKER: I'm
fine, thank you.
REGGIE WATTS: Hi, how are you?
Nice to meet you.
Hi.
Oh, why, thank you.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: So
you guys, let's discuss--
may I ask you a few questions?
How did you choose
this song to cover?
FEMALE SPEAKER: Because
it was super awesome.
FEMALE SPEAKER:
Because we we loved it.
FEMALE SPEAKER: And
everyone loved it.
Taylor Swift is so talented,
and we are so honored
to be accepting
this on her behalf.
Who loves Taylor Swift?
[CHEERING]
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: Oh.
WIN BUTLER: Not Taylor Swift,
I'm going to let you finish.
[LAUGHTER]
WIN BUTLER: Not Taylor
Swift, the YouTube phenomenon
of the year was definitely
the Harlem Shake.
I don't know.
No disrespect.
But everyone knows
that if you've ever
even been on
YouTube, so whatever.
[CHEERING]
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: Go
to the behind the-- Oh.
Guys, I love you all.
Sorry that had to happen.
FEMALE SPEAKER: It's OK.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: Please
welcome a beautiful short film
for Avicii.
Avicii!
REGGIE WATTS: Avicii!
[MUSIC_-_AVICII]
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: Stop!
All right.
Now we have come to the
Choose Your Own Adventure
portion of the short film.
And to decide what
happens next, we're
going to use a very
modern technology.
It's beyond Twitter.
It's hardly been
tested, in fact.
It's called raising your hand.
Looks like this.
Yeah, a lot of you
have them up already.
OK, so to decide what
happens to these two people,
we have to see if you think
that this girl and this boy
had a nice time tonight and
should walk off this stage,
hail a taxi, go meet
each other's parents,
and have a soup.
Or if you think that they
should just-- I don't know,
go out in a blaze
of romantic glory
in some kind of
a double tragedy.
All right, option
one is the soup.
Raise your hand for the soup.
Option two is the
double tragedy.
[CHEERING]
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: All right.
OK.
Avicii-- OK.
All right, roll it,
Avicii, option two.
[MUSIC_-_AVICII]
[CHEERING]
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: Hi.
I'm hot.
I'm hot right now.
Ah.
Up to the stage.
Come with me.
Hi, how are you?
What's your name?
SHOSHANNA: Shoshanna.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: Hi,
Shoshanna, I'm Jason.
I'll talk to you
later, all right?
Hey, how are you?
REGGIE WATTS: Jason, over here.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN:
Where are you, Reg?
REGGIE WATTS: Jason, here.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: Hi, guys.
REGGIE WATTS: Jason, this way.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN:
Can I come through?
REGGIE WATTS: Yeah,
come on this-- yeah.
No, no, this way.
Don't go through--
OK, yes, this way.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: All right.
How are you?
What's your name?
DARIUS: Darius.
REGGIE WATTS: Darius.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN:
Awesome, nice to meet you.
Thank you for your help tonight.
REGGIE WATTS: It's a good name.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: OK.
REGGIE WATTS: OK.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: Yeah.
REGGIE WATTS: OK,
zip-a-dee-doo-dah, zippy.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: OK.
REGGIE WATTS: Hey, br--
MICHAEL CERA: Guys, guys,
guys, no one can hear you.
No one can hear you.
The mics got killed.
Thank you.
Hi.
I'm here too.
Guys, no one can hear you.
But listen, I brought my own
personal microphone from home.
I knew something like
this was going to happen.
So here.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: My--
MICHAEL CERA: You know what?
It's programmed to
only react to my voice.
But here.
Take these cue cards and read
along, and move your lips.
And I'll provide
your voices, OK?
Jason, go.
Just-- here, read along.
Read along.
Well, ladies and gentlemen, this
is a total unexpected surprise.
We had no idea the
superbly talented
Michael Cera would join
us on stage tonight.
Jason, don't improvise.
Stick to the script.
This is running long.
No, Michael, Jason is right.
It's important to take
the time to acknowledge
what a special talent you are.
And I know Michael
doesn't pay any attention
to this kind of thing.
But in the past few
days, his IMDb STARmeter
went up eight points.
I don't think anyone
else who's here
could make that kind
of claim tonight.
Reggie, you'll make him blush.
He's down to earth.
When I worked with
Michael on "Scott Pilgrim
Against the Planet,"
the whole time
it was muy hard
to play his enemy.
That's what I call acting.
Impressive.
What's that?
Oh.
Apparently our microphones
are back in business.
Michael, you can leave now.
OK.
All right.
I'm sorry if I did the
wrong thing tonight.
We love you, Michael.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN:
I love you, Michael.
REGGIE WATTS:
Thank you, Michael.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN:
REGGIE WATTS:
Thank you, Michael.
Oh.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN:
Here are the nominees.
REGGIE WATTS: Here they are!
JASON SCHWARTZMAN:
For video of the year.
[MUSIC - ONE DIRECTION,
"BEST SONG EVER"]
[MUSIC - LADY GAGA, "APPLAUSE"]
[MUSIC - MILEY CYRUS,
"WE CAN'T STOP"]
[MUSIC - MACKLEMORE AND
RYAN LEWIS, "SAME LOVE"]
[MUSIC_-_PSY,_"GENTLEMAN"]
[MUSIC - DEMI LOVATO,
"HEART ATTACK"]
[MUSIC - JUSTIN BIEBER,
"BEAUTY AND A BEAT"]
[MUSIC - SELENA GOMEZ,
"COME & GET IT"]
[MUSIC - EPIC RAP BATTLES OF
HISTORY, "BARACK OBAMA VS.
MITT ROMNEY"]
[MUSIC - GIRLS'
GENERATION, "I GOT A BOY"]
REGGIE WATTS: And winner
for Video of the Year
is Girls' Generation,
"I Got A Boy."
[MUSIC - GIRLS'
GENERATION, "I GOT A BOY"]
TIFFANY: Oh my gosh,
thank you so much.
This is absolutely beautiful.
YouTube is my best friend.
Is YouTube your best friend?
Oh my gosh.
I mean, to be here at the
first-ever YouTube Music Awards
is a treat itself, but
to win Video of the Year,
this is absolutely unexpected
and exciting and altogether
humbling at the same time.
I'd like to think SM
Entertainment, our company.
[SPEAKING KOREAN]
And my sisters, my eight
members on the other side
of the planet,
working and trusting
me to represent the group.
I love you.
And last but not least, to
all our fans who totally
gave this to us.
This would not be
possible without you,
so enjoy this moment.
Thank you, and we love you.
[SPEAKING KOREAN]
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: Your earrings
are so beautiful, by the way.
TIFFANY: Oh, thank
you very much.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN:
They're really nice.
TIFFANY: Thank you.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN:
They're beautiful.
They're mesmerizing.
TIFFANY: Your face-- your
makeup is beautiful as well.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN:
Thank you very much.
Yeah, it's like I'm half
lion on one side, half blood
splatter on the other, so.
TIFFANY: It's beautiful.
REGGIE WATTS: It's
like two halves.
TIFFANY: Thank you so much.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: All
right, have a nice night.
And I appreciate it.
Be careful.
It's so slippery.
REGGIE WATTS: [SPEAKING KOREAN]
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: All right,
our next live music video
is for the song "Come Walk With
Me," and it's directed by Fafi.
Ladies and gentlemen,
please welcome M.I.A.
[CHEERING]
[MUSIC - M.I.A.,
"COME WALK WITH ME"]
[CHEERING]
REGGIE WATTS: That was some--
JASON SCHWARTZMAN:
Hi, how are you?
REGGIE WATTS: That
was pretty normal.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: How are you?
REGGIE WATTS: I feel great.
Normal.
Pretty normal.
That was amazing.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN:
That was beautiful.
I want to just say right now--
I know I said it earlier,
but I want to say that a lot
of hard work went in tonight,
and I think that every
video has been really great.
REGGIE WATTS: It's
been amazing, man.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: And I
just want to thank you,
top to bottom, to all the
artists and directors,
because it's all been
really beautiful.
REGGIE WATTS: Immersive.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: And
obviously that was incredible.
REGGIE WATTS: Yeah, I'm a big--
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: More!
I want more!
That's the best you've got?
REGGIE WATTS: That was
the best-tasting chalk.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: I need more!
REGGIE WATTS: If
you love chalk--
JASON SCHWARTZMAN:
Pour it on my head.
OK.
Artist of the Year
honors the biggest acts.
REGGIE WATTS: OK, here we go.
And--
JASON SCHWARTZMAN:
Artist of the Year
honors the biggest acts of
the last year on YouTube
based on total number of
views, likes, shares, comments,
and subscribers.
Please watch this fan video.
MALE AND FEMALE
SPEAKERS: The nominations
for YouTube 2013 Artist
of the Year are--
[MUSIC_-_PSY,_"GENTLEMAN"]
[MUSIC_-_PSY,_"GANGNAM_STYLE"]
[MUSIC_-_KATY_PERRY,_"ROAR"]
[MUSIC - KATY PERRY,
"UNCONDITIONALLY"]
[MUSIC_-_RIHANNA,_"DIAMONDS"]
[MUSIC_-_RIHANNA,_"STAY"]
[MUSIC - JUSTIN BIEBER,
"ALL AROUND THE WORLD"]
[MUSIC - JUSTIN
BIEBER, "BOYFRIEND"]
[MUSIC - NICKI MINAJ,
"POUND THE ALARM"]
[MUSIC - NICKI
MINAJ, "VA VA VOOM"]
[MUSIC - EPIC RAP BATTLES
OF HISTORY, "STEVE JOBS VS.
BILL GATES"]
[MUSIC - EPIC RAP BATTLES OF
HISTORY, "MOZART VS. SKRILLEX"]
[MUSIC - TAYLOR SWIFT, "I
KNEW YOU WERE TROUBLE"]
[MUSIC__-_TAYLOR_SWIFT,_"22"]
[MUSIC_-_EMINEM,_"BERZERK"]
[MUSIC - EMINEM, "SPACE BOUND"]
[MUSIC - ONE DIRECTION,
"BEST SONG EVER"]
[MUSIC - ONE
DIRECTION, "KISS YOU"]
[MUSIC - MACKLEMORE AND
RYAN LEWIS, "WHITE WALLS"]
RYAN LEWIS, "CAN'T HOLD US"]
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: All right.
REGGIE WATTS: Yeah!
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: Reggie?
Reggie?
REGGIE WATTS: All right, just--
JASON SCHWARTZMAN:
Open the envelope.
REGGIE WATTS: OK.
Where's the envelope?
Is there an envelope?
Oh, here.
There's no envelope.
I think we pushed it.
No, there's no envelope.
Artist of the Year.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN:
This guy stole it.
You!
REGGIE WATTS: Here.
Here, let me take that.
Guys, do not drop
the Schwartzman.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: You
don't have to call me that.
REGGIE WATTS: He is very heavy.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: All right,
the winner, Artist of the Year.
The award goes to Eminem.
[CHEERING]
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: But
let me tell you something.
Let me tell you something.
Eminem is coincidentally--
he's actually
about-- he's getting ready.
There's a lot of dust.
It's hard to breathe.
I didn't know how hard
it would be to breathe.
I thought it'd be funny.
But let me tell you something.
REGGIE WATTS: Jason, tell us
a little bit about something.
Tell us a little bit.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: We're going
to a behind the scenes clip
because Eminem is
getting ready to perform.
[MUSIC_-_REGGIE_WATTS]
JASON SCHWARTZMAN:
Here's a dancer.
[MUSIC_-_REGGIE_WATTS]
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: Ladies
and gentlemen, it's
my honor to present a live
music video by Eminem.
[CHEERING]
[MUSIC_-_EMINEM,_"RAP_GOD"]
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: That
was incredible, right?
REGGIE WATTS: That was good.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN:
That was amazing.
REGGIE WATTS: I loved it.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN:
That was incredible.
REGGIE WATTS: I had to see that.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN:
That was beautiful.
REGGIE WATTS: I mean, I saw it
from the side, but I loved it.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: You
guys, that was amazing.
Can I show you-- come here.
This is Spike Jonze.
He created this night.
Say hi, Spike.
Anything you want to say,
or anyone you want to thank?
SPIKE JONZE: I want to thank all
the artists and the directors
that came in and
worked so hard on this,
and thank YouTube for
letting us make this mess.
And thank you, beautiful men.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: Thank you.
SPIKE JONZE: Thank you so much.
REGGIE WATTS: Our pleasure.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN:
All right, listen.
Is there anything
else we should say?
Anyway, I want to just
say I love my wife.
REGGIE WATTS: I think
your wife is great.
I love her.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN:
Isn't she nice?
REGGIE WATTS: Yeah,
she's really awesome.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN:
She's the best, right?
REGGIE WATTS: Yeah.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: Hello, sir.
This is your award.
REGGIE WATTS:
Congratulations, man.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN:
That was amazing.
Thank you so much performing.
That was incredible.
Here's your microphone if
you want to say anything,
but that was cool.
EMINEM: Yeah, man.
I just want to say real
quick, man, thank you
to all the fans,
everybody who voted.
Thanks to YouTube.
Thanks to everybody
for coming out, man.
I'm out.
Thank you.
Peace.
REGGIE WATTS: Pleasure.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN:
Have a good night.
See you later.
That was incredible.
That was great.
Thank you.
All right, you guys.
REGGIE WATTS: Well, all right.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN:
All I want to say
is thank you to everyone
who participated tonight.
Thank you to whoever has
to clean up this microphone
tomorrow morning.
Thank you to Winye West Butler--
REGGIE WATTS: Yes, Winye.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN:
--for coming up.
REGGIE WATTS: Yes,
that was good.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN:
Sorry, Reggie.
REGGIE WATTS: Hey, all right.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: Didn't mean
to blow that in your face.
REGGIE WATTS: No.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: And I just
want to say I love all of you.
I love all the people
who came out tonight,
and everyone who's
watching around the world.
This really was your night.
Thank you for voting and taking
part and celebrating this.
This was more like a festival,
a festival of excitement.
So I'll see you guys.
All, be safe.
And I'll see you soon.
REGGIE WATTS: Big,
big ups to Montana
for being a great
state that I'm from.
I love all of you guys there.
Thank you.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: Oh, Spike
wants to say something else?
Does Spike want to
say something else?
SPIKE JONZE: I think we're done.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: What
a way to end the show.
"I think we're done."
That pretty much sums it up.
I think we're done, 2013
YouTube Music Awards.
I think that's it.
Play it out!
[MUSIC PLAYING]