PAT DUFFY: Yeah, man, a long-ass
time ago I guess Gonz
was doing an interview
at Thrasher.
And he was like--
they were like, who do
you think's good?
And he's like well,
I don't know.
He's like, too bad Duffy doesn't
skate anymore, 'cause
he used to be good.
This was a long time ago,
too, when I was
totally still skating.
And then he goes, you know
what he should do?
He should get on a
board like this.
I'm gonna leave it here.
And then I just happened to be
at Thrasher, and Jake's like,
hey, Mark left this for you.
Take it.
I was like, really?
That's really strange.
I was so psyched though.
I went and shot an ad on it
and stuff for playback.
MALE SPEAKER 1: Who owns the
footage of you trying the--
where you hurt your knee?
PAT DUFFY: I have
that right here.
I have one right here
on my iPod.
It was already used on that
fucking stupid MTV show.
[GROAN]
It sucks.
Ouch, that hurt.
I worked out today man.
It's coming back.
It's getting real strong man.
I'm so psyched.
I'm so embarrassed that
I did that show.
There was like roller bladers
on my episode and shit.
Like, I told them I've
done this for a
career for 15 years.
Don't lump me in with some kid
from Bakersfield who is a
backyard wrestler for fun.
Forget it, dude.
PATRICK O'DELL: Hi, welcome
back to the show.
This episode is about
Pat Duffy.
I just remember when
"Questionable" came out.
I had never heard of him.
Nobody had ever heard of him,
and his part was one of the
best skate parts in years.
Pat was probably the first
hand rail pro.
He was doing things that people
didn't think were possible.
Plan B was created as kind of a
super team to have the best
people from every genre
of skateboarding.
I think Mike Ternasky set this
template, this Plan B formula,
that I see a lot of companies
now like Zero and Baker.
You can see it all took
Plan B's lead.
SAL BARBIER: The first time I
heard about Pat Duffy was,
man, that was a long time ago.
Ternasky, Mike Ternasky, was
talking about this new guy
that he had found that lived
in Marin County.
He was coming out, and he was
filming, and he was doing a
lot of really impressive
things.
So we knew that he
was going to be a
professional right away.
PAT DUFFY: I had flown down just
to see if I would fit in
on the team, you know?
Whatever.
Yeah.
Well, Carroll I knew already
because I had-- you remember
in "Hokus Pokus" the Hensley
balance beam that they used to
skate at School W?
I had one of those,
a portable one.
So people used to come skate
that thing from everywhere.
Carroll brothers would come
skate, Danny Sargent, Henry,
and then I had a ramp
in my yard too.
So I'd known those
dudes, you know?
But it was intimidating to go
hang out with Danny Way.
I was like 17 years old.
My point of view coming from
watching him and Colin in
videos growing up.
And then NT just going,
hey you're
staying at Danny's house.
Go with him.
And I'm just like all
right, OK, whatever.
-I can't do it.
I can't do it.
Ow, fuck!
Fuck, I'm bleeding.
There's blood.
Let me give you the theory
of Pat, Taylor.
You see Pat, Pat is actually
a terminator.
PAT DUFFY: We filmed for like
three weeks every day.
They were just staying at
my house when I went
to school and shit.
MALE SPEAKER 1: Where was that
school yard with the big rail?
PAT DUFFY: That was at San
Pasqual in San Diego.
MALE SPEAKER 1: You
did it twice?
PAT DUFFY: Yeah, twice.
MALE SPEAKER 1: Why'd
you do it twice?
PAT DUFFY: Think we were
thinking different angle.
And I was like, sure.
You know, one from the top
one from the bottom.
We didn't have two cameras.
It was just Mike filming.
MALE SPEAKER 1: But I remember
at the time when that came out
too, thinking that you couldn't
grind a round bar.
What made you think you could
grind a round bar?
PAT DUFFY: Because, I don't
know, I had that balance beam
growing up.
I just got comfortable grinding
metal rails, you know?
I don't know.
I just liked doing
that at the time.
Just kind of scaring myself.
I literally lost my mind
back smithing that
kinked rail at SF State.
Because I knew I could do it
and I just wasn't doing it.
MALE SPEAKER 1: Did you know
that the Plan B video would be
as big of a deal as it was?
PAT DUFFY: I mean,
I don't really.
I mean, of course you knew it
was because you knew it was
going to be something crazy.
Because we would see the footage
going down and there
was nothing.
You know, Ternasky made it
a point that we knew what
everyone else was doing.
So that we could feed
off of it, you know?
He'd always call every day and
be like, yep Rick did this.
Carroll, got this.
And you'd just get so psyched.
He's one of my favorite
skaters of all time.
I would rather watch fucking
Carroll do a back T on a ledge
than some dude jump down a 30
stair trying to kick flip it.
His whole style is
like so sick.
JAKE ROSENBERG: I mean, when I
started working for Plan B,
Pat's part was already done.
That was kind of how it
was set up, you know?
Which I think Mike strategically
did to get
everyone fired up
for the video.
To have this amazing part and
then have everyone doing their
own part after that.
And you know, imagine being Mike
Carroll and coming down
to this new company, Plan B,
and see Pat Duffy's part.
And having Mike put your arm
around and say, you're my top
street pro.
Come on!
How could you be super stoked?
It's like, fuck.
MIKE CARROLL: I mean when we
first got Plan B started, it
was like this whole
awesome thing.
And then it seemed like there's
a little bit of--
not tension, but--
I don't know.
Just people had different
ideas.
You know?
Like all of a sudden, it's like
I have to learn a trick.
Not like ah, it'd be cool
to learn a trick.
JAKE ROSENBERG: So Mike and I
were doing this voice-over for
this project.
He's like, dude do you have
that old first version of
"Questionable" with
Gonz in it?
I was like, what are
you talking about?
He's like remember?
He was at the Pal contest, and
we had the trick of him.
And he called Mike Ternasky and
told him to take it out?
And I was like, what?
Gonz did that?
And then I vividly remembered
Mike being really bummed.
You know?
Because I think that just the
way that Mike approached
skateboarding, a lot of
skateboarders didn't like that.
But I know, that in his heart,
he loved skateboarding.
So I think it's kind of
heartbreaking when you think
you're doing something for the
better good of something and
someone else doesn't.
Mike did amazing things
while he was alive.
I'm not just saying that
because he's dead.
MALE SPEAKER 2 (OFFSCREEN):
Get down, boy.
PAT DUFFY (OFFSCREEN)
Thanks, bro.
-You know I could have
did better man.
-I believe you.
-That was tough.
Man, I like that.
What kind of wheels you got?
-Little one--
MALE SPEAKER 3 (OFFSCREEN):
What do you got
to say about that?
-The only thing I got
to say is look here.
The guy's a natural.
He's a natural.
And you know something?
When you want to make a million
dollars, hey, you come
and look for me.
You look for the baby, because
the baby knows a natural.
Hey, come on, hold
it up there.
Show them who's number one.
-That was great man.
That was great.
I especially liked the
flip of the board.
That was cool.
I can't jump that high.
My vertical leap is only about
an inch, if that high.
MALE SPEAKER 3 (OFFSCREEN)
Take it easy.
MALE SPEAKER 4 (OFFSCREEN):
Yeah, right on, man.
Have a good trip now.
PAT DUFFY: What's that?
MALE SPEAKER 1: It seemed like
those two, "Virtual Reality"
came out almost-- to me it
seemed like immediately.
I guess it was a year later?
PAT DUFFY: It was a
year later, yeah.
MALE SPEAKER 1: That's
pretty fast now.
PAT DUFFY: For now a days,
people sit on them for a
couple years now.
It was different.
It was just a different vibe
back then though, because no
one really made any money.
It was like you were
still kind of--
you were still just like
skating all the time.
There was a while white rail lip
slide that went down flat.
That took a couple times because
I kept sticking on it
and I had to set up
a slick bottom.
Jake Rosenberg filmed
that one.
JAKE ROSENBERG: I mean, Pat's
fucking first video part's one
of the greatest video parts in
the history of skateboarding.
And it's like, who the
fuck is this kid?
I've never seen it before.
And he didn't exactly have
a sophomore jinx.
I mean, I think his "Virtual
Reality" part is equally as
impressive.
MALE SPEAKER 1: When a lot of
those guys left to do their
own, did you take
that personally?
PAT DUFFY: No, I didn't take
it personally at all.
I figured they had
their reasons.
JAKE ROSENBERG: You know
what, that's what Mike
Carroll told me.
And this, I think we have to
explore at another time.
But he was like, we knew we were
leaving the company long
before we did.
And that's why we had
the Friends section.
It's because we knew there
was never going to
be a "Blind" video.
PAT DUFFY: But I did get a call
from Rick saying, this is
what we're doing.
And we want you to know that
this is what we're doing.
And then you can make a decision
on your own what
you're going to do.
Which I thought was pretty cool
of them just to let me
know what was happening
that day.
Like the day they showed
up with all the "Girl"
shirts on, you know.
MIKE CARROLL: The way we
did it was crazy but--
MALE SPEAKER 1: Just all at
once take half the team.
MIKE CARROLL: Yeah, and not tell
anyone and didn't give
any notice or anything.
But if you know how powerful
World or Rocco or any of those
dudes were back then?
If we tried to let them know,
we would never have even
existed because they would
have never let it happen.
PAT DUFFY: Just because that
happened didn't really faze me
on turning my back on MT.
Just because he kind of took
me in as one of those kids.
JAKE ROSENBERG: He looked at all
those guys like his kids.
Again, regardless of how he did
business and regardless of
how people saw him in
a certain capacity.
He cared tremendously for
everyone who skated for him.
And I think he took pride in
giving them an opportunity, or
promoting them, to
be great skaters.
So Mike died May 17th, 1994.
I went down to San Diego
for the funeral.
I remember seeing Danny outside
the funeral home where
they were having the
viewing for Mike.
Which was like the worst
idea to go there.
But Danny was just crying.
And like, Danny was crying
because he was devastated.
PAT DUFFY: I don't know, he was
just kind of like a second
dad for me.
I just appreciated everything
he taught me.
MALE SPEAKER 1: And so then when
Plan B ended did you know
where you were going
to go after that?
PAT DUFFY: No.
MALE SPEAKER 1: These are
all think boards?
PAT DUFFY: Yeah, I was going
through them the other day and
I was like, damn, man I must
have been raging when I lived
in San Francisco.
They're all booze graphics.
All of them.
It's crazy.
Gabe Morford and I grew
up together, you know.
I was hanging out with Gabe, and
he was going out with this
full deluxe staff.
So he was going out
with everybody.
I don't know.
I was back in San Francisco,
you know?
And I was just hanging out
with skateboarders again.
JAKE ROSENBERG: You know, 14
years later or whatever, I
look back on that time now.
And I'm like, holy shit.
I was involved, in my opinion,
in like some of the greatest
videos in the history
of skating.
When skateboarding was dead,
Plan B reinvigorated it.
Whether it caused people to
revolt against it or it caused
people to do more technical
better tricks, Plan B was at
the epicenter of what changed
skateboarding.