It's like a turtle.
A turtle falls on its back,
can't get back up.
What happened to your tent?
MIKE CARROLL: Unnnh.
MALE SPEAKER: Where are you?
MIKE CARROLL: I'm here.
MALE SPEAKER: Nice tech.
I like that tech.
MIKE CARROLL: What tech?
MALE SPEAKER: The technique,
look at this.
MALE SPEAKER: Coffin,
coffin style.
MIKE CARROLL: Help
me out here.
MALE SPEAKER: Need help?
MALE SPEAKER: You know
you gotta do it.
MALE SPEAKER: You gotta
try to get out.
MALE SPEAKER: You got yourself
into this mess, Mike, you got
to get yourself out of it.
MALE SPEAKER: You're saying when
we make this thing, we
should go lay it on your
party footage?
MIKE CARROLL: Because I didn't
want it to be all about that,
but I just don't remember
what it was.
And because I know you had the
camera on at all times, so I
didn't know what kind
of footage you had.
When I said that, I think it
was just at the peak of all
the stuff coming out.
And I was just like, great.
I'm just that guy.
MALE SPEAKER: Right.
MALE SPEAKER: Lean this way.
MALE SPEAKER: Lean what way?
MALE SPEAKER: Backwards.
MALE SPEAKER: Yeah, he said
he didn't want this up.
Said it'd be like too
much drunk footage.
ALEX OLSEN: Fuck that.
He was the most drunk guy on
the trip-- on the trip.
Yeah, he was fucking
nuts on that trip.
I'd never seen him like that.
MALE SPEAKER: What's up, Greg?
GREG: Morning.
MALE SPEAKER: Is
this your crib?
GREG: This is it.
MALE SPEAKER: So last night,
I guess this is it, huh?
GREG: This is the last
night, isn't it?
MALE SPEAKER: Camping.
GREG: Oh man.
That's a bummer.
SAM SMYTH : Everyone got
along just perfect.
I don't think it could
have been any better.
You know?
By the end, we were
just one team.
In that camping environment,
it's so communal.
You can't be a prick.
And you can't be--
you know?
You can't be a pussy either.
Like, there's no, like,
sitting this out.
It's like, everybody did
everything together.
[SINGING]
MALE SPEAKER: With your
triflin' ass.
Why don't you go fuck some of
your funky-ass friends?
Shit, hell, you're probably
doing that shit anyway.
MALE SPEAKER: As you may have
guessed, we are waiting for
the Girl team and the
Anti-Hero team.
Rumor has it they got lost on
their way out here because
they had to stop at the hotel
and pick up their skateboards.
So they will be here.
And everybody wants to
know how long the
demo's going to be.
Well, I said it will
be forever.
MALE SPEAKER: [INAUDIBLE]
is on his way for
those concerned folks.
They're on their way.
In the meantime, we're going to
give way free [INAUDIBLE]
T-shirts for switch
manual tricks.
So let me see something
switch.
[CHEERING]
MALE SPEAKER: Hey Mike,
what took so long?
MIKE CARROLL: Huh?
MALE SPEAKER: What
took so long?
MIKE CARROLL: I don't know.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Oh, you
fuckin' got lost.
MIKE CARROLL: Yeah,
we got lost.
MALE SPEAKER: Oh,
nothing cool.
MIKE CARROLL: Did we
miss anything?
MALE SPEAKER: Yeah, I already
killed the demo.
MALE SPEAKER: I kind of want you
to come here and just warm
up the crowd a little bit.
Get them stoked.
And then we going to come
in and just clean up.
SAM SMYTH : A lot of the little
kids, they didn't even
understand what was happening
in front of them.
But to the guys our age and a
little bit younger, there were
some younger kids that got it.
But lots of kids definitely came
up, and it was like, this
is the coolest thing
I've ever seen.
It was cool to touch those
people like that.
MALE SPEAKER: Get
this on camera.
I'm going to make this
shit right here.
MALE SPEAKER: In the window?
MALE SPEAKER: Yeah,
$5 on the line.
MALE SPEAKER: And who
would you say is
the MVP of the tour?
MALE SPEAKER: Of the tour?
MALE SPEAKER: Yeah.
MALE SPEAKER: Giving
it up to Allah.
Allah.
MALE SPEAKER: Who would you say
is the MVP of the tour?
MALE SPEAKER: Malto For sure.
That kid's killing it.
Spin wizard.
Been ripping.
MVP.
Malto.
MALE SPEAKER: Crankers.
That's it.
That's all I'm saying.
Fuck that, fuck that dude.
No, it's me.
MALE SPEAKER: MVP vote?
MALE SPEAKER: Crankers.
Yeah, I'd go with Crankers.
MALE SPEAKER: Probably Crank,
Because he did everything.
What'd you think?
MALE SPEAKER: Carroll.
Oh, well different,
different genre.
But yeah, Carroll did it
too, for part of it.
MALE SPEAKER: Are we talking
nighttime or daytime?
MALE SPEAKER: That's
up to you.
MALE SPEAKER: I'd say me.
I'm the guy.
MALE SPEAKER: Carroll's VIP.
Scare slash life.
MALE SPEAKER: Yeah.
MALE SPEAKER: Did you see
his gear yesterday?
I mean, come on.
MIKE CARROLL: What
do you think?
MALE SPEAKER: I was just
going to say you.
MIKE CARROLL: Yeah?
MALE SPEAKER: Yeah.
MIKE CARROLL: Was it because of
the other day at the park?
MALE SPEAKER: Oh yeah,
that was pretty MVP.
MIKE CARROLL: I don't remember
any of that.
MALE SPEAKER: Here you go.
One more.
[? Hold ?]
[? on. ?]
[CHEERING]
MALE SPEAKER: And I know what
you mean about it being one
team because by the end, it
was like hard to even
differentiate like who--
I mean, you didn't even
think about in terms
of like that anymore.
MALE SPEAKER: Yeah.
MALE SPEAKER: It just seemed
like, seamless like--
MALE SPEAKER: Yeah.
MALE SPEAKER: Like it-- like it
almost seemed like Carroll
was like, Anti-Hero or
something like--
MALE SPEAKER: Yeah.
Like Brian with Anti-Hero
boards.
Those guys had Girl stickers
all over their shit.
MALE SPEAKER: Captain Booya.
One more time.
MALE SPEAKER: This is great.
I'm just looking for the kid
with the most fucked-up board,
and I think found it.
See that real board with
the purple shirt?
MALE SPEAKER: What are the
things you look for?
MALE SPEAKER: I looked at their
shoes and then like how
much they skate.
MALE SPEAKER: There's
two out here now.
MALE SPEAKER: Taking the kid
with the Anti-Hero shirt and
the board sauce.
He's got a little more style,
like he's going to go further.
MALE SPEAKER: All right,
homie's leaving.
I think, just hand
it to him, huh?
MALE SPEAKER: Shoes
are fucked-up.
Your board's all fucked-up.
Truck's a little loose but--
MALE SPEAKER: Thanks
a lot, man.
MALE SPEAKER: That's
your board so--
MALE SPEAKER: Thanks a lot.
MALE SPEAKER: Have a
good summer, dude.
BRIAN ANDERSON: I don't want
to jinx it, but I'm really
already hopefully looking
forward to next year.
Because everybody
just vibes, like
everybody gets along fine.
And everybody's down at camp
and get some brats and some
stakes and light the fire up.
Wake up and do it
all over again.
It's fun.
And everybody looks up
to everybody else.
And everybody gets each
other psyched.
And we all enjoy each
other's skating.
So it's just feels totally
natural, man.
MALE SPEAKER: You guys
want a falafel?
MALE SPEAKER: Falafel?
MALE SPEAKER: It's been all
day since we got here.
There are two brand new ones.
SAM SMYTH : So we're on the ride
home, and we're heading
back to SF.
And Mike's in the van,
Brian's in the van,
Peabody, Andrew, Mo.
And we're going back through one
of those little towns in
Oregon, and we just stop
off the freeway.
And we happen on a strip club,
and we just go in there, just
for, whatever, quick beer.
And we're going to
get on the road.
Mo and Mike sit next to
each other, and I'm
sitting next to them.
And the stripper comes up
and sits next to Mo.
And it was, like, Mo looks at
her , and he goes, who's your
favorite skater, just for no
reason, right out the gate.
And she goes--
didn't even blink-- she was
like, Mike Carroll.
And Mo's just like,
are you serious?
Just leans back and he's
right there, like.
Her mind was blown.
She was like, oh my God, oh my
God, oh my God, oh my God,
it's Mike Carroll.
Like, immediately grabs him,
takes him in the back.
Starts giving him
free lap dances.
She was like, so beat, huge
rotted out front tooth, speed
head stripper.
So funny but didn't even--
didn't take her a second.
She knew who her favorite skater
was, Mike Carroll.