I'm hit.
That doesn't make
it any easier.
Man: I think I'm
going to be calling
the cops right now.
Jesse Green: Why?
Man: And have
you shut down.
Jesse Green: I am the
machine Jesse Green.
A couple of years ago, I
walked away from my job as
a truck driver to chase
my dream of owning my own
business as a master
chainsaw sculptor.
I took a huge
risk in doing it,
but the rewards of being
my own boss and doing
exactly what I want
are so worth it to me.
My employees,
including my own dad,
drive me crazy.
Get back.
But I can't
do this alone.
I'm living my dream
and I wouldn't have it
any other way.
Beth Green: Looks good.
Jesse Green: Thank you.
Beth Green: It looks
good enough that
maybe we can
take a break.
Jesse Green:
What do you got?
Beth Green: I got a
call from a couple
on Holliston, they got
a big huge stump and
they want you
to check it out.
Jesse Green: I still got
to finish up the goat.
Beth Green: Let Missy
and Keith handle that.
I just need you to
learn how to delegate.
In order to
make this business more
profitable I have to
keep Jesse on a schedule
and he really needs
to focus on carving.
All the details and things
can be done by Brett and
Keith and Missy and
we could turn these
over so much quicker.
Big stump, big money.
Can you get over
there today?
Jesse Green: Yah.
Beth Green: Yah?
Beth Green: Alright good.
Jesse Green: I prefer to
do one project at a time.
But we're a growing
business and
so I say I can't afford
to turn down work.
Jay Green: Back, back.
Jesse Green: So we're
going to load up the van
and go meet a
potential new client.
Jay Green: I'm
not moving this.
It's shut.
Jesse Green: I'm not
paying attention to you.
I have a marker.
Jay Green: I thought you
said you were watching me.
Jesse Green: I'm watching
you so you get the (bleep)
out of the way and
be safe about it.
Jay Green: I'm
out of the way.
Jesse Green: You're
like right on top
of the trailer.
I'm going to hit the
trailer with the car.
Jay Green: What
do you want me?
Where do you
want me to go?
Jesse Green: I want you to
stand away so it's safe.
How come I have
to be safe and
every time I tell you
to stand away from the
trailer while I'm
hooking it up,
you're on top
of the trailer?
Jay Green: You love me.
You ain't
going to hit me.
Jesse Green: Maybe I'm
tempted to hit you?
Jay Green: No you're not.
Jesse Green: Like I've
never done this before.
Jay Green: Hurry up.
Jesse Green:
I'll admit it;
I'm still learning
how to manage people.
But when it comes to
managing my family
I don't have a clue.
My dad doesn't
listen to me.
He always thinks
he knows better.
Jay Green: Stop.
You didn't stop when
I told you to stop.
Jesse Green: It's perfect.
Do you know what I was
doing for a living before
we started doing
sculpting full time?
I was a tractor
trailer driver dad.
Jay Green: Yes I know.
Jesse Green: So do
you know what I did
on a daily basis?
Jay Green: What did you
do on a daily basis?
Jesse Green: I
hooked up trailers.
Jay Green: Jesse has
never asked for help.
He thinks he
knows everything,
but in order for the
business to grow,
Jesse has to learn
to trust the people
who work for him.
Jesse Green: You want
to check the lights?
Jay Green: You going
to turn them on?
Jesse Green: I
turned them on.
Jay Green:
Did you really?
Jesse Green: They're on
the flashers are on.
Jay Green: Did
you plug them in?
Jesse Green: No.
Jay Green: Well
plug them in.
I told you he should
always listen to me.
You want the shovel?
Jesse Green: Yes please.
Yah give me those.
No, no.
Wait, wait, wait.
Do you think that that's
going to travel safely?
Brett: Probably not.
No.
Jesse Green: There's more
work than I can do by
myself, so Brett's
supposed to help me.
Please pull big blue out
of the (bleep) oil please.
Brett: What?
Jesse Green: The problem
is Brett is (bleep)
helping me.
No dude,
that's the tent.
Brett: Okay.
Jesse Green: That's
the nice white tent.
If there was two of
me, or three of me,
I could load
everything myself.
It would be
done perfect.
But I have to rely
on other people.
Uh, can you
hand me cones.
Keith: (grunts).
Jesse Green: Wow dude,
look at you man.
See Brett.
Do you see how a
real man works?
Keith: Yah, that's it.
Brett: ( laughing).
Jesse is the
most OCD, anal,
micromanager
I've ever seen,
but sometimes when you're
starting out you need to
be micromanaged to get
where he can trust you.
So I'm the whipping
post here at the shop.
It's ridiculous though.
Jesse Green: Alright.
Let's go.
You come with me,
you meet us there.
Brett: Okay.
Jesse Green: You
working on the what?
The Navy goat?
Keith:
(makes goat noise).
Jay Green: So why
don't you just schedule
these things early
in the morning?
Jesse Green: I, that's
a question for my wife.
Jay Green: They just call
up and she said Jesse go.
Jesse Green: Yah, I
probably could've said no.
I mean I'm in charge.
Jay Green: Ah,
she's your wife.
Who's in charge?
How are the other
sculptures doing?
Jesse Green: Good, I
feel like I don't have
nearly enough time
to work on anything.
It's a tough balance
to run this business.
On the one hand, we
have to stay on pace in
order to keep the
money coming in.
On the other hand,
we have to make sure
the sculptures
are done right.
I really feel
like everything
is on my shoulders.
Jay Green: I'm just,
you know, concerned.
Jesse Green: Thank you.
Paul: We got a big
tree that I cut down,
so I said why don't we
leave like nine feet up
and then we'll
call Jesse and
see what he
can do with it.
So we kicked around
some ideas and
Nancy came up with
something she'd like.
Nancy: We love squirrels,
I love squirrels.
Jesse Green: I heard
squirrel, is that right?
Nancy: Squirrel is right.
Jesse Green: They want me
to carve a squirrel, sure.
Okay, that's different.
I'd carve
anything I guess.
Yah awesome.
A big squirrel, I've
never done that before.
That sounds
pretty awesome.
Paul: Really?
Nancy's been feeding
them for years.
Nancy: They're
very, very friendly;
they eat out of your hand.
Jesse Green: So
you guys are like
squirrel whisperers?
Paul: (laughing).
Nancy: When Paul was
painting the barn,
they even went
up the ladder.
Paul: Looking
for peanuts,
I guess I smelled
like peanuts.
We'd go to church on
Sunday morning in the
summertime, they'd
follow us and
they'd jump up
in the window with
the window open.
Jesse Green: Come on.
Paul: And it used to
drive the priest crazy.
Nancy: Like one
of them went right
down the center aisle.
Jesse Green: I'm sorry;
they followed you
into the church?
Paul: Yah.
Nancy: Yep.
Jay Green: That's
a bit creepy.
And kind of nuts.
(laughing).
Paul: There's
your canvas Jesse.
Jesse Green: Wow.
Paul: Somewhere
hiding behind that
bark is a squirrel.
Jesse Green: Holy.
Paul: Big enough?
Jesse Green: Yah it's
a pretty big stump.
I love it.
I've got an arborist
that I'd like to
come have a look at it.
Paul: Okay sure.
Jesse Green: Just so I
know what I'm up against.
Whenever I have a
project like this,
I call in my buddy
Ken the arborist.
He'll let me know what
makes this thing tick.
Because I want to know
everything about this
stump that I possibly can
before I start carving it.
Ken: This is
a sugar maple.
This is the one they
get the syrup out of.
Maybe I should
look at the top.
Jesse Green: Brett would
you ladder me please?
Brett: Here you go Jesse.
Where do you think we uh,
where do you want it?
Jesse Green: I want
to lean it against
the stump dude,
if preferable.
Thank you.
It actually goes
the other way.
Brett: Oh does it?
Jesse Green: Yes.
Brett: Oh, who
would've thunk?
Jesse Green: Uh, the
guy who put the scans
on the bottom thunk it.
What do you see?
Ken: There's
no rot at all.
Jesse Green: Awesome.
Ken: Looks
pretty strong.
I'll tell you what;
sugar maple is one
of the hardest trees
we have in New England.
Jesse's up against
a mighty hard wood.
Jesse Green: This
is the kind of thing
that makes my
mouth water.
Stump jobs
pay top dollar.
But I only get one shot.
Can't just grow another
tree and try again and if
I screw it up, they're not
going to want to pay and
then I'll have wasted days
of my time and resources.
Paul: Great so you
think you can do it?
Jesse Green: Myself and
my crack team of uh,
chainsaw sculpting
professionals are on it.
Paul: Okay.
Jesse Green: We're
going to squirrel this
thing out for you guys.
Paul: I'm sure you are.
Jesse Green: First,
I'll carve out the
squirrels head,
outstretched arm,
tummy and tail.
Then using the sander,
I'll cut in the
fine details of the
squirrel's face and paws.
To finish up I'll stain
it, and as an added bonus,
I'll attach giant acorns
to the squirrel's hands.
This is really hard wood.
I would say this is
probably one of the
harder stumps that
I've ever had to carve.
It's a big hard tree.
It's had time to really
just turn into a big rock.
It's a hard wood.
I feel like I'm
cutting into the
top of a mountain.
Here's the snow
covered peak.
It's iced and
it's petrified.
And I have to carve it.
It's not even trying
to figure out a shape,
as just trying to simply
get into the thing
so I can try to figure out
where that squirrel is.
Dad?
Can you change that chain?
Jay Green: I'm going
to change the chain.
I can see it by the
way it's cutting.
Jesse Green: Dude this
is the hardest wood
I've ever had to
deal with I think.
Jay Green: This stump is
going to be a (bleep).
I've never seen
anything like this.
We're going to have our
work cut out for us.
Man: This noise
is too much.
I, I can't even
hear myself.
I'd say that's got to
stop and all of this.
And this is Sunday.
You have permission
to do this?
Jesse Green: This
is their tree and
I'm making them
a sculpture.
Man: On Sunday?
I mean you can hear
it for like four or
five blocks away.
Jesse Green: This guy
just marched in here and
tell me I have
to shut down and
he just wants me gone.
I'm way off the street,
I don't understand why.
Man: But, but the,
but the noise.
Jesse Green: I don't
know what to tell you.
I'm only here for, for
another day or so and,
and I, I'm on, I'm on.
Man: Another day or so.
Jesse Green:
Private property.
Man: That saw, you
would think that
you could have a
muffler on it or
something to silence it.
Jesse Green: But,
but you, you can't.
Uh.
Man: Sure you could.
Jesse Green:
No you can't.
Man: I'm going to call
the police department
and have you shut down.
Jesse Green: What?
Why?
Man: How much more
can I say to you?
(Bleep).
Jesse Green: Call
the cops right now.
Man: What are
you filming here?
Jesse Green: Hey,
hey, hey, hey.
Man: You don't have my
permission to (bleep).
Jesse Green: Sir.
Man: I'm going
to call the police
[inaudible] right now.
Jesse Green: Good
call the police,
maybe you can do it
from the street okay,
this is private property.
Man: Hello, yes.
Down here on the corner
of Washington Street
and Church Street.
Would you come
down immediately?
Jesse Green: This guy
wants to call the cops
and have me shut down.
Forget it I'm
going back to work.
I got to finish
this thing.
I'm just going to do
as much as I can do.
Ah.
[siren]
What the hell is this?
Great, the cops are here.
Jesse Green: Great
the cops are here.
Officer: I want to
see what you're
doing out here.
Jesse Green: I'm
making a squirrel.
Forgive me I've had a,
a few obstacles
on this project.
Officer: I had a little
noise complaint,
just checking on
the noise level.
You are well
within your limits.
So.
Jesse Green: When I
saw you it just made me
think that I was up
against the you know,
the ultimate obstacle.
Officer: Not a
problem, alright.
You have a good day.
Jesse Green: I
can't believe he
really called
the cops on me.
I just wasted an hour
dealing with a neighbor
and the cops.
My day is shot.
Beth Green: I want
you to be careful up
on the scaffolding today.
It's slippery up there.
Jesse Green: I will.
Beth Green: I don't
want you to get too
far behind but I
do want you to be safe.
With multiple jobs going
on at the same time it's
really important that
Jesse stays on schedule.
Jesse Green: I'm not
getting behind anymore.
This is ridiculous.
Beth Green: Okay.
Jesse Green: I love you.
Beth Green: Me too.
Missy: Keith,
he's coming.
Keith: Make sure
you have no drips.
Missy: I'm checking.
Jesse Green: I heard
you say make sure
you have no drips.
Missy: There
are no drips.
Jesse Green:
How about that?
About that.
Missy: What this?
Jesse Green:
Just, like this.
Missy: Nothing with
Jesse is ever easy,
he really needs to
just do his part,
let us do ours.
Jesse Green: Wipe it.
Missy: What the hell?
Missy: I'm not
in the mood.
I brought, Keith and
I are here to help
him be able to do more.
Jesse Green: I
have this idea.
I'm thinking I'll
make the squirrel
throwing nuts
at the house.
Missy: So you're
going to be
carving out some acorns?
Jesse Green: No I want
you to fabricate acorns.
Like I'm, like
this bigish.
Missy: Okay.
Keith: Two or three?
Jesse Green:
Make it four.
Everybody tells me
I have to delegate.
Well Keith and Missy
here's your big chance.
I'm having these guys
handle the acorns so
I can get back to
carving the squirrel.
Jump in.
Jay Green: So
your mother and
I want to plan
a vacation.
Jesse Green: To?
Jay Green: Greece.
I don't know what your
schedule is, but.
Jesse Green: Me, I'm
not going to Greece.
Jay Green: No,
I want a break.
Jesse Green: Oh.
Jay Green: Oh.
Jesse Green: I
thought my dad was
inviting me on vacation.
It turns out he just
wants to go on vacation.
Jay Green: I need a break.
It's going to be a big
deal with your momma.
Jesse Green: Yah, I can't
give you a break though.
So tell her no.
Jay Green: (laughing).
I'm not going
to tell her no.
You tell her no.
(laughing).
Jesse Green: I'm just
busting my dad's chops.
Of course he can
go on vacation,
just not right now.
We are too busy.
When even one
person is missing,
it throws the whole
operation off.
I say you don't
go, you don't go.
Jay Green: Oh
we're going.
We're the parents.
Jesse Green: Where do
you suppose Brett is?
Jay Green: Brett supposed
to meet you here?
Jesse Green: I don't
know where he is.
But he's not here.
And I, I'm already
losing time so.
Brett's new to the team,
so he's still got
a lot to learn.
You got to be kidding me.
But I only have just
so much patience
for that kid.
I expect a lot
more out of him.
We have to unload
this stuff.
Jay Green: What
the (bleep).
That's not my job.
Where's Brett?
I mean you want
to call him?
Jesse Green: I don't
know where this kid is
and I got to get
this stuff going.
Today is not starting
off too well.
Brett's not here,
I don't know why.
But it's going to take
awhile for my dad and
I now to unload this
stuff from the trailer
so I can keep working
on the squirrel.
That's strike
one on Brett.
Dammit!
Dude, where were you?
Why?
Brett: I thought
it was a day off.
Jesse Green: No dude.
(Bleep) no dude.
Like no, I have,
I told you I,
we're working straight
through on this project.
I really need to get
this done on time,
I know Brett
has potential.
But he is just not showing
it to me right now.
My dad and I had to unload
the trailer by ourselves,
which put us even
further behind.
Thank you very much.
He's creating more
work when I need him to
help me get
back on schedule.
Brett: Alright, I'm sorry,
it won't happen again.
Jesse Green: Help
me, help you help me.
Okay.
Brett: Alright.
Jesse Green: You
understand what I'm
saying?
Brett: Yah.
Jesse Green: Thank you.
It hurts.
It hurts a lot.
This hard wood is
doing a number on me.
It's doing a number
on my saws and
let me tell you
something else.
When the hardwood
hits you in the face,
it really (bleep) hurts.
It just a more abrasive
saw dust, you know,
the chips are bigger,
they're sharper,
they're coming at you
harder and faster.
They're just repelling
right off that
chain back into my
face, you know?
Ah, I'm hit.
(Bleep).
Dad?
Jay Green: He's
bleeding pretty good.
Jesse Green:
Ah, it got me.
Jay Green: Is it bad?
Jesse Green: It hurts.
Jay Green: Is it deep?
Jesse Green: I.
Jay Green: What'd you do?
Jesse Green:
I cut my hand.
Look at it.
I just took a, just
took a nice sharp piece
right off the, you
know, right off me.
That doesn't make
it any easier.
Standard operating
procedure though.
I'm not going to let.
Jay Green:
Are you sure?
Jesse Green: No,
I'm not going to
let this stop me,
I'll tell you that
much right now.
Alright back up.
Jay Green: Alright.
Jesse Green: Back up,
thank you very much.
Jay Green: I
got a Band-Aid.
Jesse Green: Forget it.
I'm fine.
Jay Green: He doesn't
want a Band-Aid.
Sometimes the job is just
so stressful Jesse just
stresses me out and I
got to find a quiet place
to just relax
and meditate.
Jesse Green: Where
the heck is my dad?
Jesse Green: He's off like
meditating somewhere.
Meditate on your own time.
Jay Green: Hey I take
my meditation serious.
Don't mess with
my meditation.
(laughing).
Brett: I don't know what
Jay is doing back there.
But I'm going to join him.
Jay Green: Hey Jesse.
Sue Green: This
is really awesome.
Jesse Green: I
want to be done.
Sue Green: I hear you.
I'm Sue Green;
I'm the mom of the
Machine Jesse Green.
It's a pretty big
nightmare to worry about
your son being around
chainsaws all day.
So when Jesse's
cutting a sculpture
I like to
check up on him.
Bake some cookies or a
little banana bread.
Like I'm coming
to feed him,
that way I have an
excuse to come over and
check out what's going on.
You sure you
don't want coffee?
Jesse Green: I can't
have coffee right now.
Sue Green: I could
just pour it down,
if you open your mouth,
I'll just pour it
right down there.
(laughing).
Jesse Green: I just uh,
I just want to eat this
and go back to work.
Sue Green: What's
on your hand?
What did you do?
Jesse Green: Nothing.
Sue Green: I don't
want to know.
But I do.
You alright?
Jesse Green:
Yah, I'm fine.
Sue Green: But I
worry about you.
Jesse Green: Thank
you very much.
Sue Green: Alright.
I'm the person who
worries about him
the most I think.
Always have, always will.
When he was little,
we bought him a
little Fisher
Price chainsaw.
I was worried about how
dangerous that was.
I'm worse now.
Every time that
thing starts up and
I can hear it,
I am sweating.
It's very nerve
racking for mom.
You're welcome,
where can I hide
this from your father?
Jesse Green: It's
a little late for
that don't you think?
Sue Green: (laughing).
Brett: Jesse was
a little over the top
about me being late.
So I figured I'd
get him back.
Jesse Green: Dude, dude.
Are you serious Brett?
Hey.
Brett: Oh!
My bad man, my bad.
Jesse Green: Uh hey dude.
You, you got something
on you right there.
Done, I am done.
Paul: Mister Machine.
Nancy and I picked out
a stain we really like.
Jesse Green: Yes,
what you got?
Paul: So hopefully
it's good with you.
My understanding
then you're going to
do two coats of
the stain and
then a coat of
uh, urethane?
Jesse Green: No, uh,
one coat of stain,
you don't want
to do two coats,
because we want that
grain to pop out.
Paul: I thought I had
heard that you were
going to do two
coats of stain.
I didn't know.
Jesse Green:
Yah, uh, no.
Paul: I told Jesse
I expected to see
two coats of stain
on there because
that's what Brett
had told me.
And uh now he tells
me there's only one.
And uh, I'm
just wondering if
I'm getting
short changed here.
Jesse Green: Well who,
Brett told you that he,
he probably shouldn't
have guessed at that.
I don't want one
of my guys to put the
wrong idea in your head.
But you're hearing
it straight from the
horse's ass,
mouth, that's me.
Paul: Okay.
Jesse Green: I'm the
horse's ass mouth.
Brett set me up
for disaster.
He tells somebody
that you're going to
put two coats
of stain on;
they expect two
coats of stain.
Can I ask you,
why would you put
me in that position?
Why would you take
a wild guess at
something you don't know?
This is Brett's
second mistake.
I don't know what I'm
going to do with that kid.
I can't run a
business like this.
Brett has one more
chance and that's it.
Brett: No, I didn't, I
shouldn't have guessed.
Jesse Green: No you
It needs one
coat of stain,
you don't know that.
You wouldn't have any
(bleep) idea of that.
So why would you
guess at that?
Why would you put
me in that position?
Why would you take
a wild guess at
something you don't know?
Brett: Jesse does
expect more from me and
from now on, I'm
going to deliver.
Jesse Green: Being
23 is only going to
get you just
so far with me.
You know what I mean?
I'm hard on these
guys because I'm
counting on them to
help run my business.
Brett is supposed to
clean up my messes.
Not the other way around.
Oh that's nice.
Jay Green: I don't know,
looks like a
cat right now.
Jesse Green: Now that the
staining is going great,
I'm going to check on
Keith and Missy and see
how they're coming
along with the acorns.
What, what
does, what does,
what does that say?
Keith: My nuts are wet.
Missy: The hardest part
of my job is making
Jesse's dreams
come reality.
He's seeing my work
for the first time.
It looks good;
I just hope he
likes it too.
You think they'll work?
Jesse Green: I love them.
Keith: We tried
to make the nuts
as real as possible.
Jesse Green: Yah.
Missy: I think they
look pretty good.
So I think the client
will like them.
Jesse Green: Keith
and Missy did a
great job on the acorns.
Now I have to mount
them on the squirrel.
Paul and Nancy have
invited a bunch of
friends over for
the unveiling of
the squirrel today.
So while Paul's off
dealing with that I have
to get the acorns attached
before anyone sees them.
Listen the nuts,
it's a surprise.
So we need time
to put them up,
what I need from
you is I need you
to go find Nancy
and occupy her.
Keep her away from the
view of the squirrel.
Brett: I think I
can handle this.
Jesse Green: This is
Brett's last chance.
If he can't take care of
this one simple thing,
I don't know what I'm
going to do with him.
Brett: What
you got there?
Nancy: It's a
squirrel book.
Brett: A squirrel book.
You had fifteen
of them right?
Nancy: Yah.
Brett: Just eating
out your hands.
Nancy: They, they
were trained.
Brett: Where have
they been anyway?
I've been, I've
been curious uh,
I haven't seen any?
Nancy: They don't like the
sound of the chainsaw.
Brett: They don't,
they should put
that in the book.
Nancy: Yah.
Brett: (laughing).
I can't mess this up.
If I do, Jesse's
going to kill me.
Jay Green: That's it.
Jesse Green: Are you
saying that's good angle?
Is that right?
Jay Green: No,
turn the nut.
Jesse Green: I'm
thinking like this.
Jay Green: No
the other way.
Tilt it towards
you just a little.
There you go,
like, like that.
Jesse Green: Is
everybody agreed that
this nut looks right?
Jay Green: Now
it looks right.
Can you move it
down a tiny bit?
Jesse Green: Oh.
Jay Green: How come he
never listens to me?
I'm always right.
I taught him.
Jesse Green: What?
What?
Jay Green: You're too;
you're too much of an
angle to the squirrel.
Jesse Green: What?
Every time I
put the thing,
you have to tell me.
Alright, here we go.
Jay Green: Can you go
down just a hair more?
Jesse Green: What?
Jay Green: Just a hair.
Jesse Green: No it
can't go down anymore.
Why won't my dad
just let me do it?
We have ten minutes
before Paul and
Nancy's friends arrive,
and I don't want them to
see it before it's done.
Jay Green: Just a hair,
just a hair more.
Jesse Green: Thank God
Brett is keeping Nancy
busy because attaching
these acorns is taking so
much longer with
my dad helping out.
Nancy: Those are all my
little squirrel doodads.
Brett: Little rascals.
Huh, you got a lot of
them over here right?
Nancy: I do, yep.
Brett: I don't know
anything about squirrels.
I don't know
what I'm doing.
Missy: Oh yeah.
Jay Green: Good, yah!
Jesse Green: That's
the nuts right there.
That is the nuts.
Keith: Your
dad was right.
Jay Green: That's good.
I gave him an opinion and
it turned out
to be correct.
He won't admit it,
but I was right.
Nancy: Um, and
the one that's up
there in the bookcase.
[phone rings]
Brett: Oh.
Hello.
It is?
Alright I will be
right out then.
Nancy: I can see him?
Brett: Alright, great.
Yah, we're ready to go.
Jesse Green: Looks
like Brett finally did
something right.
'Cause he managed
to keep Nancy busy.
Was he boring you?
Nancy: No he was not.
Jesse Green: Okay.
Nancy: He was, he
was listening to my
ranting and raving.
Jesse Green: Oh very good.
Brett: I'm so glad I
finally made Jesse happy.
This is the best
job I've ever had.
And I don't want to stop
working with these guys.
Jesse Green: Now that Paul
and Nancy's friends are
here everybody's ready
to see the squirrel.
You guys want to
see a sculpture?
Nancy: Yes.
Jesse Green: Alright,
let's do it.
Nancy, we've got a
little surprise for you.
Nancy: I hope it's still
a squirrel under there.
Jesse Green: It might be.
Now I know you guys
wanted a waving squirrel,
but I had this
other idea.
Paul: Alright.
Nancy: Okay.
Jesse Green: That I think
you're going to like.
Is everybody ready?
Crowd: Yah.
Jesse Green: There we go.
Nancy: Oh!
Wow, we loved it.
Paul: It was
unbelievable.
Much more than
we ever expected.
We know squirrels and that
squirrel is unbelievable.
Jesse Green: We had a lot
of work going on this week
and this was a tough job.
I'm still learning
how to run a business.
Every day we get
a little better,
I'm really happy with what
we accomplished this week.