Football games often start with a coin toss
and a national anthem. Sunday`s pregame ceremonies
in Kansas City also included a moment of silence.
The Kansas City Chiefs held the moment for
the victims of domestic violence and their
families. It`s an issue with an immediate
connection to the Kansas City community and
the Chiefs team. Jovan Belcher was a linebacker
for Kansas City. Police reports say that on
Saturday, Belcher shot and killed his girlfriend,
Cassandra Perkins. He drove to the team`s
practice facility where he then took his own
life. When violence like this occurs, you
might expect the issue of gun control to come
up, you might not expect it to come up during
a half-time show.
And that`s what happened on Sunday night.
NBC`s Bob Costas talked about it during the
Sunday night football broadcast. He quoted
another sports reporter, Jason Whitlock, whom
Costas agreed with. Here is what he said,
quote: "Our current gun culture ensures that
more and more domestic disputes will end in
the ultimate tragedy. Handguns do not enhance
our safety. They tempt us to escalate arguments
and bait us into embracing confrontation rather
than avoiding it."
Now, there was an immediate reaction to this
online. It was not necessarily about gun control,
it was about Costas discussing the issue during
a sports program. One sports talk show host
said, quote, "I will gladly debate Jason Whitlock
and Bob Costas on gun control, but we tuned
in for an NFL game! Ridiculous programming
decision!"
Another person on Twitter said, quote, "Big
ups to Bob Costas for standing up for gun
control. Hopefully, some day we can actually
have a conversation about it as a nation."
So, on our blog today we are tossing it to
you to get your take. We are focusing on what
Bob Costas did. Should he have weighed in
on the issue of gun control during halftime,
or was this an issue of a bad decision or
bad timing? We are looking for your thoughts
at cnnstudentnews.com
U.S. government is getting closer to the edge
of the fiscal cliff. Congress and the president
have until January 1 to agree on the plan
to lower the country`s debt. That could include
how the government takes in money through
taxes and how it spends money. If they don`t
come up with the deal, we know that taxes
will go up for all Americans, and government
spending will also get cut. Ted Rowlands looks
at what that might mean for one city.
(BEGIN VIDEOTAPE)
TED ROWLANDS, CNN CORRESPONDENT: First and
foremost, there`s the Rock Island Arsenal.
If Congress doesn`t act, defense spending
will be slashed by 55 billion next year and
450 billion over ten years. Which many fear
could put the Arsenal in jeopardy. The Arsenal
is the area`s largest employer. And though
it`s not clear how any cuts would impact the
installation specifically, the mere prospect
has people worried.
Next, is healthcare, another major employer
in the quad cities. If Congress doesn`t act,
Medicare reimbursement will initially drop
by two percent. Trinity Medical Center in
Rock Island is already budgeting for the fiscal
cliff.
Other possible fiscal cliff cuts that could
hit Rock Island include the Army Corps of
Engineers. They are here in part to manage
the locks along the Mississippi.
There is cuts to public education, which the
National School Board Association said could
have a profound effect if Congress doesn`t
act.
And there are potential cuts to social services.
More than 12 percent of Rock Island`s population
lives below the poverty line. And of course,
there are the tax hikes.
At Theo`s coffee shop, people have a lot to
say about Washington D.C. and the fiscal cliff.
James Cheeks says he`s counting on Congress
to prevent his taxes from going up.
JAMES CHEEKS, CUSTOMER: Scary. You know, it`s
scary. Where then money is going to come from?
You know, how am I going to pay this extra
tax hike?
ROWLANDS: The potential effects of the fiscal
cliff aren`t necessarily any more or less
significant here in Rock Island than they
would be in any other city across the country.
The bottom line is, if Congress doesn`t act,
there will be significant repercussions for
the entire country. Ted Rowlands, CNN, Rock
Island, Illinois.
(END VIDEOTAPE)
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: Today`s "Shoutout" goes
out to Mr. Lind`s social studies classes at
Highland High School in Ault, Colorado.
Which of these technologies is celebrating
its 20th birthday this week? Here we go, is
it the cell phone, artificial heart, DVD or
text message?
You`ve got three seconds, go!
If you guessed the text message, you are right.
The first one was sent 20 years ago this week.
That`s your answer and that`s your "Shoutout."
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: The text of the first text message -- "Merry
Christmas." The engineer was sending it to
his boss who was at a Christmas party. What
started as two words has exploded in the 2.2
trillion texts. That`s how many are sent every
year just in the U.S., so it works out to
about 6 billion per day.
Text messaging is slowing down a little bit.
So, some analysts start wondering if it`ll
BRB. But for a lot of people, especially you
guys, it`s the most common form of communication.
So, the idea of texting disappearing any time
soon might just make you LOL.
Well, the CNN Heroes program is all about
honoring people who are making a difference.
People like Malala Yousafzai. She`s the Pakistani
teenager who was shot by the Taliban because
of her support for girls` right to education
in her home country. Malala is recovering
from the attack and she has a message for
her supporters.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
ANDERSON COOPER, CNN ANCHOR: "Thank you so
much for the outpouring of love and support.
I thank the people who supported me without
distinguishing religion and color. People
have actually supported a cause, not an individual.
Let`s work together, she says. Let`s work
together to educate girls around the world.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: Anderson Cooper read Malala`s message
during Sunday night`s CNN Heroes All Star
Tribute program. Now, Kareen Wynter recaps
the night and tells us who was the 2012 CNN
Hero of the Year.
(BEGIN VIDEOTAPE)
KAREEN WYNTER, CNN CORRESPONDENT: The red
carpet outside L.A.`s Shrine Auditorium buzzed
with excitement, but this time the bright
lights shined on some special stars, everyday
people changing the world.
COOPER: Welcome to CNN Heroes, an All-Star
Tribute
WYNTER: Out of thousands of nominations submitted
by CNN`s global audience, ten amazing men
and women were singled out for their remarkable
heroic efforts to make the world a better
place. People like Razia Jan, who is providing
a free education to hundreds of girls in rural
Afghanistan.
RAZIA JAN, "HEROES" HONOREE: I think education
is the only thing in the world that can go
forward and make life better.
WYNTER: And Leo McCarthy, who gives scholarships
to kids who pledge not to drink after his
daughter was killed by a young driver.
LEO MCCARTHY: Let`s change a culture and keep
these promising, vibrant kids alive.
WYNTER: Olympic swimmer Kolin Jones helped
celebrate Wanda Butts golden moment. Motivated
by her son`s tragic drowning, she created
a non- profit that helped more than 1200 children
learn how to swim.
WANDA BUTTS, "HEROES" HONOREE: It is unbelievable
to me that I have come this far from such
a tragedy with my son.
WYNTER: It was an unforgettable night capped
off with the unveiling of the CNN Hero of
the Year: Pushpa Basnet, founder of a Children`s
Home in Nepal that helps kids whose parents
are in prison.
PUSHPA BASNET, CNN HERO OF THE YEAR: And thank
you so much for everyone who brought it for
me and who believed in my dream.
WYNTER: The hope is that their heroic example
will inspire countless others.
Kareen Wynter, CNN, Los Angeles.
(END VIDEOTAPE)
AZUZ: Last week, we told you about some Rhode
Island police officers who made a group of
young people do pushups instead of arresting
or reporting them for allegedly vandalizing
a mailbox.
On our blog, 75 percent of you sided with
the police, saying, you supported the push-up
punishment. Hannah wrote: "Although more could`ve
been done to ensure the alleged vandalism
wouldn`t happen again, it was a perfectly
good punishment. Anybody would rather do push-ups
than pay a fine.
From Robbie, "The punishment would only be
OK it if was a small, harmless crime, but
it was a larger crime, it shouldn`t be an
option."
Christine says, "As much as a punishment was
needed, it wasn`t up to the police officers
themselves to decide what it would be."
Mr. Mike`s juvenile detention class says "The
police officers let the suspects off with
a good warning as opposed to arresting them
on the spot!"
And Hong wrote, "I`m not surprised by this
punishment, because it`s quite popular in
my home country. This type of punishment does
not cause any harm."
Today`s before we go segment is a tale where
cuisine meets convenience.
This vending machine in a California mall
seems a little fishy. It`s because it`s filled
with caviar, fish eggs. Now you can snack
while you shop in style. The prices run anywhere
from 12 bucks to 500. Add it all up, and this
machine`s filled with $50,000 in merchandise.
Some critics say caviar doesn`t belong in
the food court, but if shoppers are willing
to pay, it seems like an eggselent idea. If
you do have any official complaints, you could
take it up with the sturgeon general. But
you might have to vent for yourself because
you could just be fighting an upstream battle.
We just hope you won`t start a row, because
that would be in bad taste. We hope you have
a great rest of the day. CNN STUDENT NEWS.
I`m Carl Azuz.