He would travel through pain
and suffering to reach nirvana
- the everlasting bliss we all dream of.
Symbol of peace
Symbol of compassion,
symbol of non-violence.
He was the Buddha.
He grew up in a palace surrounded
by luxury.
In his teens his privilege afforded him
every indulgence
But he gave all this up
- to gain ultimate wisdom.
He would travel the darkest corridors
of his mind to come face to face
with the devil inside him.
He founded the first world religion,
followed today by over 400 million people
- a religion where
meditation is used to reach
a state of complete peace and happiness.
Our own potential our own effort
to know the ultimate reality.
And the events of his life make up one of
the greatest stories ever told
- and the Buddha the world's most
enduring icon.
Two and a half thousand years after
his death the Buddha's message lives on.
The Dalai Lama
- the spiritual figurehead of
Tibetan Buddhism
- passes on the teachings of the Buddha
- continuing a practice that
began the day he died.
Buddhism has been adopted by many different
cultures and has many interpretations.
The Buddha's teachings of
a higher mental calm
and clarity are seen by some as a religion,
others a philosophy, even a psychotherapy.
Some people
describe Buddhism is not a religion
but Buddhism is science of mind.
The Buddha's message is as relevant today
as it was two
and a half thousand years ago.
What has made Buddhism so popular
is that it is insightful
and largely true that
the Buddha discovered
immensely important things.
Unlike other religions, Buddhism,
which centers on the mind,
has no supreme God.
Instead a great teacher
- the Buddha or the Awakened One.
It seems very almost intuitive to an age
in which psychology becomes for many people
an alternative to religion
it's the means it's a therapeutic means
to dealing with the problems of life
and so it seems very accessible
to many people.
There are many representations
of the Buddha
- and Buddhists all have their own picture
in their minds of what he was like.
Some kind of vibration of complete peace,
non-violence I think that must be there.
Until little more than
one hundred years ago
the life of the Buddha remained unknown
to the West.
By the time the British colonized India
- the country of the Buddha's birth
- Buddhism had all but died out,
destroyed by Hindu kings
and Muslim invaders.
The origins and the sites of
the Buddha's life became lost to everyone.
It wasn't until
British colonial archaeologists
began to explore Northern India
that their discoveries
began to root the Buddha's life
in historical fact.
In the 1860's,
a series of archaeologists began to try
and identify the sites associated
with the life of the Buddha.
By the 1890's many of these sites
had been successfully identified
within the Ganges area,
but that time two of the great sites
connected with Buddhism were still missing,
the site of Lumbini,
where the Buddha had actually been born,
and the site of Kapilavastu
which was the childhood home of the Buddha.
The area to the north of the Ganges
was less well known,
partly because of
the very thick jungle there,
tigers as well as malaria.
It took a breakthrough discovery to unlock
the story of the Buddha's origins.
In a remote village across the border
in Nepal a pillar was discovered.
A British expedition was sent out
to decipher its inscription.
The script is the early Brami script
and the language is
a local vernacular language
of Northern India
and indeed the inscription itself depicts
that this is where the Buddha,
the enlightened one was born.
This was the first piece of
evidence to suggest that the Buddha
was not just a legendary figure
- he actually existed.
Ancient Buddhist texts
had named the Buddha's birthplace as Lumbini
and now the archaeologists
had it located on the map.
Now they tried to find
the Buddha's childhood home
- an ancient city named in the texts as
- Kapilavastu.
It was apparent that
it was located to the west
perhaps 10 or 15 kilometers
to the west of Lumbini
and that is where the search
began to intensify.
Expeditions uncovered two possible sites
for Kapilavastu
- one in India the other in Nepal.
For a hundred years archaeologists
have argued over them.
New research by Dr Coningham
and his team
suggests the ancient city lay
at modern day Tilaurakot - in Nepal.
It's an extremely exciting site
because it is so well preserved,
we conducted that a series of
geo physical surveys
and we then identified a series of roads
laid out and it became a clear
that the entire city in its final phrase
had been laid out on a girded pattern.
At its centre lay a palace.
It is here that the Buddha's story begins.
Two and a half thousand years ago
Northern India was divided up
into Kingdoms and republics.
The Buddha's father - Sudhodana
- was the elected chieftain
of the Shakya tribe.
He ruled his kingdom from his palace
near the foothills of the Himalayas.
His queen was called Maya.
Legend tells that on the night
of the full moon
she had an extraordinary dream.
It told that a special Being known
as the Buddha
was about to be born again on earth.
The legend goes on
that Four Guardian deities of the world
carried Queen Maya up to
the Himalaya mountains in her bed.
They anointed her with divine perfumes
and decked her with heavenly flowers.
A white elephant with
six tusks descended from heaven,
carrying a lotus flower in its trunk,
and entered her womb.
The Buddha would be born of Maya.
If one looks at this story of
the Buddhist conception and compares it
to say the conception story of Jesus,
where you have angels appearing.
I suppose a similar basic idea is there.
That the forces which are beyond
are signaling that
something great is happening.
Its said that the Buddha chose the time
and the place that he would be reborn.
The baby boy was named Siddhartha
- meaning 'every wish fulfilled'.
But his mother fell ill after giving birth
and died a few days later.
Siddharta was brought up by his aunt.
The family summoned Brahmin priests
and then a trusted palace soothsayer
to predict the young prince's future
We're told that he noticed
the auspicious signs of a great
being upon Siddhartha's body,
including the mark of
a wheel upon his feet.
It's said that the Buddha was born
with certain marks on his body
the so called 32 marks of a great person.
They are seen as appearing on
the body of two kinds of people.
One who will become the Buddha
and one who will become a world Emperor.
His father was quite keen on the idea
that his son would become
a great political leader.
So this is why it is said that
he cosseted his son,
to prevent him seeing things which
might send him in a religious direction.
Everyone knew the signs meant Siddharta
was exceptional, especially the King.
But as he watched his
inquisitive young son growing up
he worried about these predictions
- that one day his son would abandon
the palace and become the spiritual leader
rather than stay to become
chief of the Shakyas.
As Siddhartha grew older his father
was delighted to see the boy's exceptional
ability at the princely sports of fencing,
wrestling and archery.
But he also noticed that Siddharta
was a deeply thoughtful and curious child.
He appeared to be more interested in
trying to understand
the nature of the world around him
than in military pursuits.
For the King these were
the most important skills
young Siddharta should learn
if he was to become a leader of men.
Siddhartha was expected to become
the future King
and defender of Kapilavasthu
- one of the very first cities
in Northern India.
The Palace where Siddhartha grew up
has long since crumbled away.
Its mud and wood construction
have left nothing
for archaeologists to examine.
But more durable materials have recently
been discovered at Tilaurakot.
We cut a trench 3 meters by 3 meters
and eventually
We had a very clear sequence at the site
and then we began to be somewhat surprised
by identifying a material known as
painted greyware which is basically
a flat bowl with black paint.
This tiny fragment has huge significance.
Dr Coningham believes it was
made in the 5th Century BC
- at the time Siddhartha was
growing up in the palace.
What we have is a centre of small industry
- We are probably dealing with a settlement
that we would even hesitate
to call a city today
- centered around a large
courtyard belonging to the ruler.
And the majority of the population living
in the agrarian hinterland.
It was this hinterland,
lying beyond the city walls
that fascinated Siddhartha.
So when at the age of nine
his father allowed him out
to celebrate the annual ploughing festival
he eagerly participated.
His first glimpse of reality beyond
the palace walls would open a door
for Siddharta to a new vision of the world
and would become
the turning point of his life.
The story recalls that
he watched a farmer ploughing.
He saw the toil and effort, struggle and
repetition of this back-breaking work,
something he'd never seen in the palace.
He managed to slip away from
the festivities and be alone.
This first experience of real life
had a profound effect upon him.
To everyone else this was a celebration
- but to Siddhartha it symbolized
something quite different.
He felt his mind leading him
into a contemplative state.
He watched the plough as it cut
and parted the ground and noticed a bird
eating a freshly unearthed worm.
He asked himself why living beings
have to suffer in this way.
If the farmer had not been ploughing
the bird would not have eaten the worm.
He realized that everything was connected
and that all actions had consequences.
This simple observation would become
one of the corner stones of his teachings
- known as karma.
As Siddharta's mind focused
on these profound thoughts he slipped
into a trance or jana
- a mental state which would become
his first step
on the road to enlightenment.
He was sat under a tree
and he was just focusing on
the plough going through the earth.
And its said while doing that
he fairly Naturally went into
a meditative state called a first Jana.
Which was very very joyful and happy.
And which he later uses
as part of his spiritual path.
The connection to Buddhist meditation
is the focusing on something
which has a calming centering effect.
Possibly also the idea of compassion
for the worms being killed as
the plough went through the earth.
So I suppose one would see this as
just part of his rather special nature.
The young prince's behavior
deeply unsettled the King.
Brahmanism
- the religious tradition of the time
- insisted that sons should follow
in the footsteps of their fathers.
One of the things that I think
makes this narrative so powerful is,
again we can imagine
this scene of his father
trying to protect his son
encountering any suffering.
Now the reason for doing this is
that there has been a prophesy that/
he'll either become a universal monarch
or he'll become a renunciant
who will gain enlightenment.
His father of course wants him to become
a king to follow in his footsteps.
As Siddhartha grew up
his father did all he could to tempt him
to stay inside the palace.
He tried to create a perfect
and seductive world for him to live in.
As was Customary for a prince,
Siddhartha was offered beautiful maidens
to entertain him with music and
to pleasure him with their physical beauty.
When Siddhartha reached the age of sixteen
the King even found him a beautiful bride
- Princess Yasodhara.
Siddharta had to compete for her hand
and the King was delighted how skillfully
his son fought off the competition.
The King began to convince himself
that palace life was beginning
to suit his son at last.
But this was wishful thinking
and Siddhartha pestered his father
to allow him out of the palace.
Unable to refuse
his son's wishes any longer,
the King desperately set about
clearing every eyesore
from the surrounds of the palace.
Like a Hollywood film set, the sick,
the poor and the old were all deleted
from the fantasy
presented to the young prince.
Despite his father's efforts,
Siddhartha's first taste of the
outside world would reveal stark realities.
With the naivety of a child
he set out with Chana,
his charioteer, as his guide.
The prince would make four journeys
and see four signs
- as predicted
by the palace fortune teller.
Early Buddhist texts place great importance
on this point in the story
as each journey would reveal to Siddhartha
an aspect of life which had been
deliberately hidden from him.
On his first trip Siddhartha
went out into the country,
away from his father's influence.
He noticed an old man painfully making
his way through a village.
He asked Chana what was wrong with the man
and Chana explained
the process of ageing to him.
Siddhartha was alarmed
when he learnt that ageing is inescapable
and happens to us all.
For Siddhartha,
reality was beginning to unveil
a cruel picture of the world.
- Where misfortune and suffering appeared
to dominate every aspect of life.
The second sign was soon to follow
when Siddhartha noticed a sick man,
his features twisted with disease.
He asked Chana if anyone could become sick
and again he was shocked
when he learnt the brutal truth
that we all can.
The protective wall of fantasy around him
was beginning to crumble.
And the further the young Prince ventured
the more of life's horrors confronted him.
Now he saw a corpse, bound in linen,
being carried to the funeral pyre
- and the story records that Siddhartha
is appalled to discover
not only that all men are mortal,
but also that it was a Brahmin belief
that after death we are all reborn
- to suffer and die time and time again.
There seemed no end
and no solution to life's miserable
and inevitable cycle.
The Buddha's life is an allegory
because the most important point in it is
that here is a young man
who is brought up with every luxury
and he realizes that isn't enough
because he has a shock.
He has a shock because for the first time
he encounters old age,
disease and death.
It's not plausible to think that
growing up as an intelligent youth
he wouldn't have known anything about it.
The point is rather to
convey the tremendous impact that
coming face to face with
these fundamental facts of human existence,
has and must have upon us,
and that it's urgent
that we do something about it.
But it was the fourth sign that would
definitively point to Siddharta's future
- a man wearing a simple robe
with a begging bowl before him.
Why should anyone want to give up
the pleasures of the world
to wander the countryside, begging?
Asked the prince.
Chana explained that the man had renounced
such pleasures in order to confront reality
and seek answers to this painful existence.
The account of the four signs
I see as quite an effective story way
of putting certain existential realizations
we all know we are going to get old
we all know we are going to get sick
we all know we are going to die
in our heads but its very different
to sit down on day
and realize here no is not just
other people who get old sick and die
its I'm going to get old
I'm going to get sick and I'm going to die
and I think the story accounts
are trying to portray
that moment of existential realization
where you see it for the first time
you are going to die
and you know it and you taste it.
When Siddartha returned to the palace
after this fourth journey
his mind was reeling
with his new understanding of the world.
The fruits and flowers around him
would rot and wither away.
Even the walls of the palace
would one day crumble.
His wife had just given
birth to a beautiful child.
But they would both one day grow old,
become ill and die. It was inevitable.
He had learnt the meaning of impermanence
and saw it in everything around him.
Siddharta knew he had to leave his family
to seek answers to the questions
that tormented him,
even though this meant
abandoning his wife and son.
Against the tradition of his family
and the Brahmin religion,
Siddhartha left home to find
his own answers to life's suffering.
One story recalls
how a hypnotic mist sent
the guards to sleep
allowing him to escape with Chana,
through the Eastern Gate of the palace.
It is said that beside the river Anoma,
he removed his jewellery,
exchanged his robes for rags
and cut off his long hair.
He asked Chana to carry them
back to the palace.
Siddhartha was alone for the first time.
He had at last escaped
the false world of palace life
where suffering had been
swept out of sight.
Now he needed to come
face to face with reality,
if he was ever to find a solution
to the pain of existence.
Siddhartha was confronted
by suffering on a scale
he'd never seen before
when he arrived in the cities.
And within those cities people
were being thrown together,
at times there was perhaps
an increase in disease and suffering.
Some people have seen
this as a particular trigger
for the Buddha's emphasis on suffering.
It accentuated a universal problems
that any human being in any society faces.
Siddhartha realized that
if he was to find an answer
to the suffering surrounding him,
he would have to challenge
the Brahmin religion under
which everyone lived.
What the Brahmins had was sacred knowledge
this sacred knowledge
centered on knowing certain texts
called the Vedas
the word Veda itself simply means knowledge
and the implication is that
that was the only knowledge
which was really worth having.
With their sacred knowledge,
Brahmin priests
oversaw every stage of life,
from birth to death.
Their blessing was essential
but their knowledge could only be
handed down to their sons.
The position of
Brahmin families remained assured
- until a new wave of thinkers
began to challenge this.
It was a time when Brahamism,
early form of Hinduism
was being questioned,
it was a little bit like
the time of the ancient philosophers
such as Plato
and Socrates in Ancient Greece.
People debating arguing with people and
the Buddha tried to cut a way through that.
He described the context as a welter
of views a jungle of views.
As Siddhartha explored
this jungle he realized that
the solution to life's suffering
needed to be available to everyone,
rather than an exclusive few
- like the Brahmin tradition.
The Buddha disagreed with the Brahmins
and he said one does not become a Brahmin
by birth one becomes a Brahmin
by living well one
does not become an outcast
by birth one becomes an outcast
by living badly.
Now that's a wonderful and important thought
its like saying in our society
a true gentleman is not one
who is born into a particular family
but one who behaves properly.
Siddhartha traveled further
on his search into Northern India.
He was looking
for an alternative way of life
that attempted to overcome
the suffering he'd seen around him.
He was interested
in all the new philosophies
but he wanted to go further
- to reach deeper into his mind.
He now decided to focus on
the technique of meditation
and sought out
the leading gurus of the day.
There been broadly speaking two kinds
of meditation in ancient India.
Which consisted in putting yourself
under various kinds of pressure
by controlling your breathing
or sometimes fasting
or undergoing other forms of discomfort
and the aim is really to obtain what
we call altered states of consciousness.
So they would think that they had climbed
to very high plains in the universe.
They're not taking this literally,
its not that they think that
they go five thousand feet up in the air,
so to speak but they think that
there are certain planes which become more
and more abstract such things
as the plane of infinity of space
and that's followed by the plane of
infinite consciousness as you got
and then the plane of infinite nothingness,
these were the sorts of things
the Buddha definitely must have learnt
from his teachers.
It is said that Siddhartha,
so excelled at mediating that
he attracted a group of five followers
and his teachers asked him to stay on
and take over their schools.
But Siddhartha decided that
this practice alone was not
the answer to the problem of suffering
and rebirth or reincarnation.
He set out to explore other techniques
- this time focusing on his body.
So he then goes to try another method
which is harsh asceticism.
This involved things like fasting,
not washing,
meditations where you hold your breath
for a very long time
and its very forceful willful way.
Ascetics may starve
and even mutilate themselves.
For them the physical body
is a barrier to spiritual liberation.
By shedding their attachment to the body
they will cleanse the mind
and liberate the soul.
Siddhartha tried to
achieve this state of liberation.
He fasted for so long
his life hung by a thread.
'All my limbs became like
the knotted joints of withered creepers,
my buttocks like a bullocks hoof,
my protruding backbone
like a string of balls,
my gaunt ribs like the crazy rafters
of a tumbledown shed.
My eyes lay deep in their sockets,
their pupils sparkling
like water in a deep well.
As an unripe gourd shrivels
and shrinks in the hot wind,
so became my scalp.
Just as Siddhartha
was about to die of starvation a young girl
saved his life by giving him
a bowl of rice and milk.
He now realized that
if he starved himself again
he would simply die
having achieved nothing.
And the story says that
he is living on one grain of rice a day.
He's practically starved himself to death
and realizes that disciplining the body
through extreme self renunciation,
aestheticism inflicting pain upon the body
that doesn't solve the problem.
When his five followers saw Siddhartha
had given up his fast
they lost faith in him.
They no longer believed he had the strength
to live up to his spiritual convictions
and abandoned him.
He feels he tried what's on offer,
they haven't worked,
and its at this stage
that he remembers meditation
that he went into spontaneously
in his teens/ and he thinks mm,
maybe that is a way through to awakening
because its not taken up the desires
of the body
but it is very joyful and happy.
By chance Siddharta came across
a musician tuning his sitar.
When the string was too slack
it would not play.
When it was too tight it snapped.
Somewhere in the middle lay
tuneful harmony.
Siddhartha realized that
this simple observation signified
something of great importance.
It was the middle way that would lead him
to the state of mind he was looking for
- to a state of tuneful harmony
- enlightenment.
But how could he achieve it?
And the way that Buddha eventually uses
is what one could call mindfulness
or awareness of the body,
which neither ignores it nor tries
to forcefully master it,
but it's a kind of middle way.
The middle way led Siddhartha
through the countryside.
He had been traveling for six years,
He had experienced pain and suffering
and had stretched
the boundaries of his mind.
But he'd still not found the inner peace
and harmony he was searching for.
The state of absolute wisdom and
everlasting bliss known as Enlightenment.
Siddhartha arrived at Bodh Gaya.
Here his torment would end.
He sat down beneath a tree and vowed not to
leave until he had reached ENLIGHTENMENT.
'Flesh may decay, bones may fall apart,
but I will never leave this place
until I find the way to enlightenment. '
He's no longer giving himself a hard time,
he's not stressing himself unbearably,
he's not undergoing anything painful,
he thinks, well life is painful without
taking the trouble to make it more painful,
but let me just calmly think things out,
think of how life works.
He starts to focus the mind by attention
to the slow movement of the breath coming
and going out a refined sensation
which exists in the body
just around the nose in a way which
starts to lead to the mind quietening,
stilling, settling, gathering, purifying.
Siddhartha's mind was now so focused
that he could successfully
enter the darkest reaches of his unconscious.
It was now that he would face
his final and greatest torment.
The demon Mara - the Lord of Ego
and illusion appeared before him.
He could make any horror real
in Siddhartha's mind.
It's very important to remember
that Mara this demon king
is not like the Christian Satan
because he isn't a tempter
and he isn't any kind of counterpart
to God,
he is purely psychological forces
which we have within us,
Mara unleashed an army of demons
to attack Siddhartha.
They fired flaming arrows at him.
But mid flight
Siddhartha turned them into lotus blossoms
and they fell harmlessly around him.
Having failed Mara
then tried to seduce Siddhartha
with his tempting daughters.
He's assailed by the demon king
who is the same time death
and desire very Freudian
that in a way desire is death,
death is desire and in fact the Demon king
offers him his three daughters
who are both passion or lust and aversion
where it is equally bad
if you shy away from this
and say it is disgusting
you are also a slave to passion
- and he can be completely calm
and indifferent
and just gaze at them without
any feelings of attraction or repulsion.
The faces of Mara's daughters
began to rot before Siddharta's eyes.
The evil daughters
then disappeared into the earth.
It is in fact
you could say the Buddha's very recognition
that Mara is an aspect of himself
the total recognition of that
is his enlightenment.
The earth is said to have trembled
as he dispelled the devil.
Siddhartha, now aged 35,
passed through four Janas
to reach enlightenment
and become the Buddha - or Awakened One.
He then spent 7 days beneath the tree
in a meditative state of absolute bliss.
This is seen as a state where the mind
is incredibly refined and sensitive,
and an image might be of a lake,
which is totally still,
which would register
even an insect on the surface.
So this is seen as a state
where the mind is very,
very powerful as
an instrument of knowledge, very sensitive.
In this highly attuned state,
the Buddha saw way to escape
the inevitable cycle of old age sickness
and death.
He realized that if we remove desire
we can remove dissatisfaction
and suffering from our lives.
A key cause of the painfulness
and frustration of life
is craving kind of demanding desires.
So There's a general mismatch
between how you want things to be
and how they actually are.
The insight the Buddha attained
beneath the tree was the birth of Buddhism
- a religion followed today
by 400 million people.
The Buddha summed up his wisdom
in four noble truths
which are the foundation
of all Buddhist beliefs
The first noble truth recognized
that there is suffering in life.
The second diagnosed
the cause of that suffering - desire.
In the third truth, like a doctor,
the Buddha revealed
that there was a cure for desire.
And in the fourth noble truth
he gave the prescription
- how to cure the illness
and achieve Enlightenment or Nirvana.
The ultimate aim was to reach
a state of mind completely free of craving,
ignorance, greed, hatred and delusion,
thereby free of all
the causes of future rebirth
when an enlightened person dies
they're seen as going beyond rebirth
to a state beyond if you like space
and time and not coming back
so that is seen as a state of liberation.
The Buddha would further teach
that morality, meditation and wisdom
were the stepping stones to enlightenment.
He would dedicate the rest of his life
helping others to follow this path
- towards freedom from suffering.
As his followers grew in number
he went on to set up a school or Sangha
Today a temple stands beside a descendant
of the very tree under
which the Buddha became enlightened.
The monks here have become
a living library of the Buddha's teachings.
Chanting his sacred words
beneath the Bodhi tree of Enlightenment
is seen by Buddhists to give special power
to their practice.
The chief monk is responsible
for preserving this tradition
at the temple.
The most important thing
is the practice of his teachings.
Practice diligently, be ever mindful.
So now I say I explain Buddhism
in two words,
practice mindfulness.
The path to enlightenment begins
with the focusing of the mind
and following a number of commandments.
Morality, meditation and wisdom.
So not to kill, not to steal,
not to have any sexual misconduct,
not to tell a lie and not to have indulge
in intoxicating drinks or intoxicants.
This was the way of life established by
the Buddha in the very first sangha.
After eight years
he went back to the palace
and the family he'd abandoned.
We're told his father now forgave
the Buddha for the deep hurt
he had caused.
King Sudhodhana now realized the importance
of his son's quest.
His stepmother even begged
to join his sangha
and she went on to become
history's first nun.
The Buddha is justified in the eyes
of all Buddhists of even leaving his wife
and child to go on his solitary journey
to try and find what the solution
to life's problems is
and how life should be lived
and for him how life should be lived
is the question infinitely more important
than having any possessions
or even the company of loved ones.
The Buddha was to abandon his family again.
He set out to teach, for forty years
- passing on to his followers the wisdom
he had attained beneath the bodi tree.
But before he left he ordained
his son as a monk.
The Buddha encouraged his followers
to live together in a monastery or Sangha
- to help them focus
on the path to enlightenment.
Some people become
a monk purely to meditate,
purely to practice meditation,
purely to practice the life of a recluse.
Some become a monk to work
for the propagation of the religion.
Monks from all over the world
come to live in monasteries established
around the temple of the Bodi Tree.
Non-Monks or lay Buddhists,
come here too, to learn from them.
Monks must be celibate
and give up every selfish desire.
And that is the one part of the training
to get rid of self tendencies,
tendencies to always think about yourself
and put yourself fully in
the context of the community of the sanga
Then when all the sacrifices
have been made the hard work begins
- committing long chants
or mantras to memory.
Mantras such as this have a purpose
- they are designed
to test the monk's memory,
concentration and commitment
to the Buddha's teachings.
Over the centuries his message has evolved
into a number of different traditions,
with their own interpretations
and monastic practices.
But the Buddha taught that lay people
can also follow the path to eternal bliss
and ultimate wisdom.
Most westerners are not drawn to Buddhism
as a way of leaving society behind
they're drawn to the practical
of meditation as a way of being
more effective within society
and that's a way in which
the message of Buddhism takes on
a very different caste
because it becomes a form
of self improvement a way of dealing
with the stresses of life a way
of clarifying your goals and objectives.
Many westerners are especially attracted
to Buddhist meditation.
I think all of us sometimes glimpse
that magic and mystery of the moment
what meditation does
is to help us touch that more often,
it helps us to be more calm
and controlled in our mind
and we can create conditions
that allow us to come into
a state of awareness of interdependence,
of impermanence, of nirvana.
Some schools of Buddhism
believe the Buddha was superhuman
a magical figure who consorted
with gods and performed miracles.
Others that he was no more than
a human being and they believe it is this
that adds power to his message.
There is no doubt that the Buddha wished
to be remembered as a human being
with human frailties not perhaps frailties
of the intellect or moral frailties
but certainly physical frailties
and the Buddha suffers from back pain
towards the end of his life
he suffers from various physical complaints
and weaknesses.
The Buddha would die at the age of eighty
from a common illness - food poisoning.
It is said that before
passing away he fell into a deep trance
on his journey from this world to Nirvana
- a state of eternal bliss
- free at last from rebirth,
free at last from suffering and death.
A council was assembled to record
for posterity the Buddha's teachings.
These were learnt by heart and handed down
the centuries by generations of monks.
The Buddha's body was cremated.
And his remains were preserved.
They were enshrined two hundred years later
by India's first Emperor King Ashoka
who converted to Buddhism.
He built vast monuments or stuppas
and erected pillars to mark the key sites
of the Buddha's life.
Asoka then becomes
an absolutely key figure,
both in terms
of the actual spread of Buddhism
but then as a model
for future Buddhist leaders throughout Asia
they look back to Ashoka as
the kind of ideal king
and supporter of Buddhism.
So far as we know the Emperor Asoka
who ruled over two thirds of modern India
in the middle of the 3rd century BC,
helped monks to send out missions
to countries bordering India,
missionaries were sent up into Kashmir
to Nepal and certainly Sri Lanka.
They converted the king,
the king give his patronize to Buddhism
and Sri Lanka has therefore been
a Buddhist country from that day to this.
And in country after country
we know over many centuries
that this is the way
that Buddhism was successfully implanted.
Ashoka's pillars outlived Buddhism in India
- they withstood Muslim invasions
and survived to catch the attention
of the first colonial archaeologists.
This gave a very significant impetus
to the revival of Buddhism
- the desire to go back to the places
associated with the Buddha.
Imagining Buddhism for people in the West
but these investigations also become
the basest for a revival
within Buddhism in Asia.
Today the sites associated
with the Budha's life attract tourists
and pilgrims flock to Bodh Gaya
to follow in the Buddha's footsteps,
hoping to find, as he did,
eternal peace and happiness
and a cure for suffering and death.
It's a great irony
that after the Buddha's death the person
who preached of the uselessness of ritual
and also the uselessness
of personality cult became
the object of ritual worship
and as big a personality cult
as has ever existed in history.
Buddhist temples have been
built in Bodh Gaya representing
the different traditions
from around the world.
Buddhism, in all its forms,
has come home, to the Bodi tree,
to the place where once a prince reached
enlightenment and became the Buddha.
The Buddha attained enlightenment on that
fleeting moment of a wink, this moment,
fleeting moment is the time that takes
to realize that moment cannot be explained.
That special moment gave birth
to the first world religion
- A religion without a God
where the path to Nirvana lies in the mind
of each and every one of us.
Ripped by:
SkyFury