JEFF BRUSHIE: Snowboarding
started out as, basically, a
way to get down a big
powdery face.
And then all of a sudden, kids
like myself and some others
that were in the skateboarding
and that kind of scene, and
style and tricks, kind
of adapted over into
snowboarding.
DAVE DRISCOLL: Right out of the
gates, Jeff was a standout.
I mean, he pushed.
He pushed the whole look and
style in snowboarding to a
whole new level, just from his
attitude and the way he
carried himself, to the
dreads to DJing, and
then on-hill, obviously.
He was one of the first people
to really bring that skate
style into snowboarding.
There could be other people
credited, too, like Noah
Salasnek and others, but he
definitely pushed the limits,
and style went a long way.
PAT BRIDGES: People were getting
big airs, but they
were traveling the pipe.
Brushie actually brought it
really high, above the lip of
the half pipe.
The tricks he was doing were
like skateboarding at the
time, like lip tricks.
He was doing airs to disaster
and revert and stuff like that
in the pipe.
Brushie really brought
the tweak into it.
PIERRE WIKBERG: Brushie
had a different style.
He would just tweak more, and
he had his allie-oop threes
that he would grab like mute
stiffy and poke them out.
And he just thought
differently.
I thought he had more
interesting
to watch than Terje.
SHAUN WHITE: I remember--
I mean, yeah, I always watched
him, and I don't think it was
ever like will I
ever get there.
You know what I mean?
He was always just like how.
How can I do that?
Because I have to.
I have to go as big as him.
How do I do it?
TREVOR ANDREW: He really was the
first one, to me, that was
in the pipe busting.
I don't know.
He had that whole hip-hop
kind of flow.
It was kind of crazy.
He was the first one doing
that, it seemed like.
And, yeah, just his style
was like nobody else's.
TODD RICHARDS: In that old
video, "Chill," it was the
first Burton video, Mike
Jacoby's like, I think that
Brushie is killer rapper dude,
and it was like from that day
on, he was the rap guy.
At first, he'd just have
this weird Tony Hawk--
like remember that flop,
that face flop?
He had that, but
to the extreme.
It was this big long thing, and
that just all of a sudden
turned into dreadlocks at some
point, and then he was the
dreadlock dude.
Right at that time was NWA,
Eazy-E. Public Enemy was
really big.
And Brush was the first guy that
kind of rolled with that.
TREVOR GRAVES: He'd always have
his tongue out, and he'd
always have a runny nose.
That was always a good
signal for Brush.
I don't know what it was, just
always snot running out of
that kid's mouth.
KEVIN ENGLISH: Brushie'd get you
thinking about your facial
expressions when you're
in the air.
You know, you're like ugh, some
sort of crazy face while
he's doing it.
TREVOR GRAVES: What Jeff would
do is he's come up, and he'd
look right at me.
Throw a stalefish right into
the lens and land it.
When you always concentrate on
the landing, you're thinking
about what you're doing.
He didn't have to.
He's like a cat.
He knew where he was
going to go.
Woop, boop, done.
KEIR DILLON: Everything
he did, he did with
just so much style.
You'd see him at the US Open,
you'd go up, and you're like
I'm buying that pant, I'm buying
that jacket, and I wish
I could buy that board.
And it was just crazy to look
back and to think that he had
that power or control over, I
think, style and the influence
of kids or us.
TREVOR ANDREW: Yeah, the first
time I saw Brushie was at
McDonald's, and I was just so
geeked that he was sitting
across from me eating fries.
You know what I mean?
It was like, damn,
that's Brushie.
Yeah, he was totally chill.
It's amazing when you have
somebody that you feel that
way about, when you meet them,
and they're actually cool.
Yeah, he was like all time
favorite for me.
For sure.
JEFF BRUSHIE: I remember--
I don't know when it was,
'87, '88, and I
went to the US Open.
I was probably only
15 or 16, so I had
to race in the juniors.
My dad brought me there
the first year.
BOB: It was kind of new, and
he harped on us for weeks,
months and whatever.
KAREN: Mm-hmm.
BOB: For a long time.
We caved in, and I
took him down.
He did pretty well.
KAREN: Bob calls me
up on the phone.
This thing is really
big, he goes.
There's people here from
France and Japan.
And I'm like, what, really?
JEFF BRUSHIE: I totally
blew it.
I didn't do good at all.
So practiced up for the next
season, and then I came back.
Maybe this was '88.
And I did the slalom, and just
went as fast as I can, and I
ended up winning by
eight seconds.
And I remember Jake Burton was
down there near the finish
line, and he came up to me and
shook my hand and stuff.
And that was kind of
the beginning.
Maybe like a year or the next
season after that, I was
traveling around with
the Burton team.
JAKE BURTON CARPENTER: Yeah,
Brush was a local kid that
we'd see at Stratton, and
he'd come to the Open.
You couldn't miss him.
He just had so much style
right in the beginning.
He went big, and he went big
sort of beyond his limits.
And so when you'd see Brush
flying through the air, there
was sort of this, well, is he
going to land this or not?
I don't mean that as
a diss at all.
I mean, the guy was incredible,
and he just had a
lot of style and attitude, and
he had NWA blaring out of his
car, I think, all the time.
And he just really made things
fresh and had just a great
spirit about him.
JEFF BRUSHIE: The guys out
west had half pipe and
freestyle contests for probably
a few years or more
before we ever had
any of that.
We all just raced gates
all the time on
icy east coast slopes.
We didn't have our first half
pipe until Tenney Mountain,
New Hampshire, in 1987.
TODD RICHARDS: That Tenney
contest was like the first
time that any of the people from
around New England that
had never--
everyone had been doing the same
thing, but we were all
brought together in one place
to see everyone else ride.
It'd be like, oh, OK, so this is
what's going on in Vermont.
I'm just in New Hampshire.
I don't know what's going on.
And you made all
these friends.
JEFF BRUSHIE: Andy and Jack
Coghlan, Chris Carol, Todd
Richards showed up.
Might have been like six feet
high at the most, but mainly
just banks.
And it was really cool because,
at the bottom, it
bowled out, so you could just
come down, do your tricks, and
then point it, kind of like
a quarter pipe at the end.
It was sick.
I remember doing big old
suitcase methods at the end.
TREVOR GRAVES: He just barreled
straight down the
middle of the pipe, hit the
cul-de-sac at the bottom, and
just boosted.
So he popped out, probably by
that time, six, seven feet,
which is pretty big suitcase
air, and landed it.
That won the contest.
That's all he needed to do.
TODD RICHARDS: Burton had the
foresight to be like, OK,
we're going to put some effort
behind this kid, and next
thing you know, Brushie's
traveling with the crew.
And he's with Craig and riding
with Craig all the time, and
he just got better and
better and better.
And we're like, holy shit,
dude, this kid--
what happened?
Like he got really crazy good,
and we're like wow, OK.
Well, we need to kind
of step our shit up.
JEFF BRUSHIE: There was a time
when people wanted you to race
and freestyle.
There was a few guys like me,
Craig, Terje, who we just
wanted to freestyle.
We just wanted to ride
pipes and stuff.
There's actually a photo of me
doing a method in the middle
of a race course.
I had to go through the race
course just for overall
points, so I just
messed around.
For a while, they just kind of
looked at us like we were the
oddballs, and a few
years after that,
freestyle's the thing.
KEIR DILLON: There are certain
people, I think, and he's one
of them, that literally dictated
where a sport could
have gone, or where
it ended up.
And just his style and attitude
and keeping it fresh
and fun and very standoffish of
the mainstream at the time
really dictated where
the sport was going.
And it's people like that that
showed you can make a living
and have fun and live your
expression and dreams through
the freestyle aspect, and the
racing doesn't need to be a
part of it.
JEFF BRUSHIE: It worked
out for us.
I think the popularity with the
freestyle growing after
just the first couple years
hooked us up, and
we got what we wanted.
No more racing.
KAREN: Hi, I'm Karen.
I'm Jeff Brushie's mom.
BOB: And I'm Bob, Jeff
Brushie's dad.
DONNA CARPENTER: His mom was
always on the side cheering
for him, and I think she was
the first snowboard mom.
JAKE BURTON CARPENTER: I think
she was one of the first sort
of snowboarding moms,
but he ran the show.
I mean, he was funny.
He called his own shots.
Nobody was really telling
Jeff what to do.
KAREN: And this is
his old room.
It was his cave.
He had all of his bibs
all the way around.
A water bed he would
not get rid of.
I'm serious.
[INAUDIBLE] room with
a lot of junk.
Those, I believe, are Trevor
Graves shots, and this was the
first competition.
This was 1990.
This is '91, was the year,
I believe, he did the
overall World Cup.
Yeah.
I was cleaning out that
snowboard bench, and I
happened to open the drawer
to see what was in there.
There was a hacky sack
and a bag of dreads.
Honest to God, I will
find those.
I will find those for you.
I went, Jeff, I have
your dreads.
I did.
I told him I had his dreads.
He goes, "Nice." Oh,
the dreadlocks.
I'll take them out for you.
I don't know, I probably need
to wash my hands after I do.
I cut them, and years
went by, years.
Here's the dreads, nasty dreads,
or natty dreads,
whatever you want
to call them.
And it took him a long time
to get those perfect.
The wall is his collection
of stickers.
I've changed a lot of things,
but I will not change this
wall until we move.
I won't.
It's got meaning.
It's part of the house, now.
And all his stuff has stayed
where he has hung it.
There's Craig Kelly.
He idolized Craig,
he really did.
And there's Shaun Palmer's
balloon.
And he just kept adding to it.
BOB: He loved McDonalds.
KAREN: Loved--
That came from Japan, I think.
Loved McDonald's.
But these are some
of the checks.
This, Nissan Snowboard Tour.
What position, I'm not
sure because it
doesn't have it on there.
They stuck him on there,
obviously.
And this was in 1992 when he won
the national competition,
and his prize was that truck.
I'm assuming that these
were first places
because he won it overall.
Unless--
no, the $1,000 ones could
have been second place.
World Pro Snowboard
Tour, Get Twisted.
That was fun.
1998.
It was fancy.
JAKE BURTON CARPENTER: It was
tough for him because he was
not really a competitor
by nature.
He was just almost too
sensitive, too nice a guy, and
I know the Open was a really
tough event for him.
All of his friends were there.
He never won there.
He never rode particularly
well there.
I think it was just too much.
You get wrapped up in all the
social stuff going on and
everything.
KAREN: And a lot of people
actually thought he was an
arrogant person because he
wouldn't really sometimes
acknowledge things.
But he was actually shy.
So that was a real misconception
about him.
What we did was when he first
started winning contests, we
basically said to him, because
he had been known to like, I
want to be a BMX biker, all
this, and he did well with
that, but he never did
any competitions.
So we said to him, well--
I mean, we didn't have a whole
ton of money at that time to
send him all around the world,
but we said, well, you set
some goals, and when you achieve
one, you can go after
another one.
So he started winning all these
contests, and then when
Burton picked him up--
obviously, to me, I mean, if
this was his calling, this
was his calling.
I mean, he didn't have to become
a doctor or lawyer.
He was making more money
than his teachers.
And I knew it was short lived,
but I knew he could
take it far, too.
But we're very proud of him.
It was really fun.
I miss it.
I miss having Jeff here, so we
have to get him to move a
little closer, bring the kids.
TODD KOHLMAN: This is one of
my personal favorites, the
1993 Jeff Brushie.
Very classic Vermont style with
the trout, and of course,
the base, the skeleton
of the fish.
BOB: And it's still in the
place that he hung it.
JEFF BRUSHIE: Well, one
of the most popular is
the very first one.
That was my least favorite
graphic, too.
My mind wasn't totally working
in the graphic mode yet, and I
think somebody kind pitched
the idea to me.
And I went with the fish because
I was a Vermont kid,
so it's kind of like the country
and fishing and stuff.
So I kind of put the fish on
there for that kind of thing,
and then the bottom was my kind
of deal, where I did the
fish skeleton on the
whole base of the
board, and my name.
I kind of got influenced with
that from Mark Gonzalez
skateboards back in the day.
JAKE BURTON CARPENTER: There
was a great story about--
I remember some dealer was
coming to our booth in Vegas,
and he's ordering.
I'll take 14 customs, this and
that, and he goes, "And give
me 50 of that one with the fish
on it." And I was like--
the dealers, they didn't
even who he was.
It was like that board
with the fish on it.
That was a very popular sig
board, and sig boards are
really happening at the time.
But just this rainbow
trout, great board.
I mean, it was super well made
and designed and very light,
lighter than anything else that
had been made at that
point in time.
And it was a great shape, and he
was riding incredibly well,
and it just reeked of
him and of Vermont.
It was just a winning graphic,
a standout for sure.
JEFF BRUSHIE: See, on
the original, that's
where my name was.
Yeah, somebody did it up for
me and sent it to me.
JEFF CURTES: That's the cool
thing about Burton.
All those little--
they really do a good job of
listening to the riders and
letting the riders take whatever
ideas they have and
scribbled on a napkin, and
literally, those ideas turn
into product development.
I'm sure Brushie, his first
shape that he made--
it's probably better for him to
talk about his first board,
but was entirely different than
anything that Burton had
put out before.
TODD KOHLMAN: Look at the shape,
very blunt nose and
tail compared to,
like, this here.
You get more of a twin, and
yeah, it's just breakthrough.
'93 was when we went to the
three hole, the 3D.
So you had, here, the five-hole,
you had limited
stance options.
And a whole new ball game, and
Jeff was a huge part of that
with rider development.
JEFF BRUSHIE: This is my second
snowboard I ever owned.
First one didn't have metal
edges, so this was kind of
like the first real
snowboard I had.
I think I won the junior slalom
on it at the US Open.
TODD KOHLMAN: This cruiser '86
here, Jeff later in '95 had a
pro model that was the same
graphic, but it was more of a
twin shape.
But it's awesome, definitely.
JEFF BRUSHIE: And an old, one of
my pro models and the board
that we copied, the original.
It was really probably
one of my favorites.
DAVE DRISCOLL: Jeff just kind of
always figured out what was
cool, and his graphics
were always like the
hot shit, for sure.
KEIR DILLON: My memories of
Brush was the first fish board
that he had, which was
just ridiculous.
And then he came out with the
graffiti art board, and then
the dice board.
JEFF BRUSHIE: My very last
board with Burton was the
craps table, and then
I kept the gambling
thing going with Ride.
I always liked to gamble.
I've always been into playing
poker and stuff, so I think
that has a lot to
do with it, too.
But I just think a lot of people
like that kind of vibe,
and I thought it would
work cool on boards.
Burton made this, the board,
into a real craps table with
sides, and I was like can
I take the craps table?
And I had this idea, got my
buddies bow ties, and it ended
up being a cool shot.
This is no Photoshop at all.
That's the actual dice.
That shot's just a different
shot of me somewhere in a half
pipe, but it looked so cool,
they made it into an ad.
KEIR DILLON: Knowing him, the
gambling is classic shots,
like the ads of the rat
pack around his board.
I'm a big gambler, and
he's a big gambler.
And he'll get us into some
celebrity tournaments and
stuff with Phil Ivy in it.
It's dope because he's like--
just to see him,
how he's moved on.
He's shooting photos, but
still the same Brush.
And you hear his voice,
and like, ah, it kind
of brings you back.
DAVE DRISCOLL: Craps board's
kind of like a foresight into
him being into gambling
for the last--
he's not a heavy gambler.
He's really smart with
this money, for sure.
But he definitely enjoys going
to the bright lights of Vegas
and playing some cards.
JEFF BRUSHIE: Rob Gracie,
he used to shoot me a
lot back in the day.
That's how we met.
And he met this guy who had
the contract with Harrah's
Casinos to be the official
photographers of the World
Series of Poker.
They took me on, and I got the
hang of it right off the bat,
and it was fun.
I love poker, so you're around
all the biggest poker guys
around and checking them
out, seeing what they
do, shooting them.
It was fun.
I did that for a couple years,
and this year I actually
didn't do it.
A little harder now with the
little kids running around,
but it was really cool.
Here comes a little
Mini-Brushie.
Come here, Mini-Brushie.
Come here.
ARABELLA: Hello.
JEFF BRUSHIE: Oh, you
got boots on?
ARABELLA: Yes.
JEFF BRUSHIE: Here, come over
here and sit with me.
Hey, Arabella, do you
want a snowboard?
ARABELLA: Uh-huh.
JEFF BRUSHIE: You do?
Woo.
INTERVIEWER: How old does she
have to be to snowboard?
JEFF BRUSHIE: I don't know.
She has a snowboard.
INTERVIEWER: Yeah?
JEFF BRUSHIE: She has a little
one, but she was scared to
stand on it in Tahoe.
But she finally standed on it
because I told her I'd give
her candy, and I wanted
to take a photo.
Right, remember that?
You stood on the snowboard,
and I gave you candy.
This year, you've got to put
the bindings on and go down
the hill and fall, and then
I give you candy.
ARABELLA: I fall down?
JEFF BRUSHIE: Yeah, that's
what happens.
You fall.
You got to fall to learn.
Right?
ARABELLA: [INAUDIBLE]
JEFF BRUSHIE: Oh,
you fell down.
ARABELLA: Yeah.
JEFF BRUSHIE: Kind of like you
were snowboarding, huh.
Woosh!
[SCREAMS AND LAUGHS]