KRISHNA: Hey guys, we're in
Sweden to learn about a quirky
geopolitical phenomenon
called micronations.
They're sort of small
self-declared countries that
aren't actually recognized by
any other official government.
Sweden has several of them, and
we're going to see two,
along with my co-pilot, Chris.
CHRIS: Hi, Krishna.
How are you doing?
KRISHNA: Good, Chris.
What time is it?
CHRIS: It's three in
the afternoon.
KRISHNA: It's 3:00 PM.
And as you can see,
the sun has set.
Because it's Sweden in
the winter time.
So we're going to have to wake
up bright and early, like 9
o'clock, when the sun comes
up, to get our start.
So Chris, tell me a little
bit more about yourself.
CHRIS: Basically, after years
of disillusionment in my
chosen profession as a
geotechnical engineer, just
hating on it, I jumped in
a boat and disappeared.
KRISHNA: Whoa.
CHRIS: I went to Canada, hung
out, snowboarded for a while.
And so where are
we off to, man?
KRISHNA: We're going to the
kingdom of Ladonia.
It's a micronation in
the south of Sweden.
CHRIS: Yeah.
KRISHNA: And it was started by
this artists, Lars Vilks.
And he was a pretty
controversial, provocative
artist, who made
these two giant
sculptures on a nature reserve.
Which you're not
allowed to do.
And so people were very
upset about it.
The government tried
to take it down.
So in an effort to keep that
sculpture up, he formed this
micronation called Ladonia.
CHRIS: So this guy might
be crazy or--
KRISHNA: It's really
hard to tell.
Crazy enough, at least, to start
a nation called Ladonia.
Hey, Lars.
LARS: Hello.
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
LARS: Nice seeing you.
Welcome here, welcome.
Just follow me.
CHRIS: So as I've noticed, we're
being followed by two
guys with earpieces in.
What's going on there?
LARS: That's been going
on for almost a year.
They are body guards.
And from the secret police.
One exhibition I had a drawing
of the prophet Muhammad.
And this one actually
was discussed and
published in a newspaper.
And Al Qaeda finally put
a price on my head,
$150,000 on my head.
KRISHNA AND CHRIS: Wow.
LARS: So I'm worth that now.
KRISHNA: So what's this
line over here?
LARS: Here's the border.
And we have Sweden here
and we have Ladonia
on the other side.
KRISHNA: So I'm currently
in Sweden,
and this is the border.
LARS: Yes.
KRISHNA: Chris, do you want
to go into Ladonia?
LARS: Yeah.
CHRIS: I'm in.
KRISHNA: You're in.
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
KRISHNA: So why did you paint
an actual border?
LARS: I think it's very good to
find out where one country
stops and another one begins.
KRISHNA: There we go.
Let's do it.
LARS: It's another a feeling
on the other side.
KRISHNA: Now we are guests
in your country.
LARS: Yeah.
The policy is normally that
we let people go in.
KRISHNA: But?
LARS: Not out.
KRISHNA: [LAUGHTER]
Did you hear that, Chris?
We're not coming out.
CHRIS: That's alright.
I brought a sandwich and
a banana, so I should
survive a few days.
LARS: Take the few
last steps here.
And then it kind of moves
into your sight here.
And here you have the
overview here.
KRISHNA: Oh, wow.
[MUSIC]
CHRIS: I feel like I'm in
Peter Pan or something.
KRISHNA: Yeah, there's like
a child-like tree house
experience.
[LAUGHTER]
KRISHNA: Who is this?
LARS: This is the Minister
of Art and Jump.
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
KRISHNA: Oh, I'm sorry.
We've been shaking hands.
CHRIS: I feel so, so rude now.
KRISHNA: Alright, here's
the president.
FREDERIK: It's not his head.
It's the whole president here
KRISHNA: That's the whole
president, a pair of loafers?
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
KRISHNA: Please tell me the
history of both these
structures, but also
of Ladonia.
LARS: This began in 1980,
when I was doing some
art projects here.
And I found a lot of
driftwood here.
So I started to build
with that.
KRISHNA: We're on a natural
reserve, is that right?
So you've built--
even though it was prohibited
to build
here, you built something.
LARS: Yeah.
KRISHNA: So are you sort
of at war with Sweden?
Do you feel like--
LARS: This was this other court
case that was removing
the pieces.
The first was the
criminal act.
But then we have the court,
where they're
moving away the pieces.
And I got away with that because
I sold the piece.
So if they want to remove it,
they have to go through him.
Swedish law doesn't work here.
It's illegal.
They can't to move it away.
So that was the basic
idea for Ladonia.
Here we have something which is
not controlled by Sweden.
So let's make a country here.
KRISHNA: Does Sweden say
that this is Ladonia?
Do they recognize Ladonia
as a country?
LARS: Of course not.
Because they think
it is a joke.
KRISHNA: They think
it's a joke.
LARS: Yeah.
KRISHNA: Is it a joke?
LARS: It's a fiction.
But the joke is also
a fiction.
KRISHNA: Explain that.
LARS: We use this as something
to hide behind.
While we're doing the
real thing, we say,
oh, we're just joking.
KRISHNA: So you're joking,
but you're not joking.
But you are joking.
LARS: We are using the joke to
actually make things the real.
CHRIS: Whoa.
KRISHNA: Lars turned Ladonia
into a micronation to protect
his art from the Swedish
authorities.
Now Chris and I are headed
north, to check out another
micronation called Jamtland.
It was established in the
1960s as a republic in a
protest against the rapid
urbanization of Sweden.
EWERT: Ah, there you are.
KRISHNA: Ewert?
EWERT: Yep.
KRISHNA: Krishna.
EWERT: Krishna.
CHRIS: Chris.
EWERT: Chris.
OK.
Let's go in and have a beer,
a president beer.
KRISHNA: President beer,
let's do it.
CHRIS: My favorite.
EWERT: [INAUDIBLE]
KRISHNA: So then what
is Jamtland?
EWERT: It started out in '63
as a reaction against the
exploitation, exploiting.
KRISHNA: What were they--
who?
The Swedish people?
The Swedish government?
EWERT: Yeah, the Swedish
government, and all the big
companies, you know, cutting
down the forests.
KRISHNA: So there's
no hierarchies?
KRISHNA: No, no.
No hierarchies.
I would have never accepted to
be president for a people who
thought they needed one.
KRISHNA: Right.
EWERT: Right.
EWERT: He's just an act
I'm putting on.
KRISHNA: Just an act?
EWERT: He's just an act, yeah.
KRISHNA: So what qualities about
yourself do you hope
people look up to?
EWERT: I've tried to do
as little as possible.
[LAUGHTER]
KRISHNA: But it seems like there
are two sides of it.
There's a serious conservation
aspect, but also playful, or
maybe a joking aspect.
Which one do you
think is more?
EWERT: The joking aspect.
KRISHNA: The joking aspect.
EWERT: Yeah.
To make fun of other
dictators.
You see, yeah.
KRISHNA: Yeah, let's see.
EWERT: That's why
I put these on.
You know the big dictators like
Qaddafi, and the other
guys, and Ceaucescu, they like
uniforms, a lot of medallions.
KRISHNA: Because being the head
of state, you're expected
to be a very strong man.
EWERT: Yeah, that's putting
on an act, alright.
[LAUGHTER]
KRISHNA: I also heard
that there's a
national anthem to Jamtland.
EWERT: Yes, there is.
KRISHNA: Can you
teach it to us?
EWERT: See what happens,
if anybody catches up.
CHRIS: We want people
catch up.
[CHEERING]
[CHANTING JAMTLAND]
CHRIS: Yeah.
KRISHNA: Way to go.
EWERT: We didn't rehearse
that, you know.
KRISHNA: Ewert told us about
the two sides of Jamtland.
And last night he showed us
Jamtland's less serious side.
Today we headed out to see the
more conservationist live off
the land side of the
micronation.
[CALM INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC]
KRISHNA: So Peter, we are at
your family's farmhouse in
Skyttmon, right in the
middle of Jamtland.
Correct?
PETER: Yes, that's correct.
KRISHNA: So what do
most people in
Jamtland do for a living?
PETER: I think they
live on tourists.
A lot of people come to Jamtland
and look for the
nature and everything.
And a lot of people work
with tourists.
KRISHNA: I see.
PETER: Hunting is very important
for Jamtland.
A lot of people in Jamtland
hunt, almost moose.
KRISHNA: Moose?
PETER: Yes.
KRISHNA: So being very isolated,
and being in the
countryside, and in the
woods, you have
to subsist for yourself.
PETER: I have I meat from the
moose in the forest, and
potatoes you can see outside.
I have fish in the pond
on the other side.
KRISHNA: And how many
dogs do you have?
PETER: I have five
[INAUDIBLE].
KRISHNA: [INAUDIBLE].
CHRIS: Am I correct that they
are the only dogs that will
actually not be scared
of a bear, and will
actually go for a bear?
PETER: Yes, the go for
the bear, not scared.
CHRIS: Much like Jamtland
is not scared of Sweden.
PETER: Exactly.
KRISHNA: Oh.
These dogs seem to like
it in the Mini, huh?
(BABY VOICE) look at their
sweet little faces.
There you go.
You cuties.
What are those, over
there, Peter?
PETER: It's the leg
from the moose.
I have saved it for the dogs.
[LAUGHTER]
CHRIS: They're actually quite
good, because you can use them
as a back scratcher as well.
PETER: And in Jamtland they
also have a competition.
They have a [INAUDIBLE]
who can--
KRISHNA: Throw them farther?
PETER: Throw them long way.
CHRIS: Do you think
we could try this?
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
PETER: Yes, you can try it.
KRISHNA: Alright.
See if I can beat that.
[LAUGHTER]
KRISHNA: I guess you win.
PETER: I think it's good
for first time.
KRISHNA: Peter was a really
sort of gentle fellow, it
seemed at first.
But after him showing us his
various hunting equipments and
telling us about how he goes
hunting 60 times a year, it
was pretty clear that he
was a pretty manly man.
[GUNSHOT]
KRISHNA: Whoa!
[LAUGHTER]
[GUNSHOT]
CHRIS: When skinny
boys become men.
[LAUGHTER]
KRISHNA: Peter looks so mild
mannered, but he is so badass.
CHRIS: Oh, it's ridiculous.
He's got dogs that
take down bears.
KRISHNA: He smokes
his own meat.
He's got a sauna that he built
from timber on his land.
He spends a day carving moose
that he kills himself.
CHRIS: Why would you import
anything when you've got this?
KRISHNA: Yeah, exactly.
Exactly.
So Chris, we have been
to a couple of
micronations here in Sweden.
What do you think?
CHRIS: I thought it was a
really cool experience.
We met some interesting
people, some
really quirky people.
And basically it reminded me of
what's going on the world
at the moment with the
Occupy protests.
And gives a real feeling of
sticking a middle finger up at
the man, and authority,
basically.
KRISHNA: I know.
I hear that.
But I'm freezing my ass off.
So, let's go warm up, alright?
CHRIS: Yeah, definitely.
KRISHNA: Our next and final
stop is Jamaica.
Mini wants us to rock a
convertible there, so they're
giving us the roadster.
And they've asked us to turn the
coupe into a micronation.
CHRIS: [PANTING]
OFFSCREEN VOICE: That
was the shot.
[LAUGHTER]
[CLOSING MUSIC]