As we crossed the Ibar River
into the mountains of Kosovo,
the weather darkened, and the
"Kosovo is Serbia" graffiti
we'd been seeing since Belgrade
became more frequent
and less nicely scrawled.
It's 1:30 in the morning.
We're going to Mitrovica,
a city in the North.
It's half Serb, half Albanian,
and there's a bunch of dudes
on a bridge who keep the
Albanians from crossing into
the area with the Serbs.
We're going to go hang out with
these guys, hopefully not
watch them beat up Albanians.
The problems in Kosovo date back
over 600 years of very,
very, very confusing history.
A long time ago, the entire
region belonged to the Serbs,
but they lost it to
the Turks in 1389.
And despite the fact that, since
then, the territory has
changed hands more times than
fucking Poland, many Serbs
still carry a grudge.
Tension simmered during the
Tito years before finally
erupting in 1989, when Serbs
rioted over discrimination by
the growing Albanian majority.
This is where Milosevic actually
became a Serbian
nationalist, and it was
basically the flash point for
all the wars that followed.
We just got to the
Kosovo border.
There's barbed wire here.
Are there men up there
with guns?
No?
It looks like a fortress.
OK.
So we are now in Kosovo.
During the '90s, the Kosovar
Albanians accused the Serbian
army of trying to ethnically
cleanse them from the area.
The Kosovo Liberation Army was
formed by the Albanians,
ostensibly to defend them from
Serbian genocide, though many
people noticed their tactics
were eerily similar their
enemy's, which is to
say atrocious.
Then Bill Clinton got a blow job
and decided to bomb Serbia
until they gave up Kosovo
to the Albanians, which
they kind of didn't.
Anyhoo, the tidiest symbol for
this ridiculous mess is a
bridge in the town
of Mitrovica.
The north side is Serbian, the
south side is Albanian, and
every night, a group of hotheads
stand on each side
and beat the shit out of anybody
who tries to cross.
Even though the war officially
ended in 1999, the bridge has
continued to be the
site of some
extremely nasty showdowns.
Most recently, in 2010, a
dispute over some local
elections turned into a rock
party between the Serbian
Bridgewatchers and their
Albanian counterparts.
That silver-haired guy chucking
a stone in the middle
of the bridge right there is the
Serbian Bridgewatchers' de
facto leader, Nebojsa Jovic.
He's been watching the bridge
for over a decade, and has
been involved in a lot of
particularly shady incidents
between the Serbs
and Albanians.
NEBOJSA JOVIC:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
THOMAS MORTON: Nebojsa's basic
point is that if his
Bridgewatchers didn't stand
guard every night, there'd be
no one to protect the
Serbs from being
driven out of Mitrovica.
NEBOJSA JOVIC:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
THOMAS MORTON: While Nebojsa
claims that his men have
called off their vigil, we
couldn't help but notice a lot
of tough-looking motorists
making extremely aggressive
U-turns right in front of the
bridge all night long.
We just got done having a little
chat with our buddy,
with the Bridgewatchers.
I guess we're just going to
hang out here and see what
happens, see if people just
circle all night or if they
get out of their cars
or whatever.
I'm kind of hoping it's
boring, because the
alternative sounds terrifying.
MALE SPEAKER: Three guys on my
left, two guys sitting on the
benches behind me, so there
is so much activity.
If you'd like to go to the
bridge, you can freely do it.
THOMAS MORTON: Oh, we can?
MALE SPEAKER:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
THOMAS MORTON: That's
a little foreboding.
Yeah.
Well, let's go to the
bridge, then.
Crossing the bridge in Mitrovica
was actually sort of
no big deal.
It was just like crossing any
bridge that has no lights and
a permanent detachment
of UN soldiers
stationed in the middle.
Still, there's something eerie
about being the only people
besides cops on a bridge
where hundreds of other
folks have bled out.
It's kind of like sneaking into
Antietam in the middle of
the night, only if the Civil
War had happened,
like, five years ago.
There's another person doing
a U-turn very fast.
MALE SPEAKER: They're coming to
the bridge, making U-turn,
going back.
There, just the same as here.
THOMAS MORTON: There's
no reason for
them to make a U-turn.
Despite the fact that nothing
kicked off while we were
there, it was definitely
spooky on the bridge.
We also had no idea whether or
not the Albanian side would be
as hectic as Nebojsa
had warned us.
Hey, it's Thomas.
I'm at the [INAUDIBLE]
Cafe, which is a very nice,
European-style place.
A couple years ago, though, an
Albanian boy walked across the
bridge and threw
a bomb in here.
And that wasn't the first bomb
that's gone off in here.
This is the bridge.
You see a heavy police
presence there,
but it's that's it.
That tiny little strip is what
divides Albanian Kosovo from
Serbian Kosovo.
And so one thing that's weird
is we noticed a lot of cars
pull over right before they
cross the bridge.
And the drivers hop out and pop
off their license plates.
And the deal is, if you're
driving a car in the wrong
neighborhood with the wrong
plates, you're basically
asking to get killed.
And you'll see a number of cars
just driving around with
no plates at all, like
it's no big thing.
I mean, we've been getting,
I feel like,
one side of the story.
So we're going to go
over there and--
basically into Albanian Kosovo
and see what it's like.
On the Albanian side of the
bridge, we met a group of kids
who didn't quite live up to the
menacing hoard Nebojsa had
led us to expect.
THOMAS MORTON: This
is the spot.
The old main drag.
Have you ever had any trouble
with the Bridgewatchers?
We keep hearing about them.
THOMAS MORTON: I'm sorry.
THOMAS MORTON: Right, they just
look like normal folks.
THOMAS MORTON: I didn't know
you'd grown up in the North.
THOMAS MORTON: A Serb friend?
And you'll go with him?
THOMAS MORTON: Right.
THOMAS MORTON: It's
like lawless.
Right.
THOMAS MORTON: Snitches
get stitches.
THOMAS MORTON: No, we walked
right through.
I was waiting for a frisk
and the dogs and stuff.
THOMAS MORTON: Our day on the
Albanian side made it totally
clear what the real
problem is here.
It isn't violence or genocide.
It's demographics.
The Serbian side is practically
empty, and what
people you do see all seem to
be pretty fucking old or
bussed-in skinheads.
Then you cross the bridge,
and it's all kids--
not scary kids, either, just
regular kids hanging out and
otherwise minding their own,
but a lot of them.
And that's what the
real threat is.
Albanian Kosovo is
growing, while
Serbian Kosovo is shrinking.
And all the beatings
in the world ain't
going to change that.