CARL AZUZ, CNN ANCHOR: Hi, I`m Carl Azuz.
You know, we think Fridays are awesome, but
for the 4229 people aboard the Carnival "Triumph"
cruise ship, this Friday probably seems especially
awesome. Because hopefully by now they are
all off that ship. On Sunday, the ship lost
power in the Gulf of Mexico after a fire in
the engine room. Tugboats eventually came
out to help pull the "Triumph" in the port
in Mobile, Alabama, but that has been very,
very slow. And when the passengers finally
get off the ship, their nightmare may not
be over. One doctor said, conditions on board
after the fire made the ship a floating petri
dish, if that sounds kind of gross, that`s
his point. No power means the toilets stop
working. Raw sewage can be a major health
risk, and we`ve heard reports about it slushing
across the floors and running down the walls.
No power means food starts rotting, spoiled
food can lead to E. coli or Salmonella. There
haven`t been any reports of any kind of outbreak
on the ship. But the doctor says, a full-
blown infection might not show up for a couple
of weeks. So, would you consider cruising
again after going through something like this?
On our Facebook page, Mason said, "Sure. That
was just one very unlucky cruise." Joseph
and Unique (ph) both said "No way." Reese
(ph) would consider taking another cruise,
but not for a very long time, and Kora`s (ph)
opinion, if it happens again, it would definitely
be something to tell your grandkids.
Remember, a week or so ago, when we talked
about the asteroid that would fly by the Earth,
today is the day. Scientists are sure it won`t
hit anything down here. But what about up
there?
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
CHAD MYERS, AMS METEOROLOGIST: This is 17,000
miles away. Now, if you are watching a dish
or Direct TV, your satellite is 22,000 miles
away. So, yes, there are some Earth satellites,
here, around the ring. The Moon is far away.
The Moon is ten times farther away than what
this thing is going to fly through our geosynchronous
Earth orbit. So, is there a chance of it hitting
something? Yes.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: A chance? Sure. But it`s not too likely.
One analyst said, other objects pass through
the same area every day. They don`t cause
any problems. This asteroid is a lot bigger
than those, but that also means, it`s easier
to keep track of. So, scientists have a better
idea of what it will or more likely will not
hit.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
LEON PANETTA, U.S. DEFENSE SECRETARY: The
work that they do, contribution that they
make does contribute to the success of combat
operations, particularly when they remove
the enemy from the field of battle.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: Defense Secretary Panetta was talking
about members of the military who are not
on the battlefield themselves. People who
operate drones, unmanned aircraft, or who
are involved in the military cyber warfare
efforts. Secretary Panetta announced a new
medal to honor those people -- the Distinguished
Warfare Medal -- he said it will be awarded
for extraordinary actions that directly impact
combat operations, but don`t actually involve
the physical risks of combat.
You probably played with some remote control
cars or planes at some point -- Secretary
Panetta says this kind of technology is changing
the way wars are fought. As drones get more
attention, they can also cause some controversy.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
NIC ROBERTSON, CNN CORRESPONDENT: Drones are
remotely controlled aircraft. They are much
more maneuverable than conventional aircraft,
much lighter, much cheaper to manufacturer,
and the person, the pilot manning them can
be many thousands of miles away on the ground.
Drones are used in two capacities: to support
troops on the ground to make sure that there
are no enemy close to them, to make sure that
no IEDs, mines, bombs have been laid in the
road ahead of them, and they are also used
in a surveillance capacity to monitor people
who might be targets, and then at the end
of that surveillance, then the trigger can
be pulled, and the missile can be fired from
that aircraft at that target.
Drones are controversial because they can
kill from a great distance without certainty
precisely who the person is on the ground
or the possibility of collateral damage that
could be women, children in the vicinity.
That`s the concern. Also, the person on the
ground, who is being killed, has no right
to defend himself. If the information is faulty,
then this can be judged by some people to
be a wrongful death.
Targets can take evasive measures, by staying
inside buildings. Drones that assigned to
circle those buildings for days, even weeks
at a time, to monitor movements who comes,
who goes. They can recognize whether it`s
a man or a woman entering that house. So targets
have been known to not leave their location
for fear of giving themselves away. Osama
bin Laden, in his compound in Abbotabad, Pakistan,
had tall trees planted, so that it was difficult
for drones take a direct and positive recognition
of him.
There is an incredible array of uses for drones
now. They can be used in agriculture to look
at crops, they can be used by architects to
look at buildings. They can be used by law
enforcement. They can be used by amateurs
as well, it`s just to take pretty pictures
from high up. There is really, at the moment,
a hugely expanded role for drones in the civilian
area.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: Today`s "Shoutout" goes
out to Mrs. Weddington`s, Mrs. Wolzen`s and
Ms. Anderson`s social studies classes at Schoo
Middle School in Lincoln, Nebraska. Which
U.S. president`s face is not featured on Mt.
Rushmore? Is it George Washington, John Adams,
Thomas Jefferson or Abraham Lincoln? You`ve
got three seconds, go!
Mt. Rushmore features the faces of Washington,
Jefferson, Lincoln and Teddy Roosevelt. But
not John Adams. That`s your answer and that`s
your "Shoutout".
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: Maybe you owned government class, maybe
you can name all the U.S presidents. But do
you know who is honored by President`s Day?
You could have asked Calvin Coolidge, but
he might have been silent on the matter. Teddy
Roosevelt might have walked softly around
the subject, despite being a rough writer.
Most Americans believe President`s Day is
about every president we`ve had. But that`s
kind of wring, at least as far as its origin
goes. President`s Day was originally Washington`s
birthday, just Washington`s. On February 22nd.
It became a federal holiday in 1885, and as
far as the U.S government`s concerned, it`s
still Washington`s birthday, not President`s
Day. In 1968, Congress voted to switch it
to the third Monday in February, giving government
employees a three day weekend. But even though
Washington`s birthday and Lincoln`s birthday
were only days apart, Congress refused to
combine them n the President`s Day, though
that`s what many Americans do. So, if you
work for the government, you`ll get a day
off for Washington`s birthday. If you don`t,
you may get a day off for President`s Day.
Those, after all, are the precedents.
Well, how do you stand out in the crowd? It`s
a question some of you might be wondering,
as you start applying to college. Last weekend,
there was a major college fair, right next
door to the CNN Center. I spoke with some
college admission officers there about what
they look for in prospective students, and
about what they think, you should do, when
you picking out a school.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
QUENTIN JOHNSON, UNIVERSITY OF TAMPA: Someone
who really stands out, someone who`s really
strong with their extracurricular activities
as well as someone that has done well academically.
JESSICA GRANT, PRESBYTERIAN COLLEGE: Probably
maybe think of the top three things that they
are looking for. I think, major does a big
part to consider. But also, what the school
offers and the things that this school focuses
on.
CLINTON HOBBS, YOUNG HARRIS COLLEGE: We tend
to find the students that are really emerged
in the high school experience, involved in
three to four or five extracurricular or co-curricular
activities, actively involved in civic opportunities,
maybe involved in their church. Tend to really
impress us more. A more well rounded student,
a more holistically developed individual is
going to be better prepared for today`s world,
career, work, life.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: Jeopardy just wrapped up its annual
team tournament. And when it came to final
jeopardy, Leonard Cooper didn`t know the answer,
but he also knew it didn`t matter.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
ALEX TREBEK, HOST, JEOPARDY: Now we go to
Leonard Cooper. He is looking pretty happy.
Why? Did he come up with Ike, Dwight David
Eisenhower?
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: No, I didn`t.
TREBEK: You didn`t.
(LAUGHTER)
TREBEK: Same guy, some guy (inaudible), but
I just won $75,000.
(APPLAUSE)
AZUZ: It sounds like the host appreciates
the smart Alecs, but I guess, you can afford
to have some fun, when your victory isn`t
in jeopardy. All right. That`s going to wrap
things up for today. Teachers, we are looking
for your feedback on today`s show. Asteroids,
cruise, college -- finally, to share your
thought on our home page, there will be no
show on Monday for President`s Day. We hope
you enjoy the long weekend, and we`ll forward
to seeing you again on Tuesday. Bye there.