come forward and say that because
oftentimes people will criticize you for
that they'll say all you're just getting
all these great uh... opportunities in
life because you're beautiful but
there's not much more to it uh... and
and she's completely honest about that
in fact let's watch a little snippet up
here to talk
i want to genetic lottery
and i and the recipient of a legacy
frick the past few centuries we have
defined beauty west tall slender figures
and femininity
and white skin and this is a legacy that
was built for me and it's a legacy that
i've been cashing out on
so she makes a ruling simply it you know
there are certain things that we get the
biologically respond to in terms of
purity so symmetry is one of them health
uh... and honestly being young right
slender has not missile had been part of
that equation abut over the last however
many years in modern times it has
become a part of the equation because of
societal expectations of saturn
shes like and genetically i happen to be
skinny
so i went a lottery even device in the
one
and i happen to be tall and paul was in
the silly
part of our d_n_a_ that were attracted
to twelve women but for whatever reason
in the modeling world
and it's mainly because they want to
close to hang offer them in you know
at that's
uh... she winds up already has made a
point com
race that i thought was really
interesting yes
she says look you know you have a tire
banks in the army and and all the stuff
in
although you know the white did to
succeed in modeling suspect them of the
problems
only four percent of them are minority
and not letting you know that that's
amazing unalloyed that's actually based
on to say that was done by then why u
p_h_d_
uh... this as didn't look at six hundred
seventy seven models that were hired
in the year two thousand seven and only
four percent of them outward not not
white
stunningly six percent white now
while cell obviously this astonishing
within the modeling community but also
really want to
giver props for it you know
in many something that's not be easy to
admit it's hard to do that and by the
way she's really intelligent she
graduated from columbia uh... any
graduates from colombia and any division
is really smart
uh... but if you listen to her whole
tent auctions extreme really articulate
very intelligent popping your you could
tell she's hard working but nobody
notices any of that because the first
thing that they notice
is the way that she looks and she says
it's unfair because you know she gets
her ted talk begets millions of hits but
you know colin powell said talked into
you as well and she's like why is it the
people are more interested to hear what
amato has to say as opposed to what
someone like colin powell has to say and
i think that that's very symbolic of
what our society is into oftentimes we
get heat for covering so-called
celebrity stories when we come in
celebrity stories because you guys and
loving you guys love to click on it you
leg as left a comment on it no decided
one day we can we try to put
are stamp on it meaning that we don't
cover like every other cigarette if
there was a slight reserves like it
did you see cardiac she's misled it
whereas in whatever we do correction we
try to have a point
rate we try to have
the reason why we're trying to make a
point about society culture et cetera
maybe we don't always succeed but let's
work going for but but you can
we fall prey to the correct article it
was really interesting
and she mentioned colin powell specific
because that is to give a speech the
same time and she got four times the
number of users that are now there are
other factors you see colin powell often
is a but you know what happened
by some of those
we got here on the show
when i was a great worry if you don't
ship
because you know and i think he's right
now is that they had so much is that i
think that
instinct was
it'll be an interesting guess this is
really smart and has a really
interesting point plus she's super hot
keep it real ight now right
yes please
into any such as the hotness to it said
he's
the category we wouldn't expect
you know ice expect of a
political conversation or interesting
cultural conversation from
someone from the nation or alternet or
political figure but since it's a model
since there for
right right yes it is leasing a quandary
two sec
do i accept all these offers
when it's kind of unfair that they're
asking me why they should be asking more
qualified people i don't think that
without a doubt she should accept the
offers and one huge misconception is
that
people were attracted get these great
opportunities right
but oftentimes when it's a real
substantive opportunity let's say like
co hosting a show for instance rain okay
you can get hired based on your lucks
but your intellect is what heating going
that's what keeps you on michelle you
can't be a moron in costa show emulate
cut too much better okay get man but you
know what i mean like oftentimes people
get those accusations if yours if you're
a cable to handle whatever the job that
is take it and your abilities will help
you pursue whatever that is uh... some
no not and i've always thought that have
been
in august kind of obvious that people
hired me for my looks
and so you know what i'm i think i ever
did over these years together doctor so