[CAR HORN].
KEVIN JONES: That's
one sick ass line.
-[INAUDIBLE].
KEVIN JONES: [INAUDIBLE].
Get out of here, [INAUDIBLE]
on the line.
MATHIEU CREPEL: I think Kevin
took freestyle snowboarding to
another level.
Like the thing that I remember
most about Kevin was that
first frontside 1080 in
the back country.
Nobody at that time thought
it was possible, and
then, boom, did it.
And it was amazing.
KEVIN JONES: And of course,
whenever you do something, you
don't know if you do
it good or not.
Because back in those days, you
had to wait two weeks for
film to be actually
transferred.
TIM MANNING: All of us filmers
would shoot as much
footage as we could.
We get the film processed.
The footage would come
back in a VHS tape.
And everybody would show up
in Mike's family room.
And you're sitting there biting
your teeth hoping that
that one shot you had in mind
came out exactly the way you
thought it would.
And then Mike or David would be
like, ah, kind of a bobble
in the beginning, like you
kind blew the shot.
MIKE HATCHETT: Shooting
film is a
totally different monster.
When you shoot film, you got
to make it count, just like
press the button and look at
your shot, and go, oh, my
framing's off.
I wish I did that.
Delete.
So the film thing
is definitely--
you learn to be more
conservative and press the
button when you know you
got your crap together.
KEVIN JONES: I mean seriously
I couldn't
sleep, I couldn't eat.
I was like, dude, if I blow
my chance with these guys,
because back then, that was
it, if I fucking blow my
chance with these dudes, I'm
done, because it's money.
MIKE HATCHETT: And this is
what we used to shoot.
It was 100-foot daylight
loads, three minutes of
footage, $1 a foot, so $100
every time you shoot this.
So four rolls, one
day of shooting.
Just the shooting costs
$400 for the one day.
So we used to shoot
on 16 millimeter.
And this is all--
what was it?
Did we go to 2005?
When did we stop
shooting film?
I think it was 2005.
So this is basically 1989.
And then, two years, I
worked for Fall Line.
And then, once we did "TB2" with
Mack Dawg, all the way to
2005, and these are stacked
double, so they're always like
twice as many in here as
you can see right now.
So yeah, it's kind of funny if
you think about the past.
When you stop to watch a
trailer, we make a movie.
And we make like the
TV for a trailer.
We put on VHS.
And then, they sent
out to the shops.
And the only way to see the
trailer is if you were in a
shop, because there
was no internet.
And now, to watch a trailer, you
just make one click, and
you just watch it.
A lot of people who are 15
years old right now are
watching the movies don't
realize you couldn't just
click and watch something.
You certainly couldn't just
click to a BitTorrent, steal
it for free.
You had to buy it or put two
VHS machines together
obviously and copy
a tape to tape.
A lot has changed,
that's for sure.
DAVE HATCHETT: There's something
cool about just
making a DVD, and something you
can hold in your hands,
and the anticipation of waiting
for that movie to come
out, and see what all the
writers did and if they can
actually one up their segments
from last year.
And I think that really
helps drive the
progression of the sport.
As much as I like the YouTube
and all the free content out
there, I really think it's
important to kind of have at
least one or two or three good
movies out there a year that
the kids can buy and watch
that's not just a YouTube
phenomenon.
JUSSI OKSANEN: I think when I
look back my snowboard career,
I think I was very lucky to get
in with those guys in the
first place, because
they're super
professional and organized.
We wake up pretty much four
in the morning every day.
AARON SEDWAY: You know, back in
the day, it was always like
pulling teeth to get the riders
to get up that early.
And I think it's still
is these days.
You know, they probably lose
some riders too that don't
want to always get up that
early to get out there.
But it's kind of what
you got to do.
JIM RIPPEY: If you want to be
one of those guys, one of
those snowboarders in those
movies, it really all comes
down to hard work.
So you're up before it's even
light, and you're getting
together and heading out to
where you've got to go.
And usually, you got to hike
through a lot of powder and
get to your obstacle, fix your
takeoff, get ready to do it.
And then, when the light comes
out, and it's good enough, be
ready to go.
MIKE HATCHETT: If you want to
get some footage in the can,
the sun comes up, and you only
have from sun rise until about
11:30 or noon to shoot, and
everything goes in the shade.
So yeah, it's all about the
lighting, and caring about the
lighting, and that's why
we get up so early.
JUSSI OKSANEN: A load of riders
came by Mike's house,
like they try to film for
a standard movie.
And then, they will get burnt
out like in two weeks.
They come and stay
like a week, and
they're like fuck this.
This sucks.
I don't want to wake up at
four in the morning.
TOM BURT: The nice thing about
Standard, they had the
willingness to put in the time
and energy to go out
there and be there.
I'd say it's one of those things
that has always set
them apart.
Now, a lot of people have
pretty much copied what
they've done.
DAVE HATCHETT: To me, the best
snowboarder film companies
will always be the ones
that show everything.
I want to grab people segments,
but I also want to
see people talking.
I want to see the guys break it
down, and just really get
to the feeling of what it's like
to ride a snowboard and
the thing that we all embrace
and love about snowboarding,
but really shows the cutting
edge of what's going on.
And I think, ultimately, the
best snowboard movie has yet
to be made.
LONNIE KAUK: I think that's
where all this
film stuff's heading.
It's not just like, oh, banger,
banger, banger,
banger, banger, stop.
We know nothing about
this person.
Who is this guy?
What does he feel?
Does he go to the store?
Does he like wash his clothes?
Does he do the things
that everybody does?
Of course, so show it.
Because really, I think with a
video part, it's all about
music and be able to capture
that person.
MATHIEU CREPEL: I've always
loved snowboarding as like a
global thing and not on the rail
or not on the contest are
not only filming or
back country.
I love to do everything.
And I think this is the heart
of Standard films.
It's just like grab your board
and try to show like what
snowboarding means to me.
And if it's like a rail,
or park day, or
[INAUDIBLE], just do it.
And that's what I love in
snowboarding because you get
your stick.
We got mountains.
Go for it.
Ride.
MIKE HATCHETT: Rewind
in 20 years.
I didn't think I'd be sitting
here now making a 20th video.
For sure, the first couple
years, I definitely didn't
think we'd be getting to 20.
When we got to 15, I was
thinking there's a good chance
we make it to 20.
Or pretty much, when we got
to 15, I knew I had
to make it to 20.
But yeah, I mean, I remember the
first couple of years just
being nervous we could
even make a movie.
Like are we going to have
enough footage?
It's not going to happen.
We're not going to
get enough--
I would be so panicked.
I'd stay up at night.
And then, after like six
or seven movies--
I think it was actually after 10
movies, I finally realized,
like you know what, you shoot
all year, you make a movie.
It might not be as good as the
one the year before or it
might be better.
You're not always going to hit
a home run, or maybe you're
never going to hit a home run as
far some people could say.
If you shoot all year,
you'll make a movie.
KEVIN JONES: If you were to
told me three years ago,
you're going to be on TV, I
would have laughed at you.
The first film I filmed was
"TB5." 15 years later, I'm
still in a movie.
And to be a part of this is
seriously a dream come true.
DAVE DOWNING: Well, I expect
"TB20" to be a diverse,
progressive snowboarding movie
with some Alaska stuff in it,
big mountain stuff, and some
handrail stuff and jumps and
everything.
So I know Mike has always wanted
it to be like that.
And I hope that's
what "TB20" is.
I'm sure it will be.
JEREMY JONES: Yeah, I'm
definitely not surprised that
Standard's still in the game
making snowboarding movies.
They have so much passion, so
much knowledge, and still
really love to get out
there and tread.
Yeah, the question is will
be there a "TB30"?
[LAUGHS]
[MUSIC PLAYING]