STEVE SPANGLER: This
is just- It's fine.
This is- So I bet you think this
is the part of this show,
where I'm going to say, don't
try these experiments at home.
And you're right.
Except there is one experiment
we want you to try.
Just look for the graphic
that's right here
that says, try it.
That's your signal that
you can try that
experiment at home.
Everything else, off limits.
Look, I've already given you
homework, and the show hasn't
even started.
I'm Steve Spangler, and I'm all
about making science fun.
For the last 20 years I've been
teaching ways to turn
ordinary science experiments
into unforgettable learning
experiences.
I have an amazing team, who will
do whatever it takes to
affect the way people
think about science.
And to do that I live by one
model- make it big, do it
right, give it class.
You know, I think it's true, you
never actually forget the
great teachers that you
had in your life.
And when I go back and think
about my high school, Heritage
High School and the Littleton
Public Schools,
one guy sticks out.
His name is Doug Hodous.
And he was my very first
chemistry teacher.
This is the guy that made things
blow up, and the funny
smells, and so forth.
And so I thought today we'd go
back to Heritage High School,
and see if we can take him back
to his old class, and
have a little lesson
in chemistry.
DOUG HODOUS: Hey, Steve.
How are you?
You're looking good.
STEVE SPANGLER: So I walk in
and you're no longer here,
because they kicked you
out 20 years ago.
How long have you
been retired?
DOUG HODOUS: It's been
a long, long time.
1996.
'97.
STEVE SPANGLER: Look at this.
My chemistry teacher,
he is here.
He's the guy that they made
sure-- well there's a lot of
stories about sneaking out, and
doing demos, and so forth.
But I was going to ask you.
Let's go back into
at the class.
Let's see if we can rummage
around a little bit.
And I'd love to have you do--
I want disappearing ink.
DOUG HODOUS: Oh.
Excellent.
STEVE SPANGLER: That's
what I want.
I want your formula for
disappearing ink.
DOUG HODOUS: Oh, that would
be a lot of fun.
Thanks for inviting me.
STEVE SPANGLER: Absolutely.
Welcome back to your
old classroom.
Some things don't
change, do they?
DOUG HODOUS: Well--
What do they call this, Steve?
I used to a chalkboard.
STEVE SPANGLER: It's
a dry erase board.
And when you get older
you forget--
there used to be chalk.
There used to be some huge demos
that we would do here.
And you would ask me to come up
with some of the demos that
you would do.
And so I got to be your
lab assistant.
It's a pretty smart decision on
your part to make me your
lab assistant, right?
DOUG HODOUS: Well, if--
the fact we know, when you were
in my AP chemistry class
as a junior.
And then I thought, because you
had passed and done well
on the exam, I thought maybe
you would be an appropriate
person for you and Todd, who
later on became a doctor, to
be my lab assistants.
Well, that was a mistake.
STEVE SPANGLER: Yeah, it was.
OK.
So.
But there were some pretty
good explosions.
DOUG HODOUS: Oh, yeah.
STEVE SPANGLER: There was
something very cool that you
did with disappearing ink.
And so what I'd like to do
is to go back in the lab.
DOUG HODOUS: Oh yeah.
STEVE SPANGLER: And show me
just your formula for
disappearing ink.
DOUG HODOUS: I'd love to.
STEVE SPANGLER: All into this.
DOUG HODOUS: It'd be great.
Yeah, sure
STEVE SPANGLER: Let's
go look at that.
Look at this, you even
dressed the part.
I love this.
DOUG HODOUS: Yes, I your always
want to look like a
professional.
STEVE SPANGLER: And
I love this, too.
Oh wait, you've got this.
Look, and he's got his little
nerd protector right here.
I love that.
DOUG HODOUS: It won't
go in there.
STEVE SPANGLER: It doesn't
even fit there.
DOUG HODOUS: Yeah, that's why
I put it in the other po--
STEVE SPANGLER: Some things
never change.
I'm serious.
DOUG HODOUS: Yeah,
that's right.
STEVE SPANGLER: I'll set
this off to the side--
DOUG HODOUS: I didn't
know I had--
STEVE SPANGLER: --just in
case you don't need it.
DOUG HODOUS: I probably
won't need it.
STEVE SPANGLER: Well, I want
you to show me how to make
disappearing ink, but it looks
like you have something else
set up instead.
DOUG HODOUS: Oh, yeah.
I wanted to sort of give you
an example of how this
particular acid-based reaction
is going to work.
Now, if you look right here, I
just have a beaker of water.
I'm going to put a little bit
of the sodium hydroxide.
Now, this is just a one molar
solution, so we're going to
just add a little bit in here.
STEVE SPANGLER: OK.
DOUG HODOUS: OK?
And it turns out, that
will be colorless.
STEVE SPANGLER: OK.
DOUG HODOUS: Because
that's a base and
water, and it's colorless.
STEVE SPANGLER: OK.
DOUG HODOUS: Now, what we're
going to add here is just a
very few drops of this.
And show everybody
what that is.
STEVE SPANGLER: It's called
phenolphthalein.
So--
DOUG HODOUS: It's
an indicator.
STEVE SPANGLER: It actually
starts, you said, as a powder.
So we have the powder here.
And so you said a couple
of drops of
phenolphthalein in there.
DOUG HODOUS: Right.
STEVE SPANGLER: All right.
DOUG HODOUS: OK.
And when I held it up before,
you actually could not see the
liquid, but it is in there.
So when I add this over
here, it turns
a pink color because--
STEVE SPANGLER: So,
the solution has
to be basic, right?
DOUG HODOUS: This is now a
basic solution, because
there's sodium hydroxide
in this.
Now what we're going
to add to the other
beaker is a little acid.
And of course, we know that acid
and bases will neutralize
each other.
But we want to put a little
excess acid in there.
STEVE SPANGLER: Got it.
So it makes a little
hydrochloric acid.
So we get one molar
DOUG HODOUS: Right, one molar.
And when I pour this into here,
of course it's going to
go back to colorless again.
This is magic.
STEVE SPANGLER: All
right, so again.
What does this have to do
with disappearing ink?
DOUG HODOUS: Well, it's the
same kind of reaction.
It's going to be an acid-base
reaction.
And we're going to
use an indicator.
But this time we'll--
STEVE SPANGLER: But I
don't want pink ink.
I really would like to
have that deep dark--
DOUG HODOUS: Well,
every indicator
has different colors.
This is our indicator for
disappearing ink.
You can see the name
right there.
Thymolphthalein.
STEVE SPANGLER: So
thymolphthalein, just like
phenolphthalein, triggers about
the same pH, right in
about the same range?
DOUG HODOUS: Right
about neutral.
STEVE SPANGLER: OK.
So that's what we're going
to use to make the
disappearing ink.
DOUG HODOUS: That's exactly
what we're going to use to
make the disappearing ink.
DOUG HODOUS: Do you remember
the formula?
DOUG HODOUS: Ah, no.
Let's do it.
STEVE SPANGLER: What
you mean no?
You don't remember
the formula?
DOUG HODOUS: I don't remember
this formula.
STEVE SPANGLER: Do you remember
the formula to make
disappearing--
DOUG HODOUS: Yes, I remember.
STEVE SPANGLER: This truly is--
do you know what's the
greatest thing about
getting old?
It's that you have new friends
every day that
you didn't even know--
DOUG HODOUS: Do you remember
the formula?
No.
C-H-A--
STEVE SPANGLER: No, I want to
know the formula to make the
disappearing ink.
I just want a liter of
the disappearing ink.
DOUG HODOUS: Yes, right.
STEVE SPANGLER: This is
pretty much how the
lectures went too.
We went for about 45 minutes
on stuff that we
really didn't want..
And, all of a sudden, bam we've
got about three minutes
[INTERPOSING VOICES].
DOUG HODOUS: I think what we
should do, opposed to what you
normally did.
Let's clean out these
beakers, so we
start with clean beakers.
STEVE SPANGLER: OK,
Martha, here.
Why don't you just set these
off to the side.
Let's use this, OK?
Ah, that's a new bea--
Oh, we're going to do
it on big time.
STEVE SPANGLER: Let's do it.
DOUG HODOUS: OK.
Now, what we're going to do is
just take about two grams of
this would be appropriate.
And I don't think you really
have to measure this exact.
So if you just put a little bit
at the end of that little
scooper there.
Have you got some at the
end of that scooper?
STEVE SPANGLER: Yeah,
absolutely.
DOUG HODOUS: Oh, perfect.
Yeah.
That's about right.
A little bit at the end
of the tip of the
spatula right there.
STEVE SPANGLER: OK.
DOUG HODOUS: All right.
Now, what we need to do is
add a little ethanol.
STEVE SPANGLER: OK.
DOUG HODOUS: And so the ethanol
will help it dissolve.
We'll get this milky
white color.
And we'll swirl it around trying
to get it to dissolve
as much as possible.
STEVE SPANGLER: And then,
you dilute the rest
of that with what?
DOUG HODOUS: Ah, We'll dilute it
with water, and then we're
going to add a little bit
of sodium hydroxide.
STEVE SPANGLER: Got it.
DOUG HODOUS: We're going
to make it basic.
And the basic color is
going to be blue.
STEVE SPANGLER: All right, so
let's add some of the water.
DOUG HODOUS: OK,
let's do that.
STEVE SPANGLER: I see what you
say, I mean about it being
that milky white.
But nobody's going to see it,
because it's finally going to
turn blue, right?
DOUG HODOUS: Right.
STEVE SPANGLER: OK.
DOUG HODOUS: OK, now we're just
going to add a little bit
of sodium hydroxide.
That's going to turn it basic.
STEVE SPANGLER: You don't
want too much.
DOUG HODOUS: No, no, no.
This is just a one molar
solution, dilute solution of
sodium hydroxide.
Now it's basic.
STEVE SPANGLER: If I remember
it correctly, we've got to
play with this a little bit,
because when we squirt it out
onto the shirt, you've got to
see what amount disappears.
DOUG HODOUS: Absolutely.
You sort of do a trial.
And you squirt it out, you
see how long it lasts.
You want the blue to last, well,
maybe 10-20 seconds.
STEVE SPANGLER: OK.
So we don't need this
big solution.
I'll pour a small amount into
this beaker, and we're set.
DOUG HODOUS: Go ahead, let's
put some of this in.
All right, so now
this is here.
STEVE SPANGLER: Ah,
it looks great.
DOUG HODOUS: That's
a perfect color.
STEVE SPANGLER: OK.
DOUG HODOUS: OK, let's
just look at it, and
see how long it lasts.
STEVE SPANGLER: So it's
changing back.
We didn't put an acid on it,
so why is it changing back?
DOUG HODOUS: Well, that's
because there's carbon dioxide
in the air.
And carbon dioxide and water,
and there's a lot of water
here, is slightly acidic.
In fact, if you'll just
blow on that.
STEVE SPANGLER: OK.
DOUG HODOUS: OK.
STEVE SPANGLER: It will actually
be a lot easier if
you just spilled hydrochloric
acid on somebody and it would
change back really fast,
but I guess that's
not what you want.
DOUG HODOUS: But that's going
to ruin the shirt, isn't it?
STEVE SPANGLER: But this, now on
somebody would look really
good, right?
DOUG HODOUS: No.
That would not look very good.
STEVE SPANGLER: No,
not like this.
But this.
It's not disappearing
too fast.
So for a joke.
DOUG HODOUS: Oh, I'd say that's
just perfect, because
then they get a little concerned
about it, like is
this really going to go away.
STEVE SPANGLER: So,
like, look, see?
See your little lab
coat is working.
How awesome is that?
DOUG HODOUS: Well
try over here.
STEVE SPANGLER: There you go.
Isn't that nice?
DOUG HODOUS: Try and stay
away from my skin,
though, would you, Ace?
STEVE SPANGLER: See, this is--
DOUG HODOUS: I think we got
enough, I get the idea.
STEVE SPANGLER: So if you just
had a source of carbon
dioxide, then you could actually
make this change
back, is that right?
DOUG HODOUS: I could get the
other fellas here, but I don't
believe they can breathe
strong enough.
STEVE SPANGLER: Never guess what
I found, which I thought
was absolutely perfect.
DOUG HODOUS: What?
They don't sell carbon
dioxide.
STEVE SPANGLER: Now, this being
carbon dioxide, not only
freezes your skin and
makes you slightly
static electric charged.
Look, it's clearing off.
DOUG HODOUS: But
I'm still wet.
STEVE SPANGLER: I know, you--
Turn around, Ace.
Turn around.
DOUG HODOUS: How about a little
respect here for an
older person?
STEVE SPANGLER: Look
at this, wow.
There's a static charge on you,
and, ah, look, all of the
ink has gone away.
DOUG HODOUS: Yeah
STEVE SPANGLER: Aside from this
shirt, that I think you
still had when I was
in high school.
DOUG HODOUS: Hey, you've got
a dry shirt with you?
Hey, take off that shirt,
let's exchange
here a little bit.
STEVE SPANGLER: We have
everything that we need for
disappearing ink.
Simple acid-based reaction.
This is the extreme.
I simply would just let
it sit out there.
And it would disappear.
DOUG HODOUS: And I think
we can see already.
This has disappeared.
STEVE SPANGLER: But this
would scare somebody.
They would really think
that maybe you
got some ink on them.
And that would be great.
DOUG HODOUS: Oh, I had a
friend I did this on.
He had a suit and tie on, and
I put that on his new white
shirt and--
STEVE SPANGLER: Yeah,
that's great.
Doug Hodous from Heritage
High School, my
first chemistry teacher.
You never forget
the great ones.
And I'm doing what I'm doing
today because of this man
right here.
And that's it.
That's all we're doing--
Well, the disappearing ink that
Doug Hodous helped us
make is very, very cool, But
no matter how cool it is--
I've put some in
this pipette--
it's just impossible, even
if loaded with a pen,
to write with it.
I just--
it's nothing.
So it's fun to squirt on people,
but it's really hard
to write with.
So I want you to have something
that you could write
with that's our kind of a modern
day disappearing ink,
that's not at a joke shop.
And I've come to find
out there really is.
Take a look at this.
It's a pilot friction pen.
There are pens that you
can find at a local
office supply place.
And they're very, very cool
because they are the kind of
pen that will erase.
The ink erases.
So, for example, here's
the pen, and you
write hello, all right?
So now, the ink actually is a
thermochromatic ink, which
means that it changes
with temperature.
It changes color with
temperature.
So watch, I can use the eraser
here and erase the ink.
What I'm actually doing is
heating up the paper.
Just like you take your hands,
and you rub your hands
together and you create
friction.
So the friction pen works just
by that by creating friction.
And so I can simply
erase the ink.
Well, It's great to be able to
erase the ink like this.
What would happen if you
used something else
to erase the ink.
I don't think the manufacturers
though about this.
Say, I owe you some money.
And I simply write a
little IOU here.
I owe you a $100, and I
sign my name to it.
That could be pretty dangerous,
because the IOU
might not really be the greatest
IOU in the world.
What if it gets hot?
Here watch this.
Here's our flame.
Watch.
Like this.
The IOU seem to vanish.
But I don't think it's
gone for good.
In fact, I can't get
it back this way.
What if I got it cold enough,
would it come back?
Let's got to the refrigerator.
Let's throw it in the freezer
and see what happens.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Look, the message is back.
And If you don't want to owe
the money anymore, you just
simply heat it back up again.
Watch.
And it's gone.
So, unless you read the contract
in a freezer, I don't
owe the hundred bucks.
So here's a challenge
that's kind of fun.
You can write a secret message
If you want to.
And you could use a combination
of a regular pen
that won't vanish, and
of course, this
friction pen from Pilot.
OK.
So, let's just say, to make
it easy, you're just doing
numbers real fast.
So let's write numbers
the way that a
calculator would have numbers.
Pretty easy now to
change these.
This was the permanent pen.
This is the friction pen.
So, here, let's change
this up.
Let's make this one
a four right here.
This is our secret message.
Let see what happen when
we heat it up.
Here you go.
One through ten.
My video guy came
up with this.
He wanted me to look
at this message.
This is his secret message.
Watch out, the guy shooting
potatoes is Steve Spangler,
who wants to be a special
effects artist in Hollywood.
This is the secret message.
Let's see what It really says.
Watch.
Watch the.
Watch the Spangler effect!
So here's what I
want you to do.
Go get yourself some of these
friction pens and come up with
your own secret message.
Some cool thing that appears.
And post it as a video response
here on this page.
The Spangler effect.
All right.
Let's take everything that we
learned, and turn this into a
segment with the meteorologist
Becky Ditchfield.
She's very, very gullible.
I could probably convince her
that this disappearing ink is
actually a biological stain.
And maybe we can have
a little surprise
ending for her as well.
BECKY DITCHFIELD: So we're going
in for a Steve Spangler
science experiment.
And, unlike a lot of other
times, I have no idea what's
going to happen.
So, this is going to be
interesting today.
STEVE SPANGLER: So today we're
talking chemistry.
And this is a biological
stain.
OK?
BECKY DITCHFIELD: What
does that mean?
STEVE SPANGLER: It's not.
This is an ink.
BECKY DITCHFIELD: Oh, OK.
STEVE SPANGLER: So, see--
Yeah.
So here is, see the
ink that's here?
BECKY DITCHFIELD: Yeah.
STEVE SPANGLER: It's this
blue little ink.
BECKY DITCHFIELD: Right.
STEVE SPANGLER: It's hard
to see it here,
so here watch this.
If I just--
See?
BECKY DITCHFIELD: Are you?
Ah There you go.
Isn't that beautiful?
So this is-- isn't that great?
Ah, this is gorgeous.
It doesn't really leak
through too much.
But it's-- isn't this great?
This is--
BECKY DITCHFIELD: Oh, no.
STEVE SPANGLER: It's fine.
It's just a stronger--
BECKY DITCHFIELD: Oh, my God.
STEVE SPANGLER: See, this is
a stronger source of--
see how fast--
see how it changes back
just like this?
BECKY DITCHFIELD: Yeah,
that's really--
STEVE SPANGLER: See,
it's changing back.
BECKY DITCHFIELD: Wow.
STEVE SPANGLER: Yeah, Let's
see on your back.
You are--
it's fine now.
BECKY DITCHFIELD: No.
STEVE SPANGLER: See,
isn't that great?
BECKY DITCHFIELD: Ah, now I know
why you had that covered
up, Steve Spangler.
STEVE SPANGLER: This is another
source-- and I just
want people to know that this
is carbon dioxide fire
extinguisher.
And look, you are completely
back to normal, minus just a
small amount of snow.
So you're fine.
You're fine.
BECKY DITCHFIELD: Uh-huh.
STEVE SPANGLER: See,
isn't that great?
This is why I use Becky.
Here she is fantastic.
But look.
This is what most people
don't realize.
Fire extinguishers will produce
a small amount of that
condensation.
And so she is kind of cold.
BECKY DITCHFIELD: Freezing.
I thought--
STEVE SPANGLER: See
how that works?
BECKY DITCHFIELD: I'm afraid
to touch this coat.
STEVE SPANGLER: You're OK.
Take off your little
microphone.
BECKY DITCHFIELD: Here we go.
STEVE SPANGLER: Look at this.
Look at this.
She is perfectly fine.
BECKY DITCHFIELD: Ahh.
STEVE SPANGLER: Minus the small
amount of coldness, see
she's fine.
She's not working
with me anymore.
BECKY DITCHFIELD: Yeah,
you're right.
STEVE SPANGLER: She's
fine, she's fine.
Well, if you've enjoyed this
week's episode, go ahead and
click the Subscribe
button here.
You'll be the first to know
when a brand new episode
appears each week.
This button right here will
show you some more cool
science experiments that we
do outside of this show.
This button right here will
take you to last week's
episode, just in case
you missed it.
And, if you want to see the
stuff that you shouldn't see--
that's the bloopers and the
outtakes-- just click this one
right over here.
If you want to hear me stop
talking through the magic of
television, just click this
button right here.
Go ahead, click it,
and I'll stop.
[MUSIC PLAYING]