TIMOTHY DELAGHETTO: [LAUGHS]
BETH HOYT: Thank you.
Thank you.
Thank you very much.
TIMOTHY DELAGHETTO: As you
could see, all tonight is
Stand-Up Night featuring the
best of up-and-coming
stand-ups you've never seen.
BETH HOYT: Oh, my god.
Holy crap!
A dead body.
TIMOTHY DELAGHETTO: Oh, my
gosh, it's Bart from
JustKiddingFilms.
And he's dead!
BETH HOYT: Oh, my god.
He's been murdered.
But who did it?
[DRUM ROLL]
BETH HOYT: Anyway, let's solve
the mystery of what's been
going on with "YouTube
Comedy Week"?
TIMOTHY DELAGHETTO: Sounds
good to me, Beth.
MARK DOUGLAS: Welcome
to Day 3 of the
Comedy Week Daily Rundown.
TODD WOMACK: I'm Todd.
He's Mark.
We've got the inside track on
some big Comedy Week events
and debut videos.
And we've got some great special
guests joining us in
the studio.
But without further ado, let's
hear our Comedy Week Specials.
MARK DOUGLAS: [ITALIAN ACCENT]
OK, you like to hear
the specials?
We got a nice little video
from Official Comedy.
It's called "Art of the Cold
Call" with David Koechner.
He from "Anchorman,"
you know, wear the
cowboy hat, very funny.
That comes with a side salad
and yucca fries.
It's a little different,
a little bitter.
You want a little taste?
Vinnie, give them a taste
of [INAUDIBLE]
kitchen!
This will be nice.
Faster.
DAVID KOECHNER: Number
1, get them to yes.
Number 2, the take-away.
Agreement.
Yes.
Nice day.
Do you believe in education?
Yes.
MARK DOUGLAS: [ITALIAN ACCENT]
Also, chef asked me to tell
you that we're all out of
astronaut singing in the
space with David Bowie.
We had a party of 2 million
coming last night.
They clean us out.
For something a little different
for the kids, we
have WWE FanNation with the
"what?" of a personality.
Spoiler alert!
This video contains
a screaming goat.
So if you're allergic to
screaming goat, you might not
want to watch.
But I think he's like.
OK, my name Vittorio.
I'll be around the back
and give you minute
to think about it.
If you want to watch anything,
you just click on
it right over here.
I bring you the wine list and
the bread for the table, maybe
some crayons for the
children, OK?
Vinnie, Italian gibberish.
DANISNOTONFIRE: Oh, I think
we're both looking forward to
the traditional Comedy
Week chicken.
AMAZINGPHIL: Oh, yes.
DANISNOTONFIRE: What
a tradition.
But more importantly--
AMAZINGPHIL: The best thing to
come out of England, Mr. Bean
is coming back.
DANISNOTONFIRE: More the Queen,
Beatles-- no, Mr. Bean.
AMAZINGPHIL: I'm so excited.
DANISNOTONFIRE: But don't do
this at home because you'll
probably tell everyone
you know.
TODD WOMACK: And we're back.
Joining us in the studio
are YouTube
heroes, Rhett and Link.
RHETT: Honored to be here.
LINK: We also heard
it was mandatory.
MARK DOUGLAS: We'll accept
both of those answers.
TODD WOMACK: Guys, the videos on
your channel, Rhett & Link,
are so funny and creative and
you're such nice guys.
But I think, what most people
out there want to know is, who
would win in a fight
to the death?
RHETT: Well, that's actually
already occurred.
And I won, Link died.
But I resuscitated him.
LINK: And now, I'm immortal.
MARK DOUGLAS: That's nice.
TODD WOMACK: Now, it's time
for Interview Tube.
Our first question,
who is who?
And can you give us a mnemonic
device to help remember?
RHETT: I'm Rhett.
I am really smart.
LINK: And I'm Link.
I'm the one with glasses--
"L," "glasses."
TODD WOMACK: Easy to
remember, though.
RHETT: We did make a video for
Comedy Week that we want to
tell everyone to watch.
TODD WOMACK: Bring it.
LINK: YouTube Challenge
Challenge.
That's what it's called.
There's the word "challenge"
is twice in the title.
But in the actual video, there
is even more challenges.
TODD WOMACK: More than two?
LINK: Yeah.
There's lots of challenge.
RHETT: We took all the
challenges that everyone does.
Cinnamon Challenge and
Baby Food Challenge--
LINK: --Tin Can Challenge.
RHETT: All that stuff.
First of all, we've never
done any of it.
We don't plan on it.
But we just talked a bunch of
YouTubers into doing all of
them in one video.
MARK DOUGLAS: So you, guys,
make really awesome local
commercials.
How did that start?
LINK: We've always been inspired
by just really bad
commercials--
used car salesman, 2 o'clock
in the morning, has his own
address, "dress up in a chicken
suit" kind of thing.
So we decided to start emulating
those on our
channel, but we wanted to make
sure they weren't just spoofs.
They were real commercials.
TODD WOMACK: If you guys
were to make a local
commercial for YouTube.
What do you really think
that would be?
LINK: I'd put a llama and a
YouTube logo and have it talk
or something.
MARK DOUGLAS: Because you could
fit the YouTube logo
right on the side of--
LINK: --of a llama.
TODD WOMACK: You, guys, spent
that much time thinking about
your other ones?
RHETT: No.
MARK DOUGLAS: Have
you ever saved a
business from collapse?
LINK: Every single one.
RHETT: I'd like to think so.
[LAUGHTER]
MARK DOUGLAS: So you, guys,
are sort of jacks of all
trades on YouTube.
You do music, advertising,
editing, directing, acting.
How about teaching the viewers
a little bit about green
screen in a segment we like to
call "Green Screen Basics With
Rhett & Link"?
LINK: I mean, we have somewhere
we got to be.
RHETT: We got to get going.
TODD WOMACK: Great.
Let's get started.
LINK: They didn't notice us.
Well, first of all, you've got
to have a green screen.
RHETT: And that's
what that is.
And then you want to think about
any environment at all
that you want to put yourself
in, like a space ship or a
classroom or a space ship.
LINK: And then you close your
eyes and you click your heels
three times.
RHETT: But you don't want to
click the fourth time because
at that point, you will open
up a hole in the space-time
continuum leading to
a evil universe.
LINK: Oop, that's four.
RHETT: Like this.
And then, of course, remember
don't wear green.
That's very important to note.
LINK: And then you strike
a pose in order
to make a fast exit.
RHETT: Do something else
with your body.
TODD WOMACK: Hey,
what did you do?
What did you do to our--
MARK DOUGLAS: Hey, Rhett, Link,
can you get us out of
here, maybe, is there
like an Apple Z?
TODD WOMACK: --like an ancient
incantation or something to
get out of here?
I know it's not a full
moon, but nice guys.
MARK DOUGLAS: Very nice,
other than this.
TODD WOMACK: Funny,
funny guys.
MARK DOUGLAS: They
know their stuff.
I really like those guys.
TODD WOMACK: Thank you,
guys, for watching.
We'll be back tomorrow.
But come back to this channel
at 9:00 PM Eastern, 6:00
Pacific for the stand-up
night.
There'll be all sorts of great
comedians, even myself.
And we'll catch up with you
tomorrow on this show.
MARK DOUGLAS: We'll
see you tomorrow.
And if we can get out of here.
Maybe go over that
way or something?
TODD WOMACK: I like a less
deadly neighborhood.
MARK DOUGLAS: I'm pretty sure
there's an evil worm in my ear
right now eating my brain.
It could just be wax.
TODD WOMACK: Get some evil ear
medicine or something.
I don't know.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
BETH HOYT: It looks like
such great stuff.
And remember that last night's
big show is available to watch
on youtube.com/comedyweek.
TIMOTHY DELAGHETTO: Be sure to
check up with all our live
events there, including
tonight's "Live Table Talk
with Philip DeFranco."
BETH HOYT: Plus, we keep
on churning out
Comedy Week epic videos.
It premieres today from The
Lonely Island, Above
Average, and more.
TIMOTHY DELAGHETTO: Plus, on the
videos from Michael Cera,
like the "Gregory Goes Boom."
BETH HOYT: Oh, Bart
tell us that--
oh, you know what?
Bart, who killed you?
BART: Timothy DeLaGhetto
did it.
BETH HOYT: Timothy,
you killed him?
TIMOTHY DELAGHETTO: What?
How'd you figure that out?
BETH HOYT: You will
never know.
TIMOTHY DELAGHETTO: Ooh!
I'm a kill you, too, bitch.
BETH HOYT: I got you
on that one.
Cool, well, great.
You, guys, just stay
tuned for the show.
Hope you all come
back tomorrow.
Right now, it's Stand-Up
Night!
[APPLAUSE]
SEAN O'CONNOR: Hey.
Hi.
Hey.
What's up?
I'm Sean, nice to
meet you all.
Let's get this energy up.
[APPLAUSE]
SEAN O'CONNOR: Cool.
Cool.
I live in Los Angeles now.
I used to live in Brooklyn,
New York.
Where is Brooklyn at?
No, it's not here.
I had to leave Brooklyn, New
York, when I saw the worst
thing ever in my neighborhood.
I saw a cop with
a face tattoo.
I'm going to repeat that one
more time because you guys are
acting like that's normal
for wherever.
I saw a cop, like a police
officer, with a face tattoo.
If you see a cop with a face
tattoo, that means one thing.
It means somewhere, there's
a dead naked cop.
It's not supposed to happen.
I was just in Austin, Texas.
I went to a restaurant
called Bikinis.
And guys, you will never guess
the uniform there.
It's bikinis.
The waitresses wear bikinis
at the restaurant.
Bikinis.
Me and my friend, Jared, went
there for a professional
business dinner.
We sat down.
The waitress came up to us and
she was like, what you all
having to drink?
And I said, a Diet Coke.
And my friend said,
a Texas Stripper.
It took five seconds.
12 minutes later,
she came back.
And she was like, hey, I'm
all out of sorts, ha-ha.
What were you all having
to drink again?
A Diet Coke, Texas Stripper.
Five seconds, maybe less, she
walked away to get those
drinks again.
She came back 21 minutes later
and said, I screwed up.
What where you all having
to drink again?
At that moment, I realized had
she been wearing a shirt, she
would have been the worst
waitress ever.
But she wasn't, so Top 5.
So it's pretty good.
I love music.
My favorite thing about music
right now is Ke$ha.
I love Ke$ha.
Not a lot of Ke$ha
fans out there?
For those of you who don't know
who Ke$ha is, she's the
new Beatles.
And she's incredible.
I want to see Ke$ha live.
It was the best night
of my entire life.
Like her audience is so diverse,
there is like me, and
the 9,000 teenage girls.
And like, we're all the same.
I don't know, whatever.
They were all the same.
They were all 15 and trying
to be slutty, but had no
idea how to do it.
They're going up to guys and,
like, you could put it
wherever you want, whatever
that means.
It's like, you're not going
to like what that means.
It means the butt.
[LAUGHS]
And then Ke$ha came out.
And guys, it was the best
fucking concert
I've ever been to.
It was incredible.
Oh, my god.
I found out so much.
Did you guys know she has
more than three songs?
That's cool.
And then this happened.
It's the best thing that's
ever happened
to me at any concert.
She was in the middle of her
seventh song, which is about
how her vagina is
a gold TransAm.
She's super classy.
The chorus says, wham,
bam, thank you, man.
You want to take a ride
in my gold TransAm.
OK.
She hits the chorus.
And then this happens.
She goes, stop!
And all the musicians stopped.
And me and the other teenage
girls all stopped because our
queen was about to speak.
Then she said, I just
realized something.
And I'm like, what did she just
realize in the middle of
her song about how her pussy
is a gold Trans Am?
She's good at multitasking.
Then she said, I just realized
there's not enough glitter on
these titties!
And then that guy with a bucket
came out and poured so
much glitter on those titties,
he saved the concert.
[APPLAUSE]
SEAN O'CONNOR: So I googled it
to see if that was the one
show where Ke$ha never
remembered to put glitties on
those titties.
No, it happened at
all 83 shows.
That was the guy's job.
That's simply a job you
get on Craigslist.
Words like, "must have
own bucket." He's,
like, I got a bucket.
Let's do it.
All right, guys.
That's been my time.
Thank you.
I'm Sean O' Connor.
Are you, guys, ready to
keep this show moving?
Your next comic is the only
female winner on "Last Comic
Standing's" history.
She's the host of the dating
show, "Excused." Please put
your hands together for
Iliza Schlesinger.
[APPLAUSE]
ILIZA SHLESINGER: What's up?
This is fantastic.
How are you, guys, doing?
Everybody here is so attractive,
is this is like a
CW casting call?
And it' just like we
didn't get it.
We're here.
That's fine.
My hair's super long.
That's fun.
Because when you have long hair,
no one expects you to
say anything, ever.
I won't even be smart.
I'm pretty sure, like, all of
Hugh Hefner's girlfriends were
rocket scientists.
And then they got long hair
because you could literally be
talking to me, like, so then
I was just thinking
I don't even know.
And guys are going to go,
oh, you got long hair?
Weiner!
Oh, yeah, it's amazing.
No idea.
Love It.
Your hair gets too long,
though, it gets creepy.
Girls know that.
OK, you.
Just if it get too long.
Yours is fine.
If it gets too long, you've
got about two inches
difference between really
hot, sexy supermodel--
religious fanatic.
It's right there.
Go a little bit longer, it's
like, ooh, ethereal, pretty,
sexy mouth, kissing,
girl everybody
wants to make out with.
Ooh, 1 of 12 brides,
right there.
That's where it's very
uncomfortable, super
uncomfortable.
It's nice outside.
This is a good time of year
because it's not too hot.
It's not too cold.
You know what I mean?
They can wear like a fun
sleeveless number.
And you're OK with it.
Don't be afraid.
This isn't live.
It's OK.
I think this is a girl's
favorite time of year because
you get to transition.
You to get rid of your
winter clothes.
I happen to like
Actually, most girls like winter
clothes, even though I
just said they didn't.
Fuck it, it's live.
We do.
We love it because you get to
put on like fun layers.
You get to do, like a scarf.
She's got a head-- she
doesn't give a fuck.
She's like, yeah, it's
half a scarf.
It's on my head.
I can pull it off-- new head
scarf, new leggings, UGGs.
We love UGGs.
The second it gets below like 70
degrees in Los Angeles, we
go bat-shit crazy.
We pop out of the ground
like gophers.
Like [SNIFFS]--
[LAUGHTER]
ILIZA SHLESINGER: Stacy,
did you feel that?
It was a breeze.
Oh, my god, cinnamon,
[GRUFFLY]
nutmeg, UGGs, leggings,
poof, poof, UGGs,
cover up your cankles.
[SCREECH]
[APPLAUSE]
ILIZA SHLESINGER:
Layer that shit.
Just eat whatever you want.
Layer a handful of almonds.
Digest it.
Layers.
Ice cream.
Leggings, do it.
White trash formal pants.
Leggings, UGGs, scarf,
cardigan.
I don't know.
That's super hot.
I don't want to wear it.
Bathing suit season's
coming up.
The girls get nervous
about that.
I don't mind.
I don't mind bathing
suit season.
I work out, obviously.
The bathing suits out there that
would bother me, like the
options out there.
They don't even have
regular bikinis.
Sometimes they have, like, girls
will use what looks like
a two-piece with like
a piece of material.
It's like this Judy Jetson thing
Paris Hilton wears it
when she's hooking.
It's just like one thing.
What kind of a fucked-up
tan are you
going to get from that?
You're going to look like a
vivisection of a cow at a
steakhouse.
Just like white line, red, red,
flank, flank, vagina,
just red haunches, filet.
A lot of bathing suits have
hardware on them.
I know these are for girls that
like to lounge around the
Bellagio pool and pick up
clients for the most part.
But I've seen bikinis that have
metal, like chain mail,
like "Game of Throne" style
Khaleesi shit all over it.
One of the intrinsic properties
of metal is that it
conducts heat.
You're going to lay outside.
Then you're going to get welts
all of over your body, knowing
that you pledged the
black fraternity.
That's what's going to happen.
Well, there's enough black
people here to get the joke.
White people were just laughing
because they're
nervous because I said black.
And that's totally fine.
I do this.
That's OK.
Nice time of year.
All my friends are getting
married this time of the year
because this is like the
weather is good.
Like, we don't want to
chance the rain.
And I want to do like
an outdoor wedding.
I do outdoor.
I planned the whole thing
on Pinterest.
I did.
It's an entire wedding
made of cheese.
Outdoor wedding.
One of my girlfriends got
married on Valentine's Day.
And like, jokingly, I was like,
oh, my god, what was
your theme?
And she's, like, we did like
"love" under the stars, but
like under the sea.
It's a wedding, not a prom.
When I get married, I'm going
to get married the day after
Valentine's Day.
And my theme is going to
be 75% off chocolate.
[APPLAUSE]
ILIZA SHLESINGER: Ssst.
Thank you.
Thank you PMS-ing women.
And it's not going to be a
wedding as much as it's just
going to be me alone in my
house listening to heavy
metal, doing wall push-ups,
eating the heads off chocolate
rabbits 'cause it's my day.
That's super fun.
All my friends get really
excited to get married.
And they should.
That's super fun.
And they all get really excited
to plan their weddings.
That's great.
I get really excited
to plan a breakup.
OK?
I put some time and
effort into this.
Just so you know when you date
me, you get a customized
breakup, OK?
I put time into this.
I put thought.
There's no template.
There's no, oh, my god.
It's me, it's not you.
No, it's you, motherfucker.
Here's a list of reasons why.
OK?
These are hand-hewn,
handcrafted, hecho in
California, "tailor-made to
highlight your insecurities"
specific breakups.
Guys, just so you know, us,
girls, we're bat-shit crazy.
And from the second we start
dating you, we keep tabs on
everything you do wrong.
So that if and when we decide to
break up with you because,
I don't know, the wind changes
direction; we can then refer
to said list and extrapolate one
isolated incident and use
that as the piece de resistance
of this breakup
masterpiece.
Dated a guy recently, I wanted
to do a rain breakup.
I thought that would
be super fun.
The rain, yeah, rain--
emblematic of the tears shed
during the courtship,
totally made sense.
Love the symbology
of it, rain.
Every girl's wanted to have
a rain breakup, right?
Every girl, but the black
girls, are like, hm-mm.
Because I want to do a rain
breakup, go on the rain.
It's raining.
You get to run out, like don't
follow me, which in girl talk
means follow me right now.
In the rain, maybe you got a
white shirt on, tits out,
nipples, go under the rain.
Hair, very-- no, but
you're out in rain.
Makeup running.
Run into woods-- don't
run into the woods.
But just rain.
Actually, if you can find woods
in LA, good for you.
Go find.
That's great.
Rain breakup.
I live in Southern California,
you can't do a rain breakup
with Southern California.
You're going to smell
like a dirty sheep.
I had on a wool sweater one
time, and it was raining.
I can't do that.
No one's going to miss you
if you're in a wool
sweater in the rain.
[GRUFFLY]
Like, you're breaking
up with me?
[SHEEP-LIKE]
I'm breaking up with you.
[BLEATS]
[NORMAL VOICE]
Had the perfect breakup plan.
I dated a guy for
three months.
So we were at a bar.
And we're hanging out.
So first date, we're drinking,
hanging out,
taking muscle relaxers.
It's a fun first date.
So we are just talking.
And we're having the obligatory
first date
conversation.
I'm like, so what do you do?
Where are you from?
[CHIRPS]
Just talking.
What's your middle name?
And he's, like, my middle
name is Paul.
Now, reciprocity in a normal
conversation would dictate
that his next question to me
should have been, [HONKS]
That's right.
But he never asked me
my middle name.
And I [GRUFFLY]
fucking remembered that shit.
[NORMAL VOICE]
You're not going to ask a girl
her middle name, it's going to
ruin our psyche because as a
girl, you interpret that very
differently than a guy would.
You don't ask my middle name,
it's, like, he doesn't want to
know my middle name, doesn't
want to get to know me,
doesn't care about my
thoughts, my fears,
my hopes, my dreams.
Doesn't want to have
a relationship.
Doesn't want to get married.
We're never going
to have a baby.
That's the way that goes.
So I had the perfect
breakup plan for
him, just so you know.
Before I tell you the perfect
breakup, the real way I broke
up with him, the fantasy
never happened.
The real way we broke up was
yours truly ended up getting a
little drunk one night and
texting him something to the
effect of, you don't even watch
"Breaking Bad," so how
can we be together?
That's really how we broke up.
But in closing, I
will tell this.
So here's the breakup
I wanted to do.
So I wanted in my fantasy-- are
you ready for my fantasy?
I'm going to pin this later--
in my fantasy, I will be
sitting on the couch.
And I would start a fight
out of nowhere.
When you're a girl,
you can do that.
Guys think we're crazy anyway,
we may as well play that card.
That's fine.
Just the fact that I might have
to have a baby one day is
enough for me to act like
a nut job today.
So I pick a fight.
Like he would cough.
[COUGH]
And I'd be like, what
did you say?
What did you say?
If a girl does this,
fucking duck and
cover, buddy, all right?
What did you say?
So you'd be like,
you know what?
Forget it.
And I would start crying.
But the way I'd start crying is
unbeknownst to him, I would
turn around.
And I would pluck a nose
hair out of my nose.
So I'd start involuntarily.
You ever plucked a nose hair?
Fucking hurts.
Why are you crying?
You want big tears.
You're going to get a
guy to feel bad, you
want crocodile tears.
You want the kind of tears the
girls on "The Bachelor" cry
when they get eliminated.
Big old French-tip
nails just--
I don't think Becky is here
for the right reasons.
The reason women
cry like this--
I found out now that I'm 30-- is
because we can maintain the
integrity of our eyeliner while
still agitating collagen
production.
[FAKE WEEPING]
And so we cry.
You ever been in a fight with
someone and you're crying and
you're kind of over being sad,
but you want to keep crying to
make them feel bad?
So you start thinking about
other things, like your mom
dying and the Holocaust, just
to keep the thoughts going?
He'd be, like, what's
your problem?
And I'm, like, forget it!
And I would run out
of my own house.
I'd sort of run into the street
because I want to have
this out in the street,
street fighter style.
Now, prior to starting this
fight, I would have set up
orange parking cones
in the street.
Because if you're going
to fight in the
street, safety first.
You cannot have a car coming in
and out of your trap of the
middle of your fight.
You can't be in the middle of
a fight and risk a Buick
coming through.
Do they even make
Buicks anymore?
I don't even know
what cars are.
So we'll be out there.
We'll be fighting.
Have the whole thing.
If a car comes through, you're
going to lose momentum.
You might stop fighting.
You might kiss.
You might make up.
But we don't fucking want that.
OK?
I'd run out and be,
like, get away!
I would yell so the neighbors
would come out.
And they start watching.
Yeah, because I need an
audience, obviously.
So you come out.
Like, don't touch me.
Iliza, what is your problem?
No, I don't want
to talk to you.
Get back inside.
You don't tell me what to do.
I'm an independent woman,
I listen to Beyonce.
Go back inside.
You're acting crazy.
What did you say?
I'm just saying, Iliza.
Go back inside.
I don't want to go
back inside.
Why not?
I just feel like this isn't
working, OK, Gary?
No, not Gary.
What is your problem?
I just feel like we don't
even know each other.
What do you mean we don't
really know each other?
I feel like we don't
communicate.
We don't even know each other.
What do you mean we don't
even know each other?
Of course, we know each other.
Really?
[GRUFFLY]
What's my middle name?
[APPLAUSE]
SEAN O' CONNOR: You're good.
You're good.
Give it up for Iliza.
Give it up for her.
Wow.
Let's keep this energy
for your next comic.
He has an album out on
ASpecialThing Records called
"Poems for the Ocean." Please
put your hands together for
Jim Hamilton.
[APPLAUSE]
JIM HAMILTON: Oh, good-looking
ladies out here.
I don't have time to hit on
you all, individually.
So I'm just going to put
out a pickup line.
And if you're interested, come
see me after the show.
[CLEARS THROAT]
Damn, girl.
You must be suicidal thoughts
because you've been running
through my mind all day.
Had Chinese food for
lunch today.
Overheard these ladies
talking.
Then one lady told her friend
that she recently went on a
first date with a comedian.
But she wasn't going to go on
a second date because all
comedians are emotionally
damaged.
I turned around, I was about
the correct her, but then I
just started crying
for no reason.
My fortune cookie read,
you will die alone.
Ch-uh, yeah, in bed.
I really think I'll
be alone forever.
Pretty decent chance I'd be
buried in a mass grave.
I had a girlfriend once--
play along.
She broke up with me because she
said I talked about Better
Than Ezra too much.
Didn't agree with her.
But it's not worth
fighting about.
So I texted her to apologize.
But the text auto-corrected
to "Better than Ezra."
What a day, what a day.
Today has been like a Red
Hot Chili Peppers song.
Not good.
I got so drunk last night, I
woke up this morning with a
penis drawn on my forehead.
Yeah, and I live alone.
I blame my doctor.
My doctor told me to
drink more whisky.
Well, his exact words were,
drink less beer.
[CHUCKLES]
But I knew what he meant.
[CLEARS THROAT]
If you know the cure for
elephantitis, I'm all ears.
Oh, man, be careful if
you're drinking.
I get these horrible nightmares
when I'm drinking.
In my nightmare, I see
my own tombstone.
My tombstone reads, here
lies Jim Hamilton.
He left this world just as he
entered it, face down in an
Applebee's toilet.
You never forget which word you
lost the Spelling Bee on.
I was about eight years old.
And I lost on the word
"faggot." Oh,
I spelled it correctly.
Unfortunately, it was
my father who
yelled it from the audience.
[LAUGHTER]
JIM HAMILTON: Oh, man,
I was an awkward kid.
I think I've aged like a fine
wine locked up in some rich
guy's cellar.
Recently, I went to a
baby christening.
It was a disaster.
It took me, like, eight tries to
break the champagne bottle.
My dad started watching "The
Wire." And he cannot stop
saying the N-word--
not in that order.
Lady Justice is blind.
So it's a good thing minorities
have an accent.
I don't care.
I don't care how many Africans
have to die,
blood oranges are delicious.
Kraft Foods.
Kraft Foods will never print
September 11 as the expiration
date on any of their products
for fear of
upsetting their customers.
What kind of world do we
live in where I can
just make that up?
The Commodores had a song
called, "Easy Like Sunday
Morning." It was written by
Lionel Richie who, apparently,
has never had hangover
diarrhea.
Enjoy the rest of
the show, guys.
Thank you.
[APPLAUSE]
SEAN O'CONNOR: Thank you.
Give it up for Jim Hamilton.
Give it up for him.
Yes, want to keep this
show moving?
You, guys, want to keep
this show moving?
Here we go.
Your next comic, he has a show
coming out on Comedy Central
called "Enjoy It." Please
put your hands
together for Brody Stevens.
[APPLAUSE]
BRODY STEVENS: Yeah!
BRODY STEVENS: I'm
a little nervous.
This is my first TED talk.
I have to keep my set tight.
I'm double-parked in the
handicap spot outside.
I'm very good-looking.
I've done a lot of modeling
in Serbia.
Who's on Lamictal?
Who takes medication here?
You got it, I do.
$10 co-pay.
Lamictal, Latuda, Lexapro,
Zocor, klonopin.
That's four for the brain
and one for the vein.
You got it.
Healthy, doing smoothies,
doing fiber.
This guy looks excited.
Looks like he got shut out
of Coachella, Day 8.
Stay with me, YouTube.
You got it.
You took down my page.
Why?
You said it was a Viacom
violation, prove it.
Your robots made mistakes
up at Google California.
You know Google owns YouTube,
like McDonald's used to own
Chipotle, but they broke away.
Did you guys know that?
You'll learn a lot from me.
I'm very smart.
I'm wearing glasses,
prescription, Urban
Outfitters.
Yes!
Positive energy, you got
it, very intense.
I get BO in the shower.
I am doing a show,
you heard it.
It's on Comedy Central.
You think I would have
a house in The Hills?
I don't.
I live in a one-bedroom
apartment on
Magnolia in the Valley.
I need more money, Viacom.
I'm sharing a banana
with a Samoan guy.
What's going on here?
I'm losing my voice.
I'm going back to Red Robin,
I'm doing fry refills.
I'm sleeping on an
air mattress.
But I got a show at
Comedy Central.
Viacom, wake up!
I'll put you on "60 Minutes."
Hold on, I have Bell's palsy.
That's a joke.
Oh, don't boo me.
How dare you?
This is my YouTube chance.
Hello, Dubai.
Hello, South Africa.
Hello, Israel, shalom.
I'm coming home, brother.
You got it.
I got a yamaka.
I got it at Lids, 7 and
3/8, New Era, fitted.
This guy's funny.
He's got hands under
the table.
Why are you playing
pocket pool?
This guy's touching
his crotch.
I got a Jerry Sandusky type
here, touching himself, trying
to distract me on Google Tube.
Don't distract me.
There's a camera right there.
Yes, Steven Brody Stevens,
looking good, getting chicks.
One lucky lady tonight is going
to be chosen out of this
crowd, is going to hang
out with me tonight.
What do you think about that?
[APPLAUSE]
BRODY STEVENS: Yeah!
Hooking up.
Venus Beach, under the pier,
playing some soccer.
Then we'll go on the boardwalk,
like Jack Tripper
on "Three's Company."
We'll reenact that.
And then I'll hold you over the
bluffs and then push you
over and then rappel down and
save you and have somebody
film it and put it on YouTube.
That's how you make stuff.
I just thought of a movie.
A guy meets a chick in a show,
hops on his moped parked in a
handicap spot.
They're sharing a helmet.
I got a big head.
I'm looking for a small-headed
woman in here.
Your head can fit on--
I love your headband.
It's very good.
Guys, give it a go for
Olivia Newton-John.
Let her hear it.
[SINGING]
Let's get physical, physical.
I want to get physical.
Let's get into physical.
Let me hear your body
talk, your body--
[STOPS SINGING]
You like me.
You're into me.
I'm going to hook up tonight.
Yeah!
How many people saw me
in "The Hangover"?
Not that many people,
I get that.
I get that not many people
recognized me from "The
Hangover." I was also in
"Hangover 2." I was in the
movie "Due Date."
But I don't get recognized
in public.
And it bothers me.
You know why?
You know why I don't
get recognized?
Because I'm a good actor,
that's why.
And I should've kept
that joke tighter.
It was too long.
I dragged you through the
mud to get to a chuckle.
Shame on me for using your ears
and your mind to listen
to a joke that didn't
have a good payoff.
I should quit comedy
right now.
No.
Let me relax.
I'm very calm.
Hi there, my name is Steve.
I'm still on Myspace.
I have a 13 friends.
Tom deleted me.
These are actually
YouTube glasses.
I'm clicking here.
I'm going through my
set list right now.
Click, click, click, click.
Oh, wow!
I'm on YouPorn.
Hello.
And pause and rewind.
Yeah.
Fred Armisen on SNL did
the whole thing.
But I'm different.
I'm different.
I'm Steven Brody Stevens.
I work out.
I do Krav Maga, ha.
I'm bloated right now.
I had a loofah sponge
for lunch.
Guys, great news.
I just got HD.
Finally, got HD.
[APPLAUSE]
BRODY STEVENS: Thank you.
Thank you.
Heart disease.
But ah--
oh, come on.
I'm feeling great.
I take Zocor.
I take Lamictal.
I take Latuda.
And I take your positive
energy.
This is one of the
best crowds.
I'm being honest.
I do a lot of shows.
I'm professional.
I've been in this business
for six weeks.
I'm telling you, this is a great
audience, Comedy Week,
YouTube, AllThingsBrody.
You can find me on Twitter
as well, BrodyismeFriend.
I answer all emails.
And you know what?
Tonight, right now, May 22,
2013, it's my birthday!
[APPLAUSE]
BRODY STEVENS: Sean,
yeah, my birthday.
SEAN O'CONNOR: Happy
birthday, Brody.
BRODY STEVENS: You got it.
Chuck E. Cheese on me.
SEAN O'CONNOR: Yeah!
Oh, give it up for
Brody Stevens.
Give it up for him.
It is his birthday.
Oh, man, Brody Stevens.
Guys, ready to keep
this show going?
Ready, ready, yeah.
Woo.
Your next comic is one of the
stars on an up-and-coming NBC
show "Undateable." He's also
one of my favorite comics.
So please put your hands
together for Ron Funches.
[APPLAUSE]
RON FUNCHES: Tells me I'm his
favorite and then he just
walks away.
Ah, thank you.
I'm excited to be here, guys.
[APPLAUSE]
RON FUNCHES: You know, when I
first started, a lot of people
told me I wouldn't make
it in comedy.
Well, I proved them wrong.
I'm on YouTube now, the
most exclusive.
[GIGGLES]
Oh, hello, Mr. Whiteface.
I mean you no harm.
So please don't come at me.
That's a conversation I
had with a kitty cat
several days ago.
It's also now the slogan for
Black History Month.
I like that you responded
to Mr. Whiteface.
That takes a lot
of confidence.
A lot of people would
have went, who me?
You were like, I'm
Mr. Whiteface.
[GIGGLES]
I have a cousin that's very
sensitive about racism.
He called me one day because
he was quite upset that he
went to a tuba recital where he
was one of only three black
tuba players.
And he thought that
was racist.
And I wanted to agree.
But then I realized three black
tuba players is a lot of
fucking black tuba players.
If you see more than five blacks
tuba players, you're
watching an Outkast video.
But I, too, can be sensitive.
One day I was running across
the street because Slurpees
were on sale for what I thought
was a limited time.
You, guys, never been there?
Well, I got stuck
on this median.
This car drives by at me.
And a guy yells out
his window.
Use the crosswalk, N-word.
I'm no girl.
I thought that was
pretty racist.
But I also thought about
that situation.
And I realized, since he was
in a car, I probably just
didn't hear the whole
conversation.
What he was trying to say was,
use the crosswalk, nigger, I'm
worried about your safety.
[APPLAUSE]
RON FUNCHES: Which is something
I've been known to
say to my son.
[GIGGLES]
Even if you didn't like that
joke, you have to admit that
was the most pleasant
use of the word
"nigger" in any YouTube.
[GIGGLES]
There's a lot of "nigger"
on YouTube, though
none of them end nice.
[GIGGLES]
Oh, you like that giggle?
My son just turned
10 years old.
Oh, thank you.
Thank you.
It's been a pleasure watching
him grow up from a little
bitty baby into a 10-year-old
fucking psychopath.
And you can chart his descent
into madness by how he's
changed his stance on pinatas.
When he was a toddler, he was
terrified of pinatas.
And it was my job to
vanquish that.
Now, he treats a pinata like
he's a mob boss from New
Jersey and Optimus Prime owes
him several thousand dollars.
He works it across the knees
for a little bit.
Takes a break to kiss his mother
pays some respect.
And then he cuts off
the fucking hand.
And I take pictures and post
it on my Facebook.
[GIGGLES]
My son and I get along very
well, except for when it comes
to watching cartoons.
See, he wants to watch
his favorites.
And I want to watch my
favorites, like the "Muppet
Babies." No, not everybody knows
the "Muppet Babies." But
everybody knows "The Muppets."
They fucked and had babies.
[LAUGHTER]
RON FUNCHES: The babies
were given a show.
And it's a little weird.
You can tell by the theme song,
which starts off wonderful.
It's just--
[SINGING]
Muppet babies, we'll make
our dreams come true.
Pap, doo, warah, wah.
Muppet babies, we'll do
the same for you.
[STOPS SINGING]
Beautiful.
It's just about dreams
coming true.
But then it takes a turn.
So next verse is, [SINGING]
If your room looks kinda weird,
and you wish that you
weren't there.
Then close your eyes
and make believe.
And you can be anywhere.
Ooh.
[STOPS SINGING]
And that's fucked up.
I told my son, if your room
looks kind of weird, and you
wish you weren't there,
do not make believe.
Call the cops.
Daddy has made an error
of some kind.
Thank you for your time.
I'm Ron Funches.
[APPLAUSE]
MR. SPRINKLES: Oh,
I've seen you.
Let me tell you something.
There is nothing worse than
being married when
your wife's in heat.
You know that voice, right?
She's always like, Mr.
Sprinkles, I'm in heat.
Let's have sex.
And I'm, like, I don't want
to fuck Garfield.
[APPLAUSE]
SEAN O'CONNOR: Oh, give
it up for Ron Funches
and stand-up time.
Yeah.
Oh, give it up for that--
both!
How are you, guys,
doing tonight?
Good?
Good.
Is anyone not having
a good time yet?
You, guys, can be vocal.
Come on, have a good
time, everyone.
Yeah!
Great, guys.
Oh, that's so great.
Whoa, are you, guys, ready
for your next comic?
AUDIENCE: Yeah!
SEAN O'CONNOR: OK.
He hasn't been doing comedy for
very long, but I know him.
So I was, like, hey, you should
probably do this show.
So can you please give
it up for Craig?
[APPLAUSE]
KYLE DUNNIGAN: All right, what's
going on you, guys?
Just going to blast you, guys,
in the faces with some of my
comedy of jokes.
Hey, before I get started,
I have a catch phrase.
It's "if you ask me, that's
nuts." So when you, guys, hear
me say, "if you ask me, that's
nuts," if you could clap after
that or something,
that'd be nice.
Let's do this.
Hey, guys, a dinosaur and a
monkey were in the woods.
And the dinosaur gave the
monkey a piggyback ride.
Now, the monkey gave the
dinosaur the piggyback ride.
One of them, either the dinosaur
or the monkey gave
the monkey or the dinosaur
a piggyback in the woods.
I don't remember
which as which.
But--
and there's a middle part,
too, I forgot.
But that's not--
important part is the beginning
part and then the
end of the joke which is end of
the dinosaur-monkey joke is
"monkey-sore-ass." If you
ask me, that's nuts.
[APPLAUSE]
KYLE DUNNIGAN: Hey,
guys, I got that
joke off the internet.
So if you, guys, still want
the middle part of the
monkey-dinosaur joke, just
Google search "monkey-dinosaur
joke." Should be the first or
second thing that pops up.
Hey, guys, knock-knock,
you, guys.
AUDIENCE: Who's there?
KYLE DUNNIGAN: Oh, I just
remembered the middle part of
the dinosaur-monkey joke
I told before.
The monkey slips on some
quicksand or a banana.
And then the dinos--
just Google search it.
It's better if you just
Google search.
Hey you, guys, like
impressions?
AUDIENCE: Yeah.
KYLE DUNNIGAN: All right.
This is my impression of my mom
when I woke her up at 4:00
in the morning.
Hey, Craig, what is this?
It's 4:00 in the morning,
go back to bed.
What is this?
Here's my impression of
Bill Murray, you guys.
This is Bill Murray.
[MIMICS BILL MURRAY]
Well, if you think you're one of
those people, was it one of
"those people"?
You're wrong.
OK?
You don't think you do
what they do, you do.
You hate your life.
You hate your family.
You hate God.
That's right, I said it.
Otherwise, you wouldn't be doing
what you've been doing,
which is exactly what
"those people" do.
OK?
[APPLAUSE]
[PIANO MUSIC]
KYLE DUNNIGAN: All right.
How are you guys doing,
all right?
Is it weird I'm normal now?
I feel like it's weird.
Let's cleanse the palate.
Let me do--
I want to try to do an improv
song, never done this.
I'm going to get some
information, and then I'll
make up a song.
What's your name, sir?
Darren?
All right, Darren.
I'm going to write a song about
you using information I
gather, all right?
What do you do for a living?
Hm.
You don't sound sure about it.
You're in tech support.
How about tech support?
What's your favorite hobby?
Again, not sure.
I feel like you're just
saying words.
Darren is into tech support,
maybe, and
he might like hiking.
[SINGING]
There was a guy named Darren.
And he was a total douche.
[END OF SONG]
This next song is a song
I wrote about--
improv's hard.
Don't be like--
you ever tried improv?
[BRITISH ACCENT]
You know it's magic, you
know, writing songs.
It was magic, you know.
[NORMAL VOICE]
I saw a Paul McCartney
interview.
That's what he said.
[BRITISH ACCENT]
It's like, it's magic.
You know, magic songs.
You know, songs fall
from the sky.
You know, lands on the
back of a turtle.
Yeah.
You know, turtle walks
up to you.
Got it, you know, magic songs.
[NORMAL VOICE]
This is a song that
John Lennon wrote
right before he died.
[SINGING]
What's that in your hand?
[BANGS]
Ugh!
Don't shoot the messenger.
[END SONG]
[PIANO MUSIC]
KYLE DUNNIGAN: That sounds like
every horror movie music
in the background.
I just made that up.
I'm not even trying.
What a ripoff profession.
The guys get paid to do that.
There are phone calls, like,
hey, Mike, we need that music
by next week.
You can have it now.
It's pretty good.
You know what I'm talking about,
like Marcia's stuck in
the basement like, you guys--
[SUSPENSE PIANO CHORDS]
KYLE DUNNIGAN: --where
are you, guys?
I'm stuck in the basement.
And everybody's up in
the kitchen, like--
[SUSPENSE PIANO CHORDS]
KYLE DUNNIGAN: --where
the fuck is Marcia?
I'm in the basement, you guys.
I'm not going down there.
I don't even like her.
Fuck Marcia.
You, guys.
This next song--
can't tell how much
time I have left.
I wrote this song for a girl.
I fell in love and she
moved off to Europe.
I didn't want her
to forget me.
So I wrote her this song.
It's called "Hold On."
[PIANO MUSIC]
[PIANO OFF-KEY]
KYLE DUNNIGAN: Tsk, hold on.
[LAUGHTER]
KYLE DUNNIGAN: Ah, hold on.
Hold on!
I still get emotional.
It's, like, four years ago.
I went to a heavy metal
show, rock show.
And they had to make
announcements.
There's, like, nothing less rock
than a heavy metal band
being like, [FALSETTO VOICE]
You ready to rock?
We just want to first
thank Coca-Cola for
having us here tonight.
Coca-Cola, that cool and
refreshing drink,
motherfuckers.
If you drove here on a Ford
Focus, you may want to check
your lights.
Someone with a Ford Focus left
their motherfucking lights on
the parking lot, bitches.
Now, you ready to rock?
I said, are you ready to rock?
Yeah?
Well, that's all we're going to
do right after I tell you
about the raffle.
There's a raffle right
after the show.
[NORMAL VOICE]
All right, this last song
I want to do is
another love song.
I wrote this for a girl.
And I sang it for her.
And she hated it.
I think it's nice.
It goes like this.
[SINGING]
Your legs are long and firm.
Your skin's as white
as a dove.
I do believe the Lord blessed
me with an angel from above.
The only thing I'll change
about you is your face.
[END OF SONG]
Thank you all very much.
That's my time.
Thank you.
[APPLAUSE]
FEMALE SPEAKER: I'm really
glad that I was chosen.
PUPPET: Not me.
SEAN O'CONNOR: Has any of you,
guys, ever been arrested?
AUDIENCE: Yeah.
SEAN O'CONNOR: Come on, guys,
who wants to admit they've
been arrested on the internet?
It's your one chance.
I feel like most of
you are lying.
AUDIENCE: Come on!
SEAN O'CONNOR: Yeah.
I used to drink and drive
like it was my
motherfucking job, guys.
And it was.
I worked at Domino's.
And let's keep this
show going.
Your next comic is hilarious.
He's also co-creator of "Barely
Political." Please put
your hands together
for Todd Womack.
[APPLAUSE]
TODD WOMACK: Keep it going
for Sean, everybody.
"Hardly Working."
Let me see here.
And we got the library from
"Game of Thrones" set here.
Nothing says comedy like that.
We got the felt tables.
All right, that's where
the ad money's going.
Sweet How are you,
guys, doing?
You all right?
AUDIENCE: Yeah!
TODD WOMACK: Fuck
this technology,
we're inside YouTube.
Does that feel good
for you, guys?
I feel weird, a little "Matrix."
I don't like
technology.
I don't like texting.
I feel like texting is ruining
the English language.
Anybody else?
AUDIENCE: Yeah.
TODD WOMACK: The kids today,
growing up, they're exposed to
so many shortcuts and
misspellings.
They're not going to be able
to read correctly.
Like your kids' going to be at
school reading a history book,
come across a semicolon, and
like, not know what to do.
"George Washington was a
skillful leader." Oh,
winky-face.
But would his constituents
vote for him?
I'm going to say, left
elephant ear?
It's a question mark, Johnny.
We used to use it all the
time back in the day.
Now, phones, everybody's
obsessed with their phones,
everybody now, It's just like,
oh, I got to look at my phone.
I got to look--
hang on--
I got to look at my phone.
You're in court, Your Honor,
put your phone down.
Put it down, convict somebody.
It changed the way we talk.
We talk about our phones like
we're in some kind of
primitive society.
Everybody's just consciously
walking around and just
[GRUFFLY]
who is your provider?
Who is your provider?
Who is the best provider?
Who can I follow and believe?
[NORMAL VOICE]
Everybody's always trying,
like, convert
you to their service.
[GRUFFLY]
Oh, my provider is
the best, yes.
It gives me everything I need.
It gives me 1,000 minutes with
which to speak per lunar
cycle, yes.
And get this, all they ask for
in return is a low monthly
offering of 79.99, which somehow
comes out to, like,
123.50 every month.
Damn it!
[NORMAL VOICE]
It's always a shock, isn't it?
Well, taxes, hm-mm TVs get
pretty rough, too.
Everything's about food.
Every show is about food.
What have we got?
Watch food while we're
eating food?
It's getting out of control.
It's those foodies, who's just
like, yeah, I appreciate food
more than the average person.
You know who else appreciates
food?
Uh, every single human
who's ever lived on
the face of the Earth.
Foodies and just that group.
You ever met anybody that
didn't like food?
What's for lunch?
Oh, food again?
Damn it!
For once, can we just try a
ranch or remote control or
some fiber optic cable
or something, please?
You've got to eat to survive.
That can't be your hobby if you
have to do it to not die.
Are we going to have people
walking around [SNIFFS], yeah,
I'm a breathie, yeah.
I just appreciate air a little
more than the average person.
Hint of watermelon there,
did you catch it?
No, I'm not surprised.
I used to really like nature
documentaries.
But they all, for
like the last 30
years, the same format.
It's boring.
You got that British narrator.
The guy sounds like he's
commentating on a golf match.
He puts you right to sleep.
You got to compete today.
It's always the [BRITISH ACCENT]
and the crab retreats back
into its home to avoid
predation by the
spider monkey.
[NORMAL VOICE]
You got to compete
today, baby.
I live in New York.
You can get anybody
on my street.
There's these Cuban dudes.
You slap one of those dudes in
it, then you only have to know
what they're talking about.
They're just fun to listen to.
Perfect ratings bonanza
right there.
At the start, perfect
narrator, you know?
[CUBAN ACCENT]
Mira, the crab.
You see muy tiny arm-y male.
He walking muy slow.
And he walking muy fast.
Bueno, he see the monkey.
He go inside the hole.
When he get down there,
the crab wife, she
always yelling at him.
Pick up the home.
Paint the hole.
Do something.
Don't watchy "Shark Week"
all the time.
You want to leave, it's
all very mal.
He go to peek outside
the home.
He peek outside with
the crab eye.
He see the monkey.
He know, number 1, the monkey
want to eat him.
Number 2, the monkey have a
birthday coming muy soon.
So he go back down inside the
hole, find the crab wife, push
her into the oven, make a crab
cake for the monkey birthday.
He lost the crab.
Azucar.
[NORMAL VOICE]
Thank you.
You put that guy in anything,
"Mad Men" is
getting pretty boring.
[CUBAN ACCENT]
Mira, Don Draper.
Why do you womanize, you drink
so much, very sad?
Azucar!
Anything you know.
Who knows what's going on?
You, guys, feeling all
right tonight?
Got to get out of house.
I like doing that crab
bit because my first
language was Spanglish.
And it's good to be back in
Southern California for that.
I went to Spain one time,
they're real nice there.
And they are like you must go
to the bullfight with us.
It is the classic sport.
Is that really a sport?
Would they put the wrong
guy in charge of making
up sports that day?
Come back at the end
of the day just--
[SPANISH ACCENT]
OK, we gonna have a little
with skinny man.
You gonna have a little black
tight with sequins all over on
the side, like pop, pop,
pop, pop, pop, pop,
pop, pop, pop, pa.
Eh, he gonna have a decoration
on the lapel.
Golden frilly shoulder pad, que
sparkle in the sunshine.
A little red business tight,
'cause he gonna mean business.
Eh, Christopher Columbus,
a tri-corner hat.
Oh, my god, he want to have more
the beautiful red crimson
cape because he will be dancing
and spinning around
all of the night with a bull.
And at the end of the
game, one team gets
stabbed in the heart.
[NORMAL VOICE]
Thanks, bro.
But at that point, you're not
really dressed to fight a
bull, you know what
I'm saying?
You're more dressed to fight,
like, Elton John, Russell
Brand, I don't know, who
dresses like shit.
Make sure, you're especially,
as Americans going overseas
though, we really do.
We're like the worst
travelers.
But everybody knows us,
their extra nice.
I went to China.
I didn't know any Mandarin--
no, I'm sorry.
I knew four words in Mandarin,
one through four.
And I flirted with a girl who
didn't know any English.
The opposite would
never happen.
Like a foreign dude cannot walk
up to an American woman
and hit on her in that way.
Just, hi, one, two,
three, four.
What's up?
You're giving to me your
numberings for I am will
calling you.
I will take you to the nice
place, the Olive Garden.
Two guys, we will share a love
that is unlimited, like the
bread sticks on the salad.
Giving to me your numberings.
And the chick will probably do
it because girls like dudes
with accents.
She'll be like, it's 587--
oh, whoa, whoa, one chauffeur
only, please, please.
Dating is insane.
I'm a little more chilled
out nowadays.
And I do like the strip
club, young
men, crazy thing anymore.
Although I was never really
like into going
into the strip club.
I always get confused I don't
know what the hell
I'm doing in there.
I feel like I'm feeding ducks.
Anybody else, you're
just, like, hey,
there's one for you.
Gosh, there's a lot of them.
Geez, look, they're just
around fuck over here.
[APPLAUSE]
TODD WOMACK: Oh, my god,
do you see that one?
So beautiful.
[CHITTERS]
Come over here.
We're just going to take
a look at you.
[CHITTERS]
We're not going to hurt you.
Ah, she's just really
beautiful, perfect.
Hey, where are you
going with that?
Dammit!
The big ones always take it
from the little ones.
You, guys, have been
very nice.
Thanks a lot.
Later!
[APPLAUSE]
SEAN O'CONNOR: Hey, give
it up for Todd Womack.
Are you, guys, ready for your
last comic of the night?
Yeah.
Put your hands together.
This next comic has a Comedy
Central half-hour debuting
next month, June.
Are you, guys, going
to watch it?
Yeah!
Now, clap--
[APPLAUSE]
SEAN O'CONNOR: --for the super
hilarious, [INAUDIBLE]
Sean Patton!
[APPLAUSE]
SEAN PATTON: Thank you.
Thank you.
Hallelujah!
The Lord is in me, folks.
The Lord is inside
of me, right now.
AUDIENCE: Amen.
SEAN PATTON: The Lord
is inside of me.
The Lord is raw-dogging
me right now, you all.
me, right now.
[LAUGHS]
You know, that exists,
Christian comedy.
And it's the stupidest
fucking thing.
Like even if you're Catholic,
it's still like-- because
Christians or Catholics--
like, comedy comes from pain.
Christians and Catholics,
they don't suffer.
The Lord hath suffered
for them.
So they got nothing to say.
It's the dumbest shit.
Like, you all, last week,
I got a parking ticket.
I did.
I wanted to yell at that
police officer.
I wanted to do that.
But I did not do that.
I paid that parking ticket,
that's what I did.
Because I know when I
go to heaven, I'll
park wherever I want.
And there ain't going
to be no tickets.
[SINGING]
Hallelujah.
Jesus still the Lord.
[STOPS SINGING]
You know, folks, I tell you.
[LAUGHS]
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Yesterday, I had to wait in
line for 2 and 1/2 hours
behind a woman at a pharmacy
buying birth control pills.
Yeah, I know, I prayed for her
because I know when I go to
heaven, I'm on a VIP list.
[SINGING]
Jesus is the tiger in the
jungle in wherever the--
Lord.
[ENDS SINGING]
You know, guys, I'm
broken right now.
I'm broken right in half.
My heart's just broken because
last night, my wife
spoke back to me.
No, I know, I asked her to have
dinner ready when I got
home from a long
day of praying.
And she said, I'll try.
Sometimes, you think you
know somebody and--
but it's like its says in
Jebediah 13:69, she with whom
you choose to walk down that
with whom is she may at times
be but the devil
in her panties.
Like, if you're a Christian,
I don't give it,
fine, just fuck off.
Leave me alone.
Like, you think life is
predestined and already
planned and God has a plan.
And I think you're an idiot.
I think you're stupid.
And you can't get pissed at me
for that because, clearly,
that's just God's plan for me.
Good, you're a dumb dumdum,
a dumdum dumdum.
I guess, if you flip that
point over though, a
completely satanic comedian
would be equally as like
boring and stupid.
Like, you know, last week, I was
drinking the blood of the
nonbelievers, right?
And I would gargle.
And I gargled fire and spit it
on the kid in the playground.
[GARGLING]
So anyway, guys, you ever
tortured a doodlebug?
And they're like, there's
no innards to eat.
I'm a beast on the inside.
Mark of the beast!
6, 6, 6, 6, 6, 6.
So yesterday, I was carving a
pentagram into the rotting
flesh of a corpse I just
dug up and dilated.
But I started thinking, aren't
shovels expensive?
You forget, they're more
expensive than you think.
I went in there with
like a 10.
It was, like, 12.99.
I was like, what?
It's going to dig the
grave for me?
Know what I mean?
[BURBLING]
That's what I think
all satanists do.
Have you, guys, noticed
how fat I've gotten?
Yeah.
[FARTING SOUND]
I try and eat healthy.
I frequent a certain
sandwich-making franchised
establishment that legally, I
am no longer allowed to say
the name of into a microphone.
But I will give you a hint.
It's named after an underground
train system in
New York City.
See?
Bam!
Right on top of that.
I've been in front of some
audiences, like 45 minutes,
like underground train system,
New York City.
Starts with an S, ends with a Y.
They're like, uh, Quiznos.
That's not--
[MUTTERS]
fucking asshole.
I have the same complaints we
all have about that place.
The food isn't that good.
The price isn't that great.
Clearly, I'm not trying
to lose weight.
But I eat there because of the
culture, because the employees
of that place refer to
themselves as sandwich artists.
And I support the arts.
I believe in them.
I feel like when I go, I place
my order, the sandwich artist
hears it, becomes inspired, and
creatively interprets it
into sandwich art right
in front of my eyes.
I say, I would like a footlong
on garlic bread, please.
Ah, white bread, close enough,
let's just move on.
This is a journey.
Let's take it together.
I think I'll have some
turkey breast.
Four slices.
Well, you're right.
The meat is the worst part
of the sandwich.
Why do I want more of that?
Yes, I'll have some half-moon
shaped cheese, triangular
shaped cheese.
Ha-ha.
You, my friend, just taught me
to expect the unexpected.
Yes, I will have it toasted.
Ding!
Burnt.
Wow!
How's about some lettuce?
One pound of lettuce.
A pound of lettuce.
Beautiful.
May I have some sweet
peppers, please?
One, single, solitary sweet
pepper atop Mount Lettuce.
Wow, I see the symbolism
in that.
It's challenging.
We are all alone.
How's about some black olives?
Handful of black olives
scattered everywhere, except
the fucking sandwich itself.
[LAUGHS DIABOLICALLY]
Wow.
Those must represent
the things we
want but cannot have.
How's about some mayonnaise?
Pffft, pffft, pffft, pffft.
One ocean.
An ocean of mayonnaise.
Your sandwich is now
a submarine in a
mayonnaise-like ocean.
A may-ocean is what
I call that.
Oh, can I have some mustard?
Ah, no, more mayonnaise.
Pffft.
I will now cut this using this
knife I just cut five tuna
sandwiches with and
did not rinse.
I did not rinse this.
It is my artistic license
to use this
tuna-caked serrated blade.
Ah!
Who'd have-- huh, that's
beautiful!
Because that was a footlong,
but now one half is nine
inches, and the other
half's only three?
It's art.
It means something.
That nine inches represents
our expectations.
But that three inches represents
our reality.
[APPLAUSE]
SEAN PATTON: Thank you.
Do you, guys, know the
film "Men in Black"?
AUDIENCE: Yes.
SEAN PATTON: Remember the
neuralyzer, the thing they use
to erase people's memories?
My little brother, who is 14
years younger than me, my
other family members called
him "the mistake." I don't
think there was a mistake.
My parents knew exactly
what was going on.
My guess is they were
playing their annual
game, Truth or Dare.
And my mother dared my father
to knock her up again.
And he did because he's a man.
But 14 years is such
a gap and, like,
it's hard to relate.
When I was 18, he was 4.
It's hard to be a brother.
I tried, you know, dude, hey,
guess what I did yesterday?
I fingered Trish Howell
in the woods.
What did you do?
Jumped in the pool
three times?
Wow, no floaties?
Like, there's no relating going
on with that age gap.
The only thing we had was his
favorite movie was "Men in
Black" when he was four.
He loved it so much, he made
his own toy neuralyzer.
He just took a paper towel tube,
stuffed some shit in
there, drew some buttons on it,
and would make a little
"beeyou" sound.
And his favorite thing in the
world was to neuralize me, his
big brother, and give
me a new identity.
So I just hear him go, beeyou!
And I'm like, oh, who am I?
And he'd be, like, you're
a butt-head.
And then run away, laughing
his little heart out.
Or I'd wake up for school, and
he'd be standing there.
Beeyou!
Who am I?
You're a fart-face.
Always made me a butt-head
or a fart-face.
Once, I'm in you butt-head,
fart-face.
Once, he made me Howard Hughes,
which caught me off-guard.
How do you know who
Howard Hughes is?
Beeyou!
Howard Hughes!
And he ran off.
I was also Asian.
I was Asian.
Apparently that was the Asian
year of his life.
Ran off to go apply
to Stanford.
But he was always working on
that thing, add new buttons,
add little pieces to it,
draw new buttons on it.
He was really proud of it.
I remember one day having that
standard teenager breakdown in
my parents' house.
It's like, no one understands me
or my pain growing up in an
upper middle-class suburb where
I'm safe in a supportive
environment, and my family
cares about me.
That's fucking bullshit.
And I tell my mom, I want
to be a performer.
She's like, well, do
good and apply to a
liberal arts college.
Fuck you, bitch.
You don't know me.
And the whole time, he's just
running along trying to
neuralize me.
And he'd added like a
tinfoil piece to it,
like another section.
He was real proud of
this neuralyzer.
He'd been working on it.
And he's just, beeyou!
Beeyou!
And I'm annoyed and
ignoring him.
And finally, I just
go, goddammit!
Stop it!
And I'd never yelled
at him before.
He's a four-year-old.
And he was just like shocked.
And like a little tear, just
like a single tear ran down
his four-year-old cheek.
And then just to destroy me for
the rest of my life, he
turned that neuralyzer
on himself.
Maybe you hit your younger
brother, maybe you framed him
for murder; neither of those are
nearly as bad as yelling
at him and make him
go, beeyou.
He didn't even give himself
a new identity.
I carried that guilt
for years.
I'm such a terrible brother.
10 years later at a family
Christmas party, I just moved
to New York, I was back home in
New Orleans for Christmas.
I'm drunk.
He's a teenager at this point.
And he's like, what's
New York like?
Can I come visit you some day?
And my reaction was, [SOBS]
I'm so, I'm so sorry.
I really--
I'm sorry I yelled.
I should have just let
you neuralize me.
I'm such a piece of shit.
I'm so sorry I yelled at you.
I'm so sorry that
I yelled at you.
And he just calmly goes, what?
I don't remember that.
That fucking thing worked!
It worked, man.
He is a genius.
Thank you very much.
YouTube!
[APPLAUSE]
SEAN O'CONNOR: Give it
up for Sean Patton.
Give it up for all the
performers you saw tonight.
Subscribe to them on YouTube.
Follow them on Twitter.
Good night, everybody.
Thanks for watching.
And tune in tomorrow night
for "CollegeHumor
All-Nighter." Goodbye.
Yeah!
[APPLAUSE]
MALE SPEAKER: No!
ALL: Oh!
[SHRIEKS]
MALE SPEAKER: I like it.
SARAH SHNEIDER: I know.
MALE SPEAKER: The All-Nighter.
MALE SPEAKER: Yes.
MALE SPEAKER: Oop.
MALE SPEAKER: Come
on, seriously?
MALE SPEAKER: The All-Nighter
is an annual event.
We've been doing it
five years now.
JAKE HURWITZ: It's a night where
we all stay up and we
make as many videos as we
possibly can for you, guys.
MALE SPEAKER: So if you're up
studying all night for finals
or you're working the night
shift or you just need a break
from all that porn--
MALE SPEAKER: Basically, it's
sort of a personal challenge
to us to see how long it takes
for us to completely lose
touch with reality.
MALE SPEAKER: We do
a live stream.
AMIR BLUMENFELD: We're like the
Lance Armstrong of comedy,
where we're just enduring,
enduring, enduring, making
things happen.
But at the end of the day,
nobody respects us.
MALE SPEAKER: One thing that's
great about the All-Nighter.
is that we get guests
to come in.
JAKE HURWITZ: "The Whitest
Kids U'Know."
AMIR BLUMENFELD: Dan McCarthy.
JAKE HURWITZ: Dan McCarthy
is a good one.
Pete Holmes.
MALE SPEAKER: Jon Gabrus has
been a favorite guest of mine
always because I think every
year that goes by, he's wore
less and less clothing.
JAKE HURWITZ: I think our
favorite guest is you.
Just like, you and your--
I'm probably yours, just
like you love--
AMIR BLUMENFELD: Well, I
would say Ben Schwartz.
MALE SPEAKER: We ask
them to join us.
And then they have the
privilege, the honor of coming
to work at 4:30 in the morning
to shoot a two-minute sketch
where they get spaghetti
dumped on their face.
MALE SPEAKER: That's
very technical.
MALE SPEAKER: Come on over to
CollegeHumor.com or check out
the live stream on YouTube.
MALE SPEAKER: Come join us--
MALE SPEAKER: --Thursday--
FEMALE SPEAKER: --May 23--
MALE SPEAKER: --at 8:00 PM and
watch the All-Nighterr--
MALE SPEAKER: --or just
upload a virus
and destroy our website.
AMIR BLUMENFELD: Who knows
how long it will go?
Maybe all night, maybe even
longer than that.
[CHUCKLES]
JAKE HURWITZ: It will
just be all night.
AMIR BLUMENFELD: No promises.
JAKE HURWITZ: We promise.
[OWL HOOTING]
[MUSIC PLAYING]