We go to different ethnic
neighborhoods, and we make babies.
That's what we do.
FEMALE SPEAKER 1: You'd
have a cute baby.
Cute baby.
EDDIE HUANG: Cute.
I mean, that could be a baby.
I could see this baby.
10 points.
There we go.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
EDDIE HUANG: Yeah, I was mad
excited about Persian LA.
Came out here, thought I'd run
into the Iron Sheik at the
grocery store, cop some
plutonium on the corner, catch
an afternoon saffron
rainstorm.
What's up?
All right, so when you lost
in Persian LA, head to the
fucking rug store, find your
neighborhood friendly Persian.
This is Nima Nabavi,
world famous.
NIMA NABAVI: Pleasure.
EDDIE HUANG: Thank you for
showing us around this
neighborhood.
So what is it that makes Persian
rugs so special?
NIMA NABAVI: The main thing is
a lot of them take like 10
years to make.
EDDIE HUANG: One rug?
NIMA NABAVI: Yeah, one rug.
EDDIE HUANG: So this was
a dude's decade?
How much is one of these?
NIMA NABAVI: Honestly, if this
was under 25 grand, I'd be
kind of surprised.
EDDIE HUANG: This is a car.
NIMA NABAVI: We'll ask them.
EDDIE HUANG: This is college.
NIMA NABAVI: Yeah.
EDDIE HUANG: Wow.
NIMA NABAVI: This
is a big deal.
EDDIE HUANG: I'ma get on this
rug game, because a lot of
people got the sneaker
game, the cars.
NIMA NABAVI: The rug game's
where it's at, man.
EDDIE HUANG: Wanna
be futuristic
with your pimp game?
Rugs.
Persian rugs.
Are those peacocks?
Or phoenix?
What bird is-- what
is like the bird?
NIMA NABAVI: They're big cocks,
because that's what
we're known for.
EDDIE HUANG: Oh wow.
Pause.
So this is like a car
dealership, like somebody
sells a rug, like a $25,000
rug, that's their month?
NIMA NABAVI: Yeah.
EDDIE HUANG: They don't got no
doughnuts in here, though, no
doughnuts and coffee?
NIMA NABAVI: Naw, they
got baklava and tea.
EDDIE HUANG: What is the food in
this neighborhood, though?
NIMA NABAVI: I mean, generally,
the stereotype is
kebab and rice and all
that, which is dope.
EDDIE HUANG: I seen it.
NIMA NABAVI: But I want to take
you to this spot that is
a sandwich spot.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
NIMA NABAVI: This area is
officially Persian Square, and
they picked this spot because
the sandwich shop we're about
to go to is the first Persian
establishment in the area.
EDDIE HUANG: Nice.
NIMA NABAVI: So, been
around since '74, so
let's go peep it out.
EDDIE HUANG: They got the
brain out on front
street, you see this?
What kind of brain is
that, cow brain?
NIMA NABAVI: Sheep.
EDDIE HUANG: I think you should
hit the brain, I'm
gonna get the tongue.
NIMA NABAVI: Try a little
bit, though.
EDDIE HUANG: I'll try
a little bit.
WAITRESS: Here's your brain.
NIMA NABAVI: That's the brains,
and two tongues.
WAITRESS: Yes.
NIMA NABAVI: What
do you think?
EDDIE HUANG: Delicious.
Tender.
NIMA NABAVI: Yeah, right?
EDDIE HUANG: This tongue feels
like I'm at Second
Avenue Deli, man.
Like really, really juicy.
NIMA NABAVI: Legit, right?
EDDIE HUANG: Yeah.
And the pickles, these types
of pickles that you get in
like Lebanese food,
Persian food.
It's like the tarter, sour,
funky, thin pickles.
NIMA NABAVI: You know,
it's almost time
for the brain, right?
EDDIE HUANG: You first, kid.
You know what brain
looks like to me?
It's like mammal oysters.
NIMA NABAVI: It really is.
EDDIE HUANG: Not even
gonna front.
I do it for y'all.
NIMA NABAVI: You'll only be
eating brain sandwiches for
the rest of your life.
Watch.
EDDIE HUANG: Here's the
thing, this is it
with all the gag foods.
I have no problem eating it--
sweetbreads, whatever.
My thing is just it's never,
like, amazing.
NIMA NABAVI: That's
what I'm saying.
EDDIE HUANG: It's
never eventful.
I'm like, this is all hype.
And that's why I don't bug
out over freak food.
NIMA NABAVI: Well, a lot of
it, too, is a lot of these
cultures, it was really like--
EDDIE HUANG: They enjoy it.
NIMA NABAVI: Well, it's
not even that.
It's like, we kill the sheep,
and we eat every part of it.
Like, my dad will come here
and swear he loves it.
EDDIE HUANG: What
do you got next?
NIMA NABAVI: Yo, next up, we're
gonna go have some real
Persian ice cream, man.
EDDIE HUANG: Dope.
NIMA NABAVI: Some real, real
shit you've never tried.
EDDIE HUANG: Persian
ice cream shop.
I'm ready, kid.
NIMA NABAVI: Alright, man.
EDDIE HUANG: I see
the saffron.
I'm getting saffron,
I already decided.
NIMA NABAVI: Did you?
EDDIE HUANG: Yeah.
All right, we'll try this
frozen, high fiber sorbet.
NIMA NABAVI: There ya go.
EDDIE HUANG: Can I do it with
the flavors, like I put
together or not?
ICE CREAM SERVER: Oh
yeah, that's how it
comes is this way.
EDDIE HUANG: Oh, good.
Are a lot of Persians
lactose intolerant?
NIMA NABAVI: Yup.
EDDIE HUANG: Because that
is an epidemic in my
neighborhood--
the milk farters.
Lot of milk farters
in Chinatown.
Thank you, sir.
NIMA NABAVI: Thank
you, [FARSI].
Oh, you're going to grow
a unibrow right now.
EDDIE HUANG: I think my
dick just got bigger.
This is like y'all's
shark's fin.
NIMA NABAVI: Yeah.
EDDIE HUANG: You know
what I mean?
Score 1,500, grandpa will
take you out for
some saffron ice cream.
NIMA NABAVI: There ya go.
EDDIE HUANG: Yo, so we ate
sandwiches, we looked at rugs.
NIMA NABAVI: True.
EDDIE HUANG: We ate ice cream.
NIMA NABAVI: Yes, sir.
EDDIE HUANG: How would
a Persian end this?
NIMA NABAVI: Definitely gotta
have some hookah.
EDDIE HUANG: OK.
NIMA NABAVI: So there's
a spot up here, it's
called Habibi Cafe.
We should go up there, meet some
homies, and fucking get
some smoking.
EDDIE HUANG: OK.
Eddie, nice to meet you.
FEMALE SPEAKER 2: Edgar.
EDDIE HUANG: Eddie.
You're Edgar?
You're Edgar.
Amazing.
Sexy.
This is nice, I like this.
I like this.
Where're you from?
FEMALE SPEAKER 2: We're
all Persian.
EDDIE HUANG: All Persian.
I'm glad you all came, because
otherwise, these Vice viewers
would've thought all
Persians were dudes
with unibrows, right?
NIMA NABAVI: Yeah.
EDDIE HUANG: Pretty much.
Oh wow.
He did put milk in the base.
NIMA NABAVI: I told you.
EDDIE HUANG: Oh,
it's an apple.
I did that in high school when
I couldn't buy pipes.
We were like, what
do Persians do?
And he was like, meet me at the
rug shop, then we're going
to go peep sandwiches, then
we're gonna eat ice cream.
I was like, dude.
FEMALE SPEAKER 2: Ok, those are
three things I've never
done in my life.
EDDIE HUANG: We went
to Persian LA.
It's like a good three to five
blocks, but it's really like a
bookstore, a music store, an ice
cream shop, a rug shop, a
sandwich shop.
You know, a collection
of business is not
necessarily a community.
You need the people in there.
You need the vigor, you need
the energy, you need the
sounds, you need the flavors.
You wish that this culture
would plant their flag a
little deeper in LA.
Next up on Fresh
off the Boat--
MALE SPEAKER: This fucking
salsa is so spicy, yo.
EDDIE HUANG: Dude, that chile
sauce is en fuego.
I'm not doing that.
My ass would be on fire
by like 7:00 PM.
Oh my god.