No strings at all.
We're doing the floating
bead trick.
See these beads?
Watch this.
They're gonna float
in the air.
[MYSTERIOUS MUSIC IMPRESSION]
Magic.
That's--
Hey, Higginsworth.
HIGGINSWORTH: Hang on, Steve.
Higginsworth.
Oh hey, mom.
No, I'm not busy.
We're just filming an episode.
Yeah, Steve's doing
his magic thing.
I guess.
STEVE SPANGLER: It is magic.
HIGGINSWORTH: Yeah.
No, it's not really
worth watching.
STEVE SPANGLER: No,
tell her to watch.
Watch, Mrs. Higginsworth.
HIGGINSWORTH: I gotta go.
All right.
Bye.
STEVE SPANGLER: Wrap it up.
Hold this.
We're doing magic.
[MYSTERIOUS MUSIC IMPRESSION]
STEVE SPANGLER NARRATING: I'm
Steve Spangler, and I'm all
about making science fun.
For the last 20 years, I've
been teaching ways to turn
ordinary science experiments
into unforgettable learning
experiences.
I have an amazing team who will
do whatever it takes to
affect the way people
think about science.
And to do that, I live
by one motto.
Make it big, do it right,
give it class.
STEVE SPANGLER: All
right, ready?
A little science magic.
This is good.
All right, get over here
and look at this.
See this in here?
No food coloring
in these cups.
See, no food coloring?
And water.
That's it.
Just water.
All right, so here's
what happens.
Watch this.
Whenever I pour with my right
hand, look at what happens.
[GASP]
It turns into Kool-Aid.
Wine?
I don't know what it is.
But when I pour with my left
hand, nothing at all.
Plain water.
When you pour it with
your right hand,
would you look at this?
This is amazing, I know
you're gonna say.
And if I pour with
my left hand.
[GASP]
Amazing.
It is amazing.
Watch this.
When you pour it in like
this, you get more.
And you get a little
bit more here.
And then you pour these
two in like this,
and watch what happens.
Ta-da!
Well, it's a pretty
easy thing to do.
This is a classic science trick
called "wine water." So
if you see it in the old
chemistry books, it was a
reaction called "wine water." In
today's day and age, you'd
probably call it,
I don't know.
Kool-Aid water?
You don't drink it in the first
place, so who knows what
to call it.
All I can tell you is it's a
cool color change, and it's an
acid base kind of indicator.
So, here's what you have to
start with-- four cups and a
container of water.
That's all I have.
And what we're actually doing is
we're causing it to change
color depending on
if something is
an acid or a base.
So you know what pH paper
is, it changes color.
Well, we're using a chemical
here called phenolphthalein.
Phenolphthalein is an indicator
that changes color
if a base is present.
And the base that we're going
to use is ammonia.
So whenever those two come in
contact with one another, you
get that characteristic
pink color.
So here's what we're gonna do.
The first thing is we're gonna
put a small amount of the
indicator in each
one of these.
So that's in the first
and the third cup.
Those are the ones that I
want to change color.
Now, we take a little of the
ammonia, and you put the
ammonia in over here.
So ammonia is a weak base.
So this works very
well over here.
So now, we're ready to go.
We had this color change at the
very end where everything
went colorless.
And so that means that
I had to put
something else in there.
And that's where the
vinegar comes in.
So, in the last cups here, the
second and the fourth cup, a
small amount of vinegar.
Nobody will see a color change
at all, but it's everything
that we need.
Perfect.
To color it back.
All right, quick aside.
Phenolphthalein is this
indicator, and if you befriend
a high school chemistry teacher,
he or she may have
some phenolphthalein to
be able to do it.
Instead of getting it from a
chemical supply company, a
long time ago people used to
take Ex-Lax and grind some
Ex-Lax up and add a little bit
of rubbing alcohol, and it's
because Ex-Lax contained
phenolphthalein.
That's not the case anymore,
so if you see stuff online
that says use phenolphthalein,
just realize that they don't
use the phenolphthalein
anymore.
You're gonna have to
befriend that high
school chemistry teacher.
[TRUMPET IMPRESSION]
It's show time.
So, you start with the
colorless, right, because
clear is not a color.
The colorless water here,
and the four cups.
Nobody will ever notice
what's inside.
Make sure they know there's not
food coloring, otherwise
it's not amazing to them.
So you say, whenever I
pour with this hand.
Whenever you see that color,
you know that it's
phenolphthalein.
Switch hands, of course
for the story.
Nothing happens here, because
all that's in there is a
little bit of that vinegar.
So when we pour this again, this
has the phenolphthalein.
Nice.
And this one pours in here.
That's great.
And you're done.
Now, you can do it
a different way.
You can have it change back
instantly and so I kind of
like this, to start with the
clear ones, to pour these in
the colorless ones.
Nice.
And now watch what happens when
you pour these two in.
It looks very cool.
And that's a cool way
to end the trick.
Why that's a cool science
magic trick?
A lot of kids have seen that
before because of a high
school chemistry class, and
it's an instant kind of
reaction, so that's what
leads us to this.
Watch.
Colorless, colorless.
When you pour them together,
they remain colorless.
Look at this.
Now I want you to cast
your thoughts.
No trick photography.
Bam.
That's cool.
And that's probably as close to
real magic in your hands as
you could ever imagine.
And it's just chemistry.
And there's somebody who taught
me how to do this years
ago, my dad.
I grew up in this family of
professional magicians, and I
think that it's probably a good
opportunity for us to go
on a little field trip and
see what the little Steve
household looked like
when I was a kid.
Let's go.
So, I wanna show you how this
whole thing started for me.
I grew up in this family
of magicians.
My mom and dad had regular
jobs, but they
also did some magic.
It's a little slice
of suburbia here.
So I wanted to show you the
home that I grew up in.
Mom and dad are probably, I
don't know, drinking coffee
and reading the paper.
Whatever it is that they do.
But the thing is, it's just
kind of a normal house and
well, it's kind of normal.
Going inside.
[MUSIC PLAYING LOUDLY]
STEVE SPANGLER: I should
probably also tell you this,
that, well, it's kind of normal,
but there's a full
theater organ and baby grand,
and they do these little
routines and shows.
We never really had guests for
dinner or anything, because
there's a full theater organ.
Hey, mom and dad, I'm
just gonna go down
to my uh, my room.
It's a little weird.
So, anyway, it's pretty normal,
and so I was just--
What did you do to my room?
Mom, dad!
[SIGHS]
This used to be my room.
And now there's magic tricks.
When did you guys move
out the furniture?
BRUCE: What was your
name again?
STEVE SPANGLER: Seriously,
when did you
move out the furniture?
This is uh--
when I left, there were some
pretty cool magic tricks in
the house, but this
is a little bit
bigger than when I left.
BRUCE: It was about 15 or 20
minutes we didn't know what we
were going to do with this room,
but this is the way it
turned out.
What do you think?
STEVE SPANGLER: Uh, I think
this has become
bigger than an obsession.
This is a--
KITTY: A disease.
STEVE SPANGLER: It
is a disease.
BRUCE: We used to think it was
a collection, and then Kitty
pointed out that collectors
collect antiques
or red things or--
we are accumulators.
We just accumulate stuff.
STEVE SPANGLER: It's
called hoarding.
BRUCE: What was that
word again?
STEVE SPANGLER: Nothing, it was
called, I am excited to be
able to say--
oh my gosh.
All right, when did you
start collecting?
Because you started doing
magic when you were--
BRUCE: Five.
STEVE SPANGLER: Five?
BRUCE: Still have my
first magic set.
STEVE SPANGLER: And so then
what happened from there?
So you started doing magic.
And then how do you feed this?
BRUCE: Well, I found a
magic shop downtown.
A lot of kids usually find their
way to a magic shop.
And on Saturdays, we went down
and the kids would all gather
in the basement, where we had
a little stage set up, and
we'd do tricks for each other.
That's how you learn
the magic.
And I was fortunate enough to
have a teacher at that time
who believed you never sold
your magic tricks.
We'd always want to sell a silk
handkerchief in order to
buy a little production box,
and he said, no, you don't
sell those.
Those are your kids.
Someday you're gonna need
everything you ever bought.
Well, this is some day.
STEVE SPANGLER: Yeah, this is.
Yeah, this is some day.
This is true.
BRUCE: These are all my
friends, you know.
STEVE SPANGLER: So,
how do magicians
pass down their equipment?
You didn't go to a magic shop
and buy all of this stuff, so
what is this a representation
of?
BRUCE: We have to
kill them off.
When they get to a certain
age, we arrange
to have them disappear.
STEVE SPANGLER: OK, please
cut that from
the record, all right?
Next.
Dad, where did you get these
cool magic tricks?
BRUCE: Well, we inherit them
from deceased magi.
STEVE SPANGLER: Yeah.
Which means that a magician
dies, and the kids are looking
at it, going, what do
I do with this crap?
BRUCE: That's right, and we say,
we like crap. and so we
agreed to keep them together
as collections of
their former magician.
And so that's what you see here,
collections that belong
to other magicians.
STEVE SPANGLER: So what I'm
noticing is that there are
things on the shelf now that are
collections, and there's a
person's name next to
each one of these.
How do you put all the
stuff together?
BRUCE: In some cases, we had
an agreement with a former
owner's wife or husband,
that we would keep
their collection together.
And so that's how this
collection is organized.
And it's unique in
that manner.
We don't think that there are
any other collections that are
maintained as collections
belonging
to a previous magician.
So you'll see lots of magic
wands because each magician
had his own magic wand.
You'll see lots of linking
rings, because every magician
has his favorite set
of linking rings.
And so that's what they are.
They're really preserved
as memories
of the former performer.
Virtually everything you see on
all of these shelves is not
what it appears to be.
You may see a drinking glass and
think, oh, that's a nice
glass, why is it in
the collection?
Well, it's because it's not
a common drinking glass.
There's something very
special about it.
It has threads, or motors, or
something that makes it
perform a specific job,
a specific feat.
STEVE SPANGLER: One of the
things that you taught me when
I was a kid was that you
practice a magic trick like a
coin vanishing, or here.
Like a ball that
may disappear.
And we would practice that for
hours and hours and hours.
BRUCE: Where the heck
did that go?
STEVE SPANGLER: Oh,
it's in my elbow.
But you would practice these
silly things for hours and--
[GASP]
it's in your ear, Dad.
I'm doing schtick.
But you would do this--
you would make me do this over
and over and over again until
I got it right.
And the only reward that you
would get is somebody to
either say, hey, do a trick,
or somebody will give you a
little smile and go,
that's cool.
But it's not like you're
trading this for money
necessarily, unless you're in
a big Vegas kind of thing.
Is that art still around?
Do you still see that dedication
with the kids that
are coming up today?
BRUCE: It's still a personal
challenge, and we have the
belief that nothing ever really
is good until you can
do it without thinking
about it.
That's why you see magicians
doing the slight of hand and
working with a deck
of cards or coins.
They're doing it over and over
and over to teach their brain
how to do when they're
doing something else.
When they're worried about, are
the lights right, or is
the music gonna start on time,
or is the stage crew going to
take something off when
they're supposed to.
So that's what they're doing.
They're practicing and teaching
that brain to do it
without really thinking
about it.
STEVE SPANGLER: I remember you
at a theater and peeking
behind the curtain and watching
you guys perform.
And then the very end is
you'd both eat fire.
And when you're five years old,
and your mom and dad eat
fire, it probably-- you win over
anybody else's parents.
So what did you do for
show and tell?
BRUCE: Well, it's what you did
for show and tell that got us
into trouble.
KITTY: You came home with
a note pinned on you.
STEVE SPANGLER: And what
did the note say?
BRUCE: The note said-- it was
from the principal, who said
we need to have a meeting.
And when we went to see the
principal of the grade school,
he said at show and tell, your
son told us that his parents
were fire eaters.
And we couldn't get him
to change his mind.
He insisted to the point of
having tears in his eyes.
And we think that maybe he needs
some psychological help.
STEVE SPANGLER: So how
do we cure that?
You came to school the next
week and ate fire.
But that's a whole
different time.
That doesn't happen now.
And let me tell you that the
counseling has been wonderful.
Honestly, I've got it all
out and I'm fine now.
BRUCE: And you know, they
rebuilt that school, and you
can't even tell that
there was a fire.
STEVE SPANGLER: No, and they
showed up so quickly, too.
And who would've thought.
Kids eating fire, and walking
on glass, or whatever else.
But maybe the best memory that I
have is bringing kids over--
not living in this house, but we
were in another house, and
bringing kids over, and there
were some blenders in the
basement because what
did you make, mom?
KITTY: We made stage blood.
STEVE SPANGLER: OK.
This is fake blood.
But it isn't any fake blood.
It's pretty special
fake blood.
KITTY: It's the best.
STEVE SPANGLER: Fake blood
in the whole world.
KITTY: It was micro
encapsulated.
So it didn't stain
your costumes.
When it dried, you just
brush it off.
STEVE SPANGLER: It's totally
a normal house.
I'm telling you, this stuff
happens to everybody.
You know what I want you to
do is show me a trick.
So there's got to be a cool
trick that you can show me.
Out of all these things
that are down
here, show me a trick.
BRUCE: You wanna see
something big time?
STEVE SPANGLER: Huge.
BRUCE: This is one of our
favorites back here.
This is a mummy cabinet that's
well over 50 years.
But you've got to help me.
If you and Kitty will help me.
You get that end.
I'll get this end.
We'll carry it outside and do
it outside, because it's too
cramped in here.
STEVE SPANGLER NARRATING:
No, we're not doing--
uh, no, you know what, Dad?
That's probably a really good
weekend project for Wayne or
Holly to help with, but I was
thinking, maybe you could do
just-- you and Mom could
do a little trick.
So Mom, you grab linking rings
and do the little ring thing
and show me what you're
working on.
Just do something small.
BRUCE: Well, that's
kind of nuts.
You don't want to see the
big illusion outside?
STEVE SPANGLER: Please.
Please just do something
small.
BRUCE: We've got something
with a bolt and a nut.
Would that work?
STEVE SPANGLER: Yeah,
that's perfect.
Let's do it.
BRUCE: All right, let's do it.
STEVE SPANGLER: I
love this stuff.
When's he's doing the small
stuff that he's working on.
BRUCE: Well, I told you it was
kind of nuts, and it is,
because we use a
bolt and a nut.
And what I'd like for you to
do is I'd like for you to
thread the nut onto the bolt.
About halfway would
be really good.
So you believe in
psychic things?
Telekinesis?
The power of the mind
to control objects?
STEVE SPANGLER: Of
course I do.
BRUCE: That's what we're
gonna try to do.
STEVE SPANGLER: All right.
BRUCE: Let me roll up my
sleeves as if I were a
professional.
STEVE SPANGLER: All right.
BRUCE: Now, the idea is to
concentrate on that--
oh, you're good.
You are really good.
Look at that.
That is amazing.
STEVE SPANGLER: There's no
threads or anything.
BRUCE: No.
This would be great if they used
these to build airplanes,
wouldn't it?
Then you'd just concentrate
on the plane and
the wing falls off.
STEVE SPANGLER: I was used to
him doing like three sponge
balls in my hand and then
there's rabbits.
And now there's a bolt
that comes off.
This is good.
BRUCE: Well, this is the way
we develop a routine, is we
practice and practice
and practice.
STEVE SPANGLER: Are you
concentrating with your mind
again to make that happen?
BRUCE: Oh, yes, absolutely.
STEVE SPANGLER: I can tell.
BRUCE: Communicating
with the spirits.
That's it.
STEVE SPANGLER: It's cool.
Magic is so cool.
Mom, do this, would you?
Do the ring thing.
Is that totally cool or what?
All right, when your
mom can [GASP]
Do you understand that birthday
parties were so
awesome at my house?
They were.
So when I was a kid, I remember
mom and dad making
these magic products.
So in addition to having the
magic school, they had these
magic products.
And so, this was
their catalog.
You have to remember this
is back in the '70s.
And inside the catalog, there
are these things about-- oh,
you remember that, the fake
blood that they were talking
about before?
But there's a whole line of
chemical magic tricks.
And I guess what was
cool is that--
I didn't realize this,
but when--
our YouTube viewers know Doug
Hotis, my chemistry teacher--
I remember getting to blow him
away when he did the classic
wine water that you just
saw where you turn the
water into the wine.
But I did your version,
and he had never seen
anything like that.
So what was the thought behind
creating a whole new line of
chemical magic for magicians?
BRUCE: Well, the whole idea
of bringing magic into the
classroom is--
we kind of go along with what
Socrates said, that wisdom
begins in wonder.
Once you get a kid
to ask, how?
How did that happen?
Why did that happen?
They're fully engaged.
The mind is open, and they're
ready then to learn something.
So we wanted to do something
that was a little different.
What they used back in those
early days was an indicator
dye that had a characteristic
pink color that's not like
anything else.
STEVE SPANGLER: Yeah, that's
exactly what they saw.
I was telling them about
grinding up the Ex-Lax and
creating the phenolphthalein.
BRUCE: So the way to change
that into a magic trick is
change the color, which is a
little harder to do, or change
the way it reacts.
And so we decided to
do the latter.
We wanted to change
the reactions.
Would you like for
me to show you?
STEVE SPANGLER: Yeah,
of course.
I'm setting you up for this.
I'm your straight man.
BRUCE: I guess.
OK, well, we start
out now with two
perfectly clear liquids.
STEVE SPANGLER: Got it.
BRUCE: OK.
And normally, when you mix those
together, you would get
an instant color change.
But you'll notice that
they remain clear.
The chemicals are fully mixed.
But they remain clear.
STEVE SPANGLER: It's just
a glass of water.
BRUCE: That's right.
We don't have to secretly add a
little dye to it or do some
of the things that we
used to have to do.
And so we have is a timed
chemical reaction.
It takes it from a science
demonstration, the typical
science demonstration.
Although many teachers
use this now
because it's in the books.
And you sell it, too.
STEVE SPANGLER NARRATING:
Yeah, a different
version of it, yeah.
You gotta carry on
the tradition.
This was very amazing.
When I walked into Doug Hotis's
class, it was an
instant reputation builder
because I said, watch this.
And immediately, I went from a
junior in high school that's
just screwing around to "get
over here, kid, I need to see
this." And that was the
beginning of that
relationship.
BRUCE: And one of the things
you said was, we need to do
something patriotic.
Can you do this in red,
white, and blue?
And so then, we added the
second part of it.
We added the red dye, changed
this pink to red, and used
blue, and actually produced a
milk-like white change, using
the same family of reactions.
STEVE SPANGLER: All right, let's
do it again and explain
the science.
BRUCE: All right.
We actually have created a
little war here between two
sets of chemicals.
They're gonna fight
for dominance.
When we mix them together, the
chemicals that produce an acid
are struggling to dominate
over those
that produce a base.
And it takes some time for
that little war to go on.
So that's what you're seeing.
STEVE SPANGLER: So they would
teach a reaction like this
when they're doing redox
reactions or whatever.
BRUCE: It's an oxidation
reduction reaction.
That's right.
So, we've got-- our dye is
actually in here, which is
colorless in its neutral
or acidic state.
So this one is slightly
acidic.
This over here contains a
reducing agent which is going
to produce this little war.
Should we do it?
STEVE SPANGLER: Yep, do it.
BRUCE: All right.
So now, that starts
the reaction.
And we're pouring it back and
forth to show how clean it is,
in terms of no gimmicks
or dyes.
But we're also giving it a
chance to mix absolutely
thoroughly, so that we get
a nice color change.
STEVE SPANGLER: So when you
produced a product called
Splash of Color, you had eight
full colors of the rainbow.
BRUCE: Isn't that crazy?
STEVE SPANGLER: I know.
BRUCE: Who in their right
mind would do that?
STEVE SPANGLER: It was hard.
Because how great-- and you
need to know that there's
teachers today in the classroom
doing a version of
that to a Kermit the Frog kind
of song, "The Rainbow Song."
But not as a time delay.
It's when they touch it, that
time delay all the way across
is absolutely gorgeous.
BRUCE: You think the teachers
were amazed?
You should've seen
the magicians.
They had never seen anything
like this.
They were accustomed to the--
well, they had a thing called
Think Ink, which was clear to
black and this color, and that
was about it.
There were a few other
variations.
But to have seven or eight
clocked reactions all going at
the same time and eight glasses,
goblets changing
color, bing bing
bing bing bing.
They had never seen anything
like that before.
So we took the science into the
magic community, rather
than the other way around.
STEVE SPANGLER: I remember as a
kid, mom and dad were on one
of the big shows, a big magic
show for magicians, and we
were in Kansas City, Missouri.
And I remember seeing
you backstage.
And I'd never seen you
in this state before,
because you were flustered.
And the pH of the water was
different in Kansas City than
it was here in Denver.
And when you went to do the
reaction, it wasn't timed
correctly to the music.
And so you literally had to
change the pH of the water and
try to buffer that for the
reaction, so it would time up
with the music.
BRUCE: And not only that, the
water had been softened, so
they had added chemicals to it,
which affected not only
the pH, but the oxidation
reduction reaction
that was going on.
So we had to literally reinvent
the chemistry on the
spot for a show that night.
And it worked out pretty
well, didn't it?
STEVE SPANGLER: It was great.
It's one of those things
I'll never forget.
There's a classic that you
do that really is yours.
Nobody's ever done it, and
it's a thing called
Switcheroo.
And so if you don't mind,
let's see Switcheroo.
BRUCE: Let's set it up.
STEVE SPANGLER: All right,
so this will
go down as a classic.
This is your signature
demonstration in my mind.
BRUCE: All right.
STEVE SPANGLER: OK, so do it
the way you do it for kids.
BRUCE: Well, in the classroom,
we ask the kids if they know
what a chameleon is.
Now, almost all the kids know
Most of them tell
us it's somebody
who tells funny stories.
And then we tell them, no,
that's a comedian.
STEVE SPANGLER: Got it.
BRUCE: OK, but then they get
the chameleon thing right.
We tell them we didn't bring
any live animals.
But we did bring a
chameleon color.
This is a yellow chameleon
color.
I think we set this up wrong.
It's in the wrong color glass.
Chameleons--
STEVE SPANGLER: It's
in the red glass.
BRUCE: Yeah, they like to
blend in with their
background.
If you'll hang on to this, let
me see what we have over here.
Oh, this is another chameleon
color, but it also is in the
wrong color glass.
STEVE SPANGLER: He's doing
schtick right now.
BRUCE: There's another
problem.
STEVE SPANGLER: Yes.
BRUCE: I know we've had
a water shortage.
STEVE SPANGLER: Of course
we have, Dad.
I mean, Mr. Magician.
BRUCE: With all these people
watching, don't you think we
could feel these
up to the top?
STEVE SPANGLER: And we should.
BRUCE: That way, everybody can
see, Those that are close to
the set, and those
farther away.
So let's fill this one
up to the very top.
STEVE SPANGLER: So there's
red in the yellow glass.
BRUCE: And yellow in
the red glass.
STEVE SPANGLER: So this
is very wrong.
BRUCE: This is like an optical
illusion, a trick of the eyes.
So keep them separate here.
That's right.
So everybody knows where
the yellow one is
and the red one is.
And we're going to bring them
closer together, without
letting them touch, because
that would be cheating.
And you keep one eye on the
yellow glass, one-- or the red
yellow chameleon.
One eye on the red, and
the other eye on you.
STEVE SPANGLER: Whatever
it might be.
BRUCE: We're short a couple
of eyes there, aren't we.
And it gets harder and harder
to tell which one's the red
one and which one's
the yellow one.
But as you stare at it, you
begin to see why we call it
the chameleon colors,
because the red has
gone to the red glass.
STEVE SPANGLER: Yes.
BRUCE: The yellow one here's
starting to look a little
orange-ish.
STEVE SPANGLER: Yes.
BRUCE: And now we can
move it away.
STEVE SPANGLER: Look at this.
There it is.
Red over here in this glass.
Yellow sits over here
in this glass.
BRUCE: And it will continue to
get yellower and yellower as
it stills there for
a little while.
STEVE SPANGLER: That's when
the kids applaud and--
there it is, right there.
That's perfect.
Would you look at that?
It's all in the story.
Yellow is over here,
red's over here.
BRUCE: And that it gives us an
opportunity then to talk to
them about oxidation
reduction reactions
and acid base reactions.
STEVE SPANGLER: But you forgot,
nobody actually cares.
They're just going, they changed
color, and you're
trying to say oxidation
reaction.
But they could care less.
They're looking at this thing.
BRUCE: The important thing is
that they start to wonder and
they start to ask questions.
And that's when the mind
is open and we can
start feeding them.
STEVE SPANGLER: Cheers.
BRUCE: Don't drink that!
Never drink your experiments.
STEVE SPANGLER: OK, Dad.
BRUCE: It's a rule.
STEVE SPANGLER: Well, I'll
probably go down with somebody
going, Mentos and Diet Coke.
You, however, are much better
than Mentos and Diet Coke.
You invented fake blood.
This is the stuff that you sold
to Universal Studios and
Paramount Pictures.
You used to make it
in the basement.
That was the coolest thing, is
you'd bring friends over to
the basement and you had these
blenders that were set up.
So how'd you get into
the blood business?
How'd you make fake blood?
BRUCE: Back in the '50s,
Universal Studios came out
with a movie called Macumba
Love, which was about voodoo.
And it was, I guess, a B-rated
movie would be--
KITTY: Not good.
BRUCE: Not the greatest movie.
But they wanted something
to promote the movie.
They wanted something--
back in those days, you'd do
something in the lobby or out
in front of the theater.
And kids on Saturday with some
money to spend would say, oh,
I think I wanna go
see that movie.
STEVE SPANGLER: Because how much
was a movie back then?
BRUCE: A quarter.
STEVE SPANGLER: It's pretty
close to that
now, so it's fine.
BRUCE: Yeah, and popcorn
was a dime.
STEVE SPANGLER: Yeah,
I got it.
BRUCE: Dinosaurs roamed
the earth.
STEVE SPANGLER: Yeah, the
earth was still cooling.
So, you're a barker.
So there'd be a show out in
front of the theater and you
created it.
So what year was that that
this all happened?
BRUCE: Oh, I'm thinking 1959.
STEVE SPANGLER: So what was your
voodoo trick that you had
to come up with?
BRUCE: You simply cleaned off
your arm, you took a needle,
and you shoved it through
your arm.
STEVE SPANGLER: That's
a great trick.
And then you marketed it under
the name You-Do Voodoo.
It wasn't invented to
be a magic trick.
It was invented to be
something to draw
people into the movie.
KITTY: A geek trick.
BRUCE: A geek trick.
A geek stunt.
So we took it down.
I was working in a magic
shop at the time.
We took it down to the shop and
packaged it up and put it
on the counter to see if
anybody would buy it.
And lo and behold, the magicians
thought it was a
magic trick.
And so we started making them
up a dozen at a time.
This is one of few tricks that
have survived all these years,
over 50, 60 years.
KITTY: We've made thousands
of them.
STEVE SPANGLER: But you don't
make them anymore, right?
So people online--
you can find them on eBay so
you're gonna pay a pretty
penny for one of these.
The kicker was, it really
fooled people.
It fooled doctors and nurses.
It really looked like you were
putting a needle in here and
coming out here.
We're not gonna be gory
on this, but--
BRUCE: One of the neatest things
to do is, when you go
in for your annual and you get
a blood check, and the
phlebotomist comes in, and
she says, now this
won't hurt a bit.
And you say, wait, I'll get it
for you here and you shove the
needle in your arm and you
get blood gushing.
STEVE SPANGLER: Do you see
why I had to be in
therapy going around?
Do you see why the three of us,
my sister and brother--
got it from them.
All right, so here, let's take
a look at the blood.
The blood was very cool.
I remember as a kid putting
blood in containers like this.
This blood's very cool,
so I'll put it on me.
But I want you to talk a little
bit about the blood.
How is this different than the
blood that you would just
make, like for Halloween?
BRUCE: We needed blood that
would look good in sunlight,
would not change color when you
brought it indoors, under
incandescent light or
fluorescent lights, that would
run smoothly across the skin,
and most importantly, if you
happen to get it on a
multi-thousand dollar
wardrobe, you had to be
able to get it out.
Well, all of the pigment in
this blood is sealed up in
tiny little capsules,
microscopic capsules
about the size of--
STEVE SPANGLER: No, I just
did that finger.
It was the wrong one.
BRUCE: --a human bloody
corpuscle.
And when they dry, you
can just brush
it off of your clothes.
STEVE SPANGLER: It
looks so good.
BRUCE: It just doesn't strain.
STEVE SPANGLER: I had a chance
to be able to see Frank Oz
here recently, you know,
with the Muppet fame.
And Jim Henson used to use your
blood for the puppets,
because there's very thin little
tubes, almost like
capillary-like tubes.
And when you look at it this
way, look, this is a whole
blood shelf.
See this?
A shelf with blood tricks.
Look at this.
This is what blew people away,
because it really looked like
there were serum and plasma.
Correct?
BRUCE: You can see that all of
the color separates to the
bottom, as it should.
KITTY: And when it dries,
you just brush it off.
STEVE SPANGLER: And not
available anymore.
BRUCE: Not available anymore.
STEVE SPANGLER: Yeah,
That's done.
This is very cool.
I've got to go see what else
you did to my room.
KITTY: What did you
do to this thing?
STEVE SPANGLER: Where's
the ping pong table?
Where's the ping pong table?
Well, I hope you enjoyed our
little trip down memory lane.
Kind of the normal house
I grew up in,
normal family, you know.
She even took down my Farrah
Fawcett poster.
There's nothing of
my room left.
Is this really how we
have to end this?
KITTY: Yeah.
Put that in there.
STEVE SPANGLER: I know, I've
done the routine before.
BRUCE: Remember all those years
you used to terrorize
your sister with this thing?
KITTY: You were so
mean to her.
STEVE SPANGLER: I know, but
she was mean to me.
BRUCE: It's payback time.
STEVE SPANGLER: All right.
BRUCE: Here we go.
One, two, three.
STEVE SPANGLER: Give me that.
Radioshack.
Magicians.
Can you get me out
of here, please?
BRUCE: Let's go play
in the street.
STEVE SPANGLER: No.
Can you guys get me out
of here, please?
BRUCE: No.
KITTY: We're going to
go play a song.
STEVE SPANGLER: Come on, guys.
Hey, this isn't funny.
Call Holly right now.
Hey!
Don't play your dumb
songs again.
Just get me out of here.
Lunch.