Take a look at the side there.
It's like a science lab.
Look at iron.
100% of your recommended
daily allowance.
Is that true?
Is there really iron in
breakfast cereal?
Only one way to find out.
You're going to be buying
a box soon, trust me.
I'm Steve Spangler, and I'm all
about making science fun.
For the last 20 years, I've
been teaching ways to turn
ordinary science experiments
into unforgettable learning
experiences.
I have an amazing team who will
do whatever it takes to
affect the way people
think about science.
And to do that, I live
by one motto.
Make it big, do it right,
give it class.
So the only way to figure out
whether or not this iron is
actually metallic
iron is to do a
little test with a magnet.
Now an ordinary magnet doesn't
seem to work that well, so if
you want the best results
possible, you're going to need
one of these.
It's a really, really
strong magnet.
You can see how it jumps
to and attaches to
anything like this.
And in fact, if you have one
magnet in your hand like this,
you can actually attract
the second magnet and
you see what happens.
This can be very, very dangerous
because if you try
to pull one magnet off and it
jumps up into the other one,
it can actually pinch
your fingers.
That's why I recommend storing
the magnets using this
particular method here.
Just take a tennis ball
and cut it open here.
So cut open the tennis ball
like this, and drop the
neodymium into the
tennis ball.
You can seal it back up with a
little glue if you want to,
but this is just the way that I
store them, because they're
easy to be able to
hook together--
and, here, that's kind of fun.
So watch this.
You can mess with people
like this.
You try to do the
balancing trick.
Remember I've got one
here and one here.
So here, watch this.
Isn't that awe--
ah, see, you can kind of
see how that works.
But what a great way to be
able to hold on to the
neodymium magnets without
pinching them accidentally
between your layer of skin.
And just a great way to be able
to mess with people at
the same time.
All right, so let's
start with this.
Simply open up the box
of Total cereal.
If you're doing this for
somebody, they're going to
think that you tampered with it,
so you really should show
them that you're opening
up the cereal.
So here is, unopened,
from the factory.
There is our cereal.
Take out a couple flakes
here like this.
If it's magnetic, then we should
be able to just pick up
the cereal using the magnet.
So, to isolate it--
here, let me hang onto
it like this.
Let's just crush it up.
All right, and so you should
be able to just pick up the
cereal, and of course, you can
see that we're no luck picking
up the cereal, unless you
look very, very closely.
Watch and look at the edges of
the cereal, you start to see,
right around the edge here--
what could either be static
electricity--
or maybe there really is iron
in that breakfast cereal.
Smashing them is not going
to convince anybody.
I don't think that's a true
test if there's iron in
breakfast cereal.
So try this.
Try reaching in and getting
some huge flakes,
and let's do this.
Let's see whether or not we can
attract them using a dish
of water, all right.
So here's our plate
with water.
The object here is that we want
an environment with as
little friction as possible.
So we're going to take the
flakes and just float them on
the surface of the
water like this.
Now watch what happens when we
get our magnet close to it.
Let me stay away,
and watch what
happens when we get close.
Now, the skeptic will say that
you're blowing on the flake,
but you're not.
Look at this, let's see if I can
get this one and actually
pull it over.
Nice.
So they're kind of ice skating
flakes, right, but it really
is just water--
I'll pull this one over
here as well--
which must mean that there is
a little bit of iron, or at
least the hypothesis would be
there's just a little bit of
iron in each and every
one of those flakes.
It's not conclusive proof,
but it is very cool.
And the only way to really see
whether or not there's iron in
Total cereal is either to take
it to a lab, or, maybe better,
we could just get somebody to
eat a bowl of cereal, then we
just remove the contents
of their stomach--
I think I got a better way.
We'll use a model.
A Ziploc bag will be
perfect for this.
So you're going to want a heavy
duty Ziploc bag, and the
suggestion here is this.
Open up the Ziploc bag, and
you're going to put about a
cup of Total cereal
in the Ziploc bag.
Now they say on the side of
the package that a cup of
cereal is equal to
one serving.
And so I'm just going to
estimate that that's about a
serving, one cup.
The next part is we've got to
liquefy the cereal, so take
water and fill the
bag with water.
Probably half to three quarters
full with water seems
to be just about right.
If it doesn't work
for you, chances
are it was too soup-like.
You need to have it far more
runny, like water.
Seal it up.
Make sure there's a little bit
of air inside like this.
And now, we just need
to shake it around.
We're going to let it sit,
believe it or not, for a half
hour to 45 minutes, because we
really want it to dissolve.
Now you could crush the cereal
ahead of time, but I think the
cleanest way to do it, and the
most conclusive way so people
don't think that you've tampered
with it, is to just
set it out here and let it
dissolve and come back to it
in a half an hour
or 45 minutes.
Otherwise, I'll just
keep on doing this.
There's a half an hour of my
life I'll never get back.
Look, I got it to you the
way that it needs to be.
Look at this.
You want it soup-like.
Fair enough?
All right.
So now you need the magnet.
So here's the technique.
Take the magnet, put it on your
hand, put the bag on top
of the magnet like this.
And now, shake it around.
You're trying to make contact
with as much of the cereal as
you can with that magnet.
Notice how there's a little bit
of air in the bag as well,
so that when we turn it over,
we can actually see what
happens without it falling
back down.
Turn the whole thing
upside down.
And now what I'm going to do is
get in there with this so
I'm not messing around
with it with my hand.
Look at this.
There's the iron in
the Total cereal.
It's actually called "roughly
sheared ingot iron." This is
food-grade metallic iron that
they put it in cereals, they
put it in breads, they put
it in other foods.
The FDA completely allows this,
and this is how they
iron fortify a food.
However, somebody who's much
smarter than I am said that
you'd have to eat the
equivalent of--
I don't know--
4,000 or 5,000 boxes of Total
cereal during a given day to
make enough iron to actually
produce a nail.
So, I think you probably
already knew that.
But, the idea is probably there,
and very, very cool.
If you look at what you're
putting inside your body,
there's a huge debate
over this iron.
Is it good for you, number
one, and is it
beneficial for you?
Just because they put it
inside, is it truly
beneficial.
But most importantly, it's just
a lot of fun to sit here
and to play with it.
Most people don't know that you
can take the iron out of
Total cereal, so it makes for
a very, very cool project.
Now, if this is the only cereal
that you test, it's not
a very good science
fair project.
If you're looking for something
like this for a
science fair project,
compare all of these
cereals over here.
As you take a look at the iron
level on all of these cereals,
you can see that on some of
them, it's as low as 45% over
here, and as high as 90% here
for like Shredded Wheat.
The real debate, and the
feedback I'd like to hear from
you is whether you think that's
beneficial for your
body, but maybe more
importantly, can your body
actually process this
reduced iron.
It its raw, metallic form, does
your body process it and
put it into a form that's usable
by your body for the
iron that you need.
It's the number one elemental
deficiency in the world.
Women need four times the amount
of iron that men do.
But it's just very, very cool
from a food science standpoint
to see that this is how they
iron fortify our food.
So when you were a kid and the
teacher said, play that game,
magnetic or not.
Like in second grade, you'd have
to go around and touch
things that were magnetic or
not, and then everybody always
ruined the TV, because
some dumb kid put
it on the TV, and--
hope that wasn't you.
So money was the thing that they
always put down and say,
is money magnetic or not.
Well of course, in the United
States, it's not, in Canada
firm, some of the money
is magnetic.
But that's not necessarily
true.
That dollar bill that
you see right there.
Magnetic or not?
Answer is, magnetic.
And I'll show you how.
Well we're back to our friend,
the neodymium magnet, and let
me put it on the knife there,
so that we can get it close.
Here, watch this.
I'm going to lift up the
dollar bill like this.
And watch what happens
as we get close.
As you get close to
the dollar bill--
no, it's not static
electricity--
it's actually the iron that's
in the dollar bill.
The iron is in the ink
of the dollar bill.
And it's one of the ways they
tell whether or not the dollar
bill is counterfeit.
So, I'm told-- although I don't
know if this is true--
that some of the vending
machines actually have an
electromagnetic circuit in
there, so that if you put just
a regular piece of paper or a
fake bill in and it doesn't
sense the iron, then that's
when the alarm goes off.
It could be just a myth, but
it kind of makes sense that
there's iron there
in that ink.
But is it the kind of iron
that you can actually
pull out and see?
Are there little
pieces of iron?
Back to the trusty
blender we go.
Oh, there you go, perfect.
Once again, we are not going to
go to jail, because we're
not going to try to
pass this money.
We're going to grind it up, we
are going to destroy it.
But we're not going to take
it and put it back into
circulation.
It's ours, and according to
the law, we can do this.
Is that right?
They said yes.
Here we go.
[BLENDING SOUND]
Now the problem with this is
you're to really going to
grind it up, so if I were
you, I would just
kind of let it go.
Not really much you
can do right now.
You're just going to have
to grind it up.
What we're trying to do is to
rip the fibers of this apart.
You will never be able to use
this blender for food again.
It's just too gross, right.
But this is exactly what
you want to see inside.
See how it's ground up and
it's almost held in
suspension.
And now it goes into
the Ziploc bag.
This is just disgusting
if you think about
how dirty money is.
All right, the money goes
into here like this.
Try to get all of it.
Hopefully there's not
much left over.
Good.
And now seal it up.
Treat it just like you did the
Total cereal for "Eating Nails
for Breakfast."
Now we're going to take our
neodymium magnet and put it on
top here, turn it upside
down, rock it around.
Take a look at this here.
Oh, this looks great.
Take a look at this, watch.
Here is the iron in
your dollar bill.
It's more impressive than
the Total cereal.
Look at this.
The iron in the ink is fairly
easy to be able to pull out.
The question always comes up,
does it only work with a
dollar bill.
And I have no idea.
So, as a response video, go
ahead and try it with $5 or
$10, o $20, or maybe some of
you wealthy ones out there,
try it with a hundred dollar
bill, post the response there.
Of course we will not
make fun of you.
All in scientific inquiry.
Just stick with a dollar.
And when you're all done, get
yourself a gallon of Clorox
and more hand sanitizer then
you could ever imagine,
because you've got
to clean up.
This is disgusting.
Well if you enjoyed this week's
episode, go ahead and
click the Subscribe button here,
and you'll be the first
to know when a brand new episode
appears each week.
This button right here will
show you some more cool
science experiments that we
do outside of this show.
This button right here will
take you to last week's
episode just in case
you missed it.
And if you want to see the stuff
that you shouldn't see,
that's the bloopers and the
outtakes, well, just click
this one right over here.
And if you want to hear me
stop talking, through the
magic of television, just click
this button right here.
Go ahead, click it
and I'll stop.
[MUSIC PLAYING]