SUROOSH ALVI: So we're
here in Baghdad.
Right down there, that's
Firdos Square.
That's where the famous scene
took place where Saddam
Hussein's statue was
pulled down.
We came here in 2006 when we
filmed "Heavy Metal in
Baghdad." It was a very, very
different city then.
It was the height of
the insurgency.
It was a war zone,
full occupation.
And that occupation
is now over.
A year ago, America pulled
out their troops.
BARACK OBAMA: Tonight, I am
announcing that the American
combat mission in
Iraq has ended.
Operation Iraqi Freedom
is over.
Last February, I announced a
plan that would bring our
combat brigades out of Iraq
while redoubling our efforts
to strengthen Iraq's security
forces and support its
government and people.
That's what we've done.
SUROOSH ALVI: We found it
strange that Baghdad is not in
the news at all these days.
What happened?
It was the biggest news
story in the world
for almost a decade.
And then overnight, it's over.
So we wanted to come here and
see what the effects of this
occupation were.
When the Americans left, Prime
Minister Nouri Al-Maliki
intensified his efforts to
consolidate power among the
Shia majority.
The Sunni minority, a group that
enjoyed great privilege
under Saddam Hussein have
been marginalized.
Naturally, the Sunnis are not
taking this lying down.
-[SPEAKING ARABIC]
[CROWD CALLING OUT IN UNISON]
[MUSIC PLAYING THROUGH
LOUDSPEAKERS]
SUROOSH ALVI: Massive protests
in Sunni areas and a surge of
sectarian killings throughout
the country become the new
normal in postwar Iraq.
In 2012 alone, there were
more than 1,600 deaths.
Through making "Heavy Metal in
Baghdad," we met Waleed, the
original singer of
Acrassicauda.
At the time, they were the
only metal band in Iraq.
[METAL MUSIC PLAYING]
SUROOSH ALVI: But shortly after
that meeting, Waleed was
forced to flee the country and
seek refugee status in the
West after receiving numerous
death threats.
With the war officially over,
Waleed decided it was time to
return to Iraq.
It would be his first visit home
since he left in 2004.
We sent a cameraman to accompany
him on his trip and
made plans to meet up with
him once we arrived.
[LAUGHING]
-[SPEAKING ARABIC]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
WALEED NESYIF: I don't even know
what I'm going to do when
I see my mother.
[ARABIC].
-[SPEAKING ARABIC]
[WHISTLING]
[SINGING]
SUROOSH ALVI: We arrived in
Baghdad a few hours after
Waleed and were headed
to the guest house
where we'd be staying.
But that's when we ran into
the Karrada Bats.
They're a group of young
punks who are
basically totally insane.
[PUNK MUSIC PLAYING]
SUROOSH ALVI: We're with a
Baghdadi biker gang, we were
wondering, what to kids
in Baghdad do for fun?
Well, this is it.
A variety of different
styles--
this hybrid soccer player meets
Mad Max look, which is
my personal favorite.
Then there's this guy who's
got the full on Fox racing
gear, leather from
head to toe.
This guy's riding with his
flip flops-- doesn't seem
totally wise.
I worry about that guy.
I'm not sure he's going
to survive the day.
So you guys are the
Karrada Bats.
Are there other gangs in other
cities, like Sadr City?
-[SPEAKING ARABIC]
SUROOSH ALVI: So do you ever get
in trouble with the cops?
-[SPEAKING ARABIC]
SUROOSH ALVI: Do
they chase you?
-[SPEAKING ARABIC]
SUROOSH ALVI: What happened?
[BIKE  GANG REVVING]
-[SPEAKING ARABIC]
SUROOSH ALVI: You guys have more
freedom now or before?
-[SPEAKING ARABIC]
SUROOSH ALVI: These
contradictory sentiments, of
wanting freedom but at the same
time missing of rule of
Saddam Hussein was something we
would hear again and again.
And while these guys longed for
American style liberties--
at least surface level
liberties, like looking and
dressing like maniacs--
it was clear that at least some
of them would trade it
all in for the stability that
they enjoyed during Saddam
Hussein's notoriously
cruel regime.
[ROCK MUSIC PLAYING]
Since it was the Muslim holy
month of Muharram, which is
especially significant for
the Shia, we decided to
head to Sadr City.
It's Friday.
We're going to check
out the big prayer.
The prayer leaves a
sight to be seen.
Everybody prays on the streets
for a huge distance-- the
mosque all the way up.
Now, just a few years back, the
idea of westerners paying
a little visit to Sadr City
would have been unthinkable,
as it was the heart of the
insurgency against the
American occupation, the home
of firebrand cleric Muqtada
Al-Sadr and his Mahdi Army.
Even now, it took a lot of work
and a Mahdi Army escort
to get us in.
It's supposedly forbidden to
fight during the month of
Muharram, but with heightened
Sunni-Shia tensions, the Iraqi
army thought it was a good idea
to have the bomb squad
present just in case.
-[SPEAKING ARABIC]
SUROOSH ALVI: More than 13,000
people turned out to pray and
to listen to a cleric who
influences the attitudes of an
even greater number of
Iraq's Shia majority.
MITHAL AL-HASNAWI:
[SPEAKING ARABIC]
SUROOSH ALVI: How do you feel
about the westernization of
the Iraqi youth since the
American occupation and since
they've left.
MITHAL AL-HASNAWI:
[SPEAKING ARABIC]
SUROOSH ALVI: The cleric made
it clear that getting the US
out of Iraq wasn't enough.
He wants to eliminate American
influence of any kind.
We headed back to the
neighborhood of Karrada to
meet up with Waleed and get
a tour of his old haunts.
Hey, welcome to Iraq, buddy.
Welcome home.
WALEED NESYIF: Thank you.
SUROOSH ALVI: Waleed wanted to
check out Acrassicauda's old
practice space--
that is, if we could find it.
There's a strange feeling
walking around, considering
the last time I was here, I
wasn't even allowed to get out
of our armored car.
WALEED NESYIF: It's been a very,
very long since I last
walked this street.
But this is filled with memories
of starving nights
with the band hitting the shit
out of the instruments,
rocking out and trying to figure
out how the fuck are we
going to go back home?
SUROOSH ALVI: So this is
basically 10 years ago.
WALEED NESYIF: Yeah.
This is it.
SUROOSH ALVI: It's
been rebuilt.
WALEED NESYIF: Yeah.
It's completely changed now.
SUROOSH ALVI: It's like
art galleries.
WALEED NESYIF: Yeah.
SUROOSH ALVI: If we hadn't been
sure this was the spot,
we would have walked
right by it.
The practice based got
completely bombed out during
the war, and today, it's
unrecognizable, which I guess
is a good thing.
WALEED NESYIF: The area changed
so much that it looks
completely different.
SUROOSH ALVI: Waleed wanted to
see if his childhood home was
still standing.
But on our way there, we were
reintroduced to one of the
most notorious features
of Baghdad--
checkpoints.
Car bombs are such an issue in
Baghdad that hundreds of the
points that were originally
established by the American
military are still
in place today.
WALEED NESYIF: Look at this
fucking shit, man.
Have you noticed every street
has a check point?
Every area has a checkpoint
of entrance and exit.
It's so sad.
Literally, you have to plan
your day to the T.
SUROOSH ALVI: Because it
slows everything down.
WALEED NESYIF: Yeah.
SUROOSH ALVI: Not only does
it make getting around a
nightmare, but doing anything
other than staring straight
ahead and hoping you get through
can throw your entire
day into a tailspin.
Put it down.
What are they saying?
You can't film?
WALEED NESYIF: Exaclty.
They're like, don't film
near a police patrol.
SUROOSH ALVI: After inspecting
our press credentials and
undergoing a thorough search, we
were allowed to slowly make
our way to Waleed's old house.
WALEED NESYIF: Everything
is blockaded.
You can't really access the
house or the neighborhood.
So we had to around, go all the
way back, and then come
through here.
SUROOSH ALVI: Did it get bombed,
this neighborhood?
WALEED NESYIF: Yeah.
And it looks pretty
fucking different.
That is pretty fucking insane.
This used to be my
old library.
Fuck.
[ACOUSTIC GUITAR
MUSIC PLAYING]
WALEED NESYIF: Looks like
a fucking junkyard, man.
SUROOSH ALVI: Right before
Waleed left the country, he
received a series of
death threats.
His work as a fixer for foreign
journalists and as a
member of a heavy metal band
made him a target.
WALEED NESYIF: I'll show
you right here.
So at 6:00 in the morning,
I would leave.
And there was a note right
here, an envelope--
right here.
And when I opened it, it was a
very, very frank letter of we
shall cleanse the soil of our
country from the stench of
people like you.
So I went kind of crazy and I
went into the street and I
started screaming and yelling--
like, if you're a
man, just going come
up right now.
I came back after two weeks.
And I left at a different
time, this
time, in the morning.
And there was another
one of those.
SUROOSH ALVI: Waiting for
you when you walked in.
WALEED NESYIF: Waiting for me.
So what I realized is that the
person who had dropped it had
to have been watching over from
somewhere around here
where he can see me leaving the
apartment and going down.
And that's when I knew that
the danger was very, very
imminent on my family
because of me.
SUROOSH ALVI: Right.
WALEED NESYIF: So yeah,
three days after
that, I was in Jordan.
SUROOSH ALVI: But the death
threats against anyone who's
not on the straight and narrow
continue to this day.
And as we would learn, these
threats are not empty.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
SUROOSH ALVI: From what we were
seeing and hearing, the
secular society that was the
hallmark of Saddam Hussein's
Iraq has largely been replaced
with religious conservatism.
Mix that with western-inspired
youth culture, and there are
going to be problems.
Subcultures in Iraq
are under attack.
For example, the Iraqi
equivalent of emo kids are
being targeted.
And in one of the biggest
stories out of Iraq since the
US has left, a number of them
were supposedly killed.
-[SPEAKING ARABIC]
SUROOSH ALVI: However, there
wasn't a lot of concrete
evidence supporting
the stories.
And some people thought that the
case of these emo killings
was just scare mongering
to keep kids from
straying from tradition.
We went to meet with Dog Faced
Corpse and Fatology, two local
metal bands, to get their
opinion on it.
-I think it's tea time.
SUROOSH ALVI: Oh, yeah.
Great.
Thanks, buddy.
Cheers.
[ARABIC].
So this emo story, is it legit
or is it bullshit?
Did it actually happen?
-It did not.
-No, it's true, man.
-It's true?
No, no.
SUROOSH ALVI: See?
There's no--
well, you're saying it happened
and you're saying it
didn't.
-Yeah, it happened.
-The media exaggerates
the things.
-I think it's bullshit.
-I think it's some bullshit.
As you know, they think
that emos are
metalheads are satanists.
It's everything.
-[SPEAKING ARABIC]
SUROOSH ALVI: So they had to
turn the freezer off to plug
in the amp.
Across the street, there's
a religious cleric.
It's the month of the Muharram,
and he gets pretty
pissed off, apparently.
So yeah--
they're a bit freaked out
about playing right now.
[METAL MUSIC]
SUROOSH ALVI: Dog Faced
Corpse-- where does
the name come from?
-[SPEAKING ARABIC]
-Sounds good?
SUROOSH ALVI: Yeah, man.
Thanks for doing that.
I know that the religious cleric
is probably not too
happy right now.
It's Muharram and everything.
Or yeah, maybe he's out there.
It was pretty clear that no
matter what kind of music
you're playing--
rap, emo, metal, or
even classical--
you could get killed.
But in terms of oppression,
the group that has it the
absolute worst is the gay
community in Iraq.
What is a situation
like here for you?
ALI AL-HAFEZ: [SPEAKING ARABIC]
SUROOSH ALVI: During Saddam
Hussein's time, you were
persecuted for being gay.
And now, you live in fear of
being persecuted as well.
So it was bad before
and it's still bad.
ALI AL-HAFEZ: [SPEAKING ARABIC]
ALI AL-HAFEZ: These
are my friends.
[SPEAKING ARABIC]
SUROOSH ALVI: That's you?
ALI AL-HAFEZ: Yeah.
SUROOSH ALVI: Yeah, that's
a good look for you.
[LAUGHING]
ALI AL-HAFEZ: Jasmine, Sorry.
Why?
Excuse me, cat.
SUROOSH ALVI: I assume it's a
very underground kind of world
that you have.
ALI AL-HAFEZ: [SPEAKING ARABIC]
SUROOSH ALVI: Even though they
might be part of the same
group that's persecuting
you guys?
ALI AL-HAFEZ: [ARABIC]
SUROOSH ALVI: Wow.
That's crazy.
And are you getting help from
the gay rights organizations
in the West?
Are you get-- no.
Not yet.
ALI AL-HAFEZ: [SPEAKING ARABIC]
SUROOSH ALVI: The US may have
withdrawn from Iraq, but the
country is far from rebuilt.
The people who know this best
are the reporters at Al Nahar,
a newspaper that's been a
thorn in the side of the
Maliki administration.
What do you think America
accomplished by coming here
and occupying your country
for eight, nine years?
HASSAN GUMAA: [SPEAKING ARABIC]
SUROOSH ALVI: To add insult to
injury, a lot of the money
that was meant to help Iraq
get back on its feets has
either been stolen or
squandered, sometimes with
deadly results--
case in point, a bomb
detecting device
known as the ADE 651.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
SUROOSH ALVI: While passing
through the various
checkpoints, we kept seeing
the military using these
little magic wands that are
supposed to detect explosives.
The thing is, they don't.
The New York Times revealed
that these devices
were a scam in 2009.
And yet, more than three years
later, the military was still
relying on them to detect
bombs being
brought into Baghdad.
No wonder so many people
were getting killed.
-[SPEAKING ARABIC]
SUROOSH ALVI: Now, with these
units being sold to the Iraqis
at up to $60,000 each,
you'd expect a
little production value.
But instead, they're a cheap
piece of plastic with an AM/FM
radio antenna on it and
no power supply.
The cards they speak of, the
ones that supposedly calibrate
the device to detect different
types of explosives, are
little more than business
cards with words like C4
written on them.
HASSAN SALMA KHALIFA:
[SPEAKING ARABIC]
SUROOSH ALVI: The wands are
the invention of Jim
McCormick, a British businessman
who sold them to
the Iraqi government for
a total of $85 million,
promising that they
would save lives.
But what they did was
the exact opposite.
They allowed bombs to slip past
checkpoints, while making
McCormick rich.
But the most insane part of the
story is that, in spite of
the obvious uselessness of the
device, and in spite of the
arrest and trial of Jim
McCormick, the Iraqi military
and police are still
using them at every
checkpoint in the city.
-[SPEAKING ARABIC]
HASSAN SALMA KHALIFA:
[SPEAKING ARABIC]
SUROOSH ALVI: With our time in
Baghdad drawing to a close, we
headed back to Waleed's place.
We wanted to see how he
was dealing about the
home he left behind.
WALEED NESYIF: The electricity's
coming back.
SUROOSH ALVI: Generator's
kicking in.
WALEED NESYIF: Yeah.
So my family has, basically,
three lines right now-- two
generators and one governmental
line.
SUROOSH ALVI: Yeah.
WALEED NESYIF: So whenever
one goes off, the
other one kicks in--
SUROOSH ALVI: That's good.
WALEED NESYIF: --and
so on and so forth.
SUROOSH ALVI: So they have
electricity around the clock.
So what was it like for you to
come home after eight years?
WALEED NESYIF: The difference
which between eight years ago
and now, it's titanic.
The city is in this complete
state of sterile living.
Everybody's trying to
keep it together,
but nothing is together.
I don't think Iraq found its
comfortable middle ground yet,
because the city still exists
within two extremes.
You have the religious massive
extreme, and then you have the
other wanting to be westernized
without really
understanding what
westernism is.
SUROOSH ALVI: So what is your
family telling you now that
you're here?
What's it like for them?
WALEED NESYIF: They're
praying for the days
of Saddam to return.
In 1991, America came and
destroyed literally 75% of
Iraqi infrastructure and
all of the cities.
It was all destroyed,
completely.
SUROOSH ALVI: Yeah.
WALEED NESYIF: Saddam restored
everything within six months.
People started saying, it was
like, well, if Saddam was able
to do it during the section--
and he nothing, really.
The country had just come
out of a major war.
Why is America incapable
of doing the same?
The worst thing America
has done to Iraq
and Iraqis is this.
They made a dictator look like
an angel in comparison to what
we have right now.
SUROOSH ALVI: And that's what
America accomplished.
They made Saddam look good.
Nostalgia is a powerful thing.
It can make the past seem better
in the present, even
when that past was ruled over by
a tyrant who murdered those
who opposed him and treated
the majority of Iraq's
population, the Shia, like
second class citizens.
For all of America's efforts,
for the billions of dollars
spent and more than a million
lives lost, today Iraq is
looking to the past instead
of the future.