president bombers budget proposal
waverly details out on it and it doesn't
look good there's massive entitlement
about cuts coming
approach to medicare cuts the social
security as well as other cuts too
together details for every of them are
summoned details of what's going to be
because next week
uh... so their overall it's expected to
reduce the deficit by one point eight
trillion dollars over ten years
how does the end of the number of
different ways that we'd be having
having four hundred billion dollars in
uh... healthcare savings or custard and
how you look at it
uh... means testing of certain benefits
and medicare
uh... a big change in how benefits or
dole down so security that they've
changed c_p_i_ is going be reintroduced
things above article we've been opposing
that
uh... some of the good things that were
actually have not
he's gonna be paying to expand access to
pre-k education
there's any limits at contact for for
retirement accounts for the wealthy and
also there's gonna be admission of the
semester to be stopping people from
collecting full disability benefits
and unemployment benefits at the same
time
uh... so so it is good some of its bad
yet most of it is bad
and uh... is as far as central to them
okay right or im go with what now
uh... i changed c_p_i_ personal security
sounds
complicated like i have the casey
periods of time or place don't worry
about it
is about the disaster
and uh...
and look let's just get right to it
uh... real liberals are saying real
progress is arce was primary all the
democrats uh... who vote for this part
now of course fee failure democrat you
bad
voted yes to services massive
consequently all my god if you vote for
gun control watch out so that they all
panicky don't vote for well they should
be some god damn consequences if you go
to customers security is a democrat so
out you know allot of people of
different reels on in my opinion is
absolutely clear they give you the
numbers first before i get into obama's
horrible rediculous
alley but their strategy projected at a
lot of additives
bernie sanders recent reports in her
eighty five years-old it up to you only
get a twelve dollars a month right from
so secure that's not what you're getting
rid of it
twelve hundred a month that's it right
as an example eighty-five let's assume
you're not that's in addition to
whatever you're making from your job
drive a role marketing is allowed to be
worded it probably does that point
anyway which a c_p_i_ but the judge and
the one market
spending etc it's like the old here and
we should do it by like it but i don't
know because she never from conversation
she tells that ever happened about well
timeouts back in a thousand dollars a
year
lasts because of this deal
afoul city year you know how much
interest
but their millionaire it's not that big
a deal
you're living off of twelve hundred a
month
have thousand lessons terrible as
and look it's not just that first of all
we're looking at so many different
numbers that are going to hurt including
uh... veterans by the way let me give
you the moron swiss favors or it could
have a sixty five-year-old
period six hundred fifty dollars a year
lesson benefits seventy five-year-old a
thousand dollars as i'm sorry eighty
five-year-old seventy five thousand
uh...
and so
then we will get better and c_b_s_
thirty-year-olds
young people to others than others and
he said this is all that benefits
you are right now your legs blown off
you got your prize
uh... blow their socks pops up at least
applied to grad forty-seven disabilities
eleven things they could happen he was
sad day for you if you're a
thirty-year-old uh...
you're gonna lose fourteen hundred
dollars a year from this plan by that
time you reach age forty five but i'm
reaching age fifty five dollars two
thousand three hundred dollars a year
but any rich age sixty five losing three
thousand two hundred dollars a year now
that's every single year they take out
your body to get out your private
by the way you know what you do
that would give it almost the same exact
amount of savings you can get rid of
just one offshore tax even will pull
there would be raised in a ballpark with
the same hundred eleven twelve billion
dollars
so we can get rid of what loophole for
corporations
or we can draw on social security
recipients we brought better is and
whether it is one extra little
shipping here
it also affects taxes thing you know
what effects
not millionaires it is an incredibly
regressive form of attacks increase
the people i gave her the most
of the people in the bracket of thirty
to forty thousand dollars a year
and uh... and you know the the one of
the things you hear that
that liberals like that i like is the
funding for prekindergarten v which is
good obscene credibly by twenty kids in
the school then with that's clear to
everyone except conservatives who don't
believe in any sort of study
for that but but it's being funded by a
increase in tobacco facts
which i guess
on some level but i mean the only people
that get if you're a millionaire smoker
whatever other tobacco tax
but if your base is forty five thousand
dollars a year in your addictive
cigarettes are deep and what your pain
like it used to get you to getting
things that are going
and going about it and making the wrong
people
but the thing that bothers me the most
about this in this there's a lot of
things that you're gonna touch on is
that
it's bad enough when you see wake okay
the republicans are able to is the
democratic presidents arm and
we give you the estate tax for two years
or something like that that was hurts
but they are fundamentally changing the
way that the benefits are doled out
there it's going to hurt not for two
years but for decades and decades until
eventually hopefully this is changed
back
but he's a he's prematurely compromising
in such along a lasting sense
there long after he's dead many
presidents later it's just going to
continue to bring to the does it it's
not in flex indexed to inflation in the
correct way
the gap is only going to get bigger and
bigger over time
but imagine this is going to be a
massive problem in a few decades
all right c_n_n_'s pass a problem for
the people who couldn't use the forty
thousand president while my kids
all the time visa told fraud in terms of
being a soap opera recife look to give
you a sense that it's not just that look
do you think that barry and you don't
mind i think that's all much back in tax
increases for the rage that you know
you know there's still the the notes the
most painful thing you did you know
anticipate is a progressive
now as usual near new york times is than
effort to demonstrate his willingness to
compromise with republicans he is
putting it off
again we've got it economy come on a
compromise with the republicans
we don't have that message already
ownership you know it's not like
compromise in the republic's yes i do
agree with republicans what house
republicans will enable republicans
it says this will not be embodied the
final compromise offer
check that
you have
it was the essay today suspected there
might all ticket and i'll give you
nothing in return so are you
roles are whatever we agree on good
cutting so security and medicare i'll
take it you'll get nothing here okay
here's the thing here's the question you
have to answer 'cause i disagree about
which of the target use of the figure as
anybody else
when you pledge to know what he actually
thinks
hotel transactions
and that is a corporate is not many guys
that one hundred-percent corporations
any tax cuts structural proper though
the patterns arrived at her we're not
going to hear the president of states
stop yelling
and tell me what you do with the house
that would be denied what would you
all nato believe has p_c_s_ how i would
do it makes it look nicer offshore tax
havens
this some thought that is a protected
okay at one o'clock p_m_ bear comes into
my office every day asking to cut your
social security i'm gonna get record
pieces you know i think that
obama's only one
sings like associate what we did say
obon i said it
hot movies that make a big issue for
house through but are you as a
politician a little bit of work missus
and as we listen to lease the political
argument here
alarms you disagree with you guys
because
your positive that end up hurting about
that
and to meet the only person with any
credibility to cut social security
is a democrat i don't think he should do
it by spending cuts make good on a
digital republican
presumably so that the credibility
'cause lister democrats have
pro-democratic process started we don't
know i have been a great you know you're
gonna get a deal where you have to cut
social security
then their argument is we strike is a
fairly reasonable one
that you should make the move and saying
this is what we're gonna cut this isn't
nothing more
method of cutting more which visit
totally fair argument to make
but from a political point of view
that at least that there are good
tumi that you strike first
and layout that position will get but
in his writing first he's laying out
it's already a about three to one
three times much cuts is the right to on
things now done by the way not only the
only way you could be two point five
trillion across the road in may
so far the cuts they've already made and
the tax increases
it's eighty percent spending-cuts twenty
percent tax increases
so he is already at four oh one right
and this is a guy to get a much better
okay
what ben
if this was the first time it happened
you've become this angry
but he was we sought no i'd vote for the
guy who it was so excited change will be
on the other better than the
establishment of the clinton as in the
first time i've seen this movie a
hundred times what is the industrial
company such as they get 'em absolutely
nothing anyone's of weakening this
so-called position but the reason i tell
you not that what i know when it's in
his heart but i know what he's gonna do
it had been white every step of the way
is because look if you keep doing
something it how do you want it to do it
what would you do under the new yelling
john but i told you i would get them and
i would say heartbreak
you guys are for cutting social security
and can for putting that
tax loophole it's kissing funny less for
twenty fourteen
and i'm going to destroy you want to
take off my money and safe
these are guys who want to cut benefits
from
disabled arizona childlike
that was a child usual blacks are
dismissing oshawa eight black girl at
shell corporations a sick these are the
sons of bitches are protecting today
money from these people you know how
badly wounded brought collections at csp
dot gov prophesied this is what we're
going to do wrote a progressive agenda
but i'll get to that 'cause he's not a
progressive
any of the latest on that
and that now i i i when reading an
article in the democrats u_s_ harry hey
listen why don't you want r_p_s_
progressive ads their spokespeople say
to the reporters
but then we would lose are formed
but then we would lose are funding
you say that
it's all about the corporations are
bought both sides this is good cop bad
cop
so don't get oklahoma progressive
one-eyed joke