sending prices sky-high.
Literally, literally taking
the grass from its own roots.
And now you've got your
ConDemNation.
Liberals noshing Tories like
altar boys picking dimps up!
Have we had a national
fucking stroke or what?
Is revolution a word,
or was it never?
Anybody watching needs to know,
we cope better than average
with irony in Chatsworth.
Well, for fucks sake,
we live in Manchester
and they charge us for water.
I wandered lonely as a clown,
necking mushrooms rarely found.
This green and pleasant land
in ancient times.
Yak, yak, yak, yak, yak, yak, yak,
yak, yak! It's not theirs any more.
This is our England now!
Paaaarty!
'I used to go out with
this lad in my teens.
'A real pin-up. Blonde, blue eyed.
'Face of an angel.
'If his timing had been better,
and his voice didn't sound like
'a hot water bottle being trod on,
'he could've been a contender,
given Gary and Robbie a run
for their money.
'Certainly had the looks. The moves.
He was charm personified.
'Everyone loved him. Everyone.
But not half as much as me.
'He was everything I'd never had
before,
'or since, come to think of it.
'Attentive,
considerate, generous, kind.
'Until the night when he
didn't take no as no.'
No!
'When I finally plucked up the
courage to tell... no-one believed me.
'"He wouldn't do
something like that."
'But he did.
'And it taught me a
really valuable lesson.
'Sometimes,
devils come dressed as angels.
'And angels come dressed as devils.
'Only problem is... sometimes
you only find out which is which
'when it's too fuckin' late!'
♪ When Jesus Comes around
♪ All that's bad goes to ground.
Where there is darkness,
I shall bring light.
And where there is hatred,
I shall bring love.
Love! Love!
All I fucking need. A McCartney
to play against my Lennon.
♪ You have the choice.
Hallelujah!
♪ Salvation or damnation... ♪
You see, one mention of religion and
it's got us all arguing,
while those cracked twats
are peddling their shite
and lining their pockets
and frightening the lives out
of the vulnerable and lonely.
Oh, fucking hell!
We're a non-profit making
organisation, actually.
Oh, L. Ron Hubbard!
You'll have to forgive him, Father.
I keep telling you, Mimi.
I'm not a priest.
Just one soul wanting to spread
a little happiness to another.
Would you be willing to put one up?
Anything we can do to help.
That's good to hear.
Bless you, one and all.
What is it you lot are on? Ritalin?
What?
'Scuse!
We haven't met...
Jesus. Jesus O'Toole.
Religious family?
Yeah, I was called Bernadette.
You know, until I came out and
they realised I weren't a girl.
I changed it by deed poll,
in honour of the boss.
Oh!
We had a lad called Moses in
our class when I was a kid.
But he got knocked over by a
forklift truck on work experience.
Got another poster?
It's just for college.
There's a few lost lambs
there, I can tell you.
Your name's Mike?
Mikey.
Mick... Micky.
Angel.
Stop it.
Michael was one of the archangels.
God's hard man.
Fighter.
Coming to the prayer meeting?
Yeah. OK.
Tell your big brother next time he
wants something, not to send you.
He needs to come in himself.
Will do.
Call it 20.
You'll be getting me arrested.
I'll see you in court then.
Can't you do something about that?
Oh, back off, miserable arse.
Can't bar them for
enjoying themselves.
Oh, I didn't mean bar them.
I just meant burn them at the stake.
That'll shut the fuckers up.
Free country, Frank.
Only if you're a Christian
Fundamentalist, apparently.
Or some other vocal minority,
like your fucking lot.
What do you mean by that?
Oh, you see? Someone dares criticise,
have an opinion, you're up in arms!
Dad, shut the fuck up!
No. You can't have a balanced
discussion, can't dare to disagree.
Oh, sorry, but the vast majority
of folk in the free world
don't share your point of
view vis a vis your God
and the way his representatives on
Earth are conducting themselves.
You're welcome to
your opinion, Frank.
Oh, cheers.
I just don't want to hear it.
And don't we know it. Someone
dares speak out of turn
and you're down on them
like a ton of bricks,
literally,
in some parts of the world.
That's bang out of order.
No. Karen. Blowing yourself up and
taking folk with you
who don't wanna go,
is bang out of order!
You need to watch
what you're saying.
Or what? You're going to get a Fatwa
on me, yeah? Frankie gets a Fatwa?
I'm not saying one religion
is any better than the other.
They're all shite.
It's just a way of administering
control, pulling strings.
God's just a bogeyman!
That is so offensive.
Well, I'd rate buggering choirboys
and abusing kids in care more
offensive, Mimi, but, hey, you know,
one man's Sistine Chapel ceiling
is another man's floor, I suppose.
So all Catholics bugger
choirboys, do they?
Can't say I have. Shane?
(CROWD CHANTING):
Go home to your wives!
I've been here ages.
Say I'm the Devil Incarnate.
I'd be insulted if I knew
what it meant.
What's this? What you playing at?
Just trying to raise awareness.
Not outside my place
of work you're not!
You're a whore.
A little Old Testament
for my tastes, but yep.
I thought you were
here to get everyone happy clappy,
not interfere with the way I earn
my living, or give an opinion on it.
Let's pray, Kelly.
Join me. Be forgiven.
I'll be on me knees as
soon as I clock on for work
and you'll be flat on your back
if you don't call your bitches off.
I don't want
or need your forgiveness.
It's the Almighty
you're asking to forgive.
And be honest, you could do with
a little guidance in your life.
No!
Tonya could've done with some, too.
With light in her life, she could
have avoided a lot of heartache.
How the fuck do you...?
Move!
And there's plenty
more where that came from, too!
I'm here to help, Kelly. Let me.
What's going on?
How do you know about our Tonya?
How do you know about me sister?
What's happening?
Let the love in, Kelly.
Fuck'd you know me name?
All right, pal. What you up to?
Spreading the word..
Well fucking spread it
somewhere else!
Jesus loves you, Shane.
I'm praying for you.
He knows your name.
He knows our names!
♪ Someone's praying, Lord, kumbaya
♪ Oh, Lord, kumbaya. ♪
He knew things about me, my family.
They could have asked someone
your name.
Every now and then,
you come across a holy man
with a direct link to him upstairs.
He's got those eyes, though,
hasn't he? Look right into you.
Know your every thought.
See right into our souls.
Trickery, Kelly. Smoke and mirrors,
like all religions.
Except yours, obviously.
Fear of an all-seeing, all-knowing,
unforgiving deity
that doesn't even exist.
Except yours,
as previously mentioned.
Hang on, got to admit it's been
a bit nicer since they arrived.
Let me give you a hand.
Kids off the street are socialising
instead of making nuisances
of themselves.
Stop!
Hallelujah! Praise the Lord!
Jesus is doing no harm.
You dropped your purse.
Thank you.
APPLAUSE
Well done!
Apart from picketing my business
and threatening to expose
my clientele, you mean?
Let them fill their boots
and move on.
How much harm are a gang of
Bible-bashers going to do us, eh?
LAUGHTER
(MUFFLED SCREAMS)
You touch me, and you're dead!
I'm a Maguire!
And when they find out what
you're doing to one of their own...
At least I got the right one.
Marty?!
Me nuts!
(LAUGHS)
We were in Spain, paradise.
Happiest ever.
We had each other.
The kids.
So what happened?
I couldn't give her what she wanted.
I tried.
Had this job in Fuengirola.
We were just scraping by,
but we were together.
Anyway, before long...
She found someone who could give her
what she wanted.
She left you.
Took my kids.
Arsin-arsin-arsin' around behind
my back with some greasy wop!
Wops are Italian.
You were in Spain.
They're all the same gel-wearing
tight trousered bastards.
Put the fire out! She...
She put out the fire - desire -
that I felt for her.
So you're back here.
Fuck, sorry.
Who is it?
Mum.
It's Carol?
I had no idea she'd...
You have had a shit time of it,
haven't you?
Look, you can't stay here.
I'll have a word with Shane.
It'll only be the couch,
but at least you'll be warm. Safe.
How about it, eh?
Yeah.
There's a prayer meeting at eight.
Does it look like I go
to prayer meetings?
Looks like you need to. There's an
Xbox on the bus. PS3. Wii.
What's your name?
Mephistopheles.
Call him Meff for short.
I've been sent by God to save you.
Many women bigger, wiser
and on the legal side of puberty
to you have tried to save me
and failed spectacularly.
Vernon Francis Gallagher.
Nine children to two different women.
Claiming disability benefits
on and off for a back condition,
which only materialises at the same
time as the possibility of a job.
What are you,
some sort of Lib-Dem-Tory spy?
Receiving child benefits
for almost 30 years.
But that money's never put a meal
on the table. Clothes on their backs.
Me and my benefits
are classified information.
It's theft, Frank. A crime
not only against your fellow man,
but God himself.
I don't give a toss
about my fellow man.
And as for God...
(BLOWS RASPBERRY)
♪ Salvation or damnation! ♪
Who the fuck are you?
♪ You have the choice! ♪
See the light!
♪ Salvation... ♪
Fuck that!
He's on his own,
in that shitty squat
the junkies used to use.
She only wants Marty staying here,
Veronica's brother.
Well, we need a fuckin' arsonist.
Mickey!
He's got nowhere to live. Mickey!
I wouldn't be able to leave
a match...
or a lighter out...
for fear of him torching the place.
Oh, God!
He's got a right potty mouth!
Fuck this, fuck that,
fuck the other.
Every other word's fuck. Or twat.
Who?
Marty. He used to shout
"cuntflaps" at the nuns.
Cilla would pick that up,
"cuntflaps".
You've got a spare room.
No chance.
You didn't move your lips.
He's a liability.
KNOCK AT DOOR
For fuck's sake!
Are you in on this, Ches?
Yeah, too right.
Did you call Lillian?
I couldn't get through.
Mickey, you know where she is,
don't you?
♪ ENNIO MORRICONE:
The Good, The Bad And The Ugly
ECSTATIC CRIES FROM CAR
KNOCKING
If the car's a rockin',
don't come knockin'.
I've gone mobile. I couldn't
get a punter past the God squad,
so I've launched Feels On Wheels.
It's an orgy!
Didn't start like that. Two of them
were late and then all
my appointments went crashing,
so I thought "Oh, to hell with it",
and I chucked 'em all in at once.
I take a 10% cut and keep film
and distribution rights.
They're being filmed?
Tiny cameras the size of
matchsticks. They have no clue.
Who'd watch that?
There's a market for chubby chasers.
I knock out DVDs on the computer,
take 'em down the car boot
on a Saturday. Make a mint!
We're going to see Jesus.
I'm fucked off with the effect
his crusade's having on business.
Jamie!
I'm with you in spirit, but if
there's a ruck,
I won't be of any use.
You're getting on a bit, so...
No, it's the love eggs. Last time I
was involved in a tussle, I lost one.
One of the girls had to come down and
suction it out
with the hose off the Dyson.
I've just brought up a bit of sick.
So have I.
Get your boss out here now,
or you'll be meeting your maker
a bit quicker
than you'd fuckin' imagined.
You want to play it the hard way,
that's fine with us.
Stop this, please!
For the love of God, stop.
None of this'd be happening
if you'd come out when you were told.
We want your pickets
removed from outside our businesses.
There's a message to be spread,
Chesney.
Your brains'll be being spread
if you don't listen up.
You're eating into our profits.
That's not on.
Your trade breeds misery.
Families ripped apart.
People have a freedom of choice.
I can't stand idly by
and watch men and women drown
in the very thing that you sell.
Look at Frank - the happiness
his children have missed out on
through his addiction.
If you knew Frank, you'd know
his kids have had a lucky escape.
Call them off.
We're here to do God's work.
Peace and love!
I can't call that off.
Can't ask it to stop.
Well, then, you leave us no choice.
You can't call it off.
But I...
can.
So why all the cloak and dagger?
Why jump me in the street,
why not just knock round?
I'm on the run.
There's a warrant out.
For?
I didn't pay maintenance.
I didn't have it. When she kicked
me out, I slept on the beach.
I lost my job.
I didn't have a pot to piss in.
Besides...
The fella
she moved in with was loaded.
It's not like the kids went short.
What?
You haven't swore.
Fuck! Yeah.
Shane doesn't want you staying.
So I thought
the best thing we could do
would be to make this place
as comfy as we can.
Got a duvet cover there, too.
Anything else you want?
A fuck.
Is that your Tourette's back?
I'll ask one of the girls
to pop round. You got a type?
Er... blonde.
About your size.
They'll be docking my pay. Bye.
'It's me. Leave a message.'
There's nothing going on here,
so I'll leave it an hour or so,
then head home.
If you're at the Jockey,
don't worry about rushing back,
bath and bed when I get in,
I'm knackered. Have a good 'un.
Love you.
(SHRIEKS)
(LAUGHS)
Hey, leave 'em on.
Shat myself then.
Oh, my God.
What do you think you're doing?
(YELPS)
Hang on, hang on. Punchline...
And all because...
The lady loves...
LAUGHTER
It's hurting.
And I pledge to thee my purity.
ALL: And I pledge to thee my purity.
And I pledge to thee my faith.
ALL: And I pledge to thee my faith.
Now and for ever. Amen.
ALL: Now and for ever. Amen.
All right, crisps and pop coming up.
Enjoy!
You missed it.
The prayer session.
I know.
You can't just turn up
for the games, crisps and pop.
You can't just reap the rewards.
You have to put the time in.
It's all new to me.
Like a big family, innit?
I'll be on time, next time.
Erm...
I'm sure God wouldn't mind
me making an exception.
Monster Munch or Nibletts?
Your cronies are fucking up
business in the pub.
And the shop.
And Lillian's.
You have to stop. Now.
I can't.
I wouldn't put myself
in the middle of it, Patty.
Jesus was never afraid of a fight
and neither am I, Jamie.
I'd sooner not do this.
Well, then don't.
Leave the devil behind
and look for salvation.
Before it's too late.
I want you off the estate
this time tomorrow.
No wonder your crew knew
all there is to know about everyone.
The font of all knowledge, hey?
I know how people
might redeem themselves.
Since he shone his light,
my life is finally worth living
and yours could be too,
so hallelujah!
ALL: Hallelujah!
Join us in the light.
And let his love illuminate
the darkest corners of your life.
I don't really do religion,
I'm a Catholic.
You think the Lord will forgive you
for all you've done? Beware!
You beware. If you think
I'm going to let you and yours
fuck up my nearest and dearest,
you're wrong.
No-one messes with my family.
If you think we're a pushover,
think again.
Blow it out your arse.
I'm New Testament, your mumbo
jumbo scaremongery's lost on me.
You want trouble, Patty,
bring it on!
Verily, God will visit upon you
fire and brimstone and damnation!
The earth shall weep, Mimi.
The earth shall weep!
Pepperoni, madam.
Extra basil like you asked.
I meant on the pizza.
Well, basil on tap. You can
have it any time you want now.
I'm glad you're not
in a hurry to get home.
No-one to hurry to.
Shane's out on family business.
You mean kicking somebody's arse?
Or telling someone they're going
to get their arse kicked.
Not sure what he gets up to lately
but I'm pretty sure it involves
arses and kicking.
Can't be easy being
married to a Maguire.
Bit of an effort lately.
All marriages go through
funny patches, eh?
Yep.
It'll just be a funny patch.
Yeah.
Mam said we need to be on red alert.
What does that mean?
Patty's made a threat which Mam
thinks we need to take seriously.
So there's a family pow wow
later to decide the next move.
Hiya. What you been up to?
Not much. Someone nearly got
their arse kicked, that's all. You?
Been with a client.
Can you smoke that?
It's basil.
You've give it a name?
No, Micky. Everyone calls it basil.
What's it for?
Cooking. Stick it in a pasta,
top of pizzas.
We're having pasta again?
No, we're not having pasta.
What the fuck you buy it for then?
It's a gift.
Some perv's buying you a plant
as a thank you
for paying to fuck you?
It wasn't a perv.
It was Marty.
So he's buying you a plant?
Shane! Punter have bought me
watches before now.
Red roses marking the anniversary
of when they first fucked me
and you and me, we laughed at that.
Why's it bothering you?
You do not buy a plant.
We were just having a laugh. We just
got talking about stuff we liked...
Shane!
Shane, come on! This is stupid!
Shane, will you...
Fuck off.
It's a plant. A fucking plant.
It was a joke, a thank you,
that's all.
Shane!
Stop it! Shane!
Shane, stop it.
Shane?
Stop it now. No! No!
Shane! Leave it. Leave it.
Fuck off. It's none of
your business. Fucking do one!
Are you OK, love?
Just leave.
(GRUNTS)
What the fuck are you doing?!
Fuck's this about?!
There's no need,
absolutely no need!
He stays away.
You don't say who can and can't...
You are my wife!
Kelly Maguire.
You got that?
Maguire.
And don't I fucking know it!
Come on. I said come on.
(CRIES)
(MOANS)
What's it like living round here?
Better than where I used to live.
We shouldn't even be
talking to each other.
Being on opposing sides, you mean?
The Maguires have asked me to find
out what your lot are planning.
And I've been asked to find out
what the Maguires are planning.
Fuck 'em.
Fuck 'em all.
I'll pray for your soul.
Don't you ever get pissed off?
I mean, um, bored,
doing this all the time?
If I can get through to one person,
just one, it'll have been worthwhile.
PHONE RINGS
Yes, mate.
Never just want a bit of fun?
I do have fun.
I enjoy my work, my mission.
Look, I believe in God but
only for an hour on a Sunday.
It hasn't taken over my whole life.
It needs to.
Don't you just want
a bit of excitement?
BANG
ALARM RINGS
Fuck.
These fuckers are harder
than we thought.
Willing to go to any lengths
to prove their point.
It might not have been them.
Who else could it have been?
I told Patty the score,
she threw down the gauntlet.
This is war.
So much for peace and goodwill, eh?
Me and my Brendan was involved
in an explosion once. 1972.
We were on a cruise,
celebrating us anniversary.
Having dinner
at the Captains' table,
when suddenly,
this God almighty bang...
and the ship tipped.
Felt it... wham.
And within an hour,
the whole vessel were upside down.
We were trapped.
That was the Poseidon Adventure.
Did it not happen?
So we're just going to sit here,
let 'em get away with it?
Would you be doing this if I'd have
been blown to fuckin' pieces?
No.
So what do we do?
Go round there and we nail them.
What? You mean kill them?
Kill Jesus?
Kill 'em all.
We tried the gentle approach,
and they wouldn't listen.
Your answer to everything that,
isn't it?
What do you suggest?
I dunno. Anything but that.
It's just wrong.
It's all wrong.
This time tomorrow, our problem
will no longer be our problem.
Kel, Kel! Are you OK?
He didn't hit you?
He wouldn't fucking dare.
Don't come round again, Marty.
Why?
He'll kill you.
I can't just stop seeing you.
You're going to have to.
I can't!
Why the fuck not?
Because I love ya.
I love ya!
You sure you're OK?
Fine, thanks, Auntie.
If you're agreeable,
you could stay with us.
Come with us. Join our Crusade.
You mean it?
Indeed we do.
Where's Grace?
Upstairs, having a lie down.
I'm off on a few messages.
If you need anything,
just call for Jesus.
I'll be in the office.
THUNDER
What you doing?
What's it look like?
It's upside down.
Hey. Jesus?
If you hadn't dragged
my husband off,
he'd have killed that poor bastard
and be looking at a life stretch.
So I owe you.
My lot have had enough
and they plan to make sure
you don't cause no more problems.
When they realise
we pose no threat...
Look, Jesus...
What's your real name?
I can't keep calling you that.
That is my real name.
What did your mam call you?
Fuck's sake, I'm trying
to have a serious conversation.
Eric.
Some folk respond well
to kindness, a soft touch.
Jamie isn't the type of man
you want to be messing with.
When the Romans came for Christ...
You want to finish up
in the foundations for a flyover...
Sit tight.
There's something
I don't understand.
You're a...
good looking bloke.
Kind, considerate, passionate.
Your love for God
tells me that much.
You never been tempted?
I pray to God to keep me pure.
You never longed for that touch?
That euphoria.
Him.
His need.
My need.
When we make love...
I could almost believe in God.
It's that good.
Don't be here.
They're coming.
See ya.
Bye.
Nice shoes, Grace.
You'd better go.
Arghh! What?!
Have you heard from Libby?
I'm the last one she'd
get in touch with!
Where is she?
I don't know!
Why are you so intent
on seeing her anyway?
She didn't say
where she was going,
or who she was going with?
Why would she tell me?
She didn't leave a note for me?
What, for her jailer?
Her tormentor?
I'm her mother.
Just because you've seen the light,
doesn't mean to say
everyone else has too.
Go seek comfort in Jesus.
Not the real one, obviously.
I'm not suggesting you should
top yourself,
but, you know, the himbo on the bus.
I'm sure he can rustle up
a few words of comfort
from some Epistle or another.
You know, rattle his tambourine.
Fuck me.
The ice maiden melteth.
I shed a few tears for her.
Mostly of regret.
You treated her like shite.
Regret that I ever met her,
that we ever picked up where
we left off,
cos truth be told, there was nothing
left to pick up.
But, I got me tea made.
Me washing done...
A good nosh now and again.
You bastard!
All she needed to hear was, "I love
you", and she was on her knees.
I've had better sex but my
shirts have never been whiter.
I wondered when the real Patty
would resurface.
And here she is.
So, this is goodbye then, is it?
I can't see any reason to stay.
Where did you go when you left here?
What turned you from the godless
old crone we knew
into the God-fearing crone
now before us?
Much like yourself,
I lived a selfish life,
attending to my needs before even
considering the needs of others.
And then I went back to Ireland
and, while there,
had what I can only describe
as my Road To Damascus experience.
Oh, so God just popped up and
showed you the error of your ways?
Yeah? Well, I don't believe a word.
I think little Patty clocked
the Jesus freaks and thought,
"Bingo! Free meals and a roof over
me head for the rest of me life."
I wouldn't expect you to believe.
I was a lost sheep and God saved me.
Liar.
May He strike me down here and now
if I tell a word of a lie.
Matty?
I'm going.
Good.
No. I mean, I'm leaving this.
You don't have to leave this.
Just here.
My head's full of everything
I've been missing.
You can have it all, you know.
I think God would let you.
How can I preach purity
when all I want to be is impure?
Preach goodness,
when all I want to do is bad?
I'm not worthy.
They deserve better than me.
What you want to do, it's normal.
It's not bad.
But I want it to be bad.
I want to bite the apple, Kelly.
Thank you.
Anyone?
Nothing.
See you got my present, then?
I won't ask where it came from.
'No, don't.'
You got my present?
I got it.
Listen, next time you're saving
souls round here, come save mine.
Bye.
They say the damage to my spine
is irreparable.
I'll never walk again.
You've taken it very well,
I'll give you that.
I've got my life back, Frank.
What could be better?
I don't understand.
The police will be here any minute.
And what I tell them
depends very much on you.
How do you mean?
Everyone on the estate
knows how much you hated me.
Everyone knows how much you
wanted me out the picture.
If you agree to have me move back,
then I agree not to tell the police
you pushed me down the stairs -
that you did this.
Well, that's just gonna be my word
against... Who's gonna believe..?
Ah! Oh, nurse!
Oh! Nurse!
Pain, oh!
Oh!
We'll have to increase
your morphine.
I'm just going to check with
the doctor. Hang on there, Patty.
Oh! Oh!
Wouldn't you be better off
back on the bus,
amongst your own kind?
With those Bible bashing bastards?
I can't stand the feckin' sight
of them!
I want to be amongst folk I know.
Familiar faces, surroundings.
I want to come home.
And I wanted to make your life
a feckin' misery, Frank.
'I ran into that old boyfriend
a few years ago.
'I was out with the girls in town,
'turned a corner and bang,
there he was.
'No longer a possible
replacement for Robbie or Gary.
'His face was etched with all
the wrong he'd done.
'All the pain he'd caused.'
Oh, they're here!
'And, if I believed in God,
'I'd like to think he'd had every
sin that he'd ever committed
'scratched into his face
as a warning to others
'to keep their distance - to beware.
'That's if I believed in God.'
What are you going on about?
It's a scratch card!
(REPORTER)
Tonight, a pensioner was brutally assaulted
in her home in Belvedere Road...
If it gets any clearer,
I'll be topping meself.
It's Frank's name on the line.
Yeah, and his head.
Don't know how you missed him!
What the fuck?
Forensics rustled a few new words
up for you, Frank.
DNA.
Positive match.
If it was you, that'd be
us finished.
I need Kev! Where is he?
Subtitles by Red Bee Media Ltd, MemoryOnSmells