you do through a constitutional
amendment
if you do it through it
constitutional convention
which is called for the state level why
why
but that the into the catalyst
national politicians are so corrupt
don't like your attitude towards of them
the same all yaya please stop the
corruption take away all my donor money
so the guy running against the
could have just as good a chance is me
dialogue ever going to do that
that's why banking on the constitution
is a different
uh... portion and it which says you
don't need to do with the federal
congress
is an important part of the constitution
the founding fathers put in there for a
reason
every once in a lifeguard constitutional
convention to and then the constitution
not the redoing the constitution
it is specific
to and then the constitution
and this is exactly what we need to do
demanded to get money out of politics
so anyway it's a mess
using because
the best progress we've had is in texas
and in vermont
the rest they analyst state
and now what we need is a little bit al
from you guys in terms of volunteers
uh... works on a local level and it's
thank settles time on the show is
something i've been moshe rocked by
ipn in our work on wolfpack
is a state politicians
actually listened
i think of a national bothered for so
long i think on no way
waited a few weeks it has to do it
you know what the issue not a builder
may get a good meeting with you
and it you really convince them
i would've said no way
it turns out state politics is totally
different as our corruption in other
ways the state province of course from
time to time there is
but we have been shot than every state
we're in
that the state representatives and
senators
actually care about their constituents f
locker say we found that in some things
that level it's amazing
now what i want is timed gender in texas
is done wing work
getting democrats and republicans on
board but he needs your help
we need a lot more volunteers to call
those representatives and the center's
kazakhstan makes a huge
shocking difference a duelist newt time
let alone the representatives
music you convince me
i'm on your side
and he doesn't over and over again we
need more guys
in texas like that so if you're in texas
please email on that their intelligence
on time
at wolf badge pack dot com
and get in touch with him
volunteer specifically in taxes would be
incredibly helpful same goes for mott we
have art director of organizer who's
working in vermont
we need a lot more it's a small state we
need a lot more people calling their
state reps
there though uh... status you know very
democratic we just need to reach those
rats and senators and i think they're
going to be on our side we've already
had shitty alliances of great state a
senator that introduce a resolution so
we need a backdrop and helper so email
mike at mike at wolf badge pack dot com
and my gratitude your hot new user help
if you're in for a month
and you know
still ask things
it's not just vermont in texas
we are coming
in california and in minnesota two great
bills
there already
past the first round they've been
introduced there dot headway there doing
crane
how could you imagine it we had texas
california minnesota in vermont
can you get any more represented in that
the middle of the country red states
blue states
where they're all we need is volunteers
more than anything else
at those states
uh... helpin out making calls talking to
your local wraps and senators shocking
they listen to and one last thing if
you're not in those states or even if
you are though in that helps obviously
is resources
so if you know wolf badge pack dot com
you sign up for membership is quick
membership
and you can just contribute like ten
bucks a month i mean if you could do
more great but he knew ten bucks a month
us basically less than a couple copy a
day
a lot of us can be a few of them you
know they got a lot of money but of all
we do is ten bucks a month
combined
that will have a tremendous amount of
money and then they better watch out has
ninety percent of country agrees with us
and we've seen it on a state-by-state
level liberals conservatives
libertarians we all agree
these national politicians are corrupt
and we've got to stop them from doing
that lobbyists and or money
allies in never going to do
with the american people want
we can regain our democracy was to right
now
thank you for your help