[toilet flush sound]
And a welcome to this episode of Genesis
Week, the weekly program of creationary
commentary on news, views and events
pertaining to the origins controversy,
made possible by the supporters of CORE
Ottawa - Citizens for Origins Research
and Education, and exclusive right here
on youtube.  Excellence in pirate
broadcasting live from the now
abandoned arrow cave, we bring you the
information the anti-creationists don't
want you to see or hear, and we give
glory to the Creator while doing it.  Once
again, #1 most talked about show in
science and technology on YouTube.
You can find us at wazooloo.com or
genesisweek.com, or click the
ever-so-convenient subscribe link up top,
and don't forget, you can also peruse
other episodes by following the links in
the upper corners of each episode. I'm
your host, Ian Juby
This past week the preliminary analysis of
the Gorilla DNA sequence was published
in Nature magazine, with loads of
headlines making bold assertions about
how identical Gorillas, Chimps and
humans are.  Well of course we're similar,
but so what? Even if we were genetically
identical, I have yet to see apes building
spaceships and flying to the moon, or
producing works of art or music, or
performing stand up comedy.  Obviously
the differences run far beyond the
genetic.  But - when one actually examines
the genetic data itself, you quickly find
out that humans and apes aren't quite as
similar as they're made out to be, and the
"similarities" actually contradict
evolutionary theory.  Chimpanzees are
supposed to be our closest relative, and
therefore most identical to us genetically.
A 2005 Nature article pinpointed the
genetic differences between humans and
chimpanzees at about 4% different. Yet
this most recent study said the chimp was
only 1.37% different, and Gorilla was only
1.75 percent different than humans, and
the orangutan is 3.4% different than
humans.
Now hold on a minute here, these are
numbers that were published in a peer
reviewed journal!  So is the chimp 4%
different or 1.37% different?  But wait - it
gets weirder - according the Ensemble
website where you can download, analyze
and compare all of these genomes
yourself, we find that the chimpanzee
genome is 3.35 BILLion letters long while
the human genome is a mere 3.1 billion
letters long - wait - that's an 8% difference
in the number of letters alone. So to turn
around and say that chimps and humans,
which are at least 8% different, are in fact
only 1.37% different shows that either a)
they're not telling you everything or b)
these scientists flunked high school
math!
Now I happen to know it's because of
what they are NOT telling you. Well if they
want to play THAT game, hey I can play
that game too!  Let's use THEIR numbers
(which aren't actually numbers at all, but
rather propaganda portrayed as data)
You'll note that if we take into account the
differences in base pair numbers, or
number of letters in the DNA, in the
genomes of the different critters, and
then we add that percentage difference
together with the acknowledged
differences from the latest Nature article,
you quickly see that we are more
genetically similar to Gorillas and
Organgutans than we are to chimps!
Now these numbers are complete fiction -
they do not portray reality whatsoever,
but neither do the figures presented in
the Nature article.  My numbers are JUST
as valid as the alleged values of similarity
given in the nature article.  Why? Because
of they are not telling you. You see, when
they make these comparisons, the
scientists are ignoring HUGE portions of
the DNA, and homing in on selected
genes that both the apes and humans
have, and comparing just those genes!
Ignoring the fact that these similar genes
are often in radically different locations in
the different organisms, we would of
course expect they genes to be similar -
they had a common designer!  You'll
notice that once a car manufacturer
builds a transmission, they'll use that
transmission in different vehicles - that's
good engineering, that's smart
engineering.  The bracket mounts and
such may be different in different
vehicles, but the transmissions are
essentially the same. That's evidence of a
common designer, not evolution.
So just what are the scientists IGNORING
to arrive at this 98.63% identical claim for
chimpanzees? Well they're ignoring
ORFAN genes - genes which are exclusive
to that organism, and not found in any
others. In other words, if we were to
compare the HUNDREDS of orfan genes
between the apes and humans, we would
find a ZERO percent match between
chimps and humans!
But wait - It gets better!  With last year's
publication of the Orangutan genome in
Nature magazine, the researchers noted
that, depending on which genes you
compared, the Orangutan was more
closely related to humans than
Chimpanzees were!
This week's report on the Gorilla genome
showed that the Gorillas were as much as
30% dissimilar to humans, and in fact if
we went on the falacious assumptions the
researchers are using, the gorilla was
more identical to humans and
chimpanzees, than the humans and
chimpanzees were to each other.  In other
words, one could interpret the genetic
data to mean that the gorilla was the
intermediate organism between
chimpanzees and humans!
At the end of the day, none of this genetic
information supports the idea of descent
from a common ancestor - because there
is nothing common about the information,
and in fact can be interpreted in a miriad
of evolutionary scenarios, the majority of
which disagree with the alleged fossil
evidence for human evolution!  However, it
all fits in quite nicely with the fact that
each organism was specially and uniquely
created, with the Creator using some
common design among the organisms.
In fact, as Ebersberger et al. explained in
their   2007 "Mapping Human Genetic
Ancestry" paper in Molecular Biology and
Evolution:
Translation: The genetic evidence does
not support common descent, but
resembles a patchwork of genes among
the organisms...... which could best be
explained by a common designer, and I
would suggest that common designer was
the one the Apostle John spoke of in
John 1:3 "All things were made by Him
and without Him was not anything made
that was made."  John was speaking of
Jesus Christ, who created a human form
to live in and sacrifice for your sins and
mine, and rising from the dead so you
could have confidence that He really was
the way to eternal life.
You'll notice a consistent reporting in
these weekly shows - it seems every week
another fossil is unearthed which shows
exactly what we would expect to see,
were the book of Genesis true: Stasis in
the fossil record.  This week, we have a
report in Public Library of Science one on
a wonderful find of fossil sea cows -
manatees.  Fossils taken from Florida,
India and Mexico all reveal that from 28
million years ago through to 3 million
years ago, we see the evolutionary
sequence of manatees evolving over
millions of years....into manatees.
Brian Thomas from Institute for Creation
Research also pointed out a recent
Chinese Science Bulletin describing fossil
salamanders so well preserved that even
their stomach contents were visible.
Allegedly 150 million years old, the
Chinese researchers remarked how these
fossil salamanders look just like the giant
Chinese salamander.  So 150 million years
has caused the salamander to evolve
into...the salamander.
This is what we typically see in the fossil
record - very little change, stasis.  In stark
contrast to what would expect to find if
evolution were true, and matching exactly
what is described ten times in the first
chapter of Genesis where God created
everything to reproduce faithfully after its
kind. This is powerful evidence for
creation, and to say it's common in the
fossil record is an understatement.
[scary, dramatic music]
Wahoo! Mail for me?
[Scary, dramatic music]
Wow - not only was there a lot of
discussion on last week's show, there
was a lot of good comments and
questions brought - and I'm afraid, I won't
be able to recite them all.
GodHasNoMother did a fine job trying to
explain prophecy and the gospel to those
who would not hear.  I salute you!
Good point - let us also remember the
jawless fish fossils found in China in
1999, allegedly dated 530 million years
old, which is some 25 million years older
than the Burgess shales, so that's
another example of vertebrate fossils
before our alleged ancient ancestor.
That's why *I* am broadcasting from a
different, top secret hideout every week.
1whitemoon wrote in with an interesting
question which stirred a lot of response:
True, and while I don't really have a
problem with people classifying
organisms in this way, the classification
in no way demonstrates evolution. For
example - where on earth would you put
the duckbilled platypus?  In fact this
classification system was actually
invented by a creationist, Linaeus, who
referred to the organism groups as
"species" because he believed they were
SPECIAlly created.  I get a lot of people
complaining about the term "kinds"
asking for a definition of "kind," which is
fair enough - but the problem is that for
both definitions of species and kinds, you
will have exceptions to the definition.  The
bottom line here I wish to make though, is
that classifying organisms does not affirm
evolutionary ascent.
MrAlienAssassin responded to
1whitemoon with:
This canard was actually answered
decades ago.  The alleged "leg bones" are
different between the males and females,
because these bones serve a purpose in
the reproductive systems of the
cetaceans.  They are muscle anchors and
claspers.  There are no vestigial hind limbs
on cetaceans, they serve a very real
purpose.
Mazle (however you say that), seeing as
how you cannot create a giraffe from
scratch, then you are in absolutely no
position to be criticizing the design of
said giraffe.  You need to watch my CrEvo
rant #67, poor design. It is horribly
ignorant and arrogant to make such
criticisms. The laryngial nerve argument
was answered a long time ago by Dr.
Jerry Bergman here:
Okay - I have no idea what you're talking
about - it's true that chickens have
recessive genes for teeth- in fact, going
by the fossil record, many birds had teeth
that have been lost over time. That's
reverse evolution.  As for "human teeth?"  I
don't know who told you that, but I'd be
asking for a reference.  Same with the tail -
I don't know what to tell you because this
person did not provide you with a
reference.  So I'd call them on that and ask
for a reference first.
Thanks for writing in, and indeed, I
recognize that if the science can meet an
unbiased test, it will get published. As I
previously mentioned, many creationists
have published in peer reviewed journals.
I've also been a part of the process, both
as the one getting reviewed, and a
reviewer. However, in this particular case,
with Springer-Verlag, the executive vice
president of corporate communications at
Springer gave the reasons why the book
was run through additional peer review:
Springer was unaware of the role of the
book editors had in the intelligent design
movement, and said Springer does not
"endorse intelligent design as a legitimate
area of scientific research."  Notice he
mentioned absolutely nothing of the
content of the book. There was no
problem - the book had already gone
through vetting by two Springer
reviewers.  It was only after Sanford's
personal beliefs were brought up that the
book was yanked.  This is open, flagrant
bigotry.
Several people asked why I didn't present
proof OF creation.
Ah, but do not mistake confidence for
smugness. I am confident, not smug.
There are numerous things wrong with
your premise: First of all, as I'm sure
you're already aware, science cannot
"prove" something, it can only "disprove"
something.  So all too often evidence FOR
creation is also evidence AGAINST
evolution - the two happen at the same
time.  Secondly, if you'd paid close
attention, you'll notice that I HAVE
provided evidence FOR creation.  One bit
of evidence I've beat to death is stasis in
the fossil record. Evolution requires
change over time - a gaining of novel
features and functions in an organism
over time, and a fossil order.  I've showed
over and over again with literally dozens
of examples, including the tetrapod
footprints, how the alleged fossil
sequence is in the wrong order, and the
organisms we find in the fossil record
show extinction and stasis - neither of
which help evolution, and both of which
fit perfectly within the creation model.  Ten
times in the first chapter of Genesis alone
it says God created life to reproduce after
its KIND, therefore good evidence for
creation would be lifeforms showing little
to no change between the fossil record
and modern times, which is exactly what
we see.  We also see profound evidence
for a worldwide flood, which does two
things: It refutes the idea of deep time,
because deep time is only used to explain
away the evidence left behind by Noah's
flood, and it simultaneously affirms the
Genesis account which talks about a
world wide flood.
And by the way - the footprints in the
Tapeats sandstone are a dead-ringer
match to the footprints in the Coconino
sandstone. Compare them for yourself.
Thanks for writing in NotJames, and yes,
you are certainly welcome to disagree
Thank you to everyone who wrote in, and
thank you for watching. I hope you'll join
me again next Genesis Week, I'm your
host Ian Juby, signing off for now.
Remember you can share this video with
your frienememies on twitfaceplus using
the convenient "share" button down
below.  Remember the words of our
Creator who gave us a hope by showing
us He was the way, the truth, and the Life.
See you next time.
[music]
Production Software was provided for
Genesis Week by the Big Valley Creation
Science Museum, located just 25 minutes
north of Drumheller, Alberta.  Visit
BVCSM.com for more details.  You can
help keep this program going by making a
tax-deductible donation to CORE Ottawa,
Kanata North Post Office Box 72075,
Ottawa, ON. Canada, K2K 2P4