ALEX JONES: Politicians are
there to lie and deceive and
to continually trick the people
into never getting
control of their
society again.
They are there to keep
the elites in power.
They are there for the upper
class to wage war against the
middle class and the
working class.
It's the two parties teamed up
against the people, two wings
on the same bird of prey.
Instead of looking at the wings
all day, let's talk
about the head, the beak, the
guts of this thing, its mind,
its eyes, what it believes,
what this bird does.
This is tyranny.
This is what globalism is.
We want a new world order?
It's the banks that engineered
the collapse and they're
bragging about it.
Folks, what we know is
off the chart crazy.
Imagine what we don't know
because truth is strange,
ladies and gentlemen.
RYAN DUFFY: So we started
shooting this piece in the
spring of 2009.
President Obama had just been
elected and was enjoying
really high approval ratings.
And most people were still
holding out hope that we could
get through the economic crisis
and things would be
back to normal soon.
But as we traveled across the
country, we began the kind of
sense that there was
something else
stirring under the surface.
There was this growing movement
of people who really
feared the government and
rejected this idea of hope all
together.
-Be out here and show
people that we--
I've never protested anything
in my life.
This is the first time.
RYAN DUFFY: Oh, really.
-This is the first time.
RYAN DUFFY: Wow.
-But I see a need for it and I'm
going to be here until the
last petal falls.
RYAN DUFFY: More and more folks
were starting to listen
to people like Alex Jones.
-[INAUDIBLE]
ALEX JONES: Come on, people.
The elite are going for broke.
The level of crimes and looting
and corruption they
have engaged means they were
going all the way to the--
RYAN DUFFY: They believed we
were standing on the edge of a
total collapse and they were
getting ready to fight in the
second American Revolution.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
CHRIS HEDGES: It's the
end of an era.
We live in a state of collective
self delusion.
My name is Chris Hedges.
I graduated from seminary at
Harvard Divinity School, did
not get ordained.
I spent almost 20 years of
my life as a foreign
correspondent, eventually,
15 of them with
the New York Times.
I came back to United States,
ran afoul of my employer over
the issue of the Iraq War.
I was told not to speak out
against the war or I would
lose my job.
And faced with that choice,
I left the paper.
I write books.
And when I'm not doing that,
I'm a soccer dad.
Conspiracy theories become a way
to explain the chaos of a
world people don't understand.
What conspiracy theorists don't
grasp is that the elite
is also inept.
And conspiracy theorists
frighten me because they can't
read reality any more than
people who naively believe
that a corrupt elite is going
to bring back the salad days
of casino capitalism
can read reality.
And the worse it gets, the less
people can confront it
because it's painful.
SGT. CHARLES DYER: American
patriots, you may or may not
agree with what I'm
about to say.
This is not the time for
reservation or political
correctness.
What lies before us is of grave
concern to freedom.
Because of what your chance to
lose by remaining silent,
silence shouldn't even
be an option.
My name is Sergeant
Charles Dyer.
I'm a United States Marine,
an Oath Keeper, and a
constitutional patriot.
I entered the Marine Corps in
1998 at the tender age of 17.
Back then I was piss and
vinegar and ready
for a fight, I guess.
I didn't care about politics.
I was all about following orders
and doing what I was
told and fighting for freedom
across the globe, I suppose,
as any young marine would.
I'm actually very new to the
resistance movement.
I've probably only been awake
with the situation for maybe
the last year or so.
It's the targets.
The patriot movement is
basically consisting of all
kinds of different organizations
all across the
United States.
You're looking at militias or
maybe the American resistance
movement, the umbrella
organization.
You may have the Ohio militia,
or Michigan militia or,
whatever militias all
over the place.
Citizens militias like in San
Diego, they're all under the
patriot movement.
And we're trying to take back
this Republic and restore this
Republic like it's supposed to
be, what it was intended from
our founders.
We're here to meet gsbamerica
from YouTube.
His name's--
well, I guess I probably
shouldn't say his name, huh?
gsbamerica from YouTube.
JALIRA: Hello.
SGT. CHARLES DYER: How
are you doing today?
JALIRA: Good, how are you?
I'm Heather.
This is the first time
we've ever met, I
mean, besides YouTube.
We've talked on the phone and
we've emailed plenty.
But everybody gets real excited
about YouTube stars.
I'm Jalira on YouTube.
SGT. CHARLES DYER: That's
our biggest
weapon now, the internet.
That's getting the
word out so fast.
I think that's where I probably
woke up at, watch
stuff on the net.
GSBAMERICA: And if even a
quarter of the stuff we read
is true, then we've
got problems.
SGT. CHARLES DYER: Just the
stuff that you can prove is--
we know we have problems with
the globalization, them saying
they want a new world order.
They want a global government.
They want everything to be
under one law, you know.
When you start delving into some
of this stuff-- and it's
not hard to get on
a path of just--
it makes you crazy, learning all
the crap that happens in
this country.
-I don't understand
what's going on.
We've got to wake the people up
to realize that our country
is just going down
the tubes and our
government is doing it.
I see if something is not done
very quickly to stop Obama and
Pelosi and everything else going
on, I can guarantee you,
we're going to be in a civil
war in a very short time.
But I will fight.
Deport Illegals.
End the deficit in California.
-No bail out for Mexico.
-So anyway, I have
a guest here.
He wanted to talk to you guys
just about the Oath Keepers.
And I don't know if everybody
knows who the Oath Keeprs.
-Yes.
-Yeah, they're awesome.
They give me a lot of hope.
SGT. CHARLES DYER: All right,
I see a lot of older faces
around here.
How many of you guys
are military?
Military?
I All right, Oath Keepers,
that's the organization that
I'm apart of and we try to touch
out to active and former
military and law enforcement,
anybody's who taken an oath to
defend the Constitution, try to
make them realize that the
oath they took doesn't expire.
So for you older gentleman,
too, you may
think I'm too old.
There's nothing I
can do, right?
That's wrong.
This is bigger than the
immigration problem.
Right now, the United States
government and governments all
over the world are trying to
bring in globalization.
I don't know if any of you have
ever heard the term new
world order.
They're trying to bring in a
new world order and destroy
our sovereignty.
That is a direct attack
on the Constitution
of this United States.
That means that they are the
domestic enemy that I swore to
defend and fight against to
defend my Constitution.
And I'm willing to put
my life on the line
to defend this country.
And I'm asking that anybody
who's taken the
oath to do the same.
And it doesn't matter
your age.
So that's all that I really
want to talk to
you guys about today.
And I thank you all for
coming out here.
ALEX JONES: This is
very exciting.
Oath Keeprs just started a few
months ago, Stewart Rhodes,
former Airborne Ranger in the
army, worked for the Ron Paul
campaign at the highest levels,
got upset about what
was happening with the new world
order after the campaign
ended, knew that things
were intensifying.
And he understood that
tyranny will come to
your door in a uniform.
-Welcome to Lexington, the
cradle of American liberty.
ALEX JONES: So perfect timing
with the first big Oath
Keepers meeting coming up on the
green in Lexington where
it all started in 1775,
April 19th.
SGT. CHARLES DYER: We went
to Lexington Green.
What we were there to do was
just to let people know about
Oath Keeprs and what Oath
Keepers were and what it was
to keep an oath and not just
take an oath because there's a
big difference between them.
-[INAUDIBLE]
-Pledging my life--
-My fortune--
-And my sacred--
-It's where the first shots of
the revolution were fired.
The first revolution, not the
new, second, upcoming
revolution.
LTD CMDR GUY CUNNINGHAM:
--studies that when I took the
oath of office to uphold and
defend the constitution of the
United States of America against
all enemies, foreign
and domestic, I knew in my
heart what I meant when I
raised my hand and
swore to it.
-Yeah.
[APPLAUSE]
STEWART RHODES: You
see the need to
stand up and say, look--
I get letters all the time from
people that are terrified
and concerned and worried that
the military's going to be
used against them.
And I saw that during Bush.
There were Democrats that were
upset about that and rightly
so, looking at the rhetoric of
the Bush administration.
Now, you got Obama in there.
And now you've got people
on the conservative side
who are waking up.
And the reason why they're so
afraid is because they all
understand that power was
grown so much and the
constraints on government has
been eroded so much that they
are all vulnerable.
When one guy's in charge, then
the other guys are terrified.
When their guy's in charge,
then their terrified.
ALEX JONES: With every
successive month that follows,
more and more people wake up
to the two puppet system.
There's a puppet on the left,
a puppet on the right.
Wait, it's one guy holding
both puppets.
I don't like that guy.
CHRIS HEDGES: There's no dispute
among the supposed
spectrum between the left and
the right, between Democratic
and Republican over the
core ideology that
is raping the country.
So corporatism is about as close
to unmitigated evil as
you can get because it has built
into it a kind of logic
of increasing profits without
any regard for the human cost.
We've destroyed our country.
We've decimated our
working class.
We are in the process of
decimating our middle class.
We've created an American
oligarchy.
We are allowing corporate
powers to destroy the
ecosystem that sustains
the human species.
Nobody is stepping up,
least of all Barack
Obama, to stop it.
And we are diverted by
bread and circus.
If you doubt it, just watch
what passes for news.
STEVE DOOCY: Hello, everybody.
I'm Steve Doocy with
your FOX Flash.
The octomom and her mother, the
octo grandma, face off in
a heated online interview.
-You already have six
beautiful children.
-You need to learn to let go.
-Why would you do this?
-But you need to learn
to let go.
-So I will never understand.
BARACK OBAMA: He's sleeping
inside the White House.
-Is he going to be in a bed?
BARACK OBAMA: Not in my bed.
-Recently, we've made some
life changing decisions.
CHRIS HEDGES: Given the gravity
of the situation
around us, it would almost
be amusing if
it wasn't so dangerous.
That's how empires die.
And we're dying.
We're dying.
SGT. CHARLES DYER: Let me
ask you a question.
Would you follow the
Constitution against any
orders, even if the President
gives an order?
You would stay with the
constitution and defend it?
-Yes.
SGT. CHARLES DYER: Then
he is an Oath Keeper.
There you go.
It's that simple.
All right, now we're at
Escondido, California at Mr.
Paint Ball.
And we come out here to play
air soft and do a little
training and stuff.
I normally meet some militia
members from San Diego.
Some of my guys help train their
guys since all my guys
are marines and they're
all civilians.
We need a citizen militia.
We need a citizen militia
to defend us from
the government, basically.
That's the only reason we have
the Second Amendment is to
defend the American people and
our country from a tyrannical
government, which is
what we're heading
toward right now.
Watch that left flank, now.
We are definitely the guardians
of the Republic and
the last stand if something
comes down because the
military, they fall under the
UCMJ and a lot of people will
follow any order just for fear
of being thrown to prison and
put in the brig.
There's a lot of us that will
defy orders as long as it's
for the Constitution and defense
of the Constitution.
We know what this
is all about.
We know why we're here.
And we're very strong in our
beliefs and our convictions.
They need to realize that the
reasons we're in Iraq and
Afghanistan right now
are not as good as
people think they are.
Right now we're doing nothing
other than feeding the
industrial military complex
and creating debt for the
Federal Reserve, which isn't
even a federal organization,
so that they can enslave
us and control us.
So join the military?
Depends on what you want
to do with it.
Me, I'm going to use my training
from the military
and, I suppose, become one of
those domestic terrorists that
we're so afraid of from the
DHS and their reports.
Ridiculous.
-Remember, I got detained
and searched
while I was in uniform.
SGT. CHARLES DYER: Really?
-Last day service uniform, two
ribbons on my breast, my
freaking [INAUDIBLE]
badge and all.
I got detained, Dallas, Fort
Worth, on my lay over.
Searched my bag.
Searched my gear.
Searched everything.
SGT. CHARLES DYER:
We are definitely
targets now, military.
We are targets.
And that is sad.
That's sad.
I've been to Iraq.
I've been deployed.
I've got nothing but
the strongest
feelings for my country.
Having marines die over there
and then we come home and
those bastards want to talk
about how we're domestic
terrorists and a threat
to this country.
It makes me so angry.
It just saddens me to think that
we come back and we're
treated like that by
our government.
You know, I got one of my
marines right here being
detained for hours because he's
in uniform trying to get
through the metal detectors
in an airport?
It's ridiculous.
Ridiculous.
Things have to change.
It can't go on like this.
Something has to be done.
ALEX JONES: I've got
this breaking news.
National security watch, 60
right wing terror plots foiled
in the ten years since the '95
Oklahoma City bombing killed
168 people.
By the way, that was
a federal bombing.
We've proven that.
Roughly 60 right wing terrorist
plots have been
uncovered in the United States
according to an upcoming
report of the Southern
Poverty Law Center's
intelligence project.
The media's saying the Tea
Parties are evil terrorists
who are basically cop killers is
what they're trying to say.
And they're a bunch of right
wingers when it isn't about
left and right.
They're desperate to divide
the American people.
CINDY MALLETTE: Barack Obama's
Department of Homeland
Security, you may have heard,
is trying to classify us as
right wing extremists, trying to
warn people to be aware of
people like us.
-Boo.
CINDY MALLETTE: Yeah, boo.
The real people we need to be
fearing are our so called
elected officials in
Washington D.C. -Amen.
CINDY MALLETTE: That's right.
-I do not believe in political
correctness.
And if somebody--
I don't care if he wears a
badge or a gun or what.
If he does something wrong, I'm
going to be right in his
face telling him.
And, well, I guess I'm a
terrorist because I'm pro-life.
-Say one word and they
mow you down.
-Yeah, you know--
-They'll mow you down.
-Die for God.
Die for the right reasons
and it's OK.
-Somebody just came up to the
stage and said we have
pictures of them taking
pictures of us.
Just call me paranoid, but that
just doesn't look like
the local news network.
Let them know you're not a
threat, you have a valid
driver's license on you, and
your passport is safely at
home, and you love America.
Isn't that perfect?
There's a bald eagle and there's
Homeland Security.
Everybody just wave at them real
big so they get a good
picture of us.
ALEX JONES: It says the number
one threat is returning
troops, gun owners,
people buying all
these guns and ammo.
This is the number one
terror threat.
That is a quote.
And they have really
upset people.
CHRIS HEDGES: Alienation and
anger is one that is very
common among returning
veterans.
You saw it after the
Vietnam War.
You're seeing it with these
guys, men and women that are
coming back.
And when you couple that with
a societal breakdown that
essentially denies them the
possibility of reintegrating
into the society, then you are
very volatile and toxic mix.
SGT. CHARLES DYER: It's
like Vietnam.
It's not a winnable war.
It's just sustainable.
The longer we stay over
there, the more debt
they can put on us.
Look at-- what did the
President say?
We were going to be out of there
as soon as he got in
office pretty much?
How long has he been
president now?
And we're still in Iraq.
I saw some stuff over there that
kind of changed my mind.
We lost a good marine.
I sat there and I kept
staring at the bodies
that were laying around.
And it kind of hit me that these
guys are nothing but me.
They're not terrorists.
They're guys that are defending
their country.
They're not terrorists.
The guys in Afghanistan,
they're not terrorists.
They're defending their country
from a foreign invasion.
We create terrorists.
You come into my house and you
kill my wife, you kill my
daughter, you kill any part of
my family, and I'm probably
going to strap on a suicide
vest, go to one of your
checkpoints.
So that's what we're creating
over there in my mind.
That's all I have to say about
that situation for the moment.
CHRIS HEDGES: When you go into
combat, you come back, you not
only suffer from trauma, but if
you become self aware, you
suffer a tremendous existential
crisis.
You realize that all the things
you were taught by both
religious and secular
institutions are a lie.
And it's very, very hard to
adjust because when you come
back that truth, the kind of
prophetic truth, is very
difficult for people who have
not been to war to hear.
You are really a stranger
in a strange land.
SGT. CHARLES DYER: Patriots,
we are not overpowered.
If we unite under one banner of
freedom and fight for our
children's liberty and the
defense of the Constitution,
our resolve is invincible
to any standing army.
They might be able to take the
very breath from our lungs,
but they can never rip the
freedoms from our souls.
CHRIS HEDGES: Rhetoric and
language is not benign.
You have to get people to talk
in the language of violence
before they commit violence.
-Good evening, ladies and
gentleman, [INAUDIBLE]
town watchmen.
I got one question to
begin this video.
I mean, you got to ask yourself,
tonight, are you
felling lucky new world order?
-It's all part of a plan that's
been in the works for
many years, the new
world order.
And I just want to be
a part of this.
I'm really more of a follower.
-I think that more women,
especially young women, need
to get more involved in this,
probably going out and
learning how to work the Mosberg
Model 88 pump action
12 gauge shot gun to
protect yourself.
And we need to fight alongside
our men and our friends and
our families for our freedom
and the Constitution.
-We don't play games.
We quit school because
it had a recess.
You put us out of work and
you stole our pensions.
So we found us a new job.
It's called chewing chewing
gum and kicking butt.
And guess what?
I'm about on my last piece
of chewing gum.
And I know you've done
strategic stuff.
And I've got the documents right
here in front of me.
Let me move this 50 caliber
right here, and I'll shell up
your nose and blow you away
if you mess with American
patriot.
-Now, listen, I love
my country.
And that's why I have to
discourage people from joining
the military with this guy
in the White House.
If you want to protect
your country, join
them or start a militia.
But you don't want Obama to be
your commander in chief.
CHRIS HEDGES: So you have these
forces unleashed and
amplified by a mass media in a
society that stands on the
cusp of disintegration.
And remember that within
American society there's a
deep undercurrent of violence.
SGT. CHARLES DYER: Back in the
90's there was a militia
movement where a lot of people
got together doing the same
thing that we're doing
now, training.
A lot of it was more weekend
warriors, really, though
because as soon as Timothy
McVeigh and those ass clowns
went and blew up buildings and
killed innocent children.
And the government tries
to blame the militia
movement for that.
No matter what, in any movement,
any group, there's
always going to be crazies.
There's always going to be the
people that are extreme one
way or the other and they think
that killing people,
just killing people period is
going to make a difference.
And it's not.
It's absolutely not.
ALEX JONES: For those that don't
understand this, we are
at a historic crossroads.
And I can see in their eyes and
their actions, I realize
they're actually intimidated.
They realize that they've
put their
criminal action into motion.
It's a machine they
can't turn off.
And I think they're starting
to brace for the fact--
I mean, it's like when
you get into fights.
Some bully punches you and then
you gear up and start
punching back.
And you can tell you're going
to whip their ass.
I mean, that's the feeling
right here.
We are going to lick the
new world order's butt.
SGT. CHARLES DYER: There's no
way we're going to be able to
get [INAUDIBLE]
unless we go way back here.
There's some people that think
something's going to happen
within the next two months.
There's some people that think
something's going to
happen in two years.
There's some people that think
nothing will ever happen.
So, I guess, time is the only
thing that can answer that.
CHRIS HEDGES: We are headed
to civil unrest.
We have dis-empowered our
working class and there are
whole pockets now in the United
States that resemble
the third world, where the end
of the world is no longer an
abstraction.
Violence is a kind of cleansing
agent because the
world around them is one
that has betrayed them
and that they hate.
And that is the lure of
apocalyptic violence.
It eradicates what almost
destroyed me.
SGT. CHARLES DYER: I just want
to ask the American people to
wake up and see what's
going on around you.
Walk outside and stop playing
your video games.
Stop watching your TV.
CHRIS HEDGES: In a corporate
state the interests and needs
of citizens don't matter.
You need to destroy the machine
because if we don't
destroy the machine, the
machine's going to destroy us.
It is destroying us.
SGT. CHARLES DYER: Vote and
become politically involved or
start a militia, which
is very important.
Do something.
Do something to make yourselves
better and more
prepared for what
may be coming.
CHRIS HEDGES: Violence
isn't going to work.
Violence is a mistake.
Machine wants violence, it
justifies further oppression.
SGT. CHARLES DYER: I'm not going
to be hiding from my
command anymore.
And I'm sure not hiding
from ATF.
I'm not hiding from FBI.
I'm not hiding from
any organization.
If they want to come take me,
I'm not going to be afraid.
If I'm afraid to that point,
we're in a tyrannical
government in the first place
and people need to rise up.
At that point, there needs to
be a violent revolution.
[MUSIC PLAYING]