[music]
And a welcome to this episode of Genesis
Week, the weekly program of creationary
commentary on news, views and events
pertaining to the origins controversy,
exclusive right here on youtube.  Still one
of the most discussed videos on youtube
in science & technology, we bring you the
information the anti-creationists don't
want you to see or hear, and we  show the
glory of God in the Creation.
Remember if you get lost in cyberspace,
just punch in wazooloo.com or
genesisweek.com, and you will find us, or
click the ever-so-convenient subscribe
link up top. I'm your host, Ian Juby.
Alan Boyle, of Cosmic log on MSNBC had
an interview with theoretical physicist
Lawrence Krauss.  Krauss, head of the
Origins Project at Arizona State
University, tackled the question of "How
did everything come from nothing?" in his
latest book entitled "A Universe from
Nothing."
So how exactly do you get a universe
from nothing? As Boyle explained it, by
calling upon energy to be converted into
matter - following the suit of Einstein's
relativitistic theory, combined with
That's right, it can work.....if we violate
the laws of physics.  translation: it would
be a miracle.
I admire Krauss's brutal honesty - we
creationists have been pointing out for
decades that the origin of the universe
and life requires a miracle - a defiance of
the laws and nature and physics.
But notice that while they are willing to
accept a miracle, they will not accept the
possibility of a miracle worker - Our
Creator, Jesus Christ?
Krause said:
Wow. One comment on the blog, left by
UnitedStates1776, summed up this utter
nonsense nicely:  "I am possible, therefore
I will be."  Krauss has envisioned a very
introspective universe that needs to plan
ahead in order to even be.  Forget about "I
think, therefore I am" - this is "I will be,
therefore I must think of how I can be, so I
can think."
Krauss defended his position by saying:
Wait a minute! You were talking about a
magical, mystical fantasy land where the
laws of physics are different or perhaps
don't even exist, and now somehow you
think this helps people learn about
reality?
Read the blog post yourself, then tell me
what you think in the comments down
below: Do you think Krauss is on to
something? Or is he perhaps on
something?  Or do you think Krauss
should be on something?
In Jesus' Name Productions is working on
a movie that re-enacts Noah's flood.
Producer Joe Bardwell invited both
Christian old-earth advocates and Young
Earth Christians to present their models
of how Noah's flood happened, or didn't
happen, in a peer-reviewed panel format.
Joe then held a competition for ten people
in a technical review panel, of which I
earned a spot. Our job as the technical
review panel was to rip all of these
models apart, scientifically, if we could.
Several old-earth advocates declined to
participate, but their models and
arguments were scrutinized as
non-responding authors.  Six Young Earth
Creation models; both flood and pre-flood
world models, were defended by their
authors in the technical review.  The
competition and technical review itself
went on for some two years, and the
findings of the review were published in a
massive e-book.  This is a must-read for
anyone interested in geology, flood
geology, Biblical catastrophism,
uniformitarianism, actualism, etc...  The
book is available for instant download for
a donation of your choosing.  If you could
though, please make it a generous
donation, as Joe put tens of thousands of
dollars into this important project.
This book, in my opinion, is going to
impact both the creation and evolution
community as much as the landmark book
"The Genesis Flood."  You can get your
copy here at In Jesus Name Productions.
This past week, Teno Groppi handed me a
video of an alleged fossil human footprint
found in South Africa. I shortly thereafter
got bombarded with questions from
viewers, asking my opinion on this track.
I was actually very grateful to see the
video, as Teno and I both belong to a
discussion group about fossil footprints,
and someone had posted some rather
poor photos of this alleged track.
Michael Tellinger posted a video report of
this odd feature in the rock, and they did
a splendid job of showing the anomaly.
I'm afraid to report however, for multiple
reasons, I do not believe this is a fossil
human footprint.
The "footprint" is in granite. Now the
conventional belief is that granite forms
from a melt.  If that is the case, then you
have humans walking around, leaving
footprints in molten rock.  Obviously, this
is impossible.  But even if the granite
formed in a cold process, I still do not
think it's a human footprint.  For example,
do watch the video yourself - here's the
link right here, where is the mud that was
displaced by the foot making the
footprint? There isn't any.  On a track that
deep, there should be some - in fact, quite
a bit.  Secondly, I have personally
investigated erosional features such as
those that make up the toes in this
"track," in multiple locations.  It is caused
by fracture and erosion, and in fact
several geologist friends and I were
discussing how this could happen.  In fact,
in the video you can see some other
overhangs off to the left of the track, in
the rock face.  They just do not bear any
resemblance to toes or anything, but they
are fracture and erosional features just
like you see in the footprint.
A Professor Pieter Wagener is quoted
regarding the allegation of erosional
features, saying
With respect Professor Wagener, as one
of the leading fossil human footprint
experts within the Creation community, I
get typically 1 to 3 requests per year to
come investigate alleged fossil human
footprints.  Of all the investigations I have
carried out, only one of them appeared to
be genuine. All the others turned out to
be foot print-shaped depressions, wave
ripples, fractures or erosion in rock -
including granite and gneiss.  Some of
them, were in fact, even more convincing
that the South African feature.  And you
know what I have learned over the years?
People get really really angry when you
tell them their fossil human footprint isn't
a fossil human footprint.
The fact is that you can so can get so
many shapes and depressions in rocks,
that you will get footprint impressions -
human or otherwise. These are pseudo
fossils.  It is just for this reason that
typically a dinosaur track is not
considered genuine unless you have
three tracks in a row, or other tracks in
that immediate locality.  The absense of a
trail of human footprints at the South
Africa site is also a major blow to the
authenticity of this feature being a human
footprint.
So while I must regretably say that "No, it
is not a fossil human footprint," I must
say well done to MIchael Tellinger on his
report. Thank you - you did an excellent
job of reporting this feature, showing
video from a far off, as well as close-in
detail.  This was much better
documentation then I'd seen thus far, so I
am grateful, thanks for your hard work.
[scary,dramatic music]
Wahoo! Mail for me?
[scary, dramatic music]
Genesis week has again found itself in the
top ten of most discussed videos for the
week in science and technology on
youtube.  I got a barrage of emails from
skeptics wanting me to cover
thermodynamics on Genesis Week, and
claiming that because I hadn't covered it,
my silence must be acknowledgement
that I was wrong about what I said a few
weeks back.  Actually, if you recall, I said I
was going to make a video dedicated to
the subject.  I am still working on it - I am
producing this show weekly, which is a lot
of work, I'm working on a book, and I'm
appearing on the Creation Today
program, so I've been swamped.  So just
....be patient!  My - I've never had such a
large group of people begging me to give
them a public caning!
Some viewers wrote in last week:
Thanks for writing in, but apparently you
missed the point.  You admit in your
comments that the evolutionism myth
claims bird hips evolved from lizard hips.
To change a lizard hip into a bird hip
takes major re-engineering of the
structure of the entire organism - muscles
need to be moved, removed, attached
elsewhere along with the major bone
changes.  Yet, you somehow seem to think
this outlandish story is more believable if
some of the dinosaurs kept their lizard
hips? Look, you are welcome to believe
that lizard hips kept right on trucking in
different organisms, but that frankly is
quite irrelevent to the discussion of
whether or not lizard hips could even
evolve into bird hips.
Actually, ten times in the first chapter of
Genesis alone, it says God created life to
reproduce after its kind.  Of course what
we actually see in the fossil record lines
up with Genesis - we see extinction, and
stasis - organisms reproducing faithfully
after their kind.  That is what is
observable.  Evolution is not observable,
testable, nor repeatable.
Vegavis also wrote in about Protoavis:
Thanks for writing in, however multiple
paleontologists, including my good friend
Joe Taylor who actually saw the original
protoavis fossil with his own two eyes,
see the fossil as a completely modern
bird. Taylor actually lives just outside of
Post, Texas where the fossil was found,
and I've actually excavated in those
triassic redbeds, with Taylor.  When
Taylor saw the fossil, he said to
Chatterjee "You know, the unbiased
person would say that looks just like a
blackbird." To which Chaterjee agreed!
The only reason protoavis is
"controversial" is because the rock layers
in which it was found are "too old" for
birds.
As for the Horton bluff fossil trackways,
you are grossly in error.  The original
claims described the track maker as a
crocodile-like creature, the Nova Scotia
Museum website claims they were made
by an amphibian, and in a 2004 GSA
paper, Lucas Spencer described the
interpretation of the tracks as
"embarassingly bad blunder."  He then
went on to make his own embarrassing
remarks and claimed the tracks were
probably made by fish fins!  I've personally
studied and mapped out the trail.  The
tracks were clearly made by a bipedal
animal with two large toes, a big claw off
the tip of the larger toe, and no tail drag
evidence anywhere. I compared those
footprints to actual ostrich tracks at an
ostrich ranch in Alberta, and they are a
dead ringer, complete with a claw
impression off the tip of the larger toe.
Interestingly, the famous Canadian
geologist, William Logan, found fossil bird
tracks in that immediate area, in 1841.
Sternberg mentioned these tracks in more
detail in a GSA bulletin in 1933, and said
the tracks "superficially ... resemble the
tracks of some of the wading birds, but of
course there is little probability of their
having been made by birds."  Because as
we all know, they can't be bird tracks,
because birds had not yet evolved in the
carboniferous, right?
CircusOfPrecision got into a lengthy
debate with several youtubers, making
numerous, significant points. I hope you
don't mind my calling you "precision" for
short. It was clear that precision had a
pretty wide range of knowledge, and I was
pretty impressed with their patience as
they tried to explain their points to people
who did not want to understand. In
response to claims that somehow letters
in the DNA were information, precision
wrote:
You are right on the money Precision.
Letters do not equal information, letters
convey information.  You need more than
letters - you need someone to assemble
the letters into information, a system for
conveying the information, a system for
reading the information and a system for
using the information, as precision
pointed out, based upon predetermined,
arbitrary rules.  A simile would be
someone speaking Arabic to someone
who speaks and understands only english
- loads of information there, but they are
operating on different rules to convey
information, and the information is lost,
and unusable because of the system
breakdown.
The incredible systems involved in life
that use the information in the DNA are
staggering in their complexity, and
necessary to read the information in the
DNA.  But the information on how to build
those systems, necessary to read
information in the DNA, comes from the
information conveyed by the DNA!  It's a
codependent system.  As we can see in
the comments left against Precision by
those who refused to understand, one
can truly say that there is none so blind
as those who will not see.  The comments
were just as shocking to follow as the
story of Jesus healing the blind man from
birth, and the reaction of those who did
not want to believe in Christ. You can see
why Jesus said "For judgment I am come
into this world, that they which see not
might see; and that they which see might
be made blind."
Precision, I don't know who you are, but
for your valiant efforts in the intellectual
battle, I salute you.
Well that's it for this week's show, thanks
for watching and ranting.  Please click
"Share" down below to share this
program with your friends on
twit-face-plus, and subscribe up top.
Remember the words of Jesus who said "I
am the way, the TRUTH, and THE LIFE -
no man comes to the Father but through
me." See you next Thursday.
[music]