CARL AZUZ, CNN ANCHOR: It`s Wednesday, I`m
Carl Azuz. This is CNN STUDENT NEWS. Just
a few minutes, we`re going to explain how
musician can make money off of viral video.
First of all, we are taking a look inside
President Obama`s cabinet. These are the president`s
top advisers who run different parts of the
U.S government. Getting into the cabinet is
a two step process. Step one, the president
has to nominate you, step 2, the U.S. Senate
has to confirm you. The Founding Fathers gave
the Senate that power in the Constitution.
It`s called advice and consent. Chuck Hagel
has been on both sides of this process. He
served two terms in the Senate, now he`s President
Obama`s pick to be the new U.S. Secretary
of Defense. Yesterday, he was approved by
the Senate for that job. The vote was originally
set for a couple of weeks ago, but there were
some controversy around Hagel because of some
of the things he`s said in the past. His confirmation
vote was delayed by a filibuster. It`s a legislative
tactic that`s used to block and delay action,
and if you`ve studied up on this, it happens
only in the Senate. The U.S. House of Representatives
doesn`t have a filibuster.
And this is how it works: the Senate allows
for unlimited debate. In order to filibuster
something, a bill, a vote, whatever -- once
the Senator is given the floor, he or she
just keeps it. You don`t even have to talk
about the issue that`s being delayed. Originally
senators had to actually talk when they wanted
to filibuster. The record for that belongs
to former South Carolina Senator Strom Thurmond.
In 1957, he went for more than 24 hours. Now,
you don`t need to speak continuously in order
to filibuster. What you need if you want to
end one, is 60 votes. It takes three fifths
of the Senate. To end that debate and the
filibuster. Yesterday, the vote to end the
debate on Chuck Hagel`s confirmation was 71
to 27. That`s stopped the filibuster, and
opened the door for the vote on Hagel to be
the new U.S. Secretary of Defense.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: What`s the word: it`s
an adjective that describes natural or raw
oil before it goes to the refining process.
Crude. That`s the word.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: When gas prices make you want to scream,
try not to deafen the guy in the convenience
store. It`s not usually his fault. Store mark
up barely adds to the price of gas. If you
really want to blame someone, you could blame
OPEC. The Organization of Petroleum Exporting
Countries, a group of 12 nations, has a significant
influence on the cost of crude oil.
For every dollar you spend on gas, crude takes
the biggest chunk -- about 72 cents. The second
largest factor in the price -- taxes. The
U.S. federal government has a tax on every
gallon bought. So do state and local governments
whose taxes depend on where you live. They
all add up to approximately 13 cents on every
gas dollar. Unfortunately for drivers, we
can`t just take oil from the ground, filter
out the dirt and stick it into our gas tanks.
We`ve got to pay for the cost of refining,
the process of turning crude into actual gasoline.
That covers about eight cents on our rapidly
shrinking dollar. And then, actually getting
gasoline to stations and maybe throwing in
an advertisement here and there makes up seven
cents on the buck. Now, all that adds up to
a dollar, 100 percent of the cost of gas.
So you can see how an actual filling station
has practically no influence on the price.
It does get a cent or two, but if you go inside
and buy a drink and a donut, that helps keep
their business fueled.
Thanks to the Oscar nominated movie "Lincoln"
there has been some talk lately about the
13th Amendment, which abolished slavery.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
DANIEL DAY-LEWIS, ACTOR: Settles the fate
for all coming time, not only of the millions
now in bondage, but of unborn millions to
come.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: The movie sent one man on a hunt for
Mississippi`s role in the 13th Amendment.
The amendment was ratified in 1865, but Mississippi
didn`t officially sign on until this year.
Except Mississippi lawmakers did ratify the
13th in 1995. The Mississippi`s Secretary
of State`s office never sent the paperwork
to Washington.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
KEN SULLIVAN, UNIV. OF MISSISSIPPI MEDICAL
CENTER: I don`t think there was any dark plot
or any -- any kind of a plan to not get this
done. I think it was just an error, and I`m
just glad that it`s corrected.
AZUZ: 18 years later, Mississippi`s vote is
officially on the books.
RANJAN BATRA, RESEARCHER, UNIV. OF MISSISSIPPI
MEDICAL CENTER: What I`ve done or Ken has
done is really just dotting an "i" or crossing
a "t". But I think -- I think it`s an important
"I` to dot and in important "t" to cross.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: Over in Europe, scientists are testing
food samples. They are looking for traces
of horse meat and products that were labeled
as beef. Officials are conducting investigations
about this, companies are pulling products
off the shelves. Some consumers are buying
and eating less meat. A lot of people have
been affected by this scandal, but farmers
may turn out to benefit.
(BEGIN VIDEOTAPE)
NIC ROBERTSON, CNN SR. INTERNATIONAL CORRESPONDENT:
The family`s focus -- quality food close to
the customer. Husband Mike helps butcher the
beef when it comes back from the abattoir.
MICHAEL BELCHER, FARMER: The supply chain
is so small and we know everything about the
animal, and there`s nothing that we don`t
know about it.
ROBERTSON: They`ve been farming here for four
generations. Nothing frustrates them more
than the horse meat scandal.
They blame big food chains driving down costs
to maximize profit. Supermarket greed that
led them to take their own meat to market.
BELCHER: I can survive on what Mr. Supermarket
charges the consumer. I can`t survive on what
he wants to pay me as the producers.
ROBERTSON: And this is where the family meat
ends up, on the table in the farmer`s market,
100 mile south in London. One of several farmer`s
markets they sell their product to, and over
the past few weeks, they tell us that business
is up.
Customers like the direct access to the meat
produced at Marshhouse (ph) farm.
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: I find the quality of the
meat is very much better, and I know where
it comes from. And I know that it has been
raised humanely.
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: I would avoid processed,
packaged stuff that`s, you know, all we see
now at the moment. You don`t know what`s -- you
don`t what`s in it. This here, you`ve talked
to the farmers directly, they -- they prepare,
they bring it in, and you can see exactly
what it is and they can tell you exactly what
it is. You can trust them.
ROBERTSON: It seems that people don`t want
the processed meat that`s in the supermarkets.
For Mike and his family and the customers
that come here, this can only mean peace of
mind. Nic Robertson, CNN, London.
(END VIDEOTAPE)
AZUZ: All right, we`ve got another story for
you about unexpected financial upside. It
starts with the "Harlem Shake." Yes, the viral
videos -- no we are not making one. Now, if
you`ve seen you`re probably more focused on
the dancing than the music. But someone did
write the song, it`s his intellectual property,
and every time someone clicks on the Harlem
shake video, he`s getting paid.
(BEGIN VIDEOTAPE)
(MUSIC)
AZUZ: The students at Colorado college broke
every library code in the book with their
version. "The Harlem Shake" even has this
year`s Daytona 500 winner Jimmy Johnson dancing,
and employees at San Antonio Sea World. Now,
Baauer, the song`s creator, is poised to hit
it big. He gets a piece of the ad revenue
-- every time someone clicks on a Harlem Shake
video.
BILL WERDE, EDITORIAL DIRECTOR, BILLBOARD
MAGAZINE: This could be a meaning for revenue
stream -- if you figure a couple of dollars
per 1,000 streams -- and you multiply that
by millions -- you start to see that this
is real money.
AZUZ: Real money is right. As of last week
100,000 "Harlem Shake" videos have been viewed,
some 400 million times on Youtube. And that`s
boosting record sales. "The Harlem Shake"
was the top song download on iTunes U.S. last
week, and one of the top downloads on iTunes
Europe. Baauer isn`t the only artist riding
the viral video wave.
(MUSIC)
AZUZ: South Korean artist Psy hit pay dirt
last year with Youtube phenomenon "Gangham
Style" with more than a billion hits.
WERDE: "Billboard" has reported that Psy made
upwards of $2 million just from the streams
of "Gangham Style", that was without selling
a single track.
AZUZ: But corporate America sees a financial
opportunity in the viral video market. Pepsi
is now promoting soda with its very own "Harlem
Shake."
(MUSIC)
AZUZ: I asked about the "Harlem Shake" on
Twitter yesterday. Most people were tweeting
they love it. Tell us what you think. If you`re
on Facebook, find us at Facebook.com/cnnstudentnews
and say whether you love or hate the "Harlem
Shake."
(END VIDEOTAPE)
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: Is this legit? In nature,
penguins are found only in the Southern Hemisphere
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: The penguins` bodies are designed to
move through the water. But getting them in
the water -- that can be tricky. At least
for this one. Walking down the board, he`s
fine. Going off the board -- ah-ah. He takes
another (pass coming up and chickens out again.
This is some serious penguin trepidation.
The bird is flightless, but he is frightful.
One more chance, probably just going to turn
around again, but this time, a little too
close to the edge. It wasn`t exactly a swan
dive, but sometimes when you need to get over
your fear, you just got to wing it. Really,
there was no pengoing (ph) off the board,
he just had to get the courage to dive in
with both feet, bird brain.
We`ll pull our resources and meet you back
here for more CNN STUDENT NEWS tomorrow. One
more thing, teachers -- don`t forget to hit
our homepage and show your feedback on today
show. Thanks for watching. Have a great day.