SHANE SMITH: So is that
why your nickname was
General Butt Naked?
SHANE SMITH: A lot of people
would drink or do
drugs before fighting?
SHANE SMITH: Yeah.
SHANE SMITH: So you
killed the child?
JOSHUA BLAHYI: Yes.
SHANE SMITH: And then
you drank the blood?
JOSHUA BLAHYI: Yeah.
MALE SPEAKER :
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
CROWD:
MALE SPEAKER 1 : So what
kind of war is this?
Guerrilla?
MALE SPEAKER 2 :
World War III.
SHANE SMITH: We here at Vice
have been fascinated by
Liberia for a long time.
It's America's first
and only foray into
quasi-colonialism in Africa.
It started as a back-to-Africa
movement for freed slaves and,
in fact, their constitution
was written in Washington.
And Monrovia, the capital city
of Liberia, is actually named
after President Monroe.
It became a state
in the 1840s.
So the freed slaves go back to
Africa and promptly enslave
the native Africans based on the
plantation method they had
learned in the US, which lasts
for about 140 years, until
Samuel K. Doe, the first native
African-born Liberian,
was elected.
But this doesn't
last very long.
Why?
Because an American-educated--
and some would say
American-backed--
rebel leader named Charles
Taylor and his buddy, Prince
Johnson, came from America
and overthrew him.
MALE SPEAKER:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
MALE REPORTER : Despite reports
that the government
wants talks with the rebels,
the violence goes on.
FEMALE REPORTER : Rebel forces
stormed into the center of the
capital today.
They are now less than a mile
from the executive mansion
where President Samuel Doe has
barricaded himself with about
500 soldiers.
SHANE SMITH: In fact, Prince
Johnson had got to Doe before
his buddy Charles, ended up
torturing him, cutting him up,
and is rumored to have
eaten him while
filming the whole thing.
[SHOUTING]
SHANE SMITH: So Charles Taylor
finally gets elected with a
campaign slogan that reads, "He
killed my ma, he killed my
pa, but I'll still vote
for him." And it
works, he gets elected.
But he's so corrupt that soon
after, there's a bunch of
warlords fighting for control
over Liberia, the country
devolves into civil war, and
things go from bad to
severely fucked up.
SHANE SMITH : But this is like
a civil war on steroids.
It's a post-apocalyptic
Armageddon with child soldiers
smoking heroin, cross-dressing
cannibals, systematic rape--
it's total hell on earth.
[GUNFIRE]
MALE SPEAKER:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
MALE SPEAKER 1: We
love the music.
There's the music.
MALE SPEAKER 2 : They call
it the sound of death.
MALE SPEAKER 1: Yeah, but it's
the sound of music to us.
SHANE SMITH: Liberia's been in
the news a lot lately because
Charles Taylor is on trial at
The Hague for war crimes.
But we wanted to know what
happened to all the other
warlords, so we contacted a
Canadian journalist who lives
in Liberia named Myles Estey,
who's kind of a Kurtz-like
character--
tall, skinny, skeleton guy who's
had malaria more times
than he's had hot dinners.
And he said he could get
us access to all these
ex-warlords.
So we said, great.
We got on a plane, and
we flew to Liberia.
[MUSIC - THE ALMIGHTY DEFENDERS,
"ALL MY LOVING"]
SHANE SMITH : When you first
get to Monrovia, the first
thing you think is,
it's really hot.
It's really hot, it's
really poor, and
it's totally chaotic.
In fact, when we went to pick
up Myles, he had just gotten
out the hospital with malaria.
He gets in the car, and he says,
are you ready to go?
We're going to Baboon Town in
the red light district to meet
our first general, General
bin Laden.
So as we drove to Baboon Town,
we asked Myles what's up with
the name, "General bin Laden?"
And he said, well, a lot of
the generals took different
names because they didn't want
to be identified after the
various wars, and these
pseudonyms were meant to strike
terror into the hearts
of their enemies.
So there's a General Rambo,
because he's scary, there was
a General Mosquito, because
mosquitoes are terrifying
because they bring malaria.
The general that fought General
Mosquito was named
General Mosquito Spray.
And of course, there's
General bin Laden.
In fact, there's two
General bin Ladens.
Our General bin Laden, we found
out en route, had just
been put in jail.
Now, he didn't know why, but
he suspected because the
authorities found out that
we were coming with
cameras to shoot him.
MYLES ESTEY: And they say
they're not gonna let him out,
but we can interview him in the
jail and we can interview
the commanders.
SHANE SMITH : Let's do that.
Let's go then.
MYLES ESTEY: Yeah.
SHANE SMITH : So the minute we
arrive in Baboon Town, our car
is surrounded by a bunch
of sketchy dudes.
So when Myles came back and said
we could interview bin
Laden in the police station, I
was like, yeah, let's get out
of here and get in there
really quick.
So we get into the police
station, and it's chaos.
Some guards are saying you can
go see him, other guards are
saying you can't go see him,
and we just have to
sit there and wait.
SHANE SMITH: I like being
in the police station.
It's nice.
[MONKEY SCREECHING]
SHANE SMITH: Monkey.
Little monkey.
He's got herpes, I think,
or something.
Hi.
What's wrong with the monkey?
Why is the monkey here?
SHANE SMITH: Why is
the monkey here?
[MONKEY SCREECHES]
SHANE SMITH: We're in a police
station in the middle of the
red light district to meet
General bin Laden, and I'm
wondering why the
monkey's here.
[SHANE SMITH SIGHS]
SHANE SMITH : Then eventually,
after sitting there for a
while, we realized, oh, we've
got to grease some palms.
So we gave them some money and
bang-- we were back into the
jail and we could talk
to bin Laden.
Hey, bin Laden?
GENERAL BIN LADEN : Yeah?
SHANE SMITH : How are you?
MYLES ESTEY : This is
my friend, Shane.
SHANE SMITH : Shane.
GENERAL BIN LADEN: [INAUDIBLE].
Yeah.
SHANE SMITH: Nice to meet you.
We're gonna try to get you
out of here now, and
then we can go back.
SHANE SMITH: All right.
We're gonna do it right now.
GENERAL BIN LADEN: Now.
SHANE SMITH: OK.
MYLES ESTEY: Yeah, I
know what he did.
We're talking about to get him
out, what do we have to do?
MYLES ESTEY: To who?
MALE SPEAKER : OK, we'll stop.
We'll stop.
SHANE SMITH : Video's off.
OFFICER : --without
the permission.
MALE SPEAKER : It's off.
SHANE SMITH : The video's off.
He's carrying-- he's just
holding it right now.
MYLES ESTEY : Look,
we're good people.
We're good--
nobody's recording anything.
MYLES ESTEY : Sure, I can
give him cash and--
can we pay him and
pay you a fine?
And then take him?
OFFICER : Fine.
MYLES ESTEY : OK, great.
OFFICER : That's good.
MYLES ESTEY : OK.
SHANE SMITH : OK, let's go,
let's go, let's go.
Let's go, let's go, let's go.
OK, let's go, let's go.
MALE SPEAKER: Hey, yeah-- you!
SHANE SMITH: We went
in there--
we're being followed by
the police right now.
SHANE SMITH: Yeah, we might
have to change tapes or do
something, because--
what we do is we shoot cars--
MALE SPEAKER : Yeah, that's--
SHANE SMITH: --and if
they come, we can
give them the tape.
There's nothing on the tape.
SHANE SMITH: Yeah.
We do, right now.
GENERAL BIN LADEN: We'll
go to my warehouse.
SHANE SMITH: OK.
GENERAL BIN LADEN: Don't
worry about that.
SHANE SMITH: Our trip is getting
progressively heavier.
SHANE SMITH: Yeah,
that'll be good.
GENERAL BIN LADEN: We're going
on top of the building.
SHANE SMITH: OK.
I'm kind of a little bit worried
that the police are
gonna come get us right now.
I gave them a fake name
and fake number.
SHANE SMITH: OK, nice
to meet you.
SHANE SMITH: Nice to meet you.
SHANE SMITH: Thank you.
Thank you.
So after we got bin Laden out
of jail, he was very excited
to get us up to his rooftop
and tell us his story.
And according to him, the
ex-generals, who are now the
community leaders, are the only
ones doing anything to
help the people.
SHANE SMITH: So maybe you could
explain a little bit
about-- so first of all, you
became known as bin Laden
during the war?
GENERAL BIN LADEN:
During the war.
SHANE SMITH: And then after the
war, now you're sort of
trying to help people by
carpentry and by karate.
GENERAL BIN LADEN: Karate.
SHANE SMITH: Do you get
any money here?
SHANE SMITH: No, but the UN or
the government doesn't give
you any money?
SHANE SMITH : Nothing?
SHANE SMITH: And is this area--
this is red light here?
GENERAL BIN LADEN:
It's a red light.
This is red light.
SHANE SMITH: And is it--
is there a lot of crime
in red light?
MALE SPEAKER : Oh yeah.
GENERAL BIN LADEN
: Yeah, it's--
this is red light.
SHANE SMITH : Red light.
SHANE SMITH : So Myles comes
over, stops the interview, and
says, we have to get the
fuck out of here now.
Bin Laden looks down and
he goes, yeah, yeah,
those aren't my guys.
You guys should really go.
SHANE SMITH : So bin Laden
gave us an escort, and a
couple of his guys got us
through the crowd to the car,
and we got the fuck out.
SHANE SMITH : So let's go.
Let's go, let's go, let's
go, let's go.
Holy fucking shit.
That was out of hand.
We gotta get out of here.
There was some heavy duty
Libs there, boy.
So after meeting and being
freaked out by General bin
Laden, we wanted to see what
the UN and government were
doing to rebuild Liberia.
We met a local journalist named
Nagbe, and we asked him,
and he said, you want to the
government and UN are doing?
I'll take you to West Point.
West Point is the worst slum in
Liberia, which makes it one
of the worst slums in West
Africa, which makes it one of
the worst slums in the world.
Now, when you first get there,
the first thing you want to do
is get the hell out.
It's open sewers everywhere--
shit, piss, garbage, everything
mixed in--
and the stench is
overpowering.
SHANE SMITH : Oh, dude.
It really stinks here.
SHANE SMITH : But, I mean, one
of the first basic rules is
don't shit where you eat.
IMMANUEL NAGBE: That's
it, but--
SHANE SMITH: That's
a number one rule.
SHANE SMITH: But the government
has to do something
about that.
SHANE SMITH: Mm-hmm.
So even in one of the worst
slums of Western Africa, you
see the cultural impact that
America has there.
All the kids are wearing Biggie
or Tupac t-shirts.
In fact, one kid came up to us
and said, hey, I'm a rapper.
Can I rap for you?
And we said yes.
And it wasn't about bling, and
it wasn't about Cristal.
SHANE SMITH: And is there a
lot of malaria in here?
SHANE SMITH : Needless to say,
in West Point, health
conditions are foul.
Disease is everywhere--
malaria, infections, and
AIDS are rampant.
SHANE SMITH : Cover
up for heroin.
SHANE SMITH : Wow.
IMMANUEL NAGBE: So
a big business.
SHANE SMITH: We heard stories
that during the war, the
rebels would go out in boats
with diamonds and trade the
diamonds for weapons and
cocaine, and there was a lot
of Colombians and Mexicans.
SHANE SMITH: We find it
interesting because cocaine
and heroin are very expensive
drugs, and so we were
surprised to find heroin here.
Usually in poorer countries,
there's speed or meth or
things you can make.
SHANE SMITH: Why is that?
[BABY CRYING]
MALE SPEAKER:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
MALE SPEAKER : You got
to smoke this up.
MALE SPEAKER :
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
SHANE SMITH: Liberian
dollars or--
IMMANUEL NAGBE: Liberian
dollars.
SHANE SMITH: So how
much is that?
SHANE SMITH : So because of the
poverty, a lot of women
have to become prostitutes?
IMMANUEL NAGBE: Yes.
SHANE SMITH: Sex worker.
IMMANUEL NAGBE: We
can go this way.
SHANE SMITH: No, you can
just show it to us.
SHANE SMITH : The legacy of
civil war in Liberia is
staggering.
It's the fourth-poorest
country in the world.
50% of the country is
illiterate, 70% of the female
population has been raped,
80% of the population is
unemployed, and a large
percentage of the population
has eaten human flesh.
MALE SPEAKER: It tastes
like real meat.
If you taste it, you'd like
to eat it every day.
You want to see some piece?
SHANE SMITH : Now one of the
warlords responsible for these
atrocities, who fought in all
three civil wars, is a guy
named General Rambo, who we
picked up at a market.
He said, I'll talk to you if
you take me to the old
headquarters of the rebel
factions outside of town.
SHANE SMITH : When did the
hotel stop working?
SHANE SMITH : Because
of the war.
GENERAL RAMBO : When
the war came.
SHANE SMITH : Yeah.
GENERAL RAMBO: Yes,
it happened.
SHANE SMITH: So you were one
of the ones that came in to
take out Taylor?
GENERAL RAMBO: Yes.
SHANE SMITH : And then, at one
point, the American government
came to try to get you
to go to Iraq?
SHANE SMITH: Yeah.
SHANE SMITH: American.
SHANE SMITH : Yeah.
And so when there was Iraq,
it was like, OK, let's go.
We can help.
So what happened?
SHANE SMITH : The government
wouldn't let you go?
SHANE SMITH: Do you think it's
a problem that you have all
these ex-combatants who grew
up fighting-- you fought in
three wars--
they have no money, they
have no job, and
isn't that a problem?
GENERAL RAMBO: It's
a big problem.
SHANE SMITH: So they're still
there with the guns?
GENERAL RAMBO: Yeah, they're
still there with the guns.
The war is hot.
SHANE SMITH : So if the rebel
forces wanted, they could take
over tomorrow?
SHANE SMITH: Two
or three hours?
GENERAL RAMBO: Sure.
SHANE SMITH: Wow.
SHANE SMITH : And do
you think there's a
possibility of that happening?
GENERAL RAMBO: Yes.
SHANE SMITH : So what Rambo is
saying is, there's still
plenty of guns in Liberia, and
him, or someone like him, can
take over Monrovia in two hours
if the UN leaves, and
the UN is scheduled to
leave next year.
And as we said our goodbyes to
Rambo, we told him we were
going back to West Point.
SHANE SMITH : Yeah?
SHANE SMITH: Cannibalism,
chaos, killing, rape,
everything.
GENERAL RAMBO : Everything.
SHANE SMITH : A few years ago,
we did an article in Vice
Magazine called "General Butt
Naked Versus the Tupac Army,"
about a particularly fierce
Liberian warlord called Butt
Naked who fought naked, his
child soldiers fought naked,
and they were cannibals.
So we asked Rambo if he knew him
by chance, and he said, in
fact, we're from the same
tribe, I know him well.
He promised to set up an
interview while we did our
follow-up in the brothels
of West Point.
[CAR HONKING]
SHANE SMITH: Driving
into West Point at
night is pretty freaky.
There's no electricity grid in
Monrovia, so it's pitch black.
SHANE SMITH: Hit
it on the wall.
Hit it on the wall.
So this is the craziest,
fucking scariest
drive ever down here.
We got a little bit lost in the
port, and you couldn't see
anything, there's
no electricity.
And then you just see people
wandering around, fucking
shit, piss--
fucking yelling at us, we want
money, we want money.
Now there's no lights in here.
We're gonna go in here,
this is the brothel.
We're gonna see what's
going on.
Hello.
How are you?
A lot of dudes are coming
in now, it's crazy.
I don't know where
we're going.
MALE SPEAKER : Straight.
SHANE SMITH: Straight.
Wow.
That room looks--
MALE SPEAKER : Now we're
in chalet number five.
SHANE SMITH: I don't know what
happens in here, but I don't
want to know.
Wow.
What the fuck goes
on in here, dude?
Wow, wow, wow, wow, wow.
Well, we were here a
little bit earlier.
There was used condoms and
bloodstained sheets, and now
they've sort of done it up.
So we're gonna interview some
of the girls, see what they
have to say.
We have a code for when
something's freaky.
We go, "It's gnar gnar."
Gnar gnar.
SHANE SMITH : One of the things
we had heard since we
arrived in Liberia was about the
alleged sexual misconduct
by the UN staff, so we asked
the girls at the
brothel about it.
IMMANUEL NAGBE: OK, paradise.
FEMALE SPEAKER: I wanted
to get me a job.
IMMANUEL NAGBE: Yeah.
FEMALE SPEAKER: For myself.
IMMANUEL NAGBE: What sort
of work do you do
in West Point now?
IMMANUEL NAGBE: OK.
IMMANUEL NAGBE: All right.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Now.
We were talking--
listen to me.
IMMANUEL NAGBE: Listen
to me and sit down.
Now listen.
IMMANUEL NAGBE: Listen.
SHANE SMITH : As soon as the
girl started screaming, a
bunch of heads popped
into the room.
And then when she started
screaming about money,
everyone's going, money, money,
money, where's the money?
And at that point, Nagbe said
to us, you'd better get the
hell out of here.
So we sort of took off through
the tangled alleyways and just
tried to get back to the car.
SHANE SMITH: We're getting the
fuck out here right now.
And when we got to the car,
our driver-- who was also
supposed to be our security--
was so freaked out that he
peeled out and nearly hit a
group of people that had
surrounded the car.
SHANE SMITH : And if you hit a
group of people down deep in
West Point, that was it.
It was a death sentence.
They would have tore us apart.
[CAR HONKING]
SHANE SMITH : And to make things
even freakier, as we're
pulling out of West Point, Rambo
texts Myles and says,
not only does Butt Naked want to
do the interview, but that
he's waiting at our
hotel for us.
Yeah, now we're going back to
sanity, to hang out with an
ex-cannibal and multi-murderer,
who's now
staying at our hotel and
decided not to leave.
Because they were there-- they
want us to hang out.
Meanwhile, he knows I have tons
of money, and he's on the
run because people
want to kill him.
Should I just leave my
door open, General?
Do you want to come in?
SHANE SMITH : Now we are very
nervous to meet General Butt
Naked, and he's very nervous to
meet us, because he's had
several assassination attempts
against him.
He wants to meet us and vet us
before he'll OK an interview.
When we told him about our
escape from West Point that
night, he laughed, and
he seemed to ease up.
After that, he asked for
a phone, he called
Rambo, and it was on.
JOSHUA BLAHYI:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
GENERAL RAMBO : Yeah?
JOSHUA BLAHYI:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
JOSHUA BLAHYI: Yeah,
some white guys.
They are good guys.
The guy's a good guy, man.
Tell the boss lady hi, yeah?
SHANE SMITH : We asked the
general, now known as Joshua
Blahyi, why people were trying
to kill him, and he told us
that it was because he had been
recently pardoned for his
war crimes.
And when we asked how he got
pardoned, he told us it was
his conversion to Christ and
his becoming a man of God.
SHANE SMITH : So we talked
with Joshua late into the
night, until he told us to get
to bed because the next day he
was going to show
us his Liberia.
[SINGING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
SHANE SMITH: In the morning,
Joshua Blahyi took us out, and
the first stop was the area
within Monrovia that he used
to control during the war.
SHANE SMITH : And who
would be attacking?
SHANE SMITH: Alive?
JOSHUA BLAHYI: Yes.
SHANE SMITH: And what
does that do?
SHANE SMITH : The next stop was
the place where there had
been an assassination attempt
on Joshua's life
just the day before.
SHANE SMITH : And he just--
he hit you and then ran?
JOSHUA BLAHYI: Yeah.
Yeah.
SHANE SMITH : You jumped
over the car?
JOSHUA BLAHYI: Yeah, jumped
over the car.
SHANE SMITH : And who
do you think it was?
SHANE SMITH : Hurt a lot
of people in the war?
JOSHUA BLAHYI: In the war.
SHANE SMITH : Next, Joshua
wanted to show us his mission
in the country, where he was
rehabilitating ex-child soldiers.
SHANE SMITH : And are there are
a lot of people who fought
during the war that can't
get rid of the violence?
JOSHUA BLAHYI: It's very hard.
SHANE SMITH: Very hard.
JOSHUA BLAHYI: It takes time
to get rid of the violence.
SHANE SMITH: Yeah.
How did you get rid
of the violence?
SHANE SMITH: Yeah.
SHANE SMITH : OK.
JOSHUA BLAHYI: Come,
you can look at--
come, come and see.
SHANE SMITH: Nobody
brought bug juice.
[LAUGHING]
SHANE SMITH: No, no, no, no.
It's OK.
Well, I don't mind
getting wet.
SHANE SMITH : About a million
people in Africa die every
year from malaria, and malaria
thrives in swamps
exactly like this.
SHANE SMITH: It's very sploochly
on my moochly.
Thanks.
Good.
Hello.
MALE SPEAKER: Hello.
SHANE SMITH: This is what
all fear stems from.
Thank you.
So these were some of the
boys that you fought
with before, or no?
SHANE SMITH: Yeah.
So is that why your nickname
was General Butt Naked?
SHANE SMITH: A lot of people
would drink or do
drugs before fighting?
SHANE SMITH: So you
killed the child--
JOSHUA BLAHYI: Yes.
SHANE SMITH: --and then
you drank the blood?
JOSHUA BLAHYI: Yeah.
SHANE SMITH : Now why would
you fight naked?
[MEN SINGING]
SHANE SMITH: This is his mission
that they're building.
They're singing now.
MALE SPEAKERS :
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
JOSHUA BLAHYI : Welcome
to our home.
SHANE SMITH : Thank you.
SHANE SMITH: So you fought
for Charles Taylor and--
SHANE SMITH: Johnson.
So you were enemies before?
JOSHUA BLAHYI : Yeah,
we're enemies.
SHANE SMITH : Yeah.
SHANE SMITH : Where
are we right now?
SHANE SMITH: Cemetery.
SHANE SMITH: So this is the
cemetery where, after the war,
there was nowhere to live, so
the people would come in,
empty out the graves, and
live in the graves.
Maybe up to about 4,000 people
lived in the graves.
SHANE SMITH: It's a
very heavy vibe.
Empty graves everywhere.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
SHANE SMITH: We were just at
lunch, we were talking about--
we ordered some ribs, and you
said, "No, I don't like to
eat--"
JOSHUA BLAHYI: Flesh.
SHANE SMITH: "--flesh." And I
said, "Why don't you like to
eat flesh?" And you told me the
story about coming back
from Nigeria.
Could you tell us that story?
SHANE SMITH: You were
eating human flesh?
SHANE SMITH : What
would you eat?
SHANE SMITH : Yeah.
JOSHUA BLAHYI : Yeah.
OK.
JOSHUA BLAHYI: Yeah.
SHANE SMITH: We're talking
about eating
human flesh in a graveyard.
It's a bit weird.
JOSHUA BLAHYI: Yeah.
SHANE SMITH: OK.
So we can go.
[JOSHUA BLAHYI SINGING]
PREACHER : In Jesus'
father name!
CONGREGATION : Amen!
PREACHER : In Jesus'
father name!
CONGREGATION : Amen!
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[APPLAUSE]
PREACHER : Let it be done
in Jesus' name.
CONGREGATION : Amen.
PREACHER : In Jesus'
mighty name.
CONGREGATION : Amen.
PREACHER: God bless you.
Put your hands together
for Jesus.
[APPLAUSE]
PREACHER: Hallelujah.
Hallelujah.
OK.
God bless you.
Amen.
[APPLAUSE]
[MUSIC PLAYING, SINGING]
SHANE SMITH : Liberia, on the
one hand, has more crime and
poverty and rape
and cannibalism
than you've ever seen.
But on the other, it's also got
a church on every street
corner, every car has a
religious slogan, they have
huge revivals with tens of
thousands of worshipers.
It's some sort of weird
heaven-and-hell scenario.
[CHEERING]
FEMALE SPEAKER :
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
[MUSIC PLAYING, SINGING]
SHANE SMITH : While hanging out
with Joshua, I started to
get a bit of Stockholm syndrome,
because he's
charming, the churches
are nice,
there's not as much danger.
And I started to like him.
[MUSIC PLAYING, SINGING]
SHANE SMITH : But as he was
preaching, I thought to
myself, this guy has killed tens
of thousands of people.
In fact, he's probably killed
the relatives of the people in
the church worshipping
and adoring him now.
And I'm thinking to myself,
what the fuck is going on?
[MUSIC PLAYING, SINGING]
FEMALE SPEAKER : Hallelujah!
FEMALE SPEAKERS : Amen!
[APPLAUSE]
SHANE SMITH: I just want to say
thank you for having me in
your church.
Praise God.
And I'd like to say thank you
to Joshua Blahyi for all the
good work he's doing.
Hopefully, we can help, and
hopefully, we can show what
we're doing here in Liberia,
what you're doing in Liberia,
and we can help make it better
and bring more awareness to
what's happened here.
JOSHUA BLAHYI: Amen.
[APPLAUSE]
SHANE SMITH : I have to admit
that when Joshua handed me the
mic, I had no idea what
I was saying.
At that point in the trip, I
felt like I was on acid.
[APPLAUSE]
[MUSIC PLAYING, SINGING]
JOSHUA BLAHYI: [SINGING]
I worship you because
of who you are.
[MUSIC - THE ALMIGHTY DEFENDERS,
"ALL MY LOVING"]
SHANE SMITH : And as I sat and
listened to Joshua preach, I
thought about the fact that the
UN is leaving in less than
a year, and Rambo had told
us that the generals
are ready to fight.
They have the soldiers, they
have the guns, and they're
living in abject poverty.
And I wondered if that happened,
would Joshua stay
with God, or would he return to
being General Butt Naked?
JOSHUA BLAHYI: Somebody
shout "Glory!"
CONGREGATION : Glory!
JOSHUA BLAHYI: Let us pray.
[MUSIC - THE ALMIGHTY DEFENDERS,
"ALL MY LOVING"]