from uh... mit romney this clip number
one
and i said well gosh cant wait
kelly find some some women that are also
qualified
and uh... and sweet we took a concerted
effort to go out and find a women
who had backgrounds that could be
qualified to become members of our
cabinet
i went to a number of women's groups and
said can you help us find folks i
brought us or a binders full of the of
women i was proud of the fact that after
i staffed by cabinet and my senior staff
at the university orca in albany did a
survey of all fifty states
and concluded that mine had more women
and seniors leadership positions than
any of the state america
now one of the reasons i was able to get
somebody good women to be part of that
team was because of our recruiting f yes
it was their recording efforts and so i
said to uh...
matt binder who is our uh... one of our
producers
ringleader binder
and uh... so we're gonna have digby on
today but it turns out
that this story
allowed uh... mit romney
not exactly true
i'm just so shocked i don't even know on
even though the say
my
uh...
it turns out that you know mit romney
didn't turn to is
his pals once he got an opposite break
binder love women
so that i may hire more women no in fact
according to david bernstein riding in
the uh... phoenix
what actually happened was that in two
thousand two prior to the election not
even know yet whether would-be
republican or democratic administration
a bipartisan group of women in
massachusetts
formed a mask at to address the problem
a few women and senior leadership
positions in state government
they created the binder
and handed it
to the incoming governor at the time
sorrow maybe a slight distinction small
fed by mit romney
of course according to burstein
uh... he did appoint fourteen women out
of his first thirty three senior level
appointments but they were all in
agencies you didn't care about
and it also raises the question
how is it that guy who had been working
in business for twenty five years in
senior management
balancing budgets
doing all the negro league
saving the olympics
never came across one woman he thought
was qualified to serve in his
administration
they've got
abundant
also throughout his administration if
there was a decline a a progressive
decline throughout his administration a
woman working under yasir ended up being
less women uh... than than than at the
beginning but
let's not get the picking
sometimes the binders are not uh... you
they just the binders don't show up