The following program is brought
to you in living colour on NBC.
Lieutenant Spock. Status report!
I estimate it will fire in 23.4 seconds.
Engineering, all power
to the aft shields.
There is none to give, is there?
Evasive manoeuvres, Mr Tyler!
The helm is not responding, sir!
Captain Pike, we are on emergency power.
Warp drive going critical.
Thank you, Number One!
10 seconds.
All hands, this is the captain!
Prepare for saucer separation.
I repeat, stand by to...
Space, the final frontier.
These are the new voyages of the Starship Enterprise
Its five-year mission,
to explore strange new worlds.
To seek out new life and new civilizations.
To boldly go where no man has gone before.
[Kirk] The Enterprise
[Spock] Captain Kirk, I do not make this request lightly,
but it is urgent that you alter course for gateway immediately.
Mr Spock, I'm afraid, I don't know
what good a starship can do.
I'm sure the scientists, there at project
"Timepiece," can handle this situation.
I knew this wouldn't work.
Captain, as I'm sure Lt Uhura has told you,
my request has priority one authorization.
You can confirm this with Starfleet
Command, but you must comply.
Spock out.
Well. Priority one it is!
Lt Uhura, sound Red Alert.
Helm, set course for "Gateway".
Aye, sir. Coming to course
zero one one mark three zero.
Commander, do you
foresee any difficulty in
navigating the time waves,
within the Gateway system?
Mr DeSalle should have
no difficulty, Captain.
Very good, Commander Kargh.
Helm, you heard our first Officer.
Maximum warp!
Aye, sir.
Welcome, Captain!
Dr MacGregor, Thank you.
This is my chief medical officer,
Dr Leonard McCoy
My 1st Officer, Commander Kargh.
How do you do?
This is Commander Spock.
Commander? There are no
Vulcans in Starfleet.
Captain, as you know, project "Timepiece" was
established as a permanent research facility
shortly after your discovery
of the artefact on this planet.
Of course, Doctor. Your
reputation does precede you.
Then I hope you will take us
seriously when we tell you,
that the natural course
of time has been altered.
These figures, represent the flow of time.
The natural flow of time, yes.
Here are the readings I
took only a few hours ago.
This is at least a magnitude ten variation.
10.2! From that point on,
history is no longer correct.
And if that's not enough,
the same anti-protons signature
shows up again, only a few months ago.
Corresponding to our battle with the
planet devouring weapon.
commonly known as the doomsday machine.
Our battle?
Captain, until this shift in time,
Mr Spock was your first Officer,
aboard the Enterprise.
Enterprise?
There's no ship named...
According to my research,
you and the crew of the Farragut,
were assigned many of
the same missions,
had many of the same experiences,
shared many of the same crises
as the crew of the Enterprise.
Parallel time-line development
is not without president.
Does that includes letting Matt Decker
die senselessly in a shuttlecraft?
Yes, including even that.
That and your discovery of
this planet and the vortex.
Captain, you loaned Cmdr Spock to us
as a research consultant.
He was protected from the
changes in the time-line.
As are we all, here on "Gateway".
Cmdr Spock, the Farragut has done
battle with several of these killers
since this "doomsday war" began.
And Matt Decker was killed flying a
shuttlecraft into the doomsday weapon.
When you detonated the Constellation
inside that same device
Dr MacGregor instruments registered a smaller,
yet otherwise identical anti-proton surge.
So what you're really saying is,
you expect us to go back in time,
and change history so things go your way?
Well, this is our life! Our history.
How do we know your "correct"
history is the right one?
The best one?
Because Jim here, in your time-line,
billions of people are dead!
As you pointed out, Doctor,
Vulcan and dozens of other worlds,
have been destroyed,
in the 14 years since the first
of these machines appeared.
In my time-line, those worlds are still there.
Vibrant, thriving, filled with life.
So, that's what we're supposed to do?
Use the vortex to travel back in time,
to 2254 and stop these things,
before they can start a war?
Without the proper preparation,
you would be annihilated
along with everything else in your path.
First, we must gather more information.
And exactly how do we do that?
Sorry, I asked.
It is our hope that by following
this smaller, more recent pulse,
from your encounter with
the doomsday weapon,
we might get some sense as to how these time-
deviations occur and how we might counter them.
The pulse leads to Earth in the 1960s.
A most tumultuous time in your history.
So much so, in fact, that I am having
difficulty getting an accurate reading.
Commander Spock,
I have located the pulse.
The energy signature proceeds
through time until, ...there.
This must be the focal point.
The temporal foci should bring us
within immediate proximity of whatever
is causing the disturbance.
Our research indicates that
you will automatically return
when your mission is a success.
Don’t ask me how the Guardian knows.
Five years to go!
Four!
This was easier with my
veins full of cordrazine.
Three.
Two.
Now, Captain.
Commander, I thought you said
we were heading for the 1960s?
This looks more like,
the end of the century.
The beginning, actually!
The readings indicate we have
successfully travelled to 2006,
where the anti-proton
readings are the strongest.
well done, Spock. Now what?
The signal emanates from that direction.
And what do you suggest we do?
Knock?
Yes?
Good afternoon, Miss...
Oh, my...
It's you!
My name is Jim Kirk. We were hoping...
Of course!
Captain Kirk.
Won't you come in, please?
My name is Veronica.
I'm so delighted that
you've finally made it.
Ma'am.... Veronica,
you were expecting us?
Well, I must admit, I had my doubts.
I've been waiting a long time.
Please, sit down.
He always said you'd show up.
Sooner or later.
He made this tape for you.
Yes, it works, it works! Just sit down!
Hello there.
Commodore Decker.
Yes.
He made this two years ago.
He died 8 months later.
Commodore Matthew Decker.
This is my report.
If you watching this tape, it means someone
from Starfleet, has come looking for me.
I betting it's Jim Kirk.
But, whoever it is,
I'm sorry I missed seeing you.
Now first of all: Please, don't worry.
I did fine.
Thanks to Veronica.
You know that I commandeered a
shuttlecraft from the Farragut.
And after setting a course
down the maul of that...
Planet-killer.
I locked the autopilot, in case I
lost my nerve.
One minute, I was staring into
the face of the devil incarnate.
And the next I'm...
flat on the floor,
of the shuttlecraft.
Drifting in space.
I must have blacked out.
The thing was gone.
The spaceships were gone.
The radio was silent.
All I could do was set
a course for Earth.
But when I got here...
I discovered, I was stuck in the past.
I was in pretty bad shape.
That was when Veronica found me.
And nursed me back to health, as it were.
helped me to find my place,
make a home, here in the 20th century.
Well, 21st now I guess.
How many men can say that they
have seen three centuries?
I suppose I should apologize to Admiral Leslie,
for not trying harder to
get back where I started,
But,... you have met Veronica.
And now, it seems the years
have finally caught up with me.
So, this is my final report.
Decker, out.
But this does not explain
the tricorder readings.
Veronica, did Matt leave anything else?
You might say that. Yes.
Does this explain your tricorder readings?
Yes, Captain. The shuttlecraft, which
disappeared along with Commodore Decker.
If the micro-tapes are still intact,
Check it out, Spock.
Matt wanted me to give this to you.
Welcome back!
Since you're here, I assume...
Fascinating. Commodore Decker's
sensor data would indicate
that the weapon's conversion
drive emits chronitons.
Chronitons?
A quantum particle of time.
Concentrations of chronitons can cause
anomalous behaviour in the local time flow.
The Klingon Empire studied the use of chronitons.
They were highly unstable.
Dr MacGregor, I noticed the Enterprise
was mentioned several times throughout your logs.
Oh Yes, Captain. The Enterprise
seems to have a knack for
being at the centre of things.
Enterprise.
Fascinating.
[Computer] Working...
The Enterprise was the first ship,
to encounter the planet killer.
Yes, Captain.
And it was destroyed almost immediately.
Also true, Doctor.
In your time-line, not in mine.
Then the Enterprise is the key
Was it not supposed to be there,
so that its crew would survive?
Or perhaps it is the planet killer,
which was in the wrong place.
The wrong time, Mr Kargh.
Do you mean that thing
came from the future?
Yes, Doctor.
It arrived in your time where there
was no power great enough to stop it.
And it began burning worlds
to fuel its anti-proton engine.
The "Doomsday War". Which was
never supposed to happened.
Mr Kargh, you said chronitons were unstable.
Yes, sir.
Could that be what happened, then?
When we detonated the Constellation,
could we have somehow of caused
a dangerous chroniton-burst?
And a smaller reaction from the
shuttlecraft could have triggered
the chronitons to send
Commodore Decker back in time.
Commander Spock
Could we somehow use
that to our advantage?
Cause a reaction that would send
this thing back to its own time?
No, Captain.
One starship would not
be able to generate
a reaction of sufficient magnitude.
Understood.
And two?
Two ships, would have a better chance.
Jim, what are you thinking?
We don't have two ships.
Yes, we do, Bones!
We have the Enterprise.
The Enterprise is in the past.
Time-travel, Captain?
We know exactly where and when the Enterprise will
encounter the first doomsday machine.
If we could be there at the same time...
Captain, the slingshot effect is not precise.
We could emerge hours or weeks from our target.
That may not be necessary.
Shuttlecraft McAuliffe. You have
been cleared for restricted airspace.
Continue on this heading until instructed to land.
Affirmative.
McAuliffe out.
If this area wasn't so
heavily shielded we would...
We would have used
the transporter.
Where would be the fun of it?
Professor Daniels discovered
this about eight months ago.
A natural dam burst downstream
and all of this was exposed.
The Federation pronounced it off-limits
and certainly we all had clearance level Alpha.
No kidding.
I'm trying to figure out what it's for.
Colonization, perhaps.
- Or invasion.
- Or research or espionage
or purely voyeurism.
The "why" has been our biggest question.
You have studied it, of course.
Not as much as we'd like.
To tell you the truth,
we are a little afraid of it.
That is wise.
If you intend to use this, to take
the Farragut back in time,
my primary concern is whether or not it will operate,
once it's cut loose and towed into space.
It's my thought too, but you might have
to use your tractor beam, to control...
No, we won't.
Mr DeSalle?
Well, sir,
I think I can fly Farragut
straight into this thing.
What?
You mean down here?
You have the precise dimensions, right?
Well, of course.
There's got to be less than a
100 feet clearance behind there.
If we're wrong about the
way this thing works...
Yes, we'll wind up as
cave paintings. I know.
Maybe, a test using a shuttlecraft?
[Communicator rings] Kirk, here.
Captain, long range sensors have
picked up a doomsday-machine.
Heading and distance?
Sir, it's on a direct course to planet "Gateway"
Here?
They have been known to track the Warp signatures
of starships, for several hundred light years.
They followed us.
Estimates put it in firing range in two hours!
Keep me posted, Lieutenant. Kirk out.
Well that's, that. We don't have time for a test!
Mr DeSalle, a starship is a creature of space.
It's not meant to be flown in the atmosphere and
certainly not at the velocities we're discussing here.
Yes, sir.
But I think I can do this.
Kirk to Farragut.
Rand here, Captain.
Lt, notify the hangar deck
and prepare the crew for collision.
- Sir?
- You heard me, Rand.
Captain, I know Chris Pike.
He will not be easy to convince.
Commander?
Open your mind, Jim.
Our minds are merging.
My thoughts, to your thoughts.
This one memory - I share with you.
Talos.
Spock, what are you doing to him?
Thank you.
Spock.
Jim, are you okay?
I'm fine, Bones, fine.
Right now we've got to get Mr DeSalle
back in the driver's seat.
- Spock, you will remain here.
- Agreed, Captain.
You’re not really going to do this?
Well, considering our options,
doctor, we don't have a choice.
It's insane, we know nothing about this device.
I can transmit the specifications from my office.
But someone will have to stay to activate it.
I do have some experience in that regard.
[Intercom] All decks, this is the captain speaking.
You all know what we're about to do.
You’re aware of what's at stake.
No matter what happens, I want you all to know,
that there's no other crew,
I'd rather serve with.
On any vessel.
Kirk out.
Status report, Mr Scott?
Engineering ready as always, Captain.
DeSalle?
Helm standing by.
Rand?
Navigation ready, sir.
Mr Kargh?
Ship's systems show green, Captain.
Structural and aerodynamic
force fields at maximum.
Lt Uhura?
All decks report ready, sir. Telemetry output
established with the Vulcan's tricorder.
Opinion, Doctor?
I think you're a damn fool.
And that guy with the ears is even worse.
I'll take that as a "yes," then Bones.
Mr DeSalle, Red Alert.
Take us in.
Aye, sir.
Lt Uhura, open a channel to the surface.
Cmdr Spock, our nose is pointed towards the barn!
I suggest you open the door.
Very well, Captain.
What are you?
A question!
Gateway, I wish to...
Since before your sun burned hot in space,
and before your race was born
I have awaited, a question.
Range to go: 50 kilometres.
Come on, Spock.
Gateway, I wish to view the history of the planet Earth!
Now, DeSalle.
Hold your positions, everyone.
Lt Uhura, status report.
All decks report ready, Captain.
No injuries or casualties, sir.
Mr Rand?
All astro-navigation landmarks, confirmed.
We are 14 years in the past, Captain. The year 2254.
Well-done, Mr DeSalle. Well-done.
Sir.
The Enterprise.
Scanning.
Confirmed. Registry NCC-1701.
Constitution class.
And in a hurry to get
wherever it's going.
Hail them, Lieutenant.
Hailing frequencies open.
This is Captain James T. Kirk of the
USS Farragut, calling the Enterprise.
This is the U.S.S. Enterprise,
Capt Christopher Pike, commanding.
And Steve Garrovick is
Captain of the Farragut.
So who the devil are you?
That's going to be, somewhat difficult to explain.
But it's absolutely vital that
you listen to what I have to say.
I invite you to beam aboard the Farragut.
Bring your senior staff
with you if you prefer.
Captain, I have verified their ship's
registry and command codes.
But much of the vessels internal configuration
does not match fleet specifications.
- I can explain that, too.
- I just bet you can.
How about this, "Captain"?
You and your senior officers beam over here.
And I promise, I'll have a security team standing by.
Pike out.
Number one, care to hear this explanation?
Certainly, sir.
Dr Boyce, meet us
in the transporter room.
You bring a Klingon to my ship,
and I'm supposed to trust you?
All explanations are off,
take them to the brig.
No, wait!
Captain Pike, you're right.
At least sort of...
It's well...
We're from your future.
Well, Doctor?
They are as they appear to be.
Two humans and one Klingon.
Completely normal.
As for if they are from the future...
Fleet personal roster, shows a James T. Kirk
assigned to USS  Farragut, Lieutenant Junior Grade.
Captain Pike, you were about...
You still haven’t said why you
are commanding the Farragut.
I have been in command of the Farragut for
the last ten years. Since Garrovick died.
It's not in the computer.
We could have destroyed
you with our torpedoes,
long before we were in range of your phasers.
Have you asked yourselves why we didn't?
I can think of a hundred reasons.
Perhaps to commandeer the
Enterprise, as you did Farragut.
I didn't commandeer the Farragut.
You are approaching a source of
high temporal disturbance, am I right?
[Intercom] Spock here. Captain, we are approaching
the coordinates of the temporal disturbance.
Thank you, Lieutenant.
have Mr Tyler reduce speed to half impulse.
And when you get there, you'll find
a device that's so destructive,
it will be laying waste to planets
for many years to come.
Chris, someone told me that you
were going to be difficult to convince.
He told me to remind you that you
once lost your heart on a world
where leaves sing and dreams find life.
Who told you that?
Another Starfleet officer who holds
his former Captain in high regard.
They tell me he is going to be
my first Officer in the future.
At least, if we survive,
to face the future.
Commander Spock.
Report.
Captain, we're approaching the
coordinates of the time ripple.
And we are not the only one.
Raise the Klingon.
No response, Captain.
It's not the same.
No. But maybe this is what they looked
like before giving years of battle.
Or perhaps this is a design from the opposing side.
The winning side.
Do you have something to share?
Captain, that is an unmanned
weapon from the future.
That's ridiculous. It would have been impossible
for a technology to have advanced so quickly.
It is not our weapon.
But we do have an idea on
how to destroy this thing.
My science officer will provide you
with the necessary specifications.
Chris, our two ships are going
to have to work together,
if we are going to destroy this thing.
You have one minute to beam back
to your ship and transmit the data.
Kirk to Farragut.
Get us back quick, Rand.
And stand-by to raise
the deflector shields,
as soon as we're aboard.
Yes, sir.
Red Alert.
Shields at full intensity.
Red Alert. All hands man your battle stations.
This is not a drill.
- You know what to do, Mr Kargh?
- Aye, sir.
Rand, plot an intercept course.
Let's see if we can take some
of the heat off the Klingons
Ships weapons at full charge, Captain.
I suggest you target these coordinates.
Very good. Mr Tyler, one
quick pass, to get its attention.
Aye, sir.
I think you've got its attention, Captain.
Recharge weapons. Number one,
what's your summary of Kirk's data?
I'd say they are being optimistic, Captain.
That was a disruptor hit.
Captain, the Klingon is firing at the Enterprise.
- Hail them.
- The Klingon is hailing us, sir.
I'm Captain James T....
Stay out of this fight, Earther.
We don't need help from your garbage scow.
And your weapons of peace.
And your weakling starship.
This prize is ours!
Commander, without our help,
there will be no prize. You will die.
With honour.
(Evasive action)
Father.
Who dares?
I am Kargh.
Son of Korogh and Bregia.
(I speak the truth)
Sir.
The Enterprise is signalling, ready!
I see my son in you
But greatly changed.
What sort of trick is this?
It is no trick, father.
We are joined with the Earthers
to stop this killing machine.
Then together we shall!
Then afterwards, you'll join me
in skinning the Earthers!
(Torpedoes fired)
Father!
Captain, it's turning back towards us.
What the hell have they gotten us into?
Deflector modifications completed.
Waiting on the signal from Farragut.
I'm getting pretty damn tired of waiting for this Captain Kirk!
We'll send that monster back where it came from.
Captain.
I see it, Mr Kargh.
As soon as we're into position,
fire into that thing.
Captain, engineering reports,
deflector is over 120 percent.
It was never made for this kind of work.
The Enterprise wants to live
as much as we do, number one.
You won't fail us!
It is preparing to fire, Captain.
Keep us out of reach, DeSalle.
That was my plan, sir.
Kyle, take over navigation.
Dr McCoy to the bridge.
Medical emergency.
You call that, staying out of reach, Mister?
No, sir.
Uhura, can you raise the Enterprise?
I'll try, sir.
Enterprise, this is Farragut.
Come in, Enterprise... do you read?
Farragut calling Enterprise.
Please respond.
- Acknowledge.
- Aye, sir.
- This is crazy.
- Steady, Mr Tyler.
In order to make this work, we have to
stay right in the line of fire. This is suicide.
It's turning towards us again.
- Mr DeSalle.
- I'm trying, Captain.
Status, Mr Scott?
The circuits overloaded, Captain!
- How long do you intend this to go on?
- As long as it takes.
Captain, the Enterprise cannot survive another attack.
Sir, Enterprise is charging weapons.
Anti-proton readings are spiking.
The planet killer is also preparing to fire.
They'll be destroyed...
Kyle! DeSalle!
Primary systems failing.
Can't control the circuits, sir.
I am getting high anti-proton readings.
All hands brace for impact.
Enterprise hold your fire.
Well I'll be damned!
The Farragut distracted it.
Made it stop firing at us.
Kirk took the heat of us.
Let's see if we can do the same for him.
- Under and over, Mr Tyler.
- Aye, sir.
Captain. I have been studying
the data from their planet-killer.
There may be a way to slow it down,
but it involves a...
... considerable amount of waste.
All this, for a history we don't know?
For people we may or may not become?
Captain. Call it off while you still can.
Shield energy is fluctuating, Captain.
Sir, the Enterprise, it is gone!
Gone?
They intercepted the beam meant for us - and then
Vaporized!
Casualty reports coming in from all decks, sir.
- Kyle.
- Sir?
Class-K planetoid, bearing two three zero.
Are we going to hide, Captain?
Hide? Your damn right, Mr Kargh.
Because I'm not ready to die with honour.
Kirk, this is Pike. Veer off!. Veer off!
Captain, it's...
Do it, helm, full thrusters.
(Success)
That will take the wind out of her. Right or not.
Kirk, if that fancy ship of yours,
can get off the mat,
it's time we finished this thing off.
Aye, Aye, Captain.
Helm, firing position.
- Keep it steady, Mr Tyler.
- I'm trying, sir.
- Number one?
- Readings are off the scale, Captain.
It is working.
Lt Uhura, stand down from
red alert and hail the Enterprise.
Coming on screen, sir.
- Captain.
Well, Kirk.
I'm surprised to see that fancy ship,
of yours, still in one piece.
Looks like the Enterprise will be around,
for a few more years, as well.
Although may heaven help the engineer
that's got to oversee that refit.
Refit?
What makes you think she needs a refit?
Thanks for your help. The Guardian
should retrieve us soon.
- Good luck, Captain Kirk.
- The same, Captain Pike.
Mr Kargh?
I have no explanation, Captain.
All indications are that by
correcting the time-line,
we should be returned to our own history.
It seems Mr Kargh miscalculated.
The planet-killer moved ahead
in time by only a few years.
How few?
- Uncertain.
- We will have to go after it.
Request permission to return to duty.
Granted, Lieutenant.
Assume your station.
Mr Kargh, feed your time calculations
to the navigation console.
- Rand - you have to follow it.
- Sir?
It gives off time ripples.
You and DeSalle will have to
track it by the flow of time.
Flows, eddies, bent blades of grass.
Whatever it takes.
- Yes, sir.
- Understood, Captain.
Mr Kargh,
Prepare their calculations
for a sling-shot effect.
Hold on, Kirk. Our two ships together,
barely survived last time.
The Enterprise will see this through.
Out of the question, Chris.
The Enterprise could never survive
the pounding of breakaway.
Shall I alert Starfleet, Captain?
No.
Even telling that many people,
may contaminate the future.
Just keep your eyes open for us.
Kirk out!
Helm, let's go.
600 days to go...
400,.. 300,.. Mr Rand.
I see it.
Adjusting course.
Farragut, do you read?
We're still in the past.
Mr Kargh?
Our time coordinates are correct, Captain.
I think I can clear up the signal, sir.
On screen, Lieutenant.
Farragut, do you read?
- Pike calling Farragut.
- Pike?
Where's Enterprise?
How did you know where to find us?
Find you? I wasn't even looking.
It is possible the currents in time
we were following…
Also washed Pike up on the same shore.
And the planet-killer is
less than 15 minutes behind us.
I was afraid you were going
to say that, Mr Kargh.
Kirk, I've got a J-class full of
green cadets on a training mission.
A J-class vessel may not
have enough power...
That's why you are headed
for the hangar deck, Mr Kargh.
I want you to find out how many shuttlecraft
and how much anti-matter, we can spare.
- Mr Scott.
- Aye, sir.
Take the mains offline and ramp them
up 25 points past the red line.
I don't want that thing to have any
trouble finding us at the supper table.
Now on your way.
Fleet Captain, shall we make sure our
guest receives the appropriate welcome?
Your place or mine?
Scott to Bridge.
It's time to ring the dinner bell.
Alright, beasty.
Come and get it!
Stand-by, DeSalle.
The Doomsday machine is coming in range.
- That's your cue, Mr DeSalle.
- Aye, sir.
Five,
Four,
Three,
Two,
One,
Zero.
Sir,
I am getting massive anti-proton readings.
On screen.
Shields. Full reverse.
Get us out of here.
Life support's gone!
Main power failure.
Switching to auxiliary.
Auxiliary will not be enough for
the deflector charge, Captain.
We need more power.
More direct power!
Captain, that heading will take us right...
Right into the belly of that beast.
Kirk, what the blazes are you doing?
Saving the future.
Not alone.
Computer, this is captain.
- Destruct sequence! Code One...
- Captain, I'm getting new readings.
From where?
This is Admiral Kirk.
Get out of there, NOW!
Do it, helm, full thrusters.
It's not dead, just knocked out for a while.
Then let's finish it!
The anti-proton charge will only overload
when the machine is operating.
He's right. The chance will come soon enough.
I suggest you begin your repairs.
I'm getting pretty damn tired of this!
Is time travel just something
you guys do in the future?
Chris, it's good to see you on your feet.
I'm guessing that you're
from the future, Admiral?
That is a logical assumption.
2373 to be precise.
You both look, remarkably well.
Ambassador Spock and I have been
through death and life together.
That is an understatement.
Admiral, I assume your
appearance here is no accident.
No.
In our time-line, the destruction of the
Farragut was insufficient,
to stop the planet killer.
We pulled every ship out of mothballs
to fight those things.
Science, of the 24th Century, is sufficiently
advanced to destroy a doomsday-machine.
Without sacrificing a starship or her crew.
And if we can stop this one,
this war will never occur.
But we have to get it from our time to yours.
- It's as simple as that.
- Captain Pike
I am reading high levels of delta-
radiation aboard your vessel.
The baffle plating around our
reactor took the worst beating.
We're making repairs. Pike out.
Admiral?
They don't say goodbye in the future?
No, more than that, he knows something.
Let's see your readings from the Guardian.
Captain?
There it is.
Farragut to Kirk. Admiral, I know
what you and Spock are trying to do.
You can't do this.
Things have to follow their natural course.
It's not the natural course,
if it's because that thing attacked.
Isn't that what we are trying to do, here?
making right what the doomsday
machine put wrong?
But this isn't wrong.
Chris Pike's accident is part of your history.
It should be part of mine.
Not this time
Admiral, there's got to be another way.
Captain, believe me when I say,
this is the better way.
The Enterprise transporters
have been activated.
Someone just beamed aboard the Daedalus.
Admiral.
- Kirk!
- He's stopped transmitting, sir.
Open that door and you will flood
this ship with delta radiation.
Not if we seal this room and recirculate the air.
Captain. Chris, you cannot.
Maybe you're right.
They'll die if we don't get them out.
Chris!
Ambassador, you are needed
back aboard the Enterprise.
Captain, Enterprise has
reactivated her transporter.
Status report, Mr Scott.
- Everything's ready, Captain.
- Well done, Scotty.
- Kargh, contact both ships.
- Yes, sir.
We have played tag with
doomsday long enough.
It's time we finished this.
Readings off the scale.
Anti-proton energy was at
sufficient levels, Captain.
It has gone back where it came from.
Well done, Admiral, well done!
Captain,
I am getting dangerously high readings
of delta radiation, from the cadet vessel.
Located near the aft reactor room.
No fatalities as best as I can tell.
Fleet Captain Pike has suffered
severe radiation poisoning.
The Daedalus will make it to Starbase 11,
where he will receive the best medical attention.
I wish we could have done more.
We will, Captain.
We will.
It's only a matter of time.
Oh, Jim
Contact Carol.
It's a boy.
[Tanoy] Dr Donovan, please report to
astrophysics lab...
[Two beeps = No]
Do not despair.
There are alternatives.
The Spock, you know will soon arrive.
His plan will work, Captain.
It is a foregone certainty.
But I must know it is what you want.
[Two beeps = No]
Captain, do you remember what Dr Boyce
often said about living one's life to the fullest?
One lives life as it happens.
Meeting it head on,
or turning his back on it and withering away.
Do not choose to wither away.
Live long and prosper.
Energize.
[One beep = Yes]
Captain Pike?
You remember these Gentlemen?
They wanted to visit you.
Spock to Enterprise.
One to beam-up.
[Gateway] Time has resumed its shape.
All is as it was before.
Many such journeys are possible.
Let me be your Gateway.
English Subtitles by Peter Walker
www.startreknewvoyages.de