JERRY HSU: You could do a trick
to land there, maybe.
BRIAN ANDERSON: I bet
you could land
in it anyway, still.
Seems like it.
Maybe it's because I
have soft wheels.
I'm not sure.
JERRY HSU: That'd be
sex with your trick
and land in it anyway.
BRIAN ANDERSON: I know.
JERRY HSU: Because it's
not skate stop.
Does anyone skate
it, you think?
BRIAN ANDERSON: I don't know.
I don't feel like people do.
[GRUNTING]
BRIAN ANDERSON: Shit.
I'd like to roll away.
JERRY HSU: That's my board.
He better not break it.
BRIAN ANDERSON: Oh, that
fucking hurts.
JERRY HSU: Oh well.
BRIAN ANDERSON: That kitty
litter doesn't
let you land in it.
BRAD STABA: We used to skate
that thing every single day.
We would take the BART
from [INAUDIBLE]
straight to [INAUDIBLE].
And we would like buy a boombox
and bring a fucking
whatever mixtape and just push
play and skate that thing like
all day, smoke weed.
We didn't go there with
cameras, you know?
PATRICK O'DELL: You would
just go to session it?
BRAD STABA: We would go there
every single day, seriously.
The thing is like he didn't go
into skateboarding like, I'm
going to be a pro.
I'm going to get sponsored.
I'm going to make this tape,
and I'm going to send it to
this guy and they're going
to give me free shit.
It just happened, you know?
And if it didn't happen, he
would be doing like--
he'd be work for the city.
He'd be work for the park.
He'd be doing a normal job.
Just living, you know?
Now he's one of the best
skateboarders ever.
[GRUNTING]
BRIAN ANDERSON: That's a make.
I don't care.
I think that's a make.
PATRICK O'DELL: We'll
run the photo.
Did you get the photo?
JERRY HSU: Yeah.
It's already--
I'm sending it out virally.
BRIAN ANDERSON: Those rocks.
Fuck.
PATRICK O'DELL: What's up?
Welcome back to the show.
This week's about
Brian Anderson.
Brian is probably a little bit
different than some pro
skaters in that he's worked in
his life full-time jobs as
like a cook and all these
different things.
So I think he's one of those
skaters that really
appreciates probably being pro,
because he knows what he
has to go back to if
he doesn't skate.
The first video I remember him
in was the "Welcome to Hell"
Toy Machine video.
He had like shaved head.
This big, beastly guy who's
got a lot of pop.
He's really gnarly.
My favorite trick Brian Anderson
does is 360 flips.
I wanted to do this episode to
kind of get an insight into
who he is as a person.
So after the Beauty and the
Beast tour, I went up to San
Francisco to meet up with him
and see what his life's like.
And I don't know, I just wanted
to get in his head.
He seems like a really
intriguing
subject for the show.
And so this is it, the Brian
Anderson episode.
Hope you like it.
FEMALE SPEAKER: OK, what
can I get for you?
DONNY BARLEY: Yeah,
I want to get the
western omelette, please.
FEMALE SPEAKER: OK, white,
wheat, or rye?
DONNY BARLEY: Wheat, please.
Does that come with
home fries?
FEMALE SPEAKER: It does.
DONNY BARLEY: Can I add
bacon to the omelette?
FEMALE SPEAKER: Inside it?
DONNY BARLEY: Yeah.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Sure.
DONNY BARLEY: Thank you.
FEMALE SPEAKER: You're
welcome.
PATRICK O'DELL: Do you come
back to Carlton a lot?
DONNY BARLEY: Yeah,
I come back like
almost every weekend.
It's funny.
This place is all remodeled.
It looks good, but it's
not the same.
Me and Brian used to come here
all the time late night.
Just get coffees sometimes, and
then get fired up and go
on late-night missions
and stuff.
Skating, or coming back from
like a punk rock show.
This is where all the freaks
would hang out late night, so
it was fun.
And then, Brian--
I think he might have been like
11 or 12, and I remember
one day we were skating my
friend Jason's halfpipe.
And these two kids just kind of
walked up the driveway with
their knee pads around
their ankles.
And it was Brian and
his friend Joe.
Brian just jumped right on the
ramp and started doing
everything.
Like, we were pretty amazed.
BRIAN ANDERSON: I probably met
Donny when I was in like sixth
grade or seventh grade or
something like that.
I was on Donny and
Jason's team--
Team 911.
And they made me do all these
different slappies in
order to get on.
They're like, all right, you've
got to do backside to
fakie or whatever and
an Ollie Smith.
And I did all these things,
and they let me
ride for Team 911.
You get the little sticker
that's the 911 emergency call
that parents put on
their home phone.
And you put it right underneath
your front truck.
So I was psyched, dude.
DONNY BARLEY: So there's a
monument right here on the
right hand side.
We used to skate it
all the time.
And it's like a Vietnam
memorial or something.
See those little slants
right there?
We used to skate those
all the time.
The veterans would come by and
be like, ready to murder us
for skating a monument that
represented these lives that
have been lost fighting
this war.
I guess it is pretty
disrespectful, but when you're
young, you don't
comprehend it.
Brian's house is over here.
This is it, yeah.
That's the house right
there, the gray one.
Brian's room at one point
was in the three
windows on the top.
I remember like ollieing down
the stairs all the time when
I'd come hang with Brian.
So this little side street--
we had like all these little
ramps and boxes and little
rails and stuff.
And Brian would just to keep
them underneath this weeping
willow tree, and we'd
just drag them out.
But Brian's parents were
like super, super
mellow and super nice.
I think Brian's parents were
like maybe somewhat strict
with his older siblings, but
by the time Brain was a
teenager, they were
probably like, eh.
BRIAN ANDERSON: The
whole story is--
I think my art teacher in high
school was telling me that if
you you do a portrait, you can
check it in the mirror.
And if it still looks
proportionate, then you did
all right or whatever.
It'll help your art.
And then so I realized that's
a way to watch my favorite--
because I'm regular footed, so
I could watch all my favorite
goofy footers skate
regular footed.
So you could put your favorite
skater on TV.
And then you chill out here with
the mirror, and you can
like see your favorite skater
skate switch, on
the opposite foot.
So that's pretty cool.
So this is the only ghetto-ass
mirror I have.
Look at it, it's regular
footage of Keith Heath.
This is so tight.
Whoa, dude, so cool, man.
DONNY BARLEY: And he's just
always had this artistic
approach, as opposed to
athletic approach.
And that's the difference
between certain like amazing,
talented skaters, you know?
I feel like maybe I have an
athletic edge, but Brian--
he's always got his
flow on, man.
Even when he's just like getting
warmed up and stuff.
And when he was a kid, it was
all about like loose shots and
slapping curves and
just cruising.
Just his own world man--
that's the way it's
supposed to be.
It's like, you can watch the
videos and get things out of
the skate videos, and a lot of
the kids kind of mimic the
skate videos.
Brian--
I feel like he was smart enough
to take a little bit
from all the videos that he
liked and incorporate that
into his own little melting
pot or whatever, you know?
CHAD MUSKA: Just
doing it, man.
Like, needed a change in
life so here I am in
New York City, Soho.
Lights, camera, action.
The early '90s--
whenever that was-- or mid '90s,
late '90s, something--
somewhere in the '90s,
it all began.
And I started hanging
around with Jamie
Thomas, got on Toy Machine--
then a little group kind
of started to form.
It was like Satva, me, Jamie,
Panama Dan, and Ed Templeton,
of course, and Donny Barley.
And I think that was kind
of like the main
clique right there.
DONNY BARLEY: All of a sudden,
we're in our early '20s, and
I'm in California, and I'm
getting hooked up, and it's
unbelievable.
And then coming home and
telling Brian about the
success that I found and begging
him to come out West
to give it a shot--
because if anybody could have
made it, Brian could have done
it all day, any day.
CHAD MUSKA: Donny Barley was
like, oh man, you guys gotta
meet my homie Brian.
He's crazy.
He's like this crazy skater.
He's insane.
And we're all like, yeah,
you always hear that.
It's like everybody gots their
homie from back in the day
that's a crazy good
skater, you know.
So he's talking about him for a
while, and then one day, oh,
my friend Brian's in town, BA.
ED TEMPLETON: We were on a
filming trip during the
"Welcome to Hell" days.
I think Donny gets off the phone
with somebody and says,
hey, my friend back from Groton,
Connecticut's in town.
Is it cool if he comes
skate with us today?
DONNY BARLEY: I called him from
Huntington Beach-- like,
me and Ed and Muska and Jamie
are going to come up to Frisco
to film-- and you have to.
You have to get to
San Francisco.
I will pick you up.
I'll pay you back for
your bus ticket--
anything.
I just begged.
And I had already spent like six
hours in the van telling
these guys, when we get to
Frisco, my friend Brian's
going to come us.
You guys are going to
trip your balls off.
This kid's the best
skater ever, ever.
It's so corny thinking back,
but I think I did say
something like, hey man, if
you really want to make
something now's the day.
I just didn't know if this
opportunity was going to come
around again, you know.
BRIAN ANDERSON: I wasn't
concerned of fanning out on
them or nothing.
I didn't even know who
Jamie Thomas was.
Ed Templeton was like my
idol when I was little.
So Jamie Thomas was news
to me, and Chad Muska--
I didn't know who
he was, either.
And he wasn't "The Muska" yet.
CHAD MUSKA: We went skating,
and all of a sudden, I was
like, damn, this dude's doing
some crazy tricks.
He's got like ill [INAUDIBLE].
And he's messing around.
He's just like rolling and just
does like a 540 flip on
flat ground or something
like out of nowhere.
And you're just like,
what the hell.
And then all of a sudden, he
just started going around us
in and just started busting and
busting and busting and
like crazy, crazy ass shit that
like none of the pros
were doing.
And we're like this dude's
not even sponsored.
He hadn't even skated in two
years, and all of a sudden, I
was just so psyched on him.
I remember being like,
this guy's insane.
He can do any trick he wants
to do, anything.
ED TEMPLETON: He starts
killing it.
Real sketchy, though.
You could tell he doesn't
skate all the time.
But he ollied over the
rail to boardslide--
and it's in the video-- he
boardslides down the long rail
and comes off.
And he's just flapping
all over the place
when he does it.
And I think at that moment, we
were just all like-- here's
the whole Toy Machine team.
We're supposed to be these dudes
who slaughter stuff.
Everyone gets to these rails,
and no one's feeling anything,
and we're all being wusses.
And then this dude from
Connecticut just
manhandles this rail.
DONNY BARLEY: I think he did it
first try, or he slid half
of it first try.
And they were just like,
what the fuck.
Chad's like, Danny,
go get the camera!
And Jamie's running to the van
and going up to Brian like,
hey Brian, can you
do this again?
BRIAN ANDERSON: I didn't
know that it was
OK to refilm something.
Like, I would land it and be
like, ah, I landed it.
I didn't know that it probably
looked kind of gross and I
should do a smoother one.
Muska got hurt that day we
skated in San Francisco.
He tried to tailslide the
[INAUDIBLE] ledge.
I don't know if it ever
came out, but he
slammed really hard.
He was in the van, I remember,
after that.
He was like, I just want to
fucking smoke this bowl.
And I was like, whoa,
this dude's bumming.
I passed the lighter through
the window to
Chad, like, here dude.
I know you need to get
stoned right now.
You're so hurt.
DONNY BARLEY: Right when Chad
and Brian connected, I knew
that that was half the battle.
And then it was just a matter of
convincing Ed and Jamie to
put them on.
CHAD MUSKA: It took everybody
else a minute.
Everybody was kind of like, I
don't know, I don't know.
And me and Donny were
like, yeah.
And I remember Ed was like, oh
my god, this guy's dope.
I think Ed liked him because he
was tall and lanky, kind of
like Ed was.
So Ed was like, oh,
I like this guy.
ED TEMPLETON: I think
all of us--
especially me and Muska, because
Muska's there-- and
we're all like, holy crap,
this guy's amazing.
Let's put him on the team.
And Jamie was just
like, no way.
What're you guys thinking?
I don't know what Jamie will say
to this, but at the time,
he was not for it.
Obviously, we're not just going
to throw a guy on right
there on the spot.
So we told him, hey, we're
really interested
in you a real way.
Do you have any footage?
BRIAN ANDERSON: Those
guys said, make me
a sponsor me tape.
So I skated around in Sac
and got some cool
stuff with Mike Rafter.
And then we went to SF one day,
I was like, I want to
front side blunt side
Hubba Hideout.
I think I can do it.
And I did it.
So we put that in
sponsor me tape.
I shaved--
bicced-- my head.
So Jamie and Ed, once they saw
the front side blunt side with
the bicced head, they were like,
oh, this dude looks like
he just got out of
fucking jail.
Cool.
ED TEMPLETON: And we were just
blown away that we were
getting a sponsor me
video from a dude--
Donny's bro from Connecticut--
and he just bicced his head
and front-blunts Hubba
Hideout, which was just
completely ludicrous.
And I mean it was like,
chill-giving, almost.
The team watch and they're
like, holy fuck.
And that just submitted
him on.
I think Jamie was instantly,
definitely on.
Chad and I were already
like, we love the guy.
And I think everybody else on
the team was just like, yeah,
no-brainer.
Front-blunt Hubba Hideout
like a man.
Yeah, I put him on.
That was definitely the one
push-over thing that he did,
and he just looks so
bad-ass doing it.
MALE SPEAKER 1: In the Toy
Machine video when he shrinks
hubba with that look.
I'm like, who the hell
is this dude?
Like 6 foot fucking 9.
MALE SPEAKER 2: He took hubba
down a foot or two with those
fucking eyes.
PATRICK O'DELL: He had
a shaved head.
MALE SPEAKER 2: Yeah, and
just looking so beast
rolling up to it.
MALE SPEAKER 1: Comes around and
he just stares right at it
and he's just like oh, it got
scared and was all [INAUDIBLE]
and shrank a little.
Brother's going to fuck me up.
DONNY BARLEY: Brian Anderson--
he's from Connecticut.
We grew up skateboarding
together.
He's the best.
CHAD MUSKA: All of a sudden, he
had a part in a video and
he went literally overnight
from being like nobody, to
giving up skateboarding, to
coming in on a random visit--
he became sponsored and started
off to his career
pretty much like that,
unexpectedly.
So I think that was really cool
to see that all go down.
BRIAN ANDERSON: Jamie Thomas and
Templeton called me, and
they're like, all right
well, we're going to
make this video soon.
We want you to fly to San
Diego and work on it.
So I said OK, great.
I think that was the
first time I
ever flew on an airplane.
And I was taking off
in [INAUDIBLE]
like, whoa my head.
This feels crazy.
And I landed in San Diego.
Jamie picked me up in his Honda
Passport, and he said,
this is Elissa Steamer.
ELISSA STEAMER: I think I
remember that day, too.
BRIAN ANDERSON: I didn't know
that you were going to be on
Toy Machine, and I didn't know
much about it either.
And I didn't know anything
about you.
ELISSA STEAMER: I think I had
seen your footage it in the
computer, maybe.
BRIAN ANDERSON: OK.
And then we just stayed at
Jamie's house in Pacific Beach
and went out filming.
ELISSA STEAMER: I have this
bad reaction when somebody
wins a trick, I'll
scream, right.
And I'll always happen
to be around the
camera for some reason.
And I remember that kinker--
BRIAN ANDERSON: It was my last
trick and you went, whoa.
ELISSA STEAMER: Yeah,
yeah, yeah.
PATRICK O'DELL: You
know, it's funny--
I always thought that
was a kid yelling.
ELISSA STEAMER: That was me.
I was a little kid.
Not really.
20-year-old.
BRIAN ANDERSON: It was awesome
because I was psyched to just
be skating with people
that ripped
constantly, all day long.
CHAD MUSKA: I remember the
process for filming for
"Welcome To Hell." It was
a crazy process, man.
So every once in a while, I got
to stay on Jamie's couch.
And that was a privilege
and a curse at the
same time, I guess.
Because I'd wake up at like 6:00
in the morning to Jamie
blasting Slayer and getting a
pan and a tin and banging them
to my head and wake up with this
dick on my shoulder or
something like that,
crazy-like.
Jamie was crazy, man.
I woke up to a lot of crazy
shit at Jamie's house.
Jamie had an agenda
all the time.
He was like, OK, we're going
to wake up today, and I got
this new angle I'm thinking
about filming of you on the
handrail, and you're going
to bust it today.
BRIAN ANDERSON: In my
part there's a line.
Jamie's like, you should
half-cab up this curb, and
then-- but he didn't
command me.
He's like, Brian, maybe
think about--
but it's helpful.
I like that about Jamie.
CHAD MUSKA: Brian started
filming the illest video part
that was competing with
all of our parts.
And we're like, oh shit,
this dude's kiling it.
We have to step up our
game to keep up
with his part, I remember.
ED TEMPLETON: For sure when that
name came on the screen,
the collective skate audience
must have been like, Brian
Anderson, what?
But then he just proceeded to
slaughter everything and skate
super big hubbas and have
this kind of groove.
You can see it in his lines.
He does a trick and does
a couple swerves.
He's just got this jazz to the
way he skated in that video.
And all of us were just
super-psyched on it.
CHAD MUSKA: And it was like the
video's coming out, we've
got to finish it.
And we worked it so hard
in the video--
at the premiere it kind of all
just fell apart that night.
DONNY BARLEY: Sure enough, Jamie
tried his ass off, but
for some reason the
computer crashed.
CHAD MUSKA: And it was, this was
the reason, and that was a
reason, and people were
drinking, and I was drinking,
and the kids were upset.
The kids wanted the videos so
there's a lot of crazy energy
that all came out
in one night.
I quit the team.
They kind of put me back on.
And then I quit again.
And then they kicked me off
and it was like this whole
thing, and it just was time
for me to move on.
DONNY BARLEY: The video
was supposed to be--
Chad, I think, was supposed
to have the last part.
Once Chad was gone, I think we
went back in rearranged it.
And so we hit the road.
And we brought the
video with us.
And every demo we'd show up and
get out of the van and try
to rip as hard as we
could for the kids.
Usually, we'd end up back
in the skate shop.
The kids would watch the video
and it was really, really nice
to see the reception
of the video.
It was so positive.
Kids would watch it and just
walk out of the skate shop
speechless.
BRIAN ANDERSON: I didn't know
how gnarly people were going
to look at "Welcome to Hell."
And at that time in
skateboarding--
obviously after amazing,
amazing Plan B
videos, and all that--
I feel like maybe there wasn't
anything huge besides
"Indecent Exposure"
or something.
So I think Jamie blew lot of
kids' minds with "Welcome to
Hell."
ELISSA STEAMER: I had
no idea what I was
getting myself into.
You know what I mean?
I had no idea it was going to
be so heavy of a video.
Because of the Toy
Machine video--
I had never even seen a Toy
Machine video before.
BRIAN ANDERSON: After that video
came out, because people
didn't know who I was, I went on
this tour and I had an easy
time doing demos.
Because they were watching Jamie
and Ed and Maldonado and
Satva, so I would just kind
of skate around, and that
introduced me to doing demos.
Because otherwise, I probably
would have been
like, uh, this is weird.
ED TEMPLETON: The rad times
about that era for me was just
tour, as a general.
I was just, like some of
the funnest tours ever.
For me, shooting photos I guess
is what I'm saying.
Like I was documenting
this whole like--
just those guys,
just the team.
I guess you can kind of equate
it to some people have this
like, I was the high school
captain of the football team
and the king of the prom,
or something.
And they live their whole life
looking back on those one
achievements in high school.
It's like, for me, that era is
one of those things I look
back on, and just be like,
man, those were
the best times ever.
Those are the times
of our lives.
That was right before the era
where it was real important to
be filming all the time.
So demos and fun were the main
focus, not let's go use every
spare minute at a spot and
trying to get footage.
It was literally like, let's go
buy a raft and go rafting
for the hell of it.
Or eat good food, skate spots
when you feel like it, show up
at the demo and kill it,
that kind of stuff.
BRIAN ANDERSON: Skating
for Ed was great.
Ed had never messed with you.
We could smoke all the weed we
wanted and drink beer, and
that was fine.
because he knew we were
all down to skate.
And we all would wake up and go
do the best demo we could.
ELISSA STEAMER: Like friends
are friends, right?
But it's almost like you form a
different special bond with
like a teammate or somebody
that you travel with
all the time for--
you know?
BRIAN ANDERSON: When we were
partying and stuff, I was kind
of her personal bodyguard.
ELISSA STEAMER: Yeah.
Where were we before we
came here, Donny?
I've still got to make a book
of people's stories of
dragging or something.
But, yeah, he's protected
me a lot.
PATRICK O'DELL: Tell
me about that.
BRIAN ANDERSON: Love
protecting her.
ELISSA STEAMER: Oh, just like
get in between some angry
person and me, or carry me home,
or find me on the side
of the road, or something.
BRIAN ANDERSON: Sometimes
somebody would be saying some
inappropriate things.
ELISSA STEAMER: Inappropriate,
that's the word.
BRIAN ANDERSON: Just
like, come on.
And I'm not a fighter
but I certainly
have a lot of sisters.
I feel this need
to protect her.
ED TEMPLETON: This was just
funny because Elissa had
dranken way too much the night
before and was just completely
fucked in the morning.
She had already barfed
there on the curb,
right where she's sitting.
Mike had some porn mag,
and it was just funny.
I wanted to kind of get a shot
of like the stuff Alissa has
to put up with, driving on tour
with a bunch of guys.
Constant porn mags everywhere,
and girls walking by the van
definitely get commented on
in pretty rude ways, and
obviously Elissa just like
laughs at all that stuff and
thinks it's funny.
ELISSA STEAMER: It really
wasn't difficult.
It was kind of like the
funnest thing ever.
Because, I mean, I had to skate
all the time in order to
get into the position to go on
tour, so therefore all I hung
out with was guys all
day, every day.
So it was just like
the same thing.
It was just like switching from
one pack of wolves to
another pack of wolves.
PATRICK O'DELL: Yeah.
BRAD STABA: Brian's
great, man.
I had to get him to
come out here.
Like, he usually denies me
for most everything.
PATRICK O'DELL: When we were
filming this, he'd be like,
ah, I'm super busy,
but OK, let's just
try to make it work.
Then I'd be like, so what do you
have to do that you're so
busy today?
Oh, I gotta go to the
grocery store.
And it was like really
[INAUDIBLE] stuff.
BRAD STABA: Stuff that he could
just do in two seconds.
And you know he lives
right next to the
grocery store, right?
PATRICK O'DELL: Yeah,
that's what he'd do.
He's right next to
the Safeway.
BRAD STABA: Dude, he could hop
his back fence, and literally
he's in the Safeway.
So he doesn't use the going to
the grocery store one on me
because I'll call him
out in a second.
But yeah, he'll whip out some
fucked up excuses, man.
Pull.
I met Brian in 1997.
And then we went on
this Europe trip.
It was Donny Barley, me, Brian,
and Josh Spiegel.
DONNY BARLEY: Brian and
Brad totally were like
instant best friends.
And I think they've just
been homies ever since.
Just weird personalities
that kind of click
for whatever reason.
PATRICK O'DELL: So then
"Jump Off A Building"
was the next video?
BRIAN ANDERSON: Oh, that's
right, yeah, "Jump Off A
Building."
PATRICK O'DELL: Is Donny Barley
in that, or had he
already left?
BRIAN ANDERSON: Nope,
Donny left.
He just didn't jive with Ed
for a little bit there.
ED TEMPLETON: "Jump Off A
Building" era was kind of like
a great era but also a strange
one at the same time.
Jamie had departed to
do Zero on his own.
Up until that point, Jamie's
took Toy Machine from--
obviously "Welcome to Hell" and
that whole era was a lot
of Jamie influence.
Me being lazy and having someone
who was super eager to
make the team rad and do all
this-- make the video awesome.
I was just like,
that's great--
do that.
When he left it was like,
oh, it's back to me.
I've got to do this up
to the same standard
that we just set.
So without Jamie, it
was kind of like
independent-contractor style.
I expected the team to go out
and film their own stuff.
Like go out and film--
give me the footage.
That was that era.
BRIAN ANDERSON: Skating was just
so easy to go film then.
I was going out with Brad
and Moreford every day.
And Brad would film me.
Brad filmed tons of my
tricks in that video.
BRAD STABA: Dude, he did this
gnarly tailslide down this
hubba ledge.
I videod it.
That stood out only because
I was behind the lens.
I really only pay attention to
stuff that involves myself.
ED TEMPLETON: At one point, the
pressure starts coming.
It's like, hey, we want you
to do this and that.
We want you get a photo for an
ad, or there's another video
we're working on.
Let's film.
And if your main focus is just
like, I could just as soon be
a chef than skateboard, then
obviously you're not going to
give your sponsor exactly
what he wants.
I remember like just
philosophizing with him,
saying something like, you
can do all that stuff.
You can still become
a chef if you want.
But you have this talent
at skateboarding.
And you can just do this for
a couple of years and
potentially make
a lot of money.
And I feel like he just
switched in his head.
He just decided, yeah, I'm
just going to slaughter
skateboarding, and
easily did it.
He just won the Moonster
contests when he wanted to,
and the world championship--
won it back-to-back, I think.
And started just killing
contests and making big
contest money and pretty much
put himself on the map just by
deciding to.
PATRICK O'DELL: How'd you find
out that you were going to be
Skater of the Year?
BRIAN ANDERSON: Well, Gabe said
he wanted to work on an
article with me to get me
shooting photos for it.
And then towards the end of the
year, I kind of realized
what those photos were
probably for.
I think around November
it was like--
somebody told me, or--
oh, and then I had to
shoot the cover.
So I knew.
The cover was me in a chair with
like a cigar and a fake
Toy Machine diamond medallion.
There's like wheels everywhere
and trucks.
It was supposed to look
like a No Limit
album cover, basically.
BRAD STABA: When he got
Skater of the Year,
it was pretty cool.
PATRICK O'DELL: I remember
I went to that party.
I remember it was like
Donny and Maldonado
and all those people.
BRAD STABA: Yeah.
Alls I remember is I saw
him for a while.
We hung out, and then I
guess I had his check.
You know they give those guys
the big checks, you know?
So I was in charge of his
check and somebody
responsible, like Ed or
somebody, was in charge of the
trophy, I think.
Brian was just in charge
of blacking out.
BRIAN ANDERSON: During
Skater of the Year--
I'm shooting photos for
Monty Carol calls me and is
like, hey dude, I heard you're
[INAUDIBLE] at Toy Machine.
I just wanted you to know,
we could help you out
over here at Girl.
I'm like, wow man,
that's so nice.
I was blown away.
And I said, no man,
I'm not doing it.
So I didn't do it, obviously,
and I stayed.
But I was really sick
of Toy Machine.
And I knew dudes were over it.
We went on a tour, and Maldonado
was bummed, Kerry
was bummed on Ed.
At the end of that, I called
Rick and I was like, hey dude,
I was wondering if that the
thing that Mike said--
that offer--
is still there, because I'm
kind of over this thing.
And Rick was very concerned.
He said, what about Ed
Templeton, dude?
I don't want to be that guy
that takes you from Ed.
And I was like, well dude,
I'll deal with Ed.
I care about him--
I love him, but this is my
progression in life.
ED TEMPLETON: Kerry left, Bam
left, Mike left, Elissa left,
so Brian's call was I'm going
to quit, because we have to
rebuild Toy Machine
from where we are.
And I don't want to do that.
But what am I going to do?
I based all my relationships
with the riders on the team on
friendship.
So none of these quittings was
like me flipping out or being
pissed at anybody.
It was always just like
OK, are you sure?
OK, go for it, you know,
what can I do?
It was sad, for sure.
I was fully bumming.
I've had these periods where
people have quit, and it
leaves me no choice but to try
to get in this rebuild mode
and try to be optimistic.
But I can't lie when I say
there's like tearful nights
when that stuff happens
and self-doubt
comes into the picture.
Am I blowing it somehow?
Am I not not making Toy Machine
not what it can be?
Is Girl that much better?
How do we run stuff that makes
everyone want to quit?
I don't know, I just
start freaking out.
I feel good about it on the
fact that I base it on
friendship and that I care about
Brian's career more than
I care about my Toy
Machine business.
So if he's going to be happy,
then I'm happy.
Brian went on to Girl and
continued his destruction,
basically, without
Toy Machine.
BRIAN ANDERSON: Me and Jake
Phelps found this on the river
in China in Beijing, I think?
Wait, is Beijing the one where
they cut down all the forest
and now it's really
windy there?
Right?
JERRY HSU: I don't know.
BRIAN ANDERSON: What's the
other major city there?
JERRY HSU: Shanghai.
BRIAN ANDERSON: Shanghai.
What's the one with the river
going through it?
JERRY HSU: Shanghai's
got the spots.
PATRICK O'DELL: Jerry knows
everything about China.
JERRY HSU: Anything else you
want to know about China, you
could just ask me.
BRIAN ANDERSON: This is where
I go grab my boards.
This is the first
in the quiver.
I'm really proud of
my quiver, lately.
We screwed my shoes in here.
And I thought I was going to
be able to boardslide a
handrail with them on.
Just rollerskate up--
I'm regular footed, so I thought
I could front board
[INAUDIBLE] handrail.
What I did was I was actually
standing on the handrail, and
I had Frank [INAUDIBLE]
he held me up and I balanced on
the rail, and then he ran
away and I jumped off the
handrail in the air and he
took the picture.
It was pretty scary, actually.
This is one board right now.
This is a tapered tail.
It's got a really good
tail for 360 flips.
So I call this my three-flip
board.
I'll ride my own pro board.
Sometimes I put some stickers
kind of close to my name or
almost over it.
I've done that before.
And then there are
times when like--
what the hell, man, I should
ride my board, you know?
This board totally sucks
to skate but I
put it together recently.
It's a Steve Alba, obviously.
I spent a lot of time on the
sticker job on the top.
Probably some serious Buddha
involved with that one.
Yeah, Efil4zaggin, man--
I forgot all about
Efil4zaggin.
PATRICK O'DELL: What's
Efil4zaggin?
BRIAN ANDERSON: I think
it's the NWA record.
It's Niggaz4Life backwards.
This is my real Steve Olsen.
And that's it.
This one's really fun.
So my quiver is up to--
these don't count--
seven.
That's pretty cool.
And I skate them all,
like all week long.
That's it.
PATRICK O'DELL: What skaters are
out now or that you know
that really inspire you?
BRIAN ANDERSON: Well, my
favorite skater is probably
Nick Trapasso.
And oh, you know my
all-time favorite
skater ever is Ben Schroeder.
He inspired me.
Even the guys in my neighborhood
I grew up with
were always like man,
Schroeder-- that guy's just
kind of a beast.
And I think as I got
older I got taller.
So when I actually see
him live now, I'm
like whoa, I get it.
That's why I understand what
he does, because it's like
he's bigger than me, for sure.
But he's pretty oafy, and
it's like the best.
I love it.
PATRICK O'DELL: What about--
you were telling Jake that you
didn't read the magazines.
BRIAN ANDERSON: Oh, yeah,
just a long time ago.
It was like--
well, I'll be 33 this summer--
so it must have been three
years ago or something.
I don't remember
the situation.
He asked me something and
I was like, dude, I'm
30 years old, man.
I don't read the mags.
And he just loved that
for some reason.
I wasn't trying to be funny.
I was like, I don't know dude,
I'm trying to not look at
those things.
JAKE PHELPS: You had
that same shirt in
the Jerry Hsu episode.
PATRICK O'DELL: Yeah.
I wear it a lot.
You got anything to
say about Brian?
Can you--
JAKE PHELPS: Encapsulate it?
PATRICK O'DELL: Yeah.
JAKE PHELPS: He's just a
good, solid boarder.
He's easy on the eyes.
I hate to say it, but a lot of
people try wicked hard and
they end up missing it.
But Brian--
he comes in the park--
he does a full line
when he comes in here.
BRIAN ANDERSON: OK.
JAKE PHELPS: What are
you going to make?
Is it possible?
BRIAN ANDERSON: Change it up.
JAKE PHELPS: Spice it
up a little bit?
BRIAN ANDERSON: Switch,
slappy, half-gallon--
JAKE PHELPS: Oh, this is sick.
This is my favorite line.
This switch slappie on that
wall of doom is gnarly.
Watch this.
Go get them, B. Yeah!
Are you okay?
BRIAN ANDERSON: Shit,
I'm going slow.
JAKE PHELPS: Black socks
and shit, that's hard.
Back tail-- oh, here it comes.
15 seconds, world cup.
Yes, and that's time.
Did you see it?
15 seconds, Daniel and Bostic
where's my wine?
Fucking bitch.
PATRICK O'DELL: Is that
why you gave him
Skater of the Year?
JAKE PHELPS: Why I gave him
PATRICK O'DELL: Or why he
won Skater of the Year?
JAKE PHELPS: Well, he was Skater
of the Year because
he's just a solid dude.
He repps the mag and people
that are good.
I mean, it's a pretty
illustrious crew.
Some people win, some
people don't.
Chad Muska never got it, fuck.
BRIAN ANDERSON: It's going
to be mad rewarding, son.
I was watching like a baseball
game, and you see the coach
out there, and he's
like 65 years old.
I kind of realized he's coaching
because he loves
baseball, obviously.
So that made me feel better
about the future of
skateboarding.
Like well, it wouldn't be
strange if I stayed and worked
in skateboarding, I guess,
because it's something I
really like.
You know, like how somebody
would like baseball or
basketball.
Because sometimes you think
like, dude, this
skateboarding thing.
You see some bozos skating
down the street and
you're like, ugh.
But for us it's different.
We really, really like it.
So fuck--
I mean, why not?
I should be proud of that
and enjoy that, so--
it was kind of like something
I just told myself, or had a
realization that everything's
okay.
JAKE PHELPS: Ta-da!
BRIAN ANDERSON: I like
that switch grip.
It was the one I wanted to do.
Thanks, Pat.
It was fun.
PATRICK O'DELL: Thank
you, Brian.